<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title> China_Business </title>
		<image>
			<title>People's Daily Online</title>
			<link>http://english.people.com.cn/</link>
			<url>http://english.people.com.cn/images/en/top_logo_e.gif</url>
		</image>
		<description>People's Daily Online</description>
		<link>http://english.people.com.cn/90778</link>
		<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese embrace digital yuan as China further promotes pilot program ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096754</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096754.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 09:43:55 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> <strong>*Chinese people are embracing the digital yuan with a positive attitude. Thanks to the promotion of banking institutions, internet companies, and retail terminals, digital yuan now can be used in a wider range of scenarios.</strong></p> <p> <strong>*China has stepped up efforts to promote the digital yuan with pilot programs. Since 2017, the country has tested the use of the digital yuan in over 10 places from Shenzhen to Shanghai and Xiong'an New Area.</strong></p> <p> <strong>*China's digital yuan transactions hit nearly 87.57 billion yuan at the end of 2021, as the country ramped up research and pilot use of the central bank's digital currency.</strong></p> <p> GUANGZHOU, May 14 (Xinhua) -- In the Canton Tower located in Haizhu District, a landmark of the southern Chinese metropolis of Guangzhou, Zhang Ling, a shopper from southwest China's Sichuan Province, bought a souvenir. Unlike her usual transactions, this time she chose to pay in digital yuan, China's digital fiat currency, or the e-CNY.</p> <p> "I feel it is very convenient as it took me less than one minute to download the application and register an account," said Zhang. "There are also some discounts available now, so I'm willing to try the digital yuan."</p> <p> Like Zhang, many Chinese people are embracing the digital yuan with a positive attitude. Thanks to the promotion of banking institutions, internet companies, and retail terminals, digital yuan now can be used in a wider range of scenarios.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150855000014122697528.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Undated photo shows a customer paying in digital yuan (e-CNY) at a retail store in Guangzhou, south China's Guangdong Province. (Xinhua)</em></p> <p> <strong>MORE CONVENIENT</strong></p> <p> China has stepped up efforts to promote the digital yuan with pilot programs. Since 2017, the country has tested the use of the digital yuan in over 10 places from Shenzhen to Shanghai and Xiong'an New Area.</p> <p> The use of digital yuan is similar to that of WeChat Pay and Alipay, which are popular online payment apps in China. With QR code or Near Field Communication (NFC) techniques, the payment can be completed easily on mobile terminals of both shoppers and merchants. What makes digital yuan different is that it can still be used without a network.</p> <p> Tourists could pay in digital yuan at ticket windows, merchandise stores and restaurants from April 15, according to Liu Yiying, a finance manager of the management branch under Canton Tower Cultural Tourism Development Co., Ltd.</p> <p> "We launched preferential activities for digital yuan after the May Day holiday, which has attracted an increasing number of tourists," said Liu.</p> <p> In the tramline in Guangzhou's Haizhu District, the upgraded checking machines in passenger cars and stations also support digital yuan payment.</p> <p> Since the digital yuan payment was launched in April, hundreds of payments have been made cumulatively, with nearly 100 orders a day at most, according to Su Jun, deputy general manager of Guangzhou Tram.</p> <p> "From the perspective of enterprises' financial management, digital yuan improves the efficiency as the money paid by consumers can be transferred to our account in real time," said Su.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150856000153108145656.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 595px;" /></p> <p> <em>People walk past a sign of digital yuan (e-CNY) during the 2021 China International Fair for Trade in Services (CIFTIS) in Beijng, capital of China, Sept. 5, 2021. (Xinhua/Wu Wei)</em></p> <p> <strong>MORE INSTITUTIONS COVERED</strong></p> <p> The pilot version of the digital yuan app was released on major Android app stores and Apple's App Store on Jan 4. Currently, the designated operators of digital yuan cover major Chinese banks, such as Industrial and Commercial Bank of China (ICBC), China Construction Bank, and online banks.</p> <p> "We promote discount campaigns for people using the digital yuan in supermarkets such as Guangzhou Grandbuy and Guangzhou Friendship Store, which can effectively stimulate the enthusiasm of consumers," said an official with the Guangzhou branch of ICBC. "The merchants are also free of service charge at the same time."</p> <p> Many internet platforms that gather rich consumption scenes are also opening up to embrace the digital currency, such as JD.COM, Tencent, Meituan and Bilibili.</p> <p> By the end of 2021, there were more than 8 million applicable scenarios of digital yuan in the pilot areas via WeChat, a social software developed by Tencent. The company said it has deeply participated in the design, research, development and operation of the digital currency since 2018.</p> <p> According to data from Meituan, more than 5 million sub-wallets of digital currency were pushed to the Meituan App, and more than 4 million users spent digital yuan on Meituan from last September to early May.</p> <p> Several banks in south China's metropolis of Shenzhen are to cooperate with Meituan to distribute red packets of digital yuan worth 30 million yuan (about 4.42 million U.S. dollars).</p> <p> "The pilot project of Meituan is a beneficial attempt to advocate simple, moderate, green and low-carbon life through digital currency," said Cao Heping, a professor at the School of Economics of Peking University.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150857000565883392938.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>A passenger pays for a bus ticket in digital yuan (e-CNY) in southwest China's Chongqing, April 29, 2022. (Photo by Luo Ling/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> <strong>MORE CITIES INVOLVED</strong></p> <p> The People's Bank of China (PBOC) announced in early April that the pilot program would be expanded to more domestic cities, including Tianjin, Chongqing, Guangzhou, Fuzhou, Xiamen and six cities in east China's Zhejiang Province hosting the 19th Asian Games, following its successful operation over the past years.</p> <p> Beijing and Zhangjiakou were also included in the program after tests in the 2022 Olympic and Paralympic Winter Games.</p> <p> A number of application modes have taken shape in wholesale and retail, catering, tourism and payment of administrative fees, which cover both online and offline scenarios and can be replicated and promoted. The scale of users, merchants and transactions in the pilot areas has grown steadily.</p> <p> Guangzhou, as one of the pilot cities, has innovatively implemented new application scenarios such as granting talent subsidies and paying parallel imported cars with digital yuan and promoted the use of digital yuan in various scenarios such as transportation, supermarkets in business circles, tourism and online consumption platforms.</p> <p> China's digital yuan transactions hit nearly 87.57 billion yuan at the end of 2021, as the country ramped up research and pilot use of the central bank's digital currency.</p> <p> A total of 261 million personal wallets for the digital yuan had been opened, and the number of pilot scenarios had exceeded 8.08 million, said Zou Lan, an official with the PBOC.</p> <p> Zou said the central bank would continue promoting research and development of the digital fiat currency and further deepen the pilot use of e-CNY in retail services, government services, and other scenarios.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China greenlights two ChiNext IPOs ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096734</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096734.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:53:28 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) -- China's securities regulator has approved the initial public offering (IPO) registration of two companies on the country's NASDAQ-style ChiNext board.</p> <p> ChinaEtek Service &amp;Technology Co., Ltd., a Beijing-based IT services provider, and Shanghai Menon Animal Nutrition Technology Co., Ltd. will be listed on the Shenzhen Stock Exchange's board of growth enterprises, the ChiNext board, according to the China Securities Regulatory Commission.</p> <p> The companies should strictly follow the prospectuses as well as the issuance and underwriting plans while issuing stocks, said the commission.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's SMEs Development Index retreats in April ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096714</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096714.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:13:36 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) -- China's Small and Medium Enterprises (SMEs) Development Index, based on a survey of 3,000 SMEs, edged down 0.3 points from the previous month to 88.3 in April, the latest industry data showed.</p> <p> This is the third consecutive month of decline for the gauge, which is lower than that of the same period last year, said the China Association of Small and Medium Enterprises.</p> <p> Halted production due to domestic COVID-19 outbreaks, coupled with industry chain disruptions and high commodity prices, has made it more difficult for some companies to cover costs, said the association.</p> <p> The sub-indexes for industry, construction, transportation and postal services, wholesale and retail, as well as hospitality and catering retreated from a month ago, while that for real estate increased.</p> <p> The industry group calls for targeted support to virus-hit small businesses in the service sector, implementation of policies like tax and fee cuts, as well as efforts to keep prices and employment stable.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Oil prices rise as supply concerns persist ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096657</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096657.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:34:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NEW YORK, May 13 (Xinhua) -- Oil prices advanced on Friday as concerns over tighter supplies remain on the market.</p> <p> The West Texas Intermediate for June delivery added 4.36 U.S. dollars, or 4.1 percent, to settle at 110.49 dollars a barrel on the New York Mercantile Exchange. Brent crude for July delivery increased 4.1 dollars, or 3.8 percent, to close at 111.55 dollars a barrel on the London ICE Futures Exchange.</p> <p> The rally came despite data released Friday by Houston-based oilfield services company Baker Hughes showing that the number of total active drilling rigs in the United States rose by nine to 714 this week.</p> <p> Oil rigs in the United States rose by six to 563 this week , gas rigs rose by three to 149, and miscellaneous rigs stayed unchanged at two, showed the data.</p> <p> Concerns over supply risks lingered as the European Union (EU) worked on gaining support for an oil embargo against Russia.</p> <p> Last week, the EU unveiled a plan to phase out Russian crude oil within six months and refined products by the end of the year, as part of its sixth sanction package aimed against Moscow.</p> <p> Hungary and other Eastern European countries, whose economies are largely reliant on Russian oil, are not ready yet to accept the sanction package in its current form.</p> <p> Traders also weighed risks to the demand side.</p> <p> In its monthly report released on Thursday, the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries revised down its forecast for world oil demand growth in 2022, citing impacts from geopolitical tensions and the COVID-19 pandemic.</p> <p> For the week, the U.S. crude standard rose 0.7 percent, while Brent declined 0.7 percent, based on the front-month contracts.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Commentary: Reasons to remain confident in Chinese economy amid pandemic ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096634</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096634.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 09:49:33 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/49/1150674847762861189.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Photo shows customers check out at a Sam's Club warehouse store at Beicai Town in Pudong New Area, east China's Shanghai, May 2, 2022. Large retail companies in Shanghai have started to reopen their supermarkets amid the recent COVID-19 resurgence. (Xinhua/Chen Jianli)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- The surge of the Omicron variant of the coronavirus has exerted downward pressure on the Chinese economy. With an array of pro-growth policies to produce their intended effects, the risk is manageable and the sound fundamentals of the world's second-largest economy in the medium-to-long term will not change.</p> <p> To cope with the pandemic, China has applied a stringent dynamic zero-COVID policy. As the pandemic is still raging across the world and coronavirus continues to mutate, there is a great deal of uncertainty concerning how the situation will develop. The country has warned against any slackening in its efforts to control the virus.</p> <p> China's stance has been firm and clear -- unswervingly adhering to the dynamic zero-COVID policy while shoring up the economy and ensuring people's lives are affected as little as possible.</p> <p> Giving proper consideration to all these aspects is a difficult task. The earnest implementation of this policy is a major test for all regions and departments.</p> <p> A string of pro-growth policies is in the pipeline. China has already adopted multi-pronged fiscal measures in tax and fee cuts, public budget expenditure and bond issuance to stabilize the economy and ensure its people's wellbeing.</p> <p> Moreover, China has accelerated the establishment of a unified domestic market, comprehensively strengthened infrastructure construction, and deepened reform and opening-up across the board.</p> <p> The State Council and relevant departments are also rolling out detailed policies and measures to help industries, individually owned businesses and micro, small and medium-sized enterprises hit hard by the pandemic, and to stabilize market entities.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/78/15009916851255006974.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Photo shows staff members work in a workshop at Songz Automobile Air Conditioning Co. Ltd in Shanghai, east China, April 29, 2022. A total of 251 automakers and auto parts and components enterprises were included in the first batch of 666 companies on the city's "white list" designed to support firms to resume production amid COVID-19 control. (Xinhua/Zhang Jiansong)</em></p> <p> Chinese authorities have ample space and diversified tools for fiscal, monetary and other policies. They have rich experience in responding to downward pressure on the economy and will further strengthen regulatory control, and will do so when the time is right.</p> <p> The Chinese economy is off to a steady start this year, with its GDP up 4.8 percent year on year in the first three months. Despite the downward pressure, the fundamentals of the Chinese economy, including its strong resilience, enormous potential, vast room for maneuver and long-term sustainability, remain unchanged. After pro-growth policies gradually produce their intended effects, China's economic performance will improve.</p> <p> By contributing approximately 30 percent to world economic growth, the Chinese economy is the largest engine driving global economic growth. The Chinese economy is at a critical moment in overcoming its difficulties. It is only by remaining confident and rising to the challenges that China can turn adverse situations into opportunities, embrace its bright prospects, continue to inject dynamism into the stability and recovery of the global economy and bring broader market opportunities for all countries.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China’s trade in services moves onto fast lane of development ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096600</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096600.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 09:01:35 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0514/FOREIGN202205140850000325097852849.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 601px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on Sept. 7, 2021 shows the exhibition area of the 2021 China International Fair for Trade in Services (CIFTIS) at the China National Convention Center in Beijing. (Photo by Fan Jiashan/People’s Daily Online)</em></p> <p> China’s services trade has maintained fast growth. Data from the country’s Ministry of Commerce (MOFCOM) showed that China’s imports and exports of services totaled over 1.45 trillion yuan ($214.6 billion) in the first quarter of 2022, rising 25.8 percent year on year.</p> <p> Its exports of services grew 30.8 percent to 713.98 billion yuan and imports of services reached 743.01 billion yuan with a year-on-year increase of 21.3 percent. The growth of services exports outpaced import growth by 9.5 percentage points, resulting in a 56.4-percent drop in the country’s services trade deficit to 29.03 billion yuan from the same period last year.</p> <p> Zhao Zhonghui, director of the translation center of BERIS Engineering and Research Corporation in Qingdao city, east China’s Shandong province, has been busy dubbing a program of Shandong TV into Lao with her colleagues.</p> <p> “This is a new service export project we launched this year. We’ve so far finished translating the Chinese subtitles into Lao, English and Romanian, and basically accomplished the dubbing work,” said Zhao, adding that the program will be aired on Lao National Television and Romanian public television TVR in a few days.</p> <p> According to Zhao, the company completed the multilingual dubbing and subtitle translation of more than 10,000 standard episodes of TV programs in 2021. The programs it exported last year, which were 450,000 minutes in total length, have been broadcast on TV stations and online video platforms in 195 countries and regions and received over 10 billion hits globally, bringing the company an export value of several billion yuan.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0514/FOREIGN202205140851000026691279557.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 675px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on Sept. 7, 2021 shows the exhibition area of the 2021 China International Fair for Trade in Services (CIFTIS) at the China National Convention Center in Beijing. (Photo by Fan Jiashan/People’s Daily Online)</em></p> <p> During the rapid development of trade in services, knowledge-intensive service industry, as a key field, made remarkable progress and showed stronger export competitiveness, noted Zhang Jianping, head of the Center for Regional Economic Cooperation under the Chinese Academy of International Trade and Economic Cooperation.</p> <p> China’s trade in knowledge-intensive services climbed 14.1 percent to 615.66 billion yuan in the first quarter of the year, according to an official with the Department of Trade in Services and Commercial Services of the MOFCOM.</p> <p> Knowledge-intensive services exports expanded 16.3 percent to 350.06 billion yuan, among which exports of such fields as telecommunications, computer and information services, other business services, as well as intellectual property royalties registered fast growth, rising 22.1 percent, 14.6 percent and 11.2 percent, respectively.</p> <p> Imports of knowledge-intensive services grew 11.4 percent to 265.6 billion yuan during the period.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0514/FOREIGN202205140851000585875901609.jpg" style="width: 828px; height: 552px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>A busy container terminal of Haikou Port, south China’s Hainan province, August 29, 2021.</em></p> <p> The sound performance of China’s trade in services is attributed to Chinese enterprises’ increasing competitiveness and the government’s policies and measures.</p> <p> On August 26, 2021, China officially began to implement a negative list for cross-border trade in services in the southern island province of Hainan. The introduction and implementation of the negative list represented a major breakthrough in the management model of trade in services and signaled further opening-up in cross-border trade in services.</p> <p> An MOFCOM official recently disclosed that the country plans to formulate a negative list for cross-border trade in services that is applicable to all of its 21 pilot free trade zones (FTZs) this year, and will promote the introduction of a national negative list for cross-border services trade in due course.</p> <p> In March, the general office of the MOFCOM issued a circular on making good use of the guidance funds for the innovative development of services trade to support the development of new trade forms and models, encouraging leveraging new ways of financing to stimulate new trade forms and models.</p> <p> The MOFCOM and six other government departments lately approved a new batch of 40 specialized bases for featured services export. China is now home to 112 bases for featured services export, which cover seven fields including culture, traditional Chinese medicine, digital services, human resources, geographic information, intellectual property and language services.</p> <p> The 2022 China International Fair for Trade in Services (CIFTIS), which is scheduled to be held both online and offline in September, will focus on trends in services trade, highlight digitalization and green development, and add a thematic exhibition of environment services.</p> <p> Six kinds of activities will be held during this year’s CIFTIS, including the Global Trade in Services Summit, exhibition, conference and forum, promotion and negotiation, achievement release as well as supporting activities.</p> <p> The exhibition will cover an area of no less than 126,000 square meters, and over 100 conferences, forums, promotion and negotiation activities will be held.</p> <p> As an important part of international trade and a major field of international economic and trade cooperation, services trade plays a key role in building a new development pattern.</p> <p> Last year, the value added of China’s service sector accounted for 53.3 percent of the country’s GDP, and the country’s total trade in services reached 5.3 trillion yuan, ranking second in the world for eight consecutive years.</p> <p> On the whole, China’s trade in services is characterized by constantly expanding scale, steadily increasing added value and continuously growing competitiveness, and still has huge potential for growth and great market opportunities.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Official: China capable of maintaining stable growth, high-quality development ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096599</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096599.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 18:43:03 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205131837000473178828500.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 533px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>A view of the Qinzhou port in Guangxi Zhuang autonomous region, on Oct 27, 2021. (Photo/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> China will continue to maintain steady economic growth and remain steadfast in its pursuit of high-quality development, despite some current difficulties and challenges, said Sheng Laiyun, deputy head of the National Bureau of Statistics in an interview.</p> <p> Although the recent COVID-19 epidemic situation in the country has weighed on its economy, giving rise to slight contractions in certain economic indicators, China’s economy still enjoys strong potential and great resilience, with fundamentals underpinning the economy’s stable development and sound momentum remaining unchanged, according to Sheng.</p> <p> Regions hit hard by COVID-19, such as Shanghai and Jilin Province in northeast China, have gradually brought the epidemic situation under control since the beginning of May, and have begun to resume work and production in an orderly way, evidenced by an increase in their electricity output&nbsp;and power consumption.</p> <p> “New growth drivers are on the rise and the country will not shift its direction in high-quality development,” Sheng remarked.</p> <p> Sheng is also optimistic about China’s economic performance throughout the year because the country has a resilient supply chain supported by its growing productive forces, the world’s most&nbsp;promising&nbsp;consumer&nbsp;market with its population of 1.41 billion, as well as various policy instruments to leverage moving forward, and more importantly, it has the marked strengths of socialism with Chinese characteristics that the country will draw upon, along with social harmony and stability.</p> <p> With regards to the main tasks at present, he noted that it is vital to ensure that the economy operates in a reasonable range. China has vowed to adhere unwaveringly to its dynamic zero-COVID policy, and guard against inbound cases and domestic resurgences, in order to consolidate the hard-won results of its prevention and control efforts.</p> <p> He also highlighted the role of pro-growth policies and giving full play to effective investments. "History has shown that expanding infrastructure investment is the most effective and fastest way out of short-term economic hardship," he said, adding that China still has broad space for infrastructure investment.</p> <p> “Measures such as tax refunds, tax and fee cuts, the deferral of social security contribution payments, special funds, and inclusive finance lending to micro and small businesses will shore up market entities,” he said.</p> <p> Besides, he highlighted efforts to stabilize employment, ensure people’s livelihood, and&nbsp;keep supplies and prices stable, particularly in critical areas such as food and energy.</p> <p> Sheng noted that weakening market expectations is a pressing problem at the moment, with the Purchasing Manager Index (PMI) for China's manufacturing industry and the index for non-manufacturing business activity in April standing at 47.4 percent and 41.9 percent, respectively.</p> <p> Sheng believes this can be ascribed to increasing uncertainties in the world economy accompanied by higher interest rates, rising costs, high inflation, and sluggish&nbsp;global&nbsp;growth, among other concerns, in addition to geopolitical events such as the Ukraine crisis, as well as certain domestic reasons such as shrinking demand and logistics hindered by recent efforts to control the epidemic.</p> <p> To cope with these problems, Sheng said that the country needs to maintain a stable macroeconomic performance to accomplish the main targets and tasks for the year,&nbsp;step up efforts to ease the difficulties encountered by market entities, roll out relevant measures at an early date, and continue reforms to improve the business environment for enterprises. He also stressed the continuity, consistency, and sustainability of macro policies.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's Shandong sees foreign trade up 14.2 pct in Jan.-April ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096554</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096554.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 16:38:10 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/88/9953737558995835400.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on May 1, 2022 shows a container vessel docking at the Qianwan Container Terminal in Qingdao, east China's Shandong Province. East China's Shandong Province posted a 14.2 percent year-on-year increase in its foreign trade in the first four months of 2022, Qingdao Customs said on Thursday. (Xinhua/Li Ziheng)</em></p> <p> JINAN, May 12 (Xinhua) -- East China's Shandong Province posted a 14.2 percent year-on-year increase in its foreign trade in the first four months of 2022, Qingdao Customs said on Thursday.</p> <p> The province's total import and export volume exceeded 968.8 billion yuan (144 billion U.S. dollars) during the period. Of the total, exports grew 22.7 percent to around 572.7 billion yuan, while imports increased 3.9 percent to about 396 billion yuan.</p> <p> Notably, Shandong's private sector reported 19 percent year-on-year growth to over 697 billion yuan, accounting for 72 percent of its total foreign-trade volume.</p> <p> During the period, Shandong's trade with countries along the Belt and Road also recorded robust growth, up 26.6 percent, with the value reaching 343 billion yuan.</p> <p> Mechanical and electronic products were among the province's major exports in the first four months, taking up 42 percent of the total export volume, said the local customs authorities.</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/35/12072107335436294351.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 626px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 1, 2022 shows a container vessel docking at the Qianwan Container Terminal in Qingdao, east China's Shandong Province. East China's Shandong Province posted a 14.2 percent year-on-year increase in its foreign trade in the first four months of 2022, Qingdao Customs said on Thursday. (Xinhua/Li Ziheng)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/64/18207416809634546364.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 601px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 1, 2022 shows a container vessel docking at the Qianwan Container Terminal in Qingdao, east China's Shandong Province. East China's Shandong Province posted a 14.2 percent year-on-year increase in its foreign trade in the first four months of 2022, Qingdao Customs said on Thursday. (Xinhua/Li Ziheng)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/42/314138766797337418.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 1, 2022 shows a container vessel docking at the Qianwan Container Terminal in Qingdao, east China's Shandong Province. East China's Shandong Province posted a 14.2 percent year-on-year increase in its foreign trade in the first four months of 2022, Qingdao Customs said on Thursday. (Xinhua/Li Ziheng)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Feature: Australian cosmetic retailer getting arms around China's e-commerce tailwinds ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096438</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096438.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 15:06:51 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> SYDNEY, May 13 (Xinhua) -- Launched on China's e-commerce platform for nearly two years, Australian beauty retailer powerhouse Mecca has built up its global influence by showcasing Australian leading beauty brands to more Chinese customers.</p> <p> As one of Australia's most popular online and offline cosmetic platforms, Mecca houses more than 150 brands. In 2020, Mecca was launched in the Chinese market via the Tmall Global platform, an online marketplace to purchase imported products.</p> <p> "Aligning with the growing beauty industry in China, we have seen rapid growth over the past two years on the Tmall platform, our followers have increased to over 100,000 members with a total of 34 brands in our portfolio, with plans to continue expanding," Alex Lu, head of MECCA e-Commerce China, told Xinhua in a recent interview.</p> <p> China has always been committed to a high-standard opening up and welcoming foreign investment. The country remains a hotspot for foreign investors seeking predictable market opportunities at a difficult time amid the COVID-19 pandemic, thanks to the country's unremitting efforts to optimize its business environment.</p> <p> Foreign direct investment into the Chinese mainland, in actual use, expanded 25.6 percent year on year to 379.87 billion yuan (56 billion U.S. dollars) in the first quarter of the year, official data showed.</p> <p> "Entering the Chinese market has always been one of our goals. China's beauty industry is one of the fastest growing sectors with a highly diverse and digitally savvy customer base, we know that there is an appetite for cosmetics in this market."</p> <p> Lu added variety has always been Mecca's strength, and as such it was well-positioned to meet the demand of a wide range of Chinese customers who care about quality cosmetics.</p> <p> "Through a comprehensive understanding of the market, we know that there is huge demand and consumption potential in the China market and paired with MECCA's magic, we could be very competitive," Lu added.</p> <p> Harnessing the power of Chinese social media, the company has a team in China that livestreams regularly on social platforms to cultivate, brand build, and engage its loyal customer base. Some Chinese influencers will also collaborate with them to highlight various Australian beauty brands, such as its own in-house brand -- Mecca Cosmetica.</p> <p> "We also get inspired by the purchase models in China and will see if it can be integrated back into our Australian business," said Lu.</p> <p> "We have conducted several successful livestreams in Australia, and we are exploring options for this to be a more regular occurrence through various social media channels such as WeChat and Instagram."</p> <p> Lu pointed out some key differences between Australia's and China's e-commerce environment. In China, online marketplaces are wildly popular and Chinese consumers are much more accustomed to making online purchases through a few clicks on their phones.</p> <p> "However, after years of highly developed online purchasing mechanisms, we have seen a shift in customer sentiment as some consumers may now feel that meeting the endless requirements to redeem promotions is quite cumbersome and tiring, especially during festival promotions on the platform."</p> <p> "Yet, this will not affect China to be the first or second largest premium beauty market globally," added Lu. "The potential for consumption is still prevalent and it's definitely an attractive market for emerging brands."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China takes measures to ease companies' challenges amid epidemic ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096184</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096184.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:07:37 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- China has taken various measures to ease the burden that COVID-19 has placed on businesses.</p> <p> Major state-owned banks are expected to increase inclusive loans for micro and small firms by 1.6 trillion yuan (about 237.1 billion U.S. dollars) this year to step up financial support for businesses, according to a State Council executive meeting earlier this month.</p> <p> The meeting also called on banks to renew loans, extend and adjust repayment arrangements, and waive default interest for micro, small and medium-sized enterprises and self-employed households as appropriate.</p> <p> "Currently, small and micro firms are facing challenges and need stronger support from the government and financial institutions," said Liu Xingguo, a researcher with China Enterprise Confederation.</p> <p> In the first quarter of 2022, outstanding inclusive loans to small and micro firms climbed 22.6 percent year on year, while total new loans issued stood at 8.6 trillion yuan, up 445.5 billion yuan from a year ago, official statistics showed.</p> <p> "We are using all possible means to help small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) overcome difficulties, increase their confidence and stabilize their expectations," Xu Xiaolan, vice minister of industry and information technology said Tuesday at a meeting for addressing the difficulties of SMEs.</p> <p> So far this year, the central government has rolled out 17 policies to support SMEs, while local governments have launched 52 policies with the same goal in mind, noted Xin Guobin, vice minister of industry and information technology.</p> <p> In COVID-hit Shanghai, financial institutions have issued 33.5 billion yuan of loans to enterprises supplying daily goods and offering logistics services since March, said Yu Wenjian, an official with the Shanghai head office of the People's Bank of China.</p> <p> The institutions have also issued 72.3 billion yuan of loans to over 10,000 companies in the catering, retail, tourism and transportation sectors, which have all been impacted by the epidemic.</p> <p> In Beijing, policy funds of no less than 150 billion yuan are expected to be issued to support market entities in 2022, according to the People's Bank of China.</p> <p> Liang Tao, vice chairman of the China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission, also noted at an interview earlier this month that more attentive and accessible financial services will be extended to hard-hit areas like the city of Shanghai and Jilin Province.</p> <p> Many of China's financial and fiscal policies have already helped enterprises through these difficult times.</p> <p> Fuxeon Fire-fighting Technology Co., Ltd., based in the private company hub of Quanzhou in east China's Fujian Province, experienced a COVID-19 resurgence in mid-March that disrupted logistics services and drove up the price of raw materials.</p> <p> "We were facing great pressure in controlling the cost," said Huang Jiafu, general manager of the company.</p> <p> He later learned from the local tax department that the company can apply for deferred tax for the fourth quarter of 2021 and the first quarter this year.</p> <p> "Benefiting from this policy, we have enjoyed more than 700,000 yuan of deferred tax amount, which effectively eased our financial strains," Huang said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ With more opening-up measures in pipeline, China set to remain appealing to overseas investors ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096154</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096154.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:48:00 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Despite multiple unexpected factors rattling global financial market, China has renewed its commitments to further opening its capital market, with pragmatic measures in the pipeline to lure more investors to one of the world's fastest-growing economies.</p> <p> China will optimize and expand the connectivity of domestic and overseas capital markets, Wang Jianjun, vice chairman of the China Securities Regulatory Commission, told Xinhua in an interview.</p> <p> The vice chairman said that the commission is expanding the scope of Shanghai-Hong Kong and Shenzhen-Hong Kong stock connect schemes, with efforts to step up the inclusion of exchange-traded funds into the two programs.</p> <p> To support Chinese firms in getting listed in overseas markets such as Hong Kong and the United States, new rules and regulations will be put into effect. In the same vein, China welcomes qualified international companies to get listed on the mainland stock market.</p> <p> On top of that, more cross-border investment and risk management products will be provided for overseas investors, the securities regulator said, pledging that it will also build up supervision capacities and enhance cooperation with other countries.</p> <p> Despite recent volatility in global capital flows, Wang said there are "no fundamental changes in the capital flow and trading of China's capital market."</p> <p> Since the start of this year, risks arising from geopolitical conflicts, the COVID-19 pandemic, and the monetary policy shifts in major economies have prompted jitters among global investors.</p> <p> According to data from the Institute of International Finance, foreign capital has been pulling out of the emerging markets in March and April, but China's equities posted about 1 billion U.S. dollars in inflows in April.</p> <p> What's worth noticing is that long-term funds have also kept flowing to China this year, a signal that foreign investors remain optimistic about the prospects of Chinese stocks and the country's economic growth.</p> <p> China's listed firms posted steady performance last year, turning in satisfying financial reports to shareholders. According to data from 4,804 listed firms, these companies raked in 66.4 trillion yuan (about 9.87 trillion U.S. dollars) in operating revenue and 5.1 trillion yuan in net profits in 2021, up 19.3 percent and 19.8 percent from a year ago, respectively.</p> <p> And the market has continued to grow with more players. In 2021, the number of listed firms on the mainland stock market rose by 524 to about 4,700, with their aggregate market capitalization ranking second globally.</p> <p> Commenting on Chinese A-share market volatilities this year, Wang said that it would not derail China's capital market from its long-term positive development trend.</p> <p> There were some "overreactions" in the market, Wang said, believing that the influence of these risks is "controllable" and the steady operation of the market is underpinned by solid foundations.</p> <p> The Chinese economy has sustained its recovering momentum as supply and industrial chains have been gradually unsnarled, Wang said, noting that pro-growth policy mixes have also sent positive signals to several primary sectors and helped anchor market expectations.</p> <p> In the eyes of Fang Xinghai, also vice chairman of the securities regulator, China's growth potential is yet to be fully unleashed, and the fundamentals of its sound economic development will remain unchanged.</p> <p> A country's foreign capital attraction capacity depends partly on its opening-up policy and China is pretty clear about the direction and means of its higher-level opening-up, said Fang.</p> <p> Li Zhan, an economist with Zhongshan Securities, said China should make its capital market more internationalized when rolling out a registration-based initial public offering system.</p> <p> More policy measures should be introduced to lower the threshold for overseas capital, facilitate cross-border investment and develop international financial products, Li said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China urges deeper ASEAN Plus Three ties in financial sector: official ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096139</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096139.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:24:35 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Financial collaboration among the member states of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations, China, Japan and the Republic of Korea (ASEAN Plus Three) should be promoted to address new challenges faced by the global economy, Chinese Finance Minister Liu Kun said on Thursday.</p> <p> Liu made the remarks while addressing a video conference attended by finance ministers and central bank governors from the ASEAN Plus Three countries.</p> <p> China will join hands with other member states in promoting innovation and exploring new areas of regional financial cooperation, Liu said.</p> <p> Efforts should be made to advance the development of the Asian bond market and meet the financing needs of the region's future development, Liu said.</p> <p> China will continue to effectively coordinate COVID-19 prevention and control with economic and social development, step up its macro-policy adjustment, and implement a proactive fiscal policy while improving its effectiveness.</p> <p> The attendees also vowed to actively maintain monetary and financial stability, ensure long-term fiscal sustainability, and effectively guard against risks and negative spillovers.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China eyes incremental policies to shore up growth ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096131</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096131.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:16:35 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- China is mulling new incremental policies to shore up economic growth and will make further adjustments when necessary, a senior economic official said on Thursday.</p> <p> "There is sufficient room for fiscal, monetary policy and other policies, and we have various policy tools," Han Wenxiu, the official with the Central Committee for Financial and Economic Affairs, said at a press conference in response to questions on China's economic development.</p> <p> "We have rich experience in coping with downward pressure on the economy, and will not hesitate to take steps," Han said.</p> <p> The official's comments follow the Chinese authorities' recognition of mounting downward pressure on the economy, which was addressed at a key meeting of the Political Bureau of the Communist Party of China Central Committee in late April.</p> <p> The meeting analyzed the current economic situation and economic work, including the rising risks caused by the resurgences of COVID-19 and the Ukraine crisis, and clearly asserted that efforts should be made to contain the epidemic, stabilize the economy and keep development secure.</p> <p> "All those aspects should be taken into account, and you cannot fix just one at a time," Han said. "It is a quite difficult work."</p> <p> Calling the epidemic "a tiger in the way" of economic and social development, Han called for scientific, precise and effective measures to prevent and control COVID-19, which is an "essential pre-condition for the normal operation of the economy and society."</p> <p> Efforts should be made to implement the existing policies in the first half of the year, Han said, adding that the State Council and relevant departments are working on detailed policy steps to help industries, small and medium-sized enterprises and individual businesses that are severely affected by the epidemic.</p> <p> Han also called for making reforms and tapping the potential of domestic demand, such as strengthening infrastructure construction, making effective investment and boosting consumption.</p> <p> "China's economy is at a critical moment in overcoming difficulties, and the problems are the growing pains in the development process," Han said. "As long as we strengthen our confidence and rise to the challenges, we will be able to turn those challenges into opportunities, and that is the basic logic of China's economic development."</p> <p> Chen Yulu, vice governor of the People's Bank of China, said that, in order to cushion the impact of the epidemic, the central bank has cut the reserve requirement ratio to keep liquidity at an ample level, lowered the financing costs of market entities, and implemented structural monetary instruments.</p> <p> China has established a re-lending facility worth 200 billion yuan (about 29.72 billion U.S. dollars) to boost scientific and technological innovation and implemented a re-lending cap of 40 billion yuan for inclusive elderly care, Chen said.</p> <p> By the end of March, the central bank had issued 138.6 billion yuan of funds through a supporting tool for carbon reduction, he added.</p> <p> The central bank will put stable growth in a more prominent position, actively plan incremental policy tools, continue to reduce financing costs and step up financial support for the real economy, Chen said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China rolls out multiple measures to help MSMEs, self-employed households pull through difficulties ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096108</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096108.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 08:59:39 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> A recent State Council executive meeting specified that China will further implement measures to support micro, small and medium-sized enterprises (MSMEs) and self-employed households, in an effort to stabilize the economy, as well as industrial and supply chains. Meanwhile, relevant government departments will adjust their policies promptly to ease the financial burdens on these businesses.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205130851000572574409501.jpg" style="width: 831px; height: 554px;" /></p> <p> <em>A worker assembles automobiles at a factory of Chinese car maker JAC Group’s branch in Qingzhou city, east China’s Shandong province, April 27, 2022. (People’s Daily Online/Wang Jilin)</em></p> <p> Although the country’s economic operation has remained generally stable despite complex domestic and international situation since the beginning of this year, the increasing complexity, severity and uncertainty of the environment for economic development has made it harder to survive for market players, especially MSMEs and self-employed households.</p> <p> The Ministry of Finance (MOF) has rolled out more than 20 tax-relief policies this year, including&nbsp;implementing value-added tax (VAT) credit refund on a large scale to fully give back outstanding VAT credits&nbsp;in certain industries; extending tax and fee reduction policies that support manufacturing, micro and small enterprises and self-employed households and expanding the scale and scope of these policies; and introducing tax policies to support the development of industries facing special difficulties caused by COVID-19, according to Xu Hongcai, vice minister of finance.</p> <p> At present, various policies concerning tax refunds and reductions and fee cuts are being implemented at a faster pace, Xu noted.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205130852000234475804163.jpg" style="width: 826px; height: 551px;" /></p> <p> <em>An inspection officer talks with the employees of a company to see whether relevant government departments have solved the company’s problems in time in Sihong county, Suqian city, east China’s Jiangsu province, April 26, 2022. (People’s Daily Online/Xu Changliang)</em></p> <p> In response to impeded logistics recently, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology (MIIT) has identified 1,624 key enterprises in four batches and instructed 17 provinces to establish regional “white lists” for key enterprises, said Xin Guobin, vice minister of the MIIT.</p> <p> It has also built a coordination platform for key industrial and supply chains involving automobiles, integrated circuits and medical supplies to ensure the smooth operation of key industrial chains, Xin added.</p> <p> The MIIT will carry out special inspections of the effects of policies aimed at reducing the burden on enterprises and promoting the development of small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) to make sure that these policies are effectively implemented, according to Xin.</p> <p> Besides, the People’s Bank of China (PBOC), the central bank of China, and the State Administration of Foreign Exchange (SAFE) put forward 23 measures covering such aspects as supporting enterprises facing difficulties and promoting foreign trade and export.</p> <p> The Bank of Communications actively improved its online foreign exchange and treasury business to enable MSMEs engaged in foreign trade to handle foreign exchange business online, thus helping them save the costs generated from seeking offline services and avoid foreign exchange risks.</p> <p> The effective measures taken by China to help companies survive the difficult times have boosted the confidence of various parties.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205130852000569307129107.jpg" style="width: 830px; height: 549px;" /></p> <p> <em>Staff members handle companies’ tax-related business to help them resume production amid the COVID-19 pandemic at the government affairs service center of Huainan city, east China’s Anhui province, April 25, 2022. (People’s Daily Online/Chen Bin)</em></p> <p> China has a mature and resilient supply chain system and is an important global consumer market, which is helpful in promoting the development of SMEs and driving corporate innovation and eventually stimulating greater economic vitality, noted Zhang Xiaolei, president of Standard Chartered Bank (China) Limited.</p> <p> “In the next three years, we will invest $300 million in China-related businesses to help clients seize the opportunities brought by China’s continuous opening-up,” Zhang said.</p> <p> According to Pu Chun, deputy head of the State Administration for Market Regulation (SAMR), the number of China’s newly established market entities registered positive growth between January and April, reaching nearly 8.99 million with a year-on-year increase of 0.7 percent.</p> <p> During the period, an average of 22,600 enterprises were newly established per day, which represent a relatively high level; and over 6.23 million individuals registered as self-employed business owners, up 2.9 percent compared with the same period in 2021.</p> <p> “Although the Chinese economy has been faced with a complex and grim environment, the number of newly established market entities this year has basically remained stable, which reflected the economy’s strong resilience and potential,” Pu said, adding that the number of market players is expected to maintain rapid growth when the pandemic is effectively controlled and the effects of relevant policies continue to be unleashed.</p> <p> Although the prolonged COVID-19 pandemic has brought difficulties and challenges to many market players, the fundamentals of the Chinese economy—its strong resilience, enormous potential, vast room for maneuver and long-term sustainability—remain unchanged.</p> <p> In the future, China’s economy will show stronger dynamism with the continuous implementation of relevant policies.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Global companies in China to expand ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096064</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096064.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 08:25:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/21/4635572795205093733.jpg" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 584px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Technicians discuss products at a joint venture in Suzhou, Jiangsu province. HUA XUEGEN/FOR CHINA DAILY</em></p> <p> Foreign enterprises operating in China, a long-term, thriving part of the nation's economy, are expected to continue to expand their investments this year, as many countries worldwide are encountering uncertainties amid the Russia-Ukraine conflict, high inflation rates and slowing economic recovery, analysts and business leaders said.</p> <p> In addition to describing China as a safe haven for foreign direct investment, they said the nation's efforts to create a unified domestic market, its sizable middle-income group and shortened negative lists will enable its economy to mitigate shocks and maintain steady growth momentum.</p> <p> By building a unified domestic market including all elements of production and resources－capital, technology and energy－China will further remove barriers to the rational flow of production factors, said Bai Ming, deputy director of international market research at the Beijing-based Chinese Academy of International Trade and Economic Cooperation. It will also cut transaction costs and ensure fair competition, which will encourage domestic and foreign companies alike to invest across the country, Bai said.</p> <p> The nation's strengths in attracting global capital will continue, he added, and business areas including new energy, consumption, high-end manufacturing and services will remain hot spots for multinational investment.</p> <p> Thanks to the nation's complete industrial chains, policy assistance and stable business environment, FDI flows into the Chinese mainland, in actual use, expanded 14.9 percent year-on-year to a record high of 1.15 trillion yuan ($170.43 billion) in 2021, according to the Ministry of Commerce.</p> <p> Apart from opening new stores in smaller cities and adding investment in apparel and children's products in the coming years throughout China, Skechers, a United States-based athletic-leisure shoe and clothing company, will start to build the second phase of its Taicang logistics center in Jiangsu province and begin operations at its new China headquarters in Shanghai in the second half.</p> <p> "We are confident about the Chinese market," said Willie Tan, CEO of Skechers China, South Korea and Southeast Asia. The company will continue to strengthen its diversified product layouts for all age groups to meet the needs of different consumers, as China has become the cradle of fostering "numerous new consumption scenarios, products and services regarding the sports and health industry", Tan said.</p> <p> Vivian Tu, marketing leader of Philips Domestic Appliances Greater China, said that the home appliances sector, spurred somewhat by work-from-home trends related to the COVID-19 pandemic, will have the potential to grow stronger than before and see new opportunities in China, as consumer demand has become more diversified and personalized.</p> <p> "We will enlarge the research team in our innovation center in Suzhou, Jiangsu province, to focus on advanced technologies such as robotics, the internet of things and artificial intelligence over the next five years. It will create new momentum for the home appliances industry with the development of digitalization and intelligence," Tu said.</p> <p> Bai Wenxi, chief economist at IP Global China, said that China, facing fierce competition in Southeast Asia in labor-intensive manufacturing sectors, has upgraded the competitiveness of its industrial chains. Its ability to attract global capital has been further strengthened by the expansion of opening-up policies and the implementation of equal treatment for foreign-funded enterprises.</p> <p> Rajat Agarwal, president of Henkel China, a German chemical and consumer goods manufacturer, said: "Looking ahead, China will continue its transformation toward high-quality growth and drive progress to reach its dual-carbon goals. We see strong future demand in the areas of packaged foods, home improvement, automotive and electronics, and Henkel will continue to support our customers and consumers with impactful innovations."</p> <p> Henkel resumed production in Changchun, Jilin province, on April 15, manufacturing products for key industries including metals, automotive and railway transportation. Its two plants in Shanghai were included in the "white list" to restart production under closed-loop management, and plan to expand production capacity as conditions allow.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Amid surging inflation, U.S. trade groups, economists urge removal of China tariffs ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096037</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096037.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 08:16:59 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> <strong>* Several White House officials, as well as President Joe Biden himself, have signaled that the administration is weighing whether to dismantle at least some of former President Donald Trump's tariffs on Chinese goods.</strong></p> <p> <strong>* As Americans continue to feel the sting of soaring inflation, economists said eliminating or at least reducing additional tariffs on Chinese goods would help lower elevated inflation and stabilize inflation expectations.</strong></p> <p> <strong>* Even Yellen said in an interview with Bloomberg Television that removing Trump-era China tariffs would have some "desirable" effects on inflation and "it's worth considering."</strong></p> <p> WASHINGTON, May 12 (Xinhua) -- As inflation hovers near a 40-year high, U.S. trade groups and economists have been urging the Biden administration to scrap Trump-era additional tariffs on Chinese imports, regarding such tariffs as counterproductive to the U.S. economy.</p> <p> These tariffs, with no good policy purpose, were an unnecessary tax on U.S. consumers and businesses, they said, noting that eliminating or at least reducing them would help lower elevated inflation and stabilize inflation expectations.</p> <p> But with the mid-term elections coming up, some lawmakers, who are keen to take a tough stance toward China, might be reluctant to support the easing of China tariffs, refraining from doing the "right thing" for American businesses and people.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/12/3607182341776824868.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on April 28, 2022 shows the Commerce Department building in Washington, D.C., the United States. (Xinhua/Liu Jie)</em></p> <p> <strong>ELEVATED INFLATION, ELEVATED PRESSURE</strong></p> <p> Several White House officials, as well as President Joe Biden himself, have signaled that the administration is weighing whether to dismantle at least some of former President Donald Trump's tariffs on Chinese goods.</p> <p> "We're discussing that right now. We're looking at what would have the most positive impact," Biden told reporters after a speech on inflation Tuesday, noting that no decision has been made.</p> <p> Biden's remarks followed recent statements by Deputy National Security Adviser Daleep Singh and Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen, who spoke about potential easing of tariffs on Chinese products in late April.</p> <p> Republican Senator Mike Crapo also called for "thoughtful application" of the Section 301 tariffs on China. "We need to cut tariffs on inputs that support American manufacturing, or on goods consumed by the American consumer, especially middle and low income families," he said at a Senate Finance Committee hearing.</p> <p> Such voices came as the United States is experiencing the highest inflation in four decades, with the consumer price index (CPI) staying over 6 percent year-on-year since October last year. According to the Labor Department's data released Wednesday, CPI in April surged by 8.3 percent from a year ago, marking the second straight month of inflation over 8 percent.</p> <p> Although price growth showed signs of easing in April, the latest CPI data "served as a stark reminder" that the Federal Reserve has a long road ahead of it in bringing down inflation," Sarah House and Michael Pugliese, economists at the Wells Fargo Securities, said in an analysis.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/91/3080473070603077483.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>A woman walks past a store in New York, the United States, May 11, 2022. U.S. consumer inflation in April surged by 8.3 percent from a year ago. (Xinhua/Wang Ying)</em></p> <p> "Americans are unhappy about rising inflation and costs, so providing tariff relief soon is one way to lower prices and increase demand, especially for consumer goods," the U.S.-China Business Council (USCBC), which represents 260 American companies that do business with China, told Xinhua on Wednesday.</p> <p> The trade group said earlier that there is "no reason" to maintain the additional tariffs on Chinese products imposed during Trump's presidency, as they were an "unnecessary tax" on U.S. consumers and businesses "for no good policy purpose."</p> <p> Americans for Free Trade, a broad coalition of trade organizations, recently warned that the Section 301 tariffs create "additional economic burden" for American businesses, manufacturers, farmers, and families, make the United States less competitive globally and cause "disproportionate economic harm to an American economy grappling with ongoing inflation concerns."</p> <p> Not only hurting U.S. businesses and workers, tariffs also drive up prices, and inflation expectations are starting to rise, according to an Axios report entitled "Trump's trade war on China was a failure in every possible way."</p> <p> <strong>LOWER TARIFFS, LOWER PRICES</strong></p> <p> As Americans continue to feel the sting of soaring inflation, economists said eliminating or at least reducing additional tariffs on Chinese goods would help lower elevated inflation and stabilize inflation expectations.</p> <p> In a recent research, Gary Hufbauer, nonresident senior fellow at the Peterson Institute for International Economics (PIIE), and his colleagues Megan Hogan and Yilin Wang argued that the direct effect of eliminating additional tariffs on Chinese products would be a 0.3 percentage point reduction in CPI, but there would also be an indirect effect, which will add "substantially" to the 0.3 percentage point.</p> <p> "It would be a pretty big signal to U.S. firms that they are going to face more competition and that might cause them to moderate their price increases as inflation rolls forward," said Hufbauer, also a former U.S. Treasury official.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/72/5538310746770904052.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on April 20, 2022 shows the U.S. Federal Reserve in Washington, D.C., the United States. (Xinhua/Liu Jie)</em></p> <p> In reaction to the argument that reducing the China tariffs would not lead to a meaningful reduction in prices, Hufbauer said it doesn't completely eliminate the inflation problem, "but it's better than doing nothing."</p> <p> "So there's raising interest rates, there's cutting back federal spending, there's reducing tariffs, all of those things have some impact," he said. Against the backdrop of a red-hot economy, "every little bit counts."</p> <p> The PIIE study showed that "a feasible trade liberalization package" could deliver a one-time reduction in CPI inflation of around 1.3 percentage points. That would save 797 dollars for every U.S. household.</p> <p> In the view of Former U.S. Treasury Secretary Lawrence Summers, this inflation reduction through tariff removal is "more significant" than anything that can be achieved over the next two to three years through antitrust action, and it is probably much "more important" than the meat packing price fixation, which has been the subject of several presidential events.</p> <p> Even Yellen said in an interview with Bloomberg Television that removing Trump-era China tariffs would have some "desirable" effects on inflation and "it's worth considering."</p> <p> <strong>RIGHT WING OR RIGHT THING?</strong></p> <p> Despite encouraging signals on tariff reduction, some lawmakers, who crave an edge in the November mid-term elections, might be reluctant to ease China tariffs, according to observers.</p> <p> "The midterms are very unlikely to result in any relaxation of the various tensions between U.S. and China, including tariff legislation," Greg Cusack, a former member of the Iowa House of Representatives, told Xinhua.</p> <p> "Candidates being fielded by the Republicans are even more right-wing and extreme than the current congressional membership, and Democratic candidates across the board will be fighting an uphill battle in which they cannot afford to be seen as 'weak' or as in any way 'caving to China'," said Cusack, a longtime Democrat.</p> <p> "Congress does not have a lot of incentive to do the 'right thing' unless it is likely to boost their poll standing or bring in more campaign funds," he noted.</p> <p> Senator Josh Hawley of Missouri, who, according to the Washington Post, "tries to grab the mantle of right-wing populism," recently tweeted that now is "not the time to go soft on China."</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/18/3057500856541974250.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Customers shop at a store in New York, the United States, May 11, 2022. U.S. consumer inflation in April surged by 8.3 percent from a year ago. (Xinhua/Wang Ying)</em></p> <p> "Enriching China &amp;woke multinational corporations on the backs of American workers is a failed policy favored by the globalists. Put American workers first," said the Republican Party's rising star.</p> <p> Leaving his comment below, a Twitter user said: "It is literally causing inflation. You complain about inflation. And you complain when they try to alleviate inflation. Just say that you don't have a value system. You want to say no."</p> <p> "We need to put what is best for our country, not a political party. Stop playing games," wrote another user.</p> <p> It's not just Republicans who want to play the China card. Democratic congressman Tim Ryan of Ohio claimed that lifting tariffs on "non-strategic" goods from China would be a major mistake, blaming China for U.S. workers' economic woes.</p> <p> Under the current political environment, Hufbauer said the Biden administration could be reluctant to remove the Trump-era tariffs, because it would have to face criticism for being "soft" on China.</p> <p> "They're worried about that, and that prevents them from doing the right thing, the right thing for the U.S. economy," Hufbauer said.</p> <p> The trade expert reckoned that the House of Representatives and the Senate might be able to reach an agreement on the America COMPETES Act, which could include billions of dollars funding for the semiconductor industry, and expanded tariff exclusion for Chinese products.</p> <p> There is a better than 50 percent chance that lawmakers could iron out disagreement by summer and provide a series of individually small, but collectively significant tariff exclusion, said Hufbauer.</p> <p> Chen Fengying, a researcher at the China Institutes of Contemporary International Relations, told Xinhua that since 2018, the trade war has escalated step by step, causing harm to both sides.</p> <p> Noting that the trade war in the context of globalization will only exacerbate inflation in the United States, the scholar said canceling relevant tariffs is conducive to alleviating U.S. economic problems.</p> <p> <em>(Xinhua reporter Luo Xin from Beijing also contributed to the story.)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's economy maintains sound momentum despite fluctuations ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095997</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10095997.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 08:16:18 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205130804000128046332253.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 584px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on Jan. 14, 2021 shows a night view of Lujiazui in Pudong of east China's Shanghai Municipality. (Xinhua/Fang Zhe)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Despite mounting domestic and external uncertainties, China's economy continues to progress with a sound momentum, an official told Xinhua in an interview.</p> <p> "Although some indicators saw short-term contractions mainly due to the COVID-19 blow, the fundamentals underpinning the economy's stable development and sound momentum remain unchanged," said Sheng Laiyun, deputy head of the National Bureau of Statistics.</p> <p> In particular, the country's general trend toward economic upgrading and high-quality development has not changed, he said.</p> <p> China's economy got off to a steady start in the first quarter of this year, with its GDP growing 4.8 percent year on year, accelerating from a 4 percent increase in the fourth quarter last year.</p> <p> However, shrinking demand, supply shocks and weakening expectations have weighed on the economy since March. Sheng said that leveraging multi-pronged macro policies is the key to reducing the COVID-19 impact to the minimum and ensuring the economy operates in a reasonable range.</p> <p> The country has vowed to adhere unwaveringly to its dynamic zero-COVID policy to consolidate the hard-won results of prevention and control work, Sheng said.</p> <p> He also stressed ramping up pro-growth policies and giving full play to effective investment. "History has shown that expanding infrastructure investment is the most effective and fastest way out of short-term economic hardship," he said.</p> <p> China's amount of infrastructure per capita is only 20 percent to 30 percent of that of developed countries, and its per capita railway operating length is less than 30 percent of the figure for the United States, showing great potential for infrastructure investment, Sheng said.</p> <p> He also mentioned measures including tax and fee cuts, the deferral of social security contribution payments and the issuance of inclusive loans to shore up market entities.</p> <p> Noting the increasing COVID-induced pressure on the job market, Sheng highlighted the importance of the full and thorough implementation of pro-employment policies.</p> <p> "With policies to coordinate pandemic control with economic and social development taking effect, the COVID-19 impact is expected to subdue gradually," Sheng said, citing positive signals already seen in power generation and consumption data.</p> <p> Efforts should also be made to ensure stable supplies and prices, he said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese automaker Chery posts strong NEV sales in Jan.-April ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095907</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095907.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 17:10:41 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> HEFEI, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Chinese automaker Chery Holding Group Co., Ltd. reported strong new energy vehicle (NEV) sales in the first four months of this year, said the company.</p> <p> Chery sold 68,587 NEVs in the January-April period, up 168.5 percent year on year. In April alone, NEV sales surged by 81.2 percent year on year to 15,533 units, according to a sales report by the company.</p> <p> The company saw strong demand from countries such as Brazil, Saudi Arabia and Chile. In the first four months of this year, it exported 84,993 vehicles, an increase of 12.6 percent year on year.</p> <p> From January to April, Chery's auto sales totaled 284,865 units, up 0.9 percent year on year.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Guangxi's pilot FTZ sees surge in cross-border e-commerce in Q1 ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095905</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095905.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 17:10:41 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NANNING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- The pilot free trade zone (FTZ) in south China's Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region saw its import and export of cross-border e-commerce hit 3.51 billion yuan (about 520 million U.S. dollars) in the first quarter of 2022, up 108.4 percent year on year.</p> <p> Meanwhile, the FTZ's cross-border e-commerce generated import and export value of some 10.2 billion yuan in 2021, an increase of 259 percent from the previous year, according to the regional department of commerce.</p> <p> Currently, the FTZ has established a major cross-border e-commerce logistics channel for the Association of Southeast Asian Nations and launched 10 air routes to countries including Indonesia, Thailand, and Malaysia, said Diao Weihong, deputy director of the regional department of commerce.</p> <p> To date, over 100 cross-border e-commerce companies have been operating in the FTZ.</p> <p> The FTZ will innovate the development policies and rules of cross-border e-commerce, build an e-commerce ecosystem of win-win cooperation, and promote cross-border e-commerce in Guangxi for breakthroughs, Diao added.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China-Belarus industrial park welcomes new resident company ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095857</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095857.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 16:34:38 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/80/907806278629320900.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Representatives of the Great Stone China-Belarus Industrial Park and Chinese enterprise Transport Complex AF LLC sign an agreement online in Minsk, Belarus on May 11, 2022. The Great Stone China-Belarus Industrial Park, a landmark cooperation project within the Belt and Road framework, held a welcome ceremony on Wednesday for a new resident company. The Chinese enterprise Transport Complex AF LLC, the 90th resident company of the industrial park located in the eastern suburbs of Minsk, plans to build a monitoring center for cross-border transportation with the help of the Internet of Things technology. (The Great Stone China-Belarus Industrial Park/Handout via Xinhua)</em></p> <p> MINSK, May 12 (Xinhua) -- The Great Stone China-Belarus Industrial Park, a landmark cooperation project within the Belt and Road framework, held a welcome ceremony on Wednesday for a new resident company.</p> <p> The Chinese enterprise Transport Complex AF LLC, the 90th resident company of the industrial park located in the eastern suburbs of Minsk, plans to build a monitoring center for cross-border transportation with the help of the Internet of Things technology.</p> <p> During the ceremony, head of the park's administration Alexander Yaroshenko voiced hope that the number of the Great Stone resident companies will reach 100 by the end of this year, and the administration stands ready to support them in all matters.</p> <p> Among the 90 enterprises in the park, 46 are financed by China, 27 by Belarus and 17 by other countries. The total investment in businesses has amounted to 1.26 billion U.S. dollars.</p> <p> The industrial park is the largest investment project of China in Belarus and an important example of the Belt and Road cooperation between the two countries.</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/97/2555971951098153621.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Head of Great Stone China-Belarus Industrial Park administration Alexander Yaroshenko (L) issues admission certificate to a representative of Chinese enterprise Transport Complex AF LLC in Minsk, Belarus on May 11, 2022. The Great Stone China-Belarus Industrial Park, a landmark cooperation project within the Belt and Road framework, held a welcome ceremony on Wednesday for a new resident company. The Chinese enterprise Transport Complex AF LLC, the 90th resident company of the industrial park located in the eastern suburbs of Minsk, plans to build a monitoring center for cross-border transportation with the help of the Internet of Things technology. (The Great Stone China-Belarus Industrial Park/Handout via Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's FDI inflow up 20.5 pct in first four months ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095855</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095855.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 16:34:30 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Foreign direct investment (FDI) into the Chinese mainland, in actual use, expanded 20.5 percent year on year to 478.61 billion yuan in the first four months of the year, the Ministry of Commerce said Thursday.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's share of global economy rises to over 18 pct: official ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095749</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095749.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 13:36:03 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- China accounted for over 18 percent of the global economy in 2021, rising from 11.4 percent in 2012, an official said Thursday.</p> <p> China has both cemented and improved its status as the world's second-largest economy over the past decade, said Han Wenxiu, a senior official with the Central Committee for Financial and Economic Affairs.</p> <p> The country's gross domestic products (GDP) topped 114 trillion yuan (about 16.94 trillion U.S. dollars) in 2021, and per capita GDP reached 12,500 U.S. dollars, close to the threshold for high-income economies, Han said.</p> <p> The contribution of China's economic growth to the world economy has stood at around 30 percent in recent years, making it the largest growth engine for the global economy, Han added.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China’s foreign trade shows resilience despite many challenges ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095723</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095723.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 12:17:41 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121128000268440904166.jpg" style="width: 520px; height: 807px;" /></p> <p> <em>①Photo shows the Qianwan Container Terminal at Qingdao Port, east China’s Shandong Province. (Photo/People’s Daily)</em></p> <p> <em>②An employee of a company is busy with production in Ganzhou city, east China’s Jiangxi Province. (Photo/Liu Qing)</em></p> <p> <em>③An international freight train that runs via the China-Laos Railway departs from a railway station in Shenyang, capital city of northeast China’s Liaoning Province. (Photo/People’s Daily)</em></p> <p> China’s foreign trade sustained resilience and growth momentum in the first three months of this year despite increasingly complex challenges and risks.</p> <p> The country’s total imports and exports expanded 7.9 percent year-on-year to reach 12.58 trillion yuan (about $1.88 trillion) in the January-March period, according to official data.</p> <p> The resilience of China’s foreign trade can be attributed to the efforts of businesses and a slew of policies to help enterprises tide over ongoing difficulties.</p> <p> Some enterprises engaging in foreign trade have promoted the better integration of the domestic and international markets and greater complementarity between domestic and global resources, improving their competitiveness in global industrial and supply chains.</p> <p> Recently, TCL China Star Optoelectronics Technology Co., Ltd. (TCL CSOT), a world-leading panel supplier under Chinese consumer electronics company TCL Corp in Shenzhen, south China’s Guangdong Province, exported its products to TCL’s plant in Mexico.</p> <p> In the past, TCL directly exported TV sets. Nowadays the company ships liquid crystal display panels and electronic parts and components to its production base in Mexico, where TV sets are assembled, in this way reducing costs. The approach has played a key role in improving the competitiveness of TCL products in North America.</p> <p> “Ten years ago, we were hindered by the short supply of screens. But we have mastered core technologies to produce major parts and components such as screens,” said Zhao Jun, chief operating officer of TCL CSOT.</p> <p> It’s estimated that China’s large-size liquid crystal display panels will reach or exceed 70 percent of the global market by 2023.</p> <p> In the first two months of this year, TCL’s exports reached $2.77 billion, up 2.2 percent year-on-year. In the first quarter of this year, TCL CSOT exported 12 million TV screens. TCL’s plant in Mexico can produce and assemble modules and inner wiring.</p> <p> “TCL’s revenue growth in overseas markets is facilitated by the building of complete industrial and supply chains across the globe,” said Li Dongsheng, founder and president of TCL. Li added that building complete industrial and supply chains globally can effectively boost enterprises’ exports of core components, materials and equipment while significantly increasing their global competitiveness.</p> <p> Meanwhile, new business forms and models of foreign trade such as cross-border e-commerce, overseas warehouses, and the market purchase trade are thriving in China, becoming new drivers for the high-quality development of the country’s foreign trade.</p> <p> Hangzhou Santa Technology Co., Ltd., a company based in Hangzhou, capital city of east China’s Zhejiang Province, saw its overseas sales of electric bicycles grow by 15 percent in a half year.</p> <p> “Overseas customers can try our bikes at sales outlets before buying, and after-sales services can be guaranteed,” said Zhu Guoqiang, general manager of the company, attributing this to the establishment of an overseas warehouse.</p> <p> To explore overseas markets, Santa Technology once rented warehouses outside China, but high rental costs and inconvenient communications made it difficult for the company to achieve its desired results.</p> <p> Zhejiang Cathy International Freight Forwarding Co., Ltd., an international freight forwarder in the city, extended an olive branch to Zhu, inviting him to join its overseas warehouse in Los Angeles, the U.S., where products can be displayed at a 200-square meter operation and service center and professionals are able to provide after-sales services.</p> <p> Zhu introduced that the overseas warehouse has helped his company save on costs adding up to more than $1 million every year.</p> <p> The international freight forwarder has so far built 16 self-operated overseas warehouses with a combined area of more than 100,000 square meters.</p> <p> Ma Shuzhong, director of the International Business Institute at Zhejiang University, said digital and intelligent overseas warehouses can solve the bottleneck problems in cross-border logistics and after-sales services to a greater extent, while helping cross-border enterprises operate at a lower cost, promoting high-quality operations, improving logistics efficiency and providing customers a better shopping experience, thus enhancing the resilience of China’s foreign trade.</p> <p> At present, Zhejiang has built 791 overseas warehouses covering a total area of 9.5 million square meters in over 40 countries and regions.</p> <p> Besides, China has continued to deepen multilateral, bilateral, and regional cooperation and promote high-quality development through the Belt and Road Initiative, creating favorable conditions for exporters to explore emerging markets.</p> <p> China has implemented the Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership (RCEP) agreement, the world’s largest free trade agreement, bringing new opportunities for enterprises to explore new markets.</p> <p> Data from the Guangdong branch of the General Administration of Customs of China (GACC) showed that the total trade volume of Guangdong with RCEP members reached 343.89 billion yuan, up 2.7 percent year-on-year, in the first two months of this year. The RCEP has improved customs clearance efficiency and cut tariffs, serving as a key fulcrum for stabilizing foreign trade.</p> <p> China will continue to improve the business environment for foreign trade and make customs clearance for returning export goods more efficient, according to the State Council executive meeting held on April 13.</p> <p> To help ease difficulties facing foreign trade firms and promote stable growth, all localities and government departments have rolled out a slew of measures to stabilize the overall performance of foreign trade and support exporters in optimizing their structure and building brands to further raise the added value of their products and improve their international competitiveness.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Interview: Standard Chartered's China chief "very confident" in China's long-term growth ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095716</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095716.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 11:22:00 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> LONDON, May 12 (Xinhua) -- The more multinationals know about and integrate their operations into the economy of China, the more confidence they will have in China's long-term growth and prosperity, Standard Chartered's China chief has said.</p> <p> "China is the world's largest manufacturer with the most comprehensive and resilient supply chain system, which has helped China's economy recover rapidly after the outbreak of the COVID-19 pandemic," Jerry Zhang, chief executive officer of Standard Chartered Bank (China), told Xinhua in a recent written interview.</p> <p> "China is also the second-largest consumer market in the world, with huge consumer demands that will continue to foster growth of SMEs (small and medium-sized enterprises), accelerate innovations, and bring even more vigour to China's economy," she added.</p> <p> In 2021, the bank's business in China has grown significantly, driven by wealth management, financial markets, trade and unsecured products, according to Zhang.</p> <p> "The bank is very optimistic about China's long-term development prospects and will continue its investment in China," she said, noting that Standard Chartered Group in February announced it will invest 300 million U.S. dollars into China related business in the next three years, "so as to help our clients seize the opportunities arising from China's continuous reform and opening-up."</p> <p> China's GDP grew 4.8 percent year on year in the first quarter, which, Zhang said, is "better than market consensus," despite the resurgence of COVID-19 and the Russia-Ukraine conflict.</p> <p> "This is a good achievement, benefiting from the economic performance and front-loading macro policy support in the first two months," she added.</p> <p> "The impact of the epidemic and global geopolitical risks may continue in the short term, but we think the fundamentals of a resilient, high-potential and prosperous economy in China remain intact," Zhang told Xinhua.</p> <p> "We are very confident about the long-term development prospect of China," she added.</p> <p> Noting China's unwavering efforts to promote high-quality development and deepen reform and opening-up, in particular financial opening-up at a higher level, she said these efforts "will continue to provide enormous development opportunities for international financial institutions including Standard Chartered Bank."</p> <p> Speaking of China's policies and measures in such fields as opening-up, common prosperity, innovation and green transformation, Zhang said, "China's great efforts to continuously open up its financial sector, as well as achievement in this regard, is well recognized."</p> <p> "In the past two years, the outbreak of COVID-19 has brought severe challenges to the world economy. In the meantime, China achieved GDP growth of 2.3 percent and 8.1 percent in 2020 and 2021 respectively, contributing significantly to the global anti-epidemic efforts and the recovery of the world economy," she said.</p> <p> Amid rising risks of stagflation worldwide, Zhang said, "the stable economic growth in China would continue to play an important role for the recovery and growth of the world economy."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Cargo throughput rises significantly at Shanghai airport ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095647</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095647.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:24:12 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> SHANGHAI, May 11 (Xinhua) -- A total of 43,000 tonnes of import and export cargo were handled at Shanghai Pudong International Airport between May 1 and 10, up 59.3 percent over the same period in April, according to the airport's customs authorities Wednesday.</p> <p> The figures show that the Pudong airport, a major global aviation hub, is gradually recovering vitality since Shanghai implemented tough control measures to contain the latest COVID-19 resurgence since late March.</p> <p> Customs at the airport has made the whole declaration process paperless and offers personalized clearance plans for businesses in key industries such as integrated circuits, biomedicine and automobiles.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Industries in epidemic-hit areas expedite production resumption ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095637</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095637.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:23:56 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- While battling against the recent flare-ups of COVID-19 in parts of the country, China has been steadily promoting work resumption in the epidemic-affected areas.</p> <p> With the epidemic situation gradually easing in Shanghai, major enterprises in the eastern Chinese metropolis have resumed stable production, as key industrial chains, such as automobiles, integrated circuits and biomedicine, continued to recover and ramp up production capacity.</p> <p> All four factories of the U.S. manufacturing company 3M in Shanghai had resumed production by Saturday, the company said, adding that it will continue to improve its production capacity.</p> <p> Since the resurgence of COVID-19 cases in March in Shanghai, 3M has not suspended its East China Distribution Center and the production of medical protective masks at its Caohejing base to ensure the stable supply of anti-epidemic materials, the company said.</p> <p> "Now, 3M is gathering the strength of the entire company to actively deploy resources, so as to ensure the closed-loop production of epidemic prevention supplies," said Ding Hongyu, president of 3M China.</p> <p> On Wednesday, a ship carrying 4,767 electric cars produced by U.S. automaker Tesla's Shanghai Gigafactory left a Shanghai port for Slovenia, according to Shanghai customs.</p> <p> It marked the first export shipment of Tesla cars from Shanghai since the company resumed production on April 19 after a hiatus of over 20 days amid the epidemic.</p> <p> The company said its Shanghai factory has already started manufacturing vehicles for export to the Asia-Pacific and European markets.</p> <p> "We believe that the epidemic situation is only a short test and challenge. We have seen the capacity of all sectors to cope with the challenges in the process of resuming work," said Tao Lin, vice president of Tesla. "We believe that production will soon return to normal."</p> <p> According to a press conference held on May 5, over 70 percent of Shanghai's 1,800-plus major enterprises had resumed work and production.</p> <p> Earlier this year, the southern city of Shenzhen, a tech hub and a major foreign-trade center in China, also saw a resurgence of COVID-19 infections.</p> <p> The city took a series of measures, such as suspending public transportation and closing some businesses, from March 14 to 20, and successfully brought the epidemic situation under control. Thanks to the effective actions, businesses gradually resumed normal work and operation starting late March.</p> <p> Sources with the on-demand delivery service provider Lalamove, known as Huolala in Chinese, said the company saw an obvious drop in the number of orders it received in Shenzhen from March 14 to 21.</p> <p> However, the number of overall orders handled by the company in the city from March 1 to April 20 was almost equal to the same period last year, with 6,037 new drivers from Shenzhen joining the platform during this period.</p> <p> During the first quarter, the total number of commercial entities in Shenzhen reached more than 3.85 million, with 88,065 newly registered ones. Over 90 percent of the newly-registered commercial entities are from the tertiary industry, according to the local government.</p> <p> The city's electricity consumption came in at more than 8.3 billion kWh in April, a year-on-year growth of 0.1 percent and month-on-month growth of 8.8 percent, said the Shenzhen branch of the China Southern Power Grid.</p> <p> The automobile manufacturing industry has been a main driving force for power consumption, showing an increase of 80 percent in April compared to the same period in the previous year. The electricity consumption of information-related services rose 8.5 percent year on year in April.</p> <p> The northeastern province of Jilin, where over 60,000 cases were reported in the latest outbreak, cut off all COVID-19 transmission chains in communities by April 14. The provincial capital Changchun announced on May 1 that it has cleared all medium and high-risk areas for COVID-19.</p> <p> Leading Chinese automaker FAW Group Co., Ltd. began work resumption on April 13 after a month-long suspension. Workers in its five main engine plants in Changchun are working in shifts while some production lines are operating at full capacity.</p> <p> The company's daily output of complete vehicles has exceeded 4,000 units, and the capacity utilization rate of its factories in Changchun has recovered to 75 percent.</p> <p> Li Risheng, a FAW employee, said many of his colleagues voluntarily gave up their holidays since the work resumption. "Everybody hopes to speed up the production to recover the losses incurred by the epidemic," he said.</p> <p> All major express delivery firms including China Postal Express &amp; Logistics, JD.com and SF Express, have seen their distribution centers in Changchun resuming work from April 24.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's consumer prices see mild uptick, factory inflation narrows ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095622</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095622.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:11:44 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121002000523045733874.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Customers buy vegetables at a supermarket in Mengzi, southwest China's Yunnan Province, May 11, 2022. China's consumer price index (CPI), a main gauge of inflation, rose 2.1 percent year on year in April, the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS) said Wednesday. (Photo by Xue Yingying/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- China's inflation has remained at an overall moderate and controllable level, with consumer prices seeing a mild uptick in April and factory prices facing cost pressure, official data showed on Wednesday.</p> <p> The consumer price index (CPI), the main gauge of inflation, rose 2.1 percent year on year in April, and went up 0.4 percent from the previous month, according to the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS).</p> <p> The rise were partly due to the domestic resurgence of COVID-19 and the continuous rise of bulk commodity prices across the globe, noted Dong Lijuan, a senior statistician with the NBS.</p> <p> Food prices went up 0.9 percent from the previous month, driving up the monthly consumer inflation by about 0.17 percentage points.</p> <p> Specifically, the price of pork, a staple meat in China, increased 1.5 percent month-on-month in April, compared with a 9.3 percent decrease in March. Hog production has gradually tempered and stockpiling of pork to replenish state reserves is in progress, Dong said.</p> <p> Pork prices still registered a year-on-year drop of 33.3 percent, narrowing by 8.1 percentage points from the previous month.</p> <p> Non-food prices rose 2.2 percent from a year earlier, the same growth recorded the previous month. The prices of gasoline, diesel and liquified petroleum gas went up by 29 percent, 31.7 percent and 26.9 percent year on year, respectively.</p> <p> The core CPI, which excludes food and energy prices, gained 0.9 percent year on year in April, down 0.2 percentage points from the previous month.</p> <p> Wednesday's data also showed that China's producer price index (PPI), which measures costs for goods at the factory gate, went up 8 percent year on year in April.</p> <p> The figure moderated from the 8.3 percent year-on-year increase registered in March this year. On a monthly basis, China's PPI gained 0.6 percent in April, compared with the 1.1 percent increase seen in March.</p> <p> "China's inflation has remained at an overall moderate and controllable level," commented Wen Bin, chief analyst at China Minsheng Bank.</p> <p> Although both the monthly and year-on-year PPI growth rates slowed, "price hikes in bulk commodities across the globe still impose imported inflationary pressure on PPI," Wen said.</p> <p> <strong>UNCERTAINTIES, POLICY RESPONSE</strong></p> <p> Experts attributed the current high inflationary pressure in the global market to Western countries' disorderly domestic governance and tendency to stir up trouble and bully other countries, per a recent symposium held by the National Development and Reform Commission.</p> <p> Major economies in the West have been issuing excess paper currency and implementing loose monetary policies since the pandemic, which has pushed up bulk commodity prices, according to the symposium.</p> <p> Experts also noted that supply chain disruptions caused by COVID-19 and some Western countries' recent sanctions on Russia have further choked the global bulk commodity supply.</p> <p> On the domestic front, a report released on Monday by the People's Bank of China said that shrinking demand, supply shocks and weakened expectations brought about by the recent domestic resurgence of COVID-19 continue to linger, with contact-based consumption such as catering and retail posting a sluggish performance.</p> <p> The central bank reaffirmed its intention of implementing prudent monetary policy this year in the report, saying that it will avoid "flood-like" stimulus and better utilize monetary policy tools to adjust both the monetary aggregate and the monetary structure.</p> <p> Supporting the real economy and small and micro businesses, and boosting technological innovation, elderly care services and the clean use of coal while defusing risks faced by financial institutions remain the policy priorities, the report said.</p> <p> In general, China's economy has been maintained in a reasonable range, with a sufficient supply of industrial and agricultural products, resuming consumption and investment demand and prudent monetary policies, which is conducive to keeping prices stable in the medium-to-long term, according to the report.</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121004000443163165186.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 628px;" /></p> <p> <em>A customer buys vegetables at a supermarket in Linquan County, east China's Anhui Province, May 11, 2022. China's consumer price index (CPI), a main gauge of inflation, rose 2.1 percent year on year in April, the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS) said Wednesday. (Photo by Lu Qijian/Xinhua)</em></p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121005000512164890366.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 610px;" /></em></p> <p> <em>A customer buys fruits at a supermarket in Chengbu Miao Autonomous County, central China's Hunan Province, May 11, 2022. China's consumer price index (CPI), a main gauge of inflation, rose 2.1 percent year on year in April, the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS) said Wednesday. (Photo by Yan Qinlong/Xinhua)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Nation to prioritize economic stability ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095618</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095618.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:08:18 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/72/8587602988099379148.jpg" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 506px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Freight trucks drives on an overpass in Liuzhou, Guangxi Zhuang autonomous region, May 11, 2022. [Photo/Xinhua]</em></p> <p> China will adopt fiscal and monetary policies prioritizing job creation, as part of efforts to maintain the overall stability of economic performance, according to a decision made at the State Council's Executive Meeting chaired by Premier Li Keqiang on Wednesday.</p> <p> "The greater-than-expected impacts from the new round of COVID resurgence and shifting dynamics in the international environment have added new downward pressure to the economy in April. It is imperative to stay confident, face difficulties and challenges squarely, and keep overall economic performance stable, to lay the foundation for coordinated progress on all fronts," Li said.</p> <p> The meeting stressed that fiscal and monetary policies should be employment-oriented. Tax refunds and breaks, deferred payment of social insurance premiums, reductions in financing costs and other measures should all focus on maintaining the stability of market entities, payrolls and employment, to ensure people's basic livelihoods, stabilize growth and drive consumption.</p> <p> It is necessary to further use a variety of policy tools to mobilize local authorities' enthusiasm and ensure their responsibilities are well fulfilled, in order to effectively stabilize employment.</p> <p> "We must attach high importance to the work of stabilizing employment. Various supportive policies should be effectively and speedily implemented to encourage and help enterprises keep their payrolls stable. Local governments must fulfill their responsibilities of supporting market entities and stabilizing jobs. Pro-employment policies should be intensified with extended coverage," Li said.</p> <p> The meeting called for efforts to maintain price stability. China has a sufficient supply of essential livelihood products. That said, work in this regard should not be taken lightly. Solid efforts are needed on grain production to ensure stable grain output and supply and strengthen the foundations of price stability.</p> <p> While ensuring effective COVID response, further efforts will be made to ensure unimpeded logistics, especially in key areas, and safeguard the stability of industrial and supply chains. The normal supply of energy will be guaranteed.</p> <p> Measures to expand the coverage and extend the time frame of the policy for deferred payments of old-age insurance premiums will be promptly explored. Localities will be guided to subsidize the utility bills of micro, small and medium-sized enterprises and self-employed households.</p> <p> "Prices are the most sensitive indication and also the most important lever of the market. We must attach great importance to price stability, food and energy security, and the stability of industrial and supply chains," Li said.</p> <p> The meeting also decided to better mobilize existing assets, broaden the channels for private investment and expand effective investment.</p> <p> The mobilization of existing assets through setting up real estate investment trusts and other means will be encouraged. Localities will be guided to introduce projects to attract investment, and all types of investors will be treated equally.</p> <p> The market-based operation mechanism will be improved to raise the returns of the projects. New projects invested by recovered funds will be given access to funding from special-purpose bonds. The principle of market-orientation and law-based operation will be upheld, and transaction prices will be set openly and transparently.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Shanghai Port sees container throughput recover ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095610</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095610.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:03:05 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- The container throughput of Shanghai Port exceeded 3.08 million 20-foot equivalent units (TEUs) in April, recovering to 82.4 percent of that of the same month last year, a transport official said Wednesday.</p> <p> During the first four months, the port handled 15.35 million TEUs, up 1.8 percent year on year, said Li Guoping, an official with the Ministry of Transport.</p> <p> The port has seen its container throughput continue to recover this month, Li added.</p> <p> With its container throughput exceeding 47 million TEUs in 2021, the Shanghai Port has ranked as the world's busiest port for 12 consecutive years.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's Hunan posts growing trade with ASEAN in January-April ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095599</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095599.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:48:23 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> CHANGSHA, May 11 (Xinhua) -- Central China's Hunan Province saw its trade with ASEAN countries at 33.1 billion yuan (about 4.9 billion U.S. dollars) in the first four months of 2022, up 37.7 percent year on year, said local customs authorities on Wednesday.</p> <p> From January to April, the province saw the value of its imports and exports total around 165.7 billion yuan, up 2.2 percent year on year. Nearly 80 percent of Hunan's foreign trade was contributed by its private sector.</p> <p> Of the total, exports rose 3.5 percent year on year to 111.6 billion yuan, while imports lost 0.2 percent to 54.1 billion yuan, said Changsha customs.</p> <p> During the period, ASEAN remained Hunan's largest trade partner with the foreign trade value accounting for over one-third of the province's total.</p> <p> Among the export products, Hunan's labor-intensive products enjoyed relatively rapid growth, while high-tech products were the major imports of the province.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ E China's railway company tries to meet transportation needs of enterprises ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095540</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095540.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:26:55 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/26/4441201622354567798.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> A staff member works at Jinan South Railway Station in Jinan, east China's Shandong Province on May 11, 2022. Since April, with the acceleration of the work resumption process of enterprises, the transportation demand for production materials has been increasing.</p> <p> China Railway Jinan Group Co., Ltd. tries to meet the transportation needs of each enterprise, implementing customized cargo transportation services, giving priority to key materials to guarantee the stability of industrial chain and supply chain. (Xinhua/Guo Xulei)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/13/3283992072904897061.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 11, 2022 shows a crane loading goods at Jinan South Railway Station in Jinan, east China's Shandong Province. Since April, with the acceleration of the work resumption process of enterprises, the transportation demand for production materials has been increasing.</p> <p> China Railway Jinan Group Co., Ltd. tries to meet the transportation needs of each enterprise, implementing customized cargo transportation services, giving priority to key materials to guarantee the stability of industrial chain and supply chain. (Xinhua/Guo Xulei)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/92/13029993485613197512.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 506px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Aerial photo taken on May 11, 2022 shows staff members working at Jinan South Railway Station in Jinan, east China's Shandong Province. Since April, with the acceleration of the work resumption process of enterprises, the transportation demand for production materials has been increasing.</p> <p> China Railway Jinan Group Co., Ltd. tries to meet the transportation needs of each enterprise, implementing customized cargo transportation services, giving priority to key materials to guarantee the stability of industrial chain and supply chain. (Xinhua/Guo Xulei)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/13/2348602356602219921.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 506px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Staff members work at Jinan South Railway Station in Jinan, east China's Shandong Province on May 11, 2022. Since April, with the acceleration of the work resumption process of enterprises, the transportation demand for production materials has been increasing.</p> <p> China Railway Jinan Group Co., Ltd. tries to meet the transportation needs of each enterprise, implementing customized cargo transportation services, giving priority to key materials to guarantee the stability of industrial chain and supply chain. (Xinhua/Guo Xulei)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/8/15586160618499447676.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 506px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Aerial photo taken on May 11, 2022 shows staff members working at Jinan South Railway Station in Jinan, east China's Shandong Province. Since April, with the acceleration of the work resumption process of enterprises, the transportation demand for production materials has been increasing.</p> <p> China Railway Jinan Group Co., Ltd. tries to meet the transportation needs of each enterprise, implementing customized cargo transportation services, giving priority to key materials to guarantee the stability of industrial chain and supply chain. (Xinhua/Guo Xulei)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/15/16041829176812660867.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 506px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Aerial photo taken on May 11, 2022 shows staff members working at Jinan South Railway Station in Jinan, east China's Shandong Province. Since April, with the acceleration of the work resumption process of enterprises, the transportation demand for production materials has been increasing.</p> <p> China Railway Jinan Group Co., Ltd. tries to meet the transportation needs of each enterprise, implementing customized cargo transportation services, giving priority to key materials to guarantee the stability of industrial chain and supply chain. (Xinhua/Guo Xulei)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's cargo transportation sees robust recovery: official ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095537</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095537.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:22:29 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- China's cargo transportation has recorded steady recovery as the country introduced multiple measures to ensure smooth logistics and supply, a transport official said Wednesday.</p> <p> On Tuesday, the number of trucks running on expressways nationwide topped 7.21 million, up 25.65 percent from April 10, said Li Guoping with the Ministry of Transport.</p> <p> With the joint efforts of various regions and departments, the unsmooth logistics flow, triggered by the COVID-19 resurgence, has been initially eased and major logistics indicators have continued to improve, Li said.</p> <p> On Tuesday, the country's railway and road cargo volume rose 5.71 percent and 6.16 percent, respectively from April 18. Cargo throughput at China's major ports rose 1.12 percent, while business volume of postal and express services increased by around 20 percent.</p> <p> The ministry will work with relevant departments to ensure smooth and orderly transportation and logistics, and provide strong support for stabilizing the industrial chains and supply chains, Li said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China to prioritize employment in fiscal and monetary policies, mobilize existing assets to boost effective investment ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095534</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095534.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:21:39 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- China will adopt fiscal and monetary policies that prioritize job creation, as part of efforts to keep overall economic performance stable, according to a decision made at the State Council's Executive Meeting chaired by Premier Li Keqiang on Wednesday.</p> <p> The meeting also decided to better mobilize existing assets, broaden the channels for private investment and expand effective investment.</p> <p> "The greater-than-expected impacts from the new round of COVID-19 resurgence and shifting dynamics in the international environment have added new downward pressure to the economy in April. It is imperative to stay confident, face difficulties and challenges squarely, and keep overall economic performance stable, to lay the foundation for coordinated progress on all fronts," Li said.</p> <p> The meeting stressed that fiscal and monetary policies should be employment-oriented. Tax refunds and breaks, deferred payment of social insurance premiums, reductions in financing costs and other measures should all focus on keeping the operation of market entities stable, keeping payrolls stable and keeping employment stable, to ensure basic livelihoods, stabilize growth and drive consumption.</p> <p> Various policy tools will be further explored, and local authorities motivated with their due responsibilities well fulfilled, to effectively keep jobs and employment stable.</p> <p> "We must attach high importance to the work of stabilizing employment. Various support policies should be effectively and speedily implemented to encourage and help enterprises to keep their payrolls stable. Local governments must step up to their responsibilities of supporting market entities and stabilizing jobs. Pro-job policies should be intensified with extended coverage," Li said.</p> <p> The meeting urged efforts to keep prices stable. China has sufficient supply of essential livelihood products. That said, work in this regard should not be taken lightly. Solid efforts are needed on grain production to ensure stable grain output and supply and strengthen the foundation for price stability.</p> <p> While ensuring effective COVID-19 response, further efforts will be made to ensure unimpeded logistics, especially in key areas, and safeguard the stability of industrial and supply chains.</p> <p> The normal supply of energy will be guaranteed. On top of the support provided to electricity producers managed by the central government, including 50 billion yuan (7.43 billion U.S. dollars) in renewable energy subsidies and 20 billion yuan of replenished funds from the state capital operations budget, an additional 50 billion yuan in subsidies and 10 billion yuan from the budget will be made available to support coal-fired power plants in overcoming difficulties and increasing electricity generation.</p> <p> Measures to expand the coverage and extend the time-frame of the policy for deferred payments of old-age insurance premiums will be promptly explored. Localities will be guided to subsidize the utility bills of micro, small and medium-sized enterprises and self-employed households.</p> <p> "Price is the most sensitive signal and also the most important lever of the market. We must attach great importance to price stability, food and energy security and the stability of industrial and supply chains," Li said.</p> <p> The meeting also noted that infrastructure and other existing assets will be put to better use. This will help broaden channels for private investment, boost effective investment and reduce government debt risks.</p> <p> The mobilization of existing assets through setting up real estate investment trusts and other means will be encouraged. Localities will be guided to introduce demonstrative projects for attracting investment, and all types of investors will be treated as equals.</p> <p> The market-based operation mechanism will be improved to raise the returns of the projects. New projects invested by recovered funds will be given access to the funding of special-purpose bonds.</p> <p> The principle of market-orientation and law-based operation will be upheld, and transactions prices will be set in an open and transparent way. The steady operation of infrastructure will be ensured to safeguard public interests.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Time for US to lift China tariffs, ‘toxic’ monetary policy biting global economy ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095516</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095516.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:15:30 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> US President Joe Biden has finally considered resorting to the option of dropping China tariffs in an effort to quell skyrocketing domestic inflation, an efficient move that could have been adopted much earlier to curb surging US consumer costs.</p> <p> Though fully aware of that, the reluctance of the Biden administration to make any substantive moves suggests it is weighing whether the benefits to its people are worth undermining political goals, observers pointed out, calling for immediate efforts to scrap China duties and warning aggressive "toxic" rate hikes will threaten the global economy.</p> <p> Addressing the nation from Washington on Tuesday, Biden said he could drop some of the tariffs imposed against Chinese imports to help control rising consumer prices in the US, noting that the White House is reviewing the penalties and could opt to "remove them altogether."</p> <p> "We're looking at what would have the most positive impact," Biden said, adding that removing the tariffs was currently under discussion.</p> <p> Biden's remarks, which came after similar signals from other US senior officials, show the administration's anxiety and desperation in the face of worsening inflation woes, Gao Lingyun, an expert at the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences in Beijing, told the Global Times on Wednesday.</p> <p> Previously, Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen, White House press secretary Jen Psaki and Trade Representative Katherine Tai all indicated that China tariff relief is an option as prices soar.</p> <p> Latest data showed that the US consumer price index (CPI) hit 8.3 percent in April on a yearly basis, slightly moderate than the 8.5 percent increase recorded in March, but still hovers near four-decade high. The figure is also higher than a previous market expectation of 8.1 percent increase.</p> <p> The current dilemma faced by the Biden administration is the bitter fruits of its own policy, analysts said, as surging inflation resulting from the high energy prices, previous extremely loose monetary policy and tariffs on Chinese imports has worsened the situation.</p> <p> <strong>Best solution</strong></p> <p> "It's time for the US government to reconsider and lift additional tariffs imposed on Chinese products as soon as possible," Zhao Lijian, a spokesperson for China's Foreign Ministry said when asked about Biden's remarks at a regular press briefing in Beijing on Wednesday.</p> <p> "The unilaterally imposed tariffs by the US not only harmed China but also the US as well as the world," he said.</p> <p> In a recent interview with Forbes, Chinese Ambassador to the US Qin Gang said that the trade war has not reduced the US' trade deficit so far; on the contrary, the trade war has increased US companies' and consumers' costs. The tariffs have cost US corporations more than $1.7 trillion and increased US household spending by $1,300 per year on average.</p> <p> Additionally, US exports to China in the three years since the start of the trade war - 2018, 2019 and 2020 - were lower than the level in 2017 before the trade war, according to Zhao. During the period, the US lost more than 240,000 jobs due to the trade war.</p> <p> Dropping tariffs imposed under former president Donald Trump, which caused price rises on everything from clothing, furniture among other daily necessities of US residents, is also believed by economists to be the most apt decision to address the woes.</p> <p> "A feasible package of liberalization could deliver a one-time reduction in CPI inflation of around 1.3 percentage points, amounting to $797 per US household, about half the size of pandemic relief in 2021," according to research by the Peterson Institute for International Economics (PIIE) in March.</p> <p> Moreover, if the US adjusts its tariffs on China, China will also reciprocate and reduce tariffs on US imports, which could be a win-win results for firms and people from both countries, Gao noted.</p> <p> "Our members have opposed tariffs from the beginning. They are an added cost paid by US businesses and consumers. They contribute to inflationary pressures which have become a major concern for Americans. It's likely that tariffs in many consumer goods will be lifted first," Douglas Barry, Vice President of the Communications and Publications at the US-China Business Council, told the Global Times in an e-mail on Wednesday.</p> <p> Lower prices will stimulate demand. Companies will have more money to invest, Barry said.</p> <p> "On the other hand, lifting the tariffs would lead to skepticism about the administration's toughness toward China, and a softer stance may cause Biden to lose some political support at home," Gao said.</p> <p> According to a report from the Wall Street Journal, citing people familiar with the matter, Biden officials are divided over easing China tariffs to slow inflation. Trade Representative Katherine Tai and others are reluctant to "relinquish US leverage over China in a continuing effort to reshape Chinese economic behavior," according to the people.</p> <p> <strong>'Toxic' medicine</strong></p> <p> Last week, the Federal Reserve announced its sharpest rate hike in more than two decades as one of the few options to quell the inflation, but analysts pointed out the rate hikes could be a toxic medicine for the world as well as its own economy.</p> <p> The Fed's current policy of accelerating monetary tightening will help relieve the situation in the long run, but will need time to take effect. Besides, rate hikes will not help to ease energy prices or address problems on the supply side, Wei Hongxu, a researcher at ANBOUND, a multinational independent think tank, told the Global Times on Wednesday.</p> <p> Wei warned that if high inflation continues for a while, the US economic growth rate will decline while the Fed maintains its tightening policy.</p> <p> Fed officials, now committed to a series of half-percentage-point rate increases, said their aggressive efforts to curb consumer and business demand for goods and services through higher borrowing costs were needed to slow the fastest inflation in 40 years, but they also acknowledged it will be "a painful ride," according to a Reuters report Wednesday.</p> <p> The recent volatility in asset markets is "painful," Cleveland Fed President Loretta Mester told Reuters, but it is also a necessary part of tightening credit conditions in the economy.</p> <p> Even worse, the spillover risks of a toxic US monetary policy shift have already emerged, as moving from an extremely loose monetary policy to being forced to tighten it to deal with inflation, US monetary policy will cause chaos in international capital flows, which poses great risks to international financial markets and other economies, especially highly indebted countries.</p> <p> The increase in investment costs has led to a new round of adjustment in the global capital market, including the US, and triggered the return of international capital. This has already happened, Wei said</p> <p> Furthermore, the appreciation of the US dollar will have an impact on the currencies of other countries, especially emerging markets which will face increased pressure on capital outflows, thereby affecting the monetary, financial and economic stability of these countries. In particular, countries with heavy external debt burdens are constantly experiencing sovereign debt defaults, Wei warned.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China strives to improve business environment for higher vitality of market entities ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095524</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095524.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:09:12 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> China’s continuous efforts to deepen its reforms to streamline administration, delegate power, improve regulation and upgrade services for building a world-class business environment have greatly vitalized market entities and made important contributions to promoting high-quality economic and social development.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205120901000097668475242.jpg" style="width: 831px; height: 555px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on April 15, 2022 shows people applying for engineering construction approvals at a one-stop service center in Ningdu county, Ganzhou, east China’s Jiangxi province. (People’s Daily Online/Zeng Rongfeng)</em></p> <p> So far, the number of market entities across the country has exceeded 150 million, with an average annual increase of more than 12 percent. The number of private enterprises in the country increased fourfold in the past decade.</p> <p> As of the end of 2020, the time needed for starting a company in China had been reduced to less than four workdays, down from 22.9 since the country kicked off its national business system reform in 2014.</p> <p> “It used to take six months for us to get a business license, but now we can get it in just one workday the soonest possible,” said Phyllis Cheung, CEO of McDonald’s China.</p> <p> Cheung explained that in the past, her company had to apply for a series of certificates when opening a new restaurant, such as business license, food business license, organization code certificate, tax registration certificate, social insurance registration certificate, and pollutants discharge license.</p> <p> According to Cheung, some of the certificates have merged into one today and some have been canceled, which significantly saves time for enterprises.</p> <p> While streamlining approvals, China is also working to improve its management. It launched the National Enterprise Credit Information Publicity System in 2017, which strengthens supervision on delegated matters when they are being handled and after they have been handled.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205120901000214538786603.jpg" style="width: 828px; height: 552px;" /></p> <p> <em>Shanghai recently issued a guideline to instruct work resumption of industrial enterprises and established a “white list” mechanism for major enterprises. Photo taken on April 29, 2022 shows employees working in a workshop of Weben Smart Manufacturing System (Shanghai) Co., Ltd. (People’s Daily Online/Jiang Huihui)</em></p> <p> As of March this year, more than 700 entities had been listed as enterprises with serious illegal and dishonest acts by market regulation authorities across the country, and their information has been disclosed on the system.</p> <p> Besides, China is constantly enhancing its services for enterprises by optimizing business procedures. In the past, if an enterprise made a mistake when filling an application form, then it had to go to the department in charge again and refill the form. Today, thanks to e-government services, enterprises can apply for certificates online.</p> <p> So far, 31 provincial-level regions in China have electronized business registration procedures since the country piloted a national electronized registration program in 2016.</p> <p> According to Zhou Hui, who runs a private vocational school in Changzhou, east China’s Jiangsu province, it took him about one and a half months to apply for a permit for running private vocational schools in the past, but the same application only takes a day nowadays.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205120901000335619324934.jpg" style="width: 830px; height: 513px;" /></p> <p> <em>Employees of a bulk packaging bags producer in Suqian, east China’s Jiangsu province work on a production line, on May 8, 2022. (People’s Daily Online/Zhang Lianhua)</em></p> <p> “The survival and development of market entities rely on business environment. Great environment makes great enterprises. Relevant departments across China, upholding the vision that business environment means productivity, have constantly optimized business environment with multifaceted measures, which has continuously stimulated the passion of market entities for investment,” said Liu Quanhong, director of the International Economics Research Institute of the Chinese Academy of Macroeconomic Research.</p> <p> To cope with the impacts of COVID-19 on some market entities, a new version of the new regulation on market entity registration unveiled last year allows market entities with management difficulty to register for suspension, which has provided a “buffer zone” for these entities.</p> <p> “The business suspension rule is quite considerate and helps enterprises lower cost. It is lending a hand to us,” said Wu Jieping, owner of a tech firm based in Shenzhen, south China’s Guangdong province.</p> <p> According to a plan advancing the modernization of China's market regulation over the 14th Five-Year Plan period (2021-2025), the country will improve its market regulation system and efficiency eying on the general market, quality and supervision. It will promote the modernization of market regulation, strive to build an international business environment that is market-oriented and law-based, and vitalize the market.</p> <p> An official with the State Administration for Market Regulation told People’s Daily that the department will further advance pilot programs on improving the business environment and make the market entry and exit mechanism more open, transparent, standard and efficient, so as to set more examples in business environment building and better serve the high-quality economic and social development of the country.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ American businesses optimistic about Chinese market ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095519</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095519.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 08:53:39 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> As trade ties between China and the United States run deep and closely intertwined, many American companies are reasonably optimistic about the Chinese market and plan to increase investment, Craig Allen, President of the U.S.-China Business Council (USCBC) told People’s Daily.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205120851000337138489184.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 534px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on April 25, 2022, shows that more than 200 new vehicles manufactured by U.S. carmaker Tesla’s Shanghai Gigafactory are transported to Yantai Port, east China’s Shandong province. (People’s Daily Online/Tang Ke)</em></p> <p> Win-win cooperation between China and the U.S. plays a key role in driving world economic recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic. Many voices have been heard from the American business community urging its government to cooperate with China instead of decoupling so that the two countries could work together for a more peaceful and prosperous world.</p> <p> Founded in 1973, the USCBC has actively served as a trade bridge between the two countries, which has attracted more than 200 U.S. member companies doing business in China, including many of the world’s iconic brands. The membership is still growing.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205120852000091060756978.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 450px;" /></p> <p> <em>Aerial photo taken on March 28, 2022, shows cranes are carrying out container loading operations orderly in Jinhua city, east China’s Zhejiang province. (People’s Daily Online/Hu Xiaofei)</em></p> <p> Most of the USCBC members have invested in China for decades with a long vision and commitment, as China remains one of the most essential markets in the world. According to a 2021 survey conducted by USCBC among 107 U.S. firms operating in China, up to 95 percent of the respondents said they were profitable in the past year, and over 40 percent said they will increase investments.</p> <p> China continues efforts to deepen reform and opening up, optimizing an active and friendly business environment for foreign investors. “American businesses that we talk to are reasonably optimistic about the future,” Allen added.</p> <p> It’s the most impressive accomplishment of China to lift hundreds of millions of people out of poverty and improve their quality of life, Allen marked, looking forward to more high-quality goods and services in the country with the continuous improvement of living standards.</p> <p> China’s trade with the U.S. in 2021 reached a record $755.6 billion, up nearly 30 percent year-on-year. Another record shows that the U.S. goods exports to China increased by 21 percent to $149 billion, said a USCBC recent report.</p> <p> 2021 saw strong trade ties between China and the U.S. Agricultural exports and a big boost to the economies of the U.S. states with large agricultural sectors.&nbsp;</p> <p> All 50 U.S. states exported goods and services to China and benefited from the 858,000-strong American jobs supported by these exports, Allen said. Greater stability can bring more opportunities to businesses and people in both countries.</p> <p> Imposing tariffs and decoupling from China are not good for the country, for the U.S., and for the world, Allen said, stressing the positive aspects of economic globalization.</p> <p> “We should reject trade blocs and spheres of influence in favor of enhancing the positive aspects of globalization that have improved standards of living for billions of people over the last several decades,” Allen said. “The world needs China and the U.S. to play a positive role in continuing this contribution to a global public good.”&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Mild, controllable inflation expected ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095485</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095485.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 08:47:41 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/51/17003909244746178315.jpg" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 624px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Residents shop at a supermarket in Songjiang district of Shanghai, on May 10, 2022. [Photo/Xinhua]</em></p> <p> China's inflation is expected to remain mild and controllable this year, leaving room for macro policy fine-tuning and adjustment, experts and analysts said on Wednesday.</p> <p> They warned of multiple pressures from shrinking demand, supply shocks and weakening expectations amid resurgent domestic COVID-19 cases, as well as a more complicated and grimmer external environment, and said a stronger macro policy response was likely in order to stabilize expectations and shore up growth.</p> <p> The country's consumer price index, a main gauge of inflation, rose 2.1 percent year-on-year in April amid rising prices of fresh vegetables, fresh fruit and diesel fuel, marking the fastest pace in five months, the National Bureau of Statistics said on Wednesday.</p> <p> Meanwhile, the country's factory-gate prices rose in April at the slowest rate in a year as the government took steady steps to ensure stable supplies and prices amid international commodity price hikes. China's producer price index, which gauges factory-gate prices, increased 8 percent year-on-year in April, the NBS said.</p> <p> Wen Bin, chief researcher at China Minsheng Bank, said China's overall inflation level is mild and controllable. Wen said he expected policymakers to increase monetary policy support for hard-hit enterprises and sectors amid COVID-19 outbreaks, which will help ease enterprises' burden and promote economic growth to a reasonable range.</p> <p> Wen attributed the growth in consumer inflation to food and energy, warning of inflation pressure amid rising international commodity prices. He said more efforts are needed to ensure stable supplies and prices and ensure smooth logistics.</p> <p> Zhou Maohua, an analyst at China Everbright Bank, said that while the slower increase of the producer price index will help ease pressures on costs for some midstream and downstream manufacturing enterprises, the 8 percent increase in the PPI suggests that raw material prices remain high.</p> <p> "Many midstream and downstream manufacturing enterprises still face pressure from high production costs," he said.</p> <p> Looking ahead, Zhou estimated that China's consumer inflation may continue the uptrend seen in the last month but will remain mild overall.</p> <p> He said the uptrend may continue in the following months, given the resurgent domestic COVID-19 cases, fluctuation of energy prices, a recovery in pork prices and a low comparison base.</p> <p> However, overall, China's inflation will remain mild given the government's solid moves to control the epidemic, increase the support for enterprises, ensure stable supplies and prices, stabilize industrial and supply chains and ensure smooth logistics, Zhou added.</p> <p> <em>Zhou Lanxu contributed to this story.</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China speeds up future-oriented infrastructure development ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095470</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095470.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 08:34:12 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> <strong>* China's central authorities have vowed to build a modern infrastructure system and strengthen infrastructure construction in an all-around way.</strong></p> <p> <strong>* Economists believe that China's efforts in infrastructure development will inject new impetus for the country to achieve its economic growth target, and the modern infrastructure system will invigorate China's high-quality development in the long run.</strong></p> <p> <strong>* Despite the resurgence of COVID-19 infections, China's investment in infrastructure construction rose 8.5 percent year on year in the first quarter of this year.</strong></p> <p> SHENYANG, May 11 (Xinhua) -- Eyeing infrastructure as a pillar for economic and social development, China's central authorities have vowed to build a modern infrastructure system and strengthen infrastructure construction in an all-around way.</p> <p> Comprehensively strengthening infrastructure construction is of great significance to ensuring national security, smoothing domestic circulation, facilitating the "dual circulation" of domestic and overseas markets, expanding domestic demand and promoting high-quality development, according to a meeting of the Central Committee for Financial and Economic Affairs held last month.</p> <p> Economists believe that China's efforts in infrastructure development will inject new impetus for the country to achieve its economic growth target, and the modern infrastructure system will invigorate China's high-quality development in the long run.</p> <p> Despite the resurgence of COVID-19 infections, China's investment in infrastructure construction rose 8.5 percent year on year in the first quarter of this year.</p> <p> During the same period, China's fixed-asset investment in road and waterway infrastructure jumped 11.4 percent year on year to 512 billion yuan (about 76 billion U.S. dollars), according to data from the Ministry of Transport.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/94/8460808767137088190.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Builders work at the construction site of a tunnel, which is a part of a high-speed railway linking Shenyang with the Changbai Mountains, in northeast China's Liaoning Province, April 20, 2022. (Xinhua/Yang Qing)</em></p> <p> Since the beginning of the second quarter, a host of infrastructure projects have commenced across the country. Among them are 45 projects worth 29.2 billion yuan in east China's Fujian Province and 54 projects worth 32.1 billion yuan in Wuhan of central China's Hubei Province.</p> <p> In addition to traditional infrastructure projects such as water conservancy and transportation facilities, the construction of modern infrastructure such as 5G and big data centers and the construction of green energy systems have become new highlights of the current infrastructure layout, said Xu Hongcai, an economist with the China Association of Policy Science.</p> <p> "Traditional and modern infrastructure systems will jointly energize China's economic restructuring," Xu added.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/89/15280778082544867705.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>The construction site of an artificial intelligence center is seen in Shenyang, northeast China's Liaoning Province, April 29, 2022. (Xinhua/Yang Qing)</em></p> <p> China has been working on an integrated big data system across the country, which involves eight national computing hubs and 10 national data center clusters, the National Development and Reform Commission, the top economic planner, said in February.</p> <p> "The country's move to channel more computing resources from the eastern areas to the less developed western regions offers a huge opportunity for enterprises," said Yu Junfang, deputy general manager with the local branch of China Unicom in southwest China's Guizhou Province, home to one of China's computing hubs.</p> <p> Yu added the company will speed up the construction of data center projects, and strengthen the connection between the Guizhou computing hub and other computing hubs.</p> <p> On April 26, China Huaneng Group, a major state-owned power company, started the construction on seven large-scale offshore wind power projects in northeast China's Liaoning Province, with a total investment of more than 14 billion yuan. The power generation capacity is expected to reach 1.7 million kilowatts.</p> <p> Shu Yinbiao, chairman of China Huaneng Group, said the total investment in new energy projects launched by the company in the first half of 2022 will reach 90 billion yuan.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/72/13255934546604867184.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on April 26, 2022 shows an offshore wind power project of China Huaneng Group in Yingkou, northeast China's Liaoning Province. (Xinhua)</em></p> <p> During the first three months of the year, some 81,000 5G base stations were built across the country, bringing the total to over 1.5 million, official data showed.</p> <p> "Infrastructure construction plays a supporting role in promoting national and local high-quality economic development," said Yang Delong, chief economist with First Seafront Fund.</p> <p> Projects that boost industrial development, such as new energy, smart power grids, cloud computing and smart roads, will benefit the public in the long run and lay a solid foundation for basically achieving socialist modernization by 2035, Yang added.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/94/17334161460512734614.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Aerial photo taken on March 1, 2022 shows a cloud computing base in Zhongwei City, northwest China's Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region. (Xinhua/Wang Peng)</em></p> <p> According to this year's government work report, the country plans to issue a total of 3.65 trillion yuan of special-purpose local government bonds in 2022, and launch the construction of an array of major projects, modern infrastructure and renovation of old public facilities.</p> <p> China has signaled that infrastructure construction investment will play a significant role in expanding domestic demand, promoting circulation and stabilizing growth, said Liang Qidong, vice president of the Liaoning Academy of Social Sciences.</p> <p> For 2022, China's policymakers set the full-year economic growth target at around 5.5 percent, while the country's GDP grew 4.8 percent year on year in the first three months.</p> <p> Wang Qing, analyst with Golden Credit Rating, forecast that the growth rate of infrastructure investment will rise in the second quarter, further bolstering China's future economic growth.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Interview: China to unveil timely measures to stabilize employment: official ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095415</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095415.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 08:18:12 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205120808000305652197140.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>A staff member briefs policies to residents at an employment service center of a relocation site for poverty alleviation in Xingye County, south China's Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, Jan. 18, 2022. (Xinhua/Cao Yiming)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- China will roll out effective measures in time to stabilize employment in a bid to safeguard and improve people's livelihood, a senior official has said.</p> <p> "The country's employment situation has remained generally stable since the beginning of this year," Yu Jiadong, vice minister of human resources and social security, told Xinhua in an interview.</p> <p> According to official data, 4.06 million new urban jobs were created in the first four months, and China's surveyed urban unemployment rate stood at 5.5 percent in the first quarter, within the expected target.</p> <p> However, employment data has fluctuated since March, as a series of factors including the COVID-19 resurgence weighed on China's job market.</p> <p> Noting that stable employment is a key factor for the economy to function within an appropriate range, Yu called for strengthening the employment-first policy by fully implementing relevant employment measures.</p> <p> "The top priority is to ensure employment of key groups such as college graduates and migrant workers," Yu said.</p> <p> China will see the number of new graduates from the country's universities and colleges in 2022 exceed 10 million for the first time, hitting a historic high.</p> <p> China will expand employment channels for college graduates through multiple measures such as using job-creation subsidies to encourage firms to increase hiring or helping graduates start their own businesses by offering loan support, Yu noted.</p> <p> Various online recruitment activities will be launched to provide adequate information to the graduates, training courses will be designed to enhance their skills, and targeted services will be offered to graduates experiencing difficulties, Yu said.</p> <p> For boosting employment among those that had shaken off poverty, Yu urged efforts to deepen labor cooperation between eastern and western regions, develop distinctive industries in regions having been lifted out of poverty, and help cultivate business startups, among other moves.</p> <p> A total of 31.35 million people that had shaken off poverty found jobs by end-March, official data showed.</p> <p> Efforts will also be made to stabilize market entities by offering preferential policies including the deferred payment of social insurance, the vice minister said.</p> <p> "China's economic fundamentals for long-term growth remain sound and the momentum of sustained economic recovery stays unchanged, laying a solid foundation for employment stability," Yu added.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Gold trading volume up in China in first quarter ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095356</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095356.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 17:13:26 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- Gold trading volume climbed in China in the first quarter, the central bank said.</p> <p> Gold trading volume on the Shanghai Gold Exchange (SGE) went up 2.6 percent to 9,579.04 tonnes in the first quarter, said a report issued by the People's Bank of China.</p> <p> Gold trading value on the exchange stood at 3.69 trillion yuan (550.75 billion U.S. dollars) in the first quarter, up 5.2 percent year on year.</p> <p> The price of gold of 99.99 percent pure or above on the SGE closed at 394.14 yuan per gram at the end of March, up 5.4 percent from that at the end of 2021.</p> <p> The international gold price closed at 1,942.15 U.S. dollars per ounce at the end of March, up 8.3 percent from that at the end of 2021, the report said.</p> <p> The SGE, established in October 2002, provides trading, clearing, delivery and vaulting services for gold, silver and platinum.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China expands public welfare jobs for vulnerable groups in push for common prosperity ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095348</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095348.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 17:13:09 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> JINAN, May 11 (Xinhua) -- After four years of living without a stable income, 43-year-old Wang Junru from east China's Shandong Province now works at a local nucleic acid test site.</p> <p> "Please use your mobile phone to scan the QR code and fill in your information," Wang, dressed in a white hazmat suit, kept telling people queued up at a test site in Linqing City.</p> <p> Wang got the job after submitting an application to a local public welfare employment program in March. Now she makes around 2,000 yuan (about 297 U.S. dollars) per month, which is enough to cover her basic living expenses.</p> <p> Created and funded by the government, public welfare jobs refer to management and service positions that serve public interests. The policy, which has been implemented in China for decades, has effectively assisted long-term unemployed people to find jobs and helped absorb rural surplus labor and improve the livelihood of the country's low-income population.</p> <p> In 2020, China's Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security and six other departments jointly issued a notice on making better use of public welfare jobs to enhance employment security. Last month, the ministry once again noted the policy at a press conference, saying that more public welfare jobs will be created as part of the efforts to improve the employment situation of vulnerable groups.</p> <p> In Linqing, a city with around 800,000 residents, over 3,000 people have benefited from public welfare employment this year, most of them from low-income rural households or the so-called "zero-employment families," whose members are all jobless.</p> <p> The policy also helps those who face the risk of falling into extreme poverty due to illnesses or disabilities. Ma Xiuzhong, a 31-year-old resident in Zhaoguanying East Village of Linqing, suffers from uremia and is incapable of any heavy labor. Thanks to the public welfare jobs program, he got a "river conservator" job in March, mainly responsible for patrolling the river in his village and cleaning up floating garbages from the water.</p> <p> "This job requires no heavy labor and fits me well," said Ma, adding that the job means a lot to him and his family -- economically in particular.</p> <p> Some public welfare jobs have emerged as a result of new, urgent needs of the society, such as Wang's job at the nucleic acid test site amid the COVID-19 outbreak.</p> <p> Elsewhere in Shandong, the city of Linyi, which has a forest coverage rate of over 23 percent, has enrolled nearly 3,000 people for forest patrol and fire prevention, while Yicheng District of Zaozhuang City has offered seven types of public welfare jobs related to ecological protection, such as afforesting mountains and restoring wetlands.</p> <p> To date, Shandong has created a total of 409,700 such jobs, 80 percent of which are based in rural areas where employment opportunities are scarcer and public services are often in short supply.</p> <p> "Public welfare posts attract more people to participate in rural community-level governance, and to engage in major public affairs such as epidemic prevention and protection of farming infrastructure," said Yi Junqiang, director of the Shandong provincial public employment and talent service center.</p> <p> In December 2021, Shandong put forth a new plan to create about 1.2 million public welfare jobs between 2021 and 2025, mainly for vulnerable social groups and the older people.</p> <p> "China's active promotion of public welfare jobs will not only help offset the negative impact of COVID-19 on employment, but also give hope to more low-income and low-skilled people in their pursuit of a better life," said Sun Tao, a professor in economics at Shandong University.</p> <p> As China has set the ambitious goal of achieving "common prosperity" for its 1.4 billion people, Sun said, in the future government expenditures on public services and transfer payments to primary-level governments are expected to further increase, so as to improve both the quantity and quality of public welfare jobs.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's CPI up 2.1 pct in April ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095198</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095198.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 15:17:02 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/73/1774443282269459389.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>A resident shops for fruits at a supermarket in Zheng'an County, southwest China's Guizhou Province, April 11, 2022. (Photo by Zhao Yongzhang/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- China's consumer price index (CPI), a main gauge of inflation, rose 2.1 percent year on year in April, the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS) said Wednesday.</p> <p> On a monthly basis, the CPI inched up 0.4 percent partly due to the domestic resurgence of COVID-19 and the continuous rise of bulk commodity prices across the globe, noted Dong Lijuan, a senior statistician with the NBS.</p> <p> Food prices went up 0.9 percent from the previous month, driving up the monthly consumer inflation by about 0.17 percentage points, according to the data.</p> <p> Specifically, the price of pork, a staple meat in China, increased 1.5 percent month-on-month in April, compared with a 9.3-percent decrease in March. Hog production has gradually tempered and stockpiling of pork to replenish state reserves is in progress, Dong said.</p> <p> However, pork prices still registered a year-on-year drop of 33.3 percent, narrowing by 8.1 percentage points from the previous month.</p> <p> Non-food prices rose 2.2 percent from a year earlier, the same growth recorded the previous month. The prices of gasoline, diesel and liquified petroleum gas went up by 29 percent, 31.7 percent and 26.9 percent year on year, respectively.</p> <p> Wednesday's data also showed that China's producer price index, which measures costs for goods at the factory gate, went up 8 percent year on year in April.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Southeast Asian fruits ride RCEP wave to Chinese market ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095043</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095043.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 10:06:25 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NANNING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Durians have entered their best season, and orders for the "stinky" fruit in China began to soar in late April, driving its imports from Southeast Asia, its main producing area.</p> <p> The Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership (RCEP) agreement, the world's largest free trade deal to date that took effect on Jan. 1, 2022, has further boosted its sales this year.</p> <p> The RCEP countries account for roughly 30 percent of the world's gross domestic product and population. Over 90 percent of trade in goods among approved member states will gradually be tariff-free.</p> <p> "We received 100 boxes of durians, which were distributed soon after arrival. Besides community convenience stores, there are also many individual customers," said Huang Meixia with a subsidiary of Charoen Pokphand Group in south China's Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region. Charoen Pokphand Group is a leading agribusiness conglomerate in Thailand.</p> <p> Huang noted that compared with the same period of last year, the durians are selling well despite a price increase this year.</p> <p> Durians have conquered the taste of an increasing number of foodies across China. In 2021, the import volume of fresh durians was four times that of 2017.</p> <p> Nisachol Thaithong, a Thai national in Nanning, Guangxi's capital city, runs a business importing durians from her family's orchard in Thailand to China and has accumulated a stable customer source over the past years.</p> <p> "When it came to durians in the past, many consumers only knew Golden Pillow. Now they can recognize many more durian varieties," said Nisachol Thaithong.</p> <p> In Guangxi, more investment is being poured into infrastructure and cold-chain logistics to facilitate cross-border fresh fruit trade.</p> <p> Wei Pan, a social media influencer in Guangxi, has partnered with Nisachol Thaithong to airlift freshly-picked durians from Thailand to Chinese cities such as Guangzhou and Kunming.</p> <p> "It takes only two to three hours for the durians to fly from Thailand to China. Their shells are still turquoise when they appear on the Chinese market, indicating their freshness," Wei said.</p> <p> Guangxi's Qinzhou Port has opened several direct container routes to Thailand. The fruit express line from Laem Chabang to Qinzhou runs four times a week, and the fruits can reach China in about three to four days.</p> <p> Chinese consumers have strong purchasing power and a massive demand for high-quality products, noted Benjamas Tanvetyanont, Thai consul-general in Nanning.</p> <p> Apart from Thai durians, durians from Malaysia are also gaining in popularity in China.</p> <p> Chinese and Malaysian enterprises have recently signed 11 agreements to promote investment and strategic cooperation in cross-border trade, among which the trade of durians has become the focus of attention.</p> <p> Malaysian Deputy Minister of International Trade and Industry Lim Ban Hong said that the RCEP would bring considerable cooperation opportunities to enterprises from both Guangxi and Malaysia. He hopes that under the RCEP, China and Malaysia can establish closer economic and trade cooperation.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China to encourage foreign investment in more industries ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095017</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095017.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 09:57:33 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- China will further expand the industry catalog of sectors encouraging foreign investment, authorities said.</p> <p> The new list will add 238 more items, while up to 114 existing ones will be modified with expansion, said a notice issued by China's National Development and Reform Commission and the Ministry of Commerce (MOC).</p> <p> The increase is particularly relevant to items related to manufacturing, producer services, and those in the central and western regions, said the notice.</p> <p> The sub-catalog of competitive industries in the central and western areas encouraging foreign investment will introduce 188 new items, having modified 52.</p> <p> New items added to the national-level sub-catalog will include components and parts and equipment manufacturing in the manufacturing sector. It will also add professional design, technical services, and development in the producer services sector.</p> <p> Foreign direct investment into the Chinese mainland, in actual use, expanded 25.6 percent year on year to 379.87 billion yuan in the first quarter of the year, the MOC said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Shanghai's Pudong clears 2.7 bln USD worth of goods despite COVID-19 impact ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094980</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10094980.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 09:55:49 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> SHANGHAI, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Shanghai's Pudong Customs has cleared goods worth 2.7 billion U.S. dollars from March 28 to May 8 despite the impact of the COVID-19 epidemic, according to customs statistics.</p> <p> The customs handled 22,000 customs declarations and ensured the smooth passage of 2.75 million tonnes of goods during the period, the statistics showed.</p> <p> Pudong has among the most complete integrated circuit (IC) industry chains in the region. The customs has taken a series of measures to facilitate the clearance of relevant raw materials and equipment around the clock, it said.</p> <p> During the period, the customs cleared IC products worth around 260 million U.S. dollars in the Shanghai Jinqiao Comprehensive Bonded Zone, where IC enterprises are clustered.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China speeds up green, low-carbon transformation of data centers ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094990</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10094990.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 09:39:20 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205110928000412821190999.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 503px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo shows a data center of GDS Services Ltd. (GDS), a Chinese data center operator and service provider, located in Changshu city, east China’s Jiangsu province.</em></p> <p> The rapid proliferation of green data centers in China may be attributed to the rapid development of the country's digital economy, which is driving a wave of green transformation among traditional data centers and resulting in the continual expansion of newly developed ones.</p> <p> GDS Services Ltd. (GDS), a Chinese data center operator and service provider, exemplifies the green development of Chinese data centers.</p> <p> A green data center of the company, located in Shunyi district of Beijing, covers more than 15,000 square meters and houses over 2,000 equipment cabinets. It ensures smooth video streaming on the smart phones of users from thousands of miles away thanks to its real-time scheduling for computing power</p> <p> The data center’s power usage effectiveness (PUE) ratio has been drastically reduced to 1.22 by far, said Yang Tao, vice president of GDS. According to him, the green data center, when running at full capacity, can save about 10 million kWh of electricity a year.</p> <p> What brought down the PUE ratio for the GDS data center were the company's efforts to increase efficiency in both the supply and consumption of electricity.</p> <p> So far, 34 percent of GDS data centers across China are using green electricity, according to Yang. Besides, the company is also able to make optimal decisions and optimize the use of equipment through dynamic monitoring of key indicators, such as server load changes, indoor and outdoor temperature and humidity, as well as the starting frequency of heating and ventilation equipment.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205110929000176537246043.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>An employee checks servers at a cloud computing data center of Hangzhou Iron and Steel Group Co., Ltd., a conglomerate based in Hangzhou, capital of east China’s Zhejiang province, Sept. 1, 2020. (People’s Daily Online/Long Wei)</em></p> <p> The number of data centers, known as the cornerstone of digital economy, has increased exponentially in China in recent years. However, their escalating energy consumption is causing growing worry, despite their impressive computer capacity.</p> <p> China believes that to promote green development of data centers is not only beneficial to the sustainable development of digital economy, but also critical to energy conservation of new infrastructure. Therefore, it has ramped up efforts to advance the green and low-carbon transformation of data centers.</p> <p> According to data released by the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology (MIIT) and other authorities, 153 national-level green data centers have been built in three batches across the country.</p> <p> Besides, the country has selected and promoted five batches of 157 advanced technologies to accelerate its pace to lead the green and low-carbon development of data centers.</p> <p> “Data centers are major power consumers. Their expansion inevitably causes a substantial rise in energy consumption,” pointed out Chen Ying, secretary general of the Chinese Institute of Electronics.</p> <p> It’s estimated that data centers in China accounted for 1.5 percent to 1.9 percent of the total electricity consumption in the country in 2020, according to Chen.</p> <p> Besides, a new generation of information technology is significantly driving the demands for data storage, computing, and application, Chen said, adding it is also urgent to standardize the recycling and disposal of obsolete equipment from data centers to avoid environmental pollution.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205110929000517806269910.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on Dec. 24, 2021 shows a 125MW distributed wind power project in Xiamen township, Kongtong district, Pingliang city, northwest China’s Gansu province. (People’ s Daily Online/Wu Xihui)</em></p> <p> By 2025, the computing power of data centers in China will rise to 3.3 times that of 2020, said a plan for the development of China’s information and communication sector during the 14th Five-Year Plan (2021-2025) period.</p> <p> “Speeding up the construction of green data centers has become a basic requirement to ensure the sustainability of resources and environment. Besides, it is helpful for increasing the utilization efficiency of energy resources and achieving the carbon peak and neutrality goals,” said an official with the department of energy conservation and integrated use of the MIIT.</p> <p> At present, quite a number of companies are actively developing new technologies for the green transformation of data centers.</p> <p> In November 2020, an integrated energy station built by the Ningbo branch of the State Grid Corporation of China in east China’s Zhejiang province was put into operation. The data center of the energy station became the first of its kind in Zhejiang to use container-type equipment room with a liquid cooling system, which can save more than 430,000 kWh of electricity a year.</p> <p> Alibaba Cloud, the cloud computing division of Chinese e-commerce giant Alibaba, has made available to companies its self-developed immersion liquid cooling technology. By immersing servers in a special insulating coolant to enable heat generated by servers to be quickly carried away to external circulation by the coolant, the technology can reduce energy consumption by over 70 percent.</p> <p> Not long ago, China has approved a project to build eight national integrated computing hubs with 10 data center clusters across the country, completing the overall layout for the country’s national integrated big-data center system while indicating that its strategy to channel more computing resources from the eastern regions to its less developed yet resource-rich western regions is in full swing.</p> <p> The east-to-west computing resource transfer project is expected to guide the development of data center industry in western China, which will effectively increase the utilization of renewable energy sources, including wind, solar, and water, in the country’s western regions and eventually achieve an effective balance between industrial supply and energy consumption.&nbsp;</p> <p> By the end of 2023, the PUE ratio of newly built large and super large data centers in China will be reduced to less than 1.3, according to a three-year action plan on the development of large data centers between 2021 and 2023 released by the MIIT last July.</p> <p> Such rigid targets and timetable are believed to further speed up the green transformation of data centers across the country.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Global shipping firms get boost in China ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094915</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10094915.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 08:38:20 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/1/16977307515356505857.jpg" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 525px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p align="center" class="pictext"> <em>Yangshan Port in Shanghai. JI HAIXIN/FOR CHINA DAILY</em></p> <p> China has freed up the coastal piggyback system for shipping of foreign trade containers between ports within China, enabling foreign logistics giants such as A.P.Moller-Maersk and Orient Overseas Container Line to plan first voyages by the end of this month, analysts said on Monday.</p> <p> The move highlights China's willingness to further its opening-up policy, they said.</p> <p> Meanwhile, the administrative committee of Shanghai's Lin-gang Special Area of China (Shanghai) Pilot Free Trade Zone said at a news conference on Monday that China will introduce a container freight forward rate contract trading platform.</p> <p> Despite a complex international situation and given the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic, the Yangshan Special Comprehensive Bonded Zone in Shanghai has encouraged enterprises to resume production, and the business in the bonded zone has operated smoothly in the first quarter, the committee said.</p> <p> "The new service (for shipping of foreign trade containers between ports within China) is expected to help cut the logistics costs for both exporters and importers, improve the utilization rates of container ships, and relieve the tightness of shipping capacity to a certain extent," said Zhou Zhicheng, a researcher at the Beijing-based China Federation of Logistics and Purchasing.</p> <p> Jens Eskelund, China chief representative of Danish shipping and logistics giant A.P. Moller-Maersk, said the permission for foreign carriers to carry out international relay is very welcome news and represents a tangible step for foreign carriers in China toward achieving market access on reciprocal terms.</p> <p> "International relay will allow us to improve services, giving our customers more flexibility and options for their shipments. We are preparing the first shipment in Yangshan terminal in Shanghai, together with the Lin-gang Special Area Administration and other relevant stakeholders," Eskelund said.</p> <p> Hong Kong-based Asia Shipping Certification Services Co Ltd has been officially approved to carry out statutory ship inspection work in the Lin-gang Special Area as the first inspection agency that is not incorporated in the Chinese mainland.</p> <p> In March and April, the daily average container throughput in Yangshan terminal reached 66,000 and 59,000 twenty-foot equivalent units or TEUs, each accounting for 90 percent and 85 percent, respectively, of the average level seen in the first quarter.</p> <p> "Despite the recent resurgence of local COVID-19 cases, operations at ports have been relatively stable. With more companies resuming their business in late April, operations are foreseen to improve further this month," said Lin Yisong, an official of the Lin-gang Special Area Administration.</p> <p> As of Sunday, 193 companies operating in the Yangshan Special Comprehensive Bonded Zone, or 85 percent of the total, had resumed operations. About half of total employees who work in the bonded zone arrived at their workplaces physically.</p> <p> "The coastal piggyback system will help boost logistics capacity, improve efficiency and provide more business opportunities for global companies to further expand their market presence in China," said Bai Ming, deputy director of international market research at the Chinese Academy of International Trade and Economic Cooperation.</p> <p> "The move is more advanced than the coastal transportation policies being practiced in some countries. Major economies such as the United States and Japan have not opened up coastal transportation for global shipping firms yet," Bai said.</p> <p> China's total imports and exports of goods expanded 1.9 percent year-on-year to a record 32.16 trillion yuan ($4.77 trillion) last year, despite a worldwide slump in shipments due to the pandemic.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ PBOC steps up support for real economy ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094912</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10094912.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 08:38:12 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/55/16847454138858589691.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>A worker counts Chinese currency renminbi at a bank in Linyi, East China's Shandong province. [Photo/Xinhua]</em></p> <p> China is expected to deepen deposit rate reforms to lower corporate financing costs as part of the central bank's well-calibrated efforts to strike a balance between stabilizing economic growth and sheltering from the risk of capital outflows, economic experts said on Tuesday.</p> <p> They gave the remarks after the People's Bank of China, the country's central bank, said it had guided banks to form a market-based adjustment mechanism of deposit rates last month, helping send the weighted average deposit rate in the last week of April to 2.37 percent, down 0.1 percentage point from a week earlier.</p> <p> The central bank will employ the "significant role" of the adjustment mechanism and improve the market-based formation of interest rates to promote a reduction in corporate financing costs, said the first-quarter monetary policy report released on Monday.</p> <p> The new mechanism marks part of the central bank's stepped-up support for the real economy, as the report pledged to give proactive responses to stabilize the economy, boost market confidence, and focus on assisting smaller businesses and those hampered by COVID-19.</p> <p> Shao Yu, chief economist at Orient Securities, said the adjustment mechanism functions somewhat like a cut in deposit rates, which will help reduce the funding costs of banks, stabilize their profit margins in lending, and boost credit expansion in the real economy.</p> <p> Under the mechanism, banks are encouraged to adjust their deposit rates based on interest rates in the bond and lending markets, the report said.</p> <p> Thanks to the mechanism, loan prime rates－the benchmark lending rates calculated based on lending rates quoted by banks to their highest quality customers－could have greater room to decline going forward and would help alleviate the financing burden in the real economy, said Ying Xiwen, a senior researcher at China Minsheng Bank.</p> <p> The experts said the launch of the new mechanism, instead of high-profile moves like policy interest rate cuts, reflected the worst-case scenario mindset of policymakers, which takes risks into full consideration and reacts accordingly.</p> <p> Being alert to risks of capital outflows and currency depreciation, the central bank created the new tool to bolster the economy, Ying said. This was the case, given that the typical move of policy rate cuts could be significant in signaling monetary easing and amplifying the risks of capital outflows.</p> <p> The monetary policy report showed the central bank's emphasis on coping with risks, including policy adjustments by overseas central banks, global inflationary risks aggravated by geopolitical tensions, and a surge in local COVID cases.</p> <p> The report said major developed economies have sped up monetary tightening with spillover effects such as greater volatility in global financial markets and cross-border capital flows. The central bank will pay close attention to monetary adjustments in developed economies, strengthen macroprudential management of cross-border capital flows and improve the management of market expectations, the report added.</p> <p> The report said efforts will be made to assist in the supply of food and energy, ramp up structural monetary aids and support local governments in improving property market policies while refraining from taking the property market as a tool for short-term stimulus.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Ethio-Telecom partners with Huawei to launch pilot 5G services in Ethiopia ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094906</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10094906.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 08:34:58 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/20/3443566404599148092.png" /></p> <p> <em>A participant experiences 5G service demonstrations during the launching ceremony of pre-commercial 5G services trial in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, on May 9, 2022. Ethiopia's state-owned Ethio-Telecom on Monday evening launched a pre-commercial 5G services trial in the capital Addis Ababa in partnership with Chinese telecom giant Huawei. (Xinhua/Michael Tewelde)</em></p> <p> ADDIS ABABA, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Ethiopia's state-owned Ethio-Telecom on Monday evening launched a pre-commercial 5G services trial in the capital Addis Ababa in partnership with Chinese telecom giant Huawei.</p> <p> Ethiopia's first 5G services, which was launched across six mobile stations in Addis Ababa, is said to be part of the Ethiopian government's digital transformation aspirations.</p> <p> "We are pleased and honored to launch the world's advanced fifth-generation network. We are committed to seeing a digital Ethiopia, which will uplift our people's overall living conditions," Frehiwot Tamiru, CEO of Ethio-Telecom, said during the launching event.</p> <p> Tamiru said the 5G network service, characterized by the fastest speed and low latency and massive communication capability that offers service for up to 1 million connections within 1 square km, can unlock blazing fast speeds in more places, real-time responses and massive connectivity.</p> <p> Tamiru noted that Ethio-Telecom will expand its pre-commercial trial service across the capital and regional cities, reaching up to 150 sites over the coming 12 months.</p> <p> With high speeds, superior reliability and negligible latency, 5G will impact industries such as critical services requiring real-time decisions, manufacturing plants, remote healthcare, precision agriculture, as well as facilitate the Internet of Things (IoT), said Tamiru.</p> <p> "This 5G service will provide our customers with best-in-class solutions, improve their experience and allow our enterprise customers to boost productivity, enhance operational efficiency, and introduce new solutions to their customers," Tamiru said.</p> <p> Ethio-Telecom, which is the sole telecom services provider in Ethiopia so far, said the pre-commercial trial of the 5G service was launched after a temporary 5G Spectrum approval by the Ethiopian Communication Authority while its strategic partner Huawei technologies deployed the 5G network.</p> <p> Hou Wei, Vice President of Huawei Northern Africa, said as one of Ethio-Telecom's strategic partners, Huawei will keep focusing on cooperating with Ethiopia's state-owned telecom service provider through the provision of state-of-the-art solutions, reliable delivery, fast response and trustable maintenance.</p> <p> "Huawei has been devoting (itself) to this market for more than 20 years, and we have observed the fast development and great evolution of the telecom industry in this country," he said.</p> <p> Ethio-Telecom said the full commercialization of the 5G service is dependent on the readiness and demand from the players in the ecosystem, which includes customers' readiness to use the service as well as availability of 5G-enabled devices and smartphones.</p> <p> The company, which is recognized as one of Africa's oldest telecom service providers, has more than 60.8 million subscribers, with about 25 million data and Internet users.</p> <p> As part of its ambition to provide modern telecom service to its users, the company partners with Chinese tech companies, mainly Huawei and ZTE.</p> <p> The company said it has already expanded 3G and 4G networks throughout the East African nation effectively, achieving 97 percent telecom services coverage while densifying the network and upgrading the earlier technologies to the latest ones.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/81/6636743592211478153.png" /></p> <p> A 5G technology supported robot interacts with participants during the launching ceremony of pre-commercial 5G services trial in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, on May 9, 2022. Ethiopia's state-owned Ethio-Telecom on Monday evening launched a pre-commercial 5G services trial in the capital Addis Ababa in partnership with Chinese telecom giant Huawei. (Xinhua/Michael Tewelde)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/14/14989964152183082710.png" /></p> <p> A 5G technology supported robot interacts with participants during the launching ceremony of pre-commercial 5G services trial in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, on May 9, 2022. Ethiopia's state-owned Ethio-Telecom on Monday evening launched a pre-commercial 5G services trial in the capital Addis Ababa in partnership with Chinese telecom giant Huawei. (Xinhua/Michael Tewelde)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/83/13045825342394086439.png" /></p> <p> A participant experiences 5G service demonstrations during the launching ceremony of pre-commercial 5G services trial in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, on May 9, 2022. Ethiopia's state-owned Ethio-Telecom on Monday evening launched a pre-commercial 5G services trial in the capital Addis Ababa in partnership with Chinese telecom giant Huawei. (Xinhua/Michael Tewelde)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China endeavors to guarantee logistics, buoy economic flows ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094883</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10094883.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 08:33:47 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205110824000262969798010.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Villagers load oranges onto a truck in Zigui County, central China's Hubei Province, April 26, 2022. (Photo by Nie Shuang/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Amid COVID-19 disruptions, China has spared no effort in ensuring unimpeded logistics and stable supply chains as part of its resilience advancement of economic flows.</p> <p> "We must consider a full picture of national development to ensure unimpeded transportation and logistics, normalizing key industrial and supply chains, suppliers for COVID response, and critical infrastructure," said a recent meeting of the Political Bureau of the Communist Party of China Central Committee.</p> <p> A raft of policies and measures has transpired to facilitate flows of logistics and industries across the nation.</p> <p> <strong>PASSAGES UNBLOCKED</strong></p> <p> Efforts have been made to implement targeted traffic control by category, improve services for truck drivers, and ensure the transport of vital medical supplies, and people's livelihood, energy and agricultural supplies, according to departments, including the Ministry of Transport (MOT) and the Ministry of Public Security.</p> <p> To ensure efficient operation of the transportation network's backbone, a unified national pass for vehicles transporting vital supplies was adopted by 24 Chinese provinces by the end of April, with transit stations for emergency supplies opened in epidemic-hit regions such as Shanghai.</p> <p> MOT data showed that all expressway toll stations and service areas once temporarily closed nationwide had reopened as of May 4, without any temporary closure of toll stations on provincial highways.</p> <p> "Currently, logistics in Shanghai and other key areas are gradually improving, with initial results in rectifying excessive prevention and control problems," said MOT official Shu Chi, citing improvements in the country's transport capacity indicators and once-impeded logistics.</p> <p> <strong>TARGETED SUPPORT</strong></p> <p> Apart from preferential taxation support, Chinese authorities announced that eligible express delivery income would be exempt from value-added tax from May 1 to the end of the year. It is likely to reduce the burden for related enterprises by about 1 billion yuan (148.96 million U.S. dollars).</p> <p> These offered only a glimpse of nine primary policies and measures targeted at firms in the transport and logistics sectors introduced by the Ministry of Finance and other departments, along with incentives from the central bank and the country's top forex and banking regulators.</p> <p> Dong Yu, executive vice president of the China Institute for Development Planning, Tsinghua University, said to enliven logistics by smoothing micro-circulation, "we should make better use of new technology with more efficient scheduling."</p> <p> As intelligent unmanned delivery vehicles deliver goods on roads in Guangdong and Shanghai, cities including Beijing have established a "white-list" mechanism to secure the delivery capacity of fresh produce suppliers.</p> <p> <strong>STABILIZING CHAINS</strong></p> <p> Efforts will ensure the solid implementation of the "white-list" approach to support the resumption of work for key companies and remove bottlenecks in some places, said Xin Guobin, vice minister of industry and information technology, in an interview with Xinhua.</p> <p> His remarks came in light of the new challenges that have emerged since mid-March, including sporadic resurgences of COVID-19 and a complex external environment, resulting in the suspension of some factory activities and freight transport.</p> <p> In southwest China's Chongqing Municipality, millions of integrated chips are produced on a daily basis and delivered to downstream enterprises from the China Resources Microelectronics industrial park.</p> <p> Zhuang Hengqian, deputy general manager of the company, said that much of the company's raw materials are from the Yangtze River Delta. But since the government promoted active resumption of "white-listed" enterprises, their production has gradually returned to normal.</p> <p> Currently, the country is seeing an accelerated pace of resumption of production in key areas and industries, Xin said, adding that 86.8 percent of enterprises among the 666 companies included in the first batch of the "white list" in Shanghai had resumed work by April 28.</p> <p> With swift countermeasures to stabilize the industrial and supply chains, the country's industrial economy has shown positive signs of stabilization, seen in a narrowed decline in industrial electricity consumption for two consecutive weeks since the second week of April, Xin added.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
	</channel>
</rss>