<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title> English </title>
		<image>
			<title>People's Daily Online</title>
			<link>http://english.people.com.cn/</link>
			<url>http://english.people.com.cn/images/en/top_logo_e.gif</url>
		</image>
		<description>People's Daily Online</description>
		<link>http://english.people.com.cn</link>
		<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese embrace digital yuan as China further promotes pilot program ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096754</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096754.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 09:43:55 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> <strong>*Chinese people are embracing the digital yuan with a positive attitude. Thanks to the promotion of banking institutions, internet companies, and retail terminals, digital yuan now can be used in a wider range of scenarios.</strong></p> <p> <strong>*China has stepped up efforts to promote the digital yuan with pilot programs. Since 2017, the country has tested the use of the digital yuan in over 10 places from Shenzhen to Shanghai and Xiong'an New Area.</strong></p> <p> <strong>*China's digital yuan transactions hit nearly 87.57 billion yuan at the end of 2021, as the country ramped up research and pilot use of the central bank's digital currency.</strong></p> <p> GUANGZHOU, May 14 (Xinhua) -- In the Canton Tower located in Haizhu District, a landmark of the southern Chinese metropolis of Guangzhou, Zhang Ling, a shopper from southwest China's Sichuan Province, bought a souvenir. Unlike her usual transactions, this time she chose to pay in digital yuan, China's digital fiat currency, or the e-CNY.</p> <p> "I feel it is very convenient as it took me less than one minute to download the application and register an account," said Zhang. "There are also some discounts available now, so I'm willing to try the digital yuan."</p> <p> Like Zhang, many Chinese people are embracing the digital yuan with a positive attitude. Thanks to the promotion of banking institutions, internet companies, and retail terminals, digital yuan now can be used in a wider range of scenarios.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150855000014122697528.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Undated photo shows a customer paying in digital yuan (e-CNY) at a retail store in Guangzhou, south China's Guangdong Province. (Xinhua)</em></p> <p> <strong>MORE CONVENIENT</strong></p> <p> China has stepped up efforts to promote the digital yuan with pilot programs. Since 2017, the country has tested the use of the digital yuan in over 10 places from Shenzhen to Shanghai and Xiong'an New Area.</p> <p> The use of digital yuan is similar to that of WeChat Pay and Alipay, which are popular online payment apps in China. With QR code or Near Field Communication (NFC) techniques, the payment can be completed easily on mobile terminals of both shoppers and merchants. What makes digital yuan different is that it can still be used without a network.</p> <p> Tourists could pay in digital yuan at ticket windows, merchandise stores and restaurants from April 15, according to Liu Yiying, a finance manager of the management branch under Canton Tower Cultural Tourism Development Co., Ltd.</p> <p> "We launched preferential activities for digital yuan after the May Day holiday, which has attracted an increasing number of tourists," said Liu.</p> <p> In the tramline in Guangzhou's Haizhu District, the upgraded checking machines in passenger cars and stations also support digital yuan payment.</p> <p> Since the digital yuan payment was launched in April, hundreds of payments have been made cumulatively, with nearly 100 orders a day at most, according to Su Jun, deputy general manager of Guangzhou Tram.</p> <p> "From the perspective of enterprises' financial management, digital yuan improves the efficiency as the money paid by consumers can be transferred to our account in real time," said Su.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150856000153108145656.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 595px;" /></p> <p> <em>People walk past a sign of digital yuan (e-CNY) during the 2021 China International Fair for Trade in Services (CIFTIS) in Beijng, capital of China, Sept. 5, 2021. (Xinhua/Wu Wei)</em></p> <p> <strong>MORE INSTITUTIONS COVERED</strong></p> <p> The pilot version of the digital yuan app was released on major Android app stores and Apple's App Store on Jan 4. Currently, the designated operators of digital yuan cover major Chinese banks, such as Industrial and Commercial Bank of China (ICBC), China Construction Bank, and online banks.</p> <p> "We promote discount campaigns for people using the digital yuan in supermarkets such as Guangzhou Grandbuy and Guangzhou Friendship Store, which can effectively stimulate the enthusiasm of consumers," said an official with the Guangzhou branch of ICBC. "The merchants are also free of service charge at the same time."</p> <p> Many internet platforms that gather rich consumption scenes are also opening up to embrace the digital currency, such as JD.COM, Tencent, Meituan and Bilibili.</p> <p> By the end of 2021, there were more than 8 million applicable scenarios of digital yuan in the pilot areas via WeChat, a social software developed by Tencent. The company said it has deeply participated in the design, research, development and operation of the digital currency since 2018.</p> <p> According to data from Meituan, more than 5 million sub-wallets of digital currency were pushed to the Meituan App, and more than 4 million users spent digital yuan on Meituan from last September to early May.</p> <p> Several banks in south China's metropolis of Shenzhen are to cooperate with Meituan to distribute red packets of digital yuan worth 30 million yuan (about 4.42 million U.S. dollars).</p> <p> "The pilot project of Meituan is a beneficial attempt to advocate simple, moderate, green and low-carbon life through digital currency," said Cao Heping, a professor at the School of Economics of Peking University.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150857000565883392938.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>A passenger pays for a bus ticket in digital yuan (e-CNY) in southwest China's Chongqing, April 29, 2022. (Photo by Luo Ling/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> <strong>MORE CITIES INVOLVED</strong></p> <p> The People's Bank of China (PBOC) announced in early April that the pilot program would be expanded to more domestic cities, including Tianjin, Chongqing, Guangzhou, Fuzhou, Xiamen and six cities in east China's Zhejiang Province hosting the 19th Asian Games, following its successful operation over the past years.</p> <p> Beijing and Zhangjiakou were also included in the program after tests in the 2022 Olympic and Paralympic Winter Games.</p> <p> A number of application modes have taken shape in wholesale and retail, catering, tourism and payment of administrative fees, which cover both online and offline scenarios and can be replicated and promoted. The scale of users, merchants and transactions in the pilot areas has grown steadily.</p> <p> Guangzhou, as one of the pilot cities, has innovatively implemented new application scenarios such as granting talent subsidies and paying parallel imported cars with digital yuan and promoted the use of digital yuan in various scenarios such as transportation, supermarkets in business circles, tourism and online consumption platforms.</p> <p> China's digital yuan transactions hit nearly 87.57 billion yuan at the end of 2021, as the country ramped up research and pilot use of the central bank's digital currency.</p> <p> A total of 261 million personal wallets for the digital yuan had been opened, and the number of pilot scenarios had exceeded 8.08 million, said Zou Lan, an official with the PBOC.</p> <p> Zou said the central bank would continue promoting research and development of the digital fiat currency and further deepen the pilot use of e-CNY in retail services, government services, and other scenarios.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Nucleic acid test support teams from Hubei leave Shanghai with mission accomplished ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096757</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096757.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 09:32:06 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150916000032010264518.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 618px;" /></p> <p> Members of nucleic acid test support team enter the airport terminal in east China's Shanghai, May 14, 2022. A total of 207 members of nucleic acid test support teams from Hubei Province left Shanghai after they accomplished their mission. (Xinhua/Li He)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150917000089573830265.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 601px;" /></p> <p> Members of nucleic acid test support team wave goodbye to people in east China's Shanghai, May 14, 2022. A total of 207 members of nucleic acid test support teams from Hubei Province left Shanghai after they accomplished their mission. (Xinhua/Li He)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150919000490893595076.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 628px;" /></p> <p> Members of nucleic acid test support team enter the airport terminal in east China's Shanghai, May 14, 2022. A total of 207 members of nucleic acid test support teams from Hubei Province left Shanghai after they accomplished their mission. (Xinhua/Li He)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ U.S. urged not to rope in Southeast Asian countries out of geopolitical interests ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096756</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096756.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 09:32:02 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150908000197676617846.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on Nov. 23, 2021 shows the White House in Washington, D.C., the United States. (Photo by Ting Shen/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> <strong>The United States "shall fail in attempts to counter China, because most ASEAN countries want to expand economic exchanges and other cooperation with (their) regional neighbor China," Wilson Lee Flores, a columnist for the English daily The Philippine Star, told Xinhua.</strong></p> <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) -- The just-concluded U.S.-ASEAN summit will not draw regional countries closer to the U.S. side, and the U.S. attempt to court support among ASEAN in pursuit of its geopolitical interests is unlikely to gain traction, experts have said.</p> <p> U.S. President Joe Biden met leaders of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) countries at the White House during a summit held on Thursday and Friday, a move widely seen as an attempt by the world's sole superpower to pull members of the bloc into its camp against a rising China.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150910000074870687142.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>U.S. President Joe Biden arrives at the White House in Washington, D.C., the United States on Jan. 24, 2022. (Photo by Ting Shen/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> U.S. ATTEMPTS SHALL FAIL</p> <p> Against the backdrop of escalating tensions between Russia and Ukraine, the U.S.-initiated summit was widely viewed as a signal to highlight the importance of what America calls the "Indo-Pacific" region out of strategic concerns, and to counter the rising influence of China in the region.</p> <p> Lee Pei May, a political expert at the International Islamic University Malaysia, said while the summit occurred amid the tougher Russia-Ukraine conflict, the primary concern of the Biden administration is not about Russia, but more about ensuring a so-called "free and open" Indo-Pacific.</p> <p> "For the Biden administration to advance this vision, they have to get ASEAN countries on the American side and potentially for the U.S. to play a role in managing the disputes in the South China Sea," she said. "Such moves can be interpreted as challenging China's position in the region and hindering peaceful progress between China and ASEAN countries."</p> <p> The summit's significance lies in its timing, reported Foreign Affairs magazine on Wednesday. "It is being held as war rages in Ukraine, demonstrating that the United States has not lost its focus on the Indo-Pacific," the report said, adding "U.S. President Joe Biden seeks to better position his country in the wider geopolitical competition with China."</p> <p> Yet, the United States "shall fail in attempts to counter China, because most ASEAN countries want to expand economic exchanges and other cooperation with (their) regional neighbor China," Wilson Lee Flores, a columnist for the English daily The Philippine Star, told Xinhua.</p> <p> Flores noted that Washington was also aimed at convincing ASEAN countries to take tougher public positions and join its sanctions against Russia, which, likewise, shall fail. "Most of ASEAN seek to promote dialogue, diplomacy and stability in crisis areas due to ASEAN's traditional position of non-interference and upholding consensus."</p> <p> Joseph Matthews, a senior professor at the BELTEI International University in Phnom Penh, said that the United States should not use the summit to coerce and pressure ASEAN into submitting to its will and approach against Russia and China.</p> <p> Commenting on the Western sanctions and illegal embargoes on Russia, Ky Sereyvath, director general of the Institute of China Studies at the Royal Academy of Cambodia, said these sanctions will harm the global economy.</p> <p> "I think the rise in fuel prices will not slow down if the Ukraine crisis still continues and the U.S. still push this war forward," Sereyvath added.</p> <p> As the United States is scrambling to combat a sluggish economy and simmering social disorder amid COVID-19, its capability to fulfill promises to other countries has come under question.</p> <p> "The U.S. now has limited capacities to deliver on its promises, due to its own political and economic challenges, especially with the upcoming midterm elections in November," Flores cautioned.</p> <p> "The U.S. can still lobby to export its weapons to ASEAN. It can still attempt (to carry out) political or diplomatic initiatives. It can also attempt to pursue security alliances. But its waning economic activities and influence in Asia will weaken its strategic presence and leverage," the columnist noted.</p> <p> From the "Pivot to Asia" to the "Indo-Pacific Strategy," the United States has been teaming up its allies and regional countries to contain China. Washington never stops hyping up the concept of "Indo-Pacific" to peddle the targeted strategy at economic, political and military levels.</p> <p> A recent report by the U.S. Center for Strategic and International Studies showed that many ASEAN members have expressed concerns that the so-called "Indo-Pacific Economic Framework" is "primarily a political endeavor meant to counter China, rather than a sincere and thoughtful economic policy integration initiative."</p> <p> This viewpoint was echoed by Veronika Saraswati, researcher at Indonesia's the Center for Strategic and International Studies. "It is not hard to see that although the United States wants to strengthen its influence in ASEAN, it has not built cooperation with ASEAN countries in a more concrete level, only symbolic."</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150911000108339247797.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>ASEAN foreign ministers pose for a group photo during the ASEAN foreign ministers' meeting (AMM Retreat) in Phnom Penh, Cambodia, Feb. 17, 2022. (Photo by Sovannara/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> <strong>ASEAN NATIONS WON'T TAKE SIDE</strong></p> <p> Many believe that ASEAN members, now with a primary focus on post-pandemic economic recovery, will maintain neutrality at the forefront and neglect the attempts to pressure them into a U.S. sphere of influence.</p> <p> With China rising "sharply out of expectation," the United States "is afraid of losing its control" in Southeast Asia and found it necessary to hold tighter their hegemonic power, Saraswati pointed out.</p> <p> The Indonesian researcher stressed that Southeast Asian countries, including Indonesia, certainly do not want to be dragged into the competition between major powers.</p> <p> "Powerful countries should never use coercive measures to force other countries to choose side," she noted. "For a long time, the exercise of hegemonic power by the U.S. and its allies has had a deep impact on the survival and development of many countries."</p> <p> The United States will find itself unable to make any headway among ASEAN members, especially after Malaysia and Indonesia voiced concerns over the AUKUS trilateral security partnership involving Australia and Britain, said Azmi Hassan, a senior research fellow at Nusantara Academy for Strategic Research.</p> <p> Hassan gave the persuasive example that the United States has been unable to exert pressure on ASEAN over the Russia-Ukraine conflict, with most of the 10-member bloc abstaining from voting in favor of a resolution to suspend Russia from the United Nations Human Rights Council last month.</p> <p> "Bringing up controversial issues, forcing and coercing ASEAN member states to support its approach and agenda in the region, and trying to divide ASEAN on any issues will undermine the credibility and authenticity of the whole summit. The U.S. should be mindful of it," Matthews told Xinhua.</p> <p> Rather than pressing the bloc to follow its scenarios or agendas against other countries, Washington should use the meeting to express support for ASEAN's post-COVID-19 socioeconomic recovery, Kin Phea, director-general of the International Relations Institute at the Royal Academy of Cambodia, told Xinhua.</p> <p> "What the U.S. should do is encouraging ASEAN to adhere to its principle of centrality, solidarity and unity," he said, adding the United States should also respect ASEAN's rights in making decisions and refrain from using economic, political or security pressure to bargain with ASEAN or to force ASEAN to make decisions in its favor.</p> <p> "The U.S. must respect the common interests of the ASEAN, the region and the world, and should not put forward any scenarios or agendas that lead to ASEAN's rift and instability in the region," he said.</p> <p> <strong>VIGILANCE, UNITY URGED IN ASEAN</strong></p> <p> It is essential for the 10-member bloc to stand in solidarity against the U.S. interference for the sake of regional peace, stability, development and prosperity, Phea said.</p> <p> Matthews also urged ASEAN leaders to be vigilant about the Quadrilateral Security Dialogue among the United States, Japan, Australia and India, and the Australia-U.K.-U.S. pact, saying both military-cum-security alliances are posing a major security threat to ASEAN and the whole Asia region.</p> <p> "These alliances will trigger a conventional and nuclear arms race in the region, and thus destabilize peace and security, undermine economic development and destroy the ASEAN's centrality," he said.</p> <p> Unless it can demonstrate unity, ASEAN may find itself in a position where different members pursue different paths, which could compromise its cohesiveness, Lee cautioned. "This can be remedied by member states forging a consensus when dealing with the United States."</p> <p> "Having a consensus on key issues is not easy, but it is crucial as it would allow the members to speak with one united voice at the summit," the Malaysian expert noted. "The members can send a signal to the U.S. that ASEAN would remain neutral in whatever circumstances."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Finland, Sweden joining NATO are likely to have far-reaching implications ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096755</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096755.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 09:31:58 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150904000223799012230.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Swedish Foreign Minister Ann Linde (R) and Minister of Defense Peter Hultqvist attend a press conference on a security analysis in Stockholm, Sweden, on May 13, 2022. (Ninni Andersson/Government Offices of Sweden/Handout via Xinhua)</em></p> <p> <strong>Finland and Sweden have been members of the European Union since 1993, but until now they have been among a small minority of EU member states not part of the NATO military alliance. Once they join, it will leave only four of the EU's 27 member states Austria, Cyprus, Ireland, and Malta -- outside NATO.</strong></p> <p> Swedish Foreign Minister Ann Linde (R) and Minister of Defense Peter Hultqvist attend a press conference on a security analysis in Stockholm, Sweden, on May 13, 2022. (Ninni Andersson/Government Offices of Sweden/Handout via Xinhua)</p> <p> Finland and Sweden have been members of the European Union since 1993, but until now they have been among a small minority of EU member states not part of the NATO military alliance. Once they join, it will leave only four of the EU's 27 member states Austria, Cyprus, Ireland, and Malta -- outside NATO.</p> <p> ROME, May 14 (Xinhua) -- The likely ascension of Finland and Sweden to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) has been sparked by fears in those countries of the ongoing Russia-Ukraine conflict. But analysts said the development could have consequences that go beyond the current crisis.</p> <p> Finland and Sweden have been members of the European Union since 1993, but until now they have been among a small minority of EU member states not part of the NATO military alliance. Once they join, it will leave only four of the EU's 27 member states Austria, Cyprus, Ireland, and Malta -- outside NATO.</p> <p> It also means that 24 of NATO's 32 members will be members of the European Union.</p> <p> Analysts said that the two countries' membership in NATO will strengthen the alliance: both countries are among the world's richest nations, according to World Bank data, and military spending in both countries is broadly in line with NATO averages stated as a percentage of each country's gross domestic product.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150905000415000754359.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Swedish Foreign Minister Ann Linde (6th L), Minister of Defense Peter Hultqvist (5th L) and other parliamentary party representatives present the result of a security analysis at a press conference in Stockholm, Sweden, on May 13, 2022. (Ninni Andersson/Government Offices of Sweden/Handout via Xinhua)</em></p> <p> "What this means is that the ties between NATO and the European Union will become even closer," Elena Sciso, an international law professor at Rome's LUISS University, told Xinhua. "Consider that the European Union's Lisbon Treaty from 2009 includes a clause on mutual, collective defense, just as NATO does."</p> <p> Nicolai von Ondarza, a political scientist and head of the European Union division at the German Institute for International and Security Affairs said Finland and Sweden were never "entirely neutral" when it came to security issues, noting their armed forces already coordinated activities with those from NATO countries and they shared intelligence. Instead, they practiced what he called "armed neutrality" -- meaning they are willing to use military force to maintain their neutrality if needed.</p> <p> "One of the things this will mean is that the Baltic Sea will now become largely a NATO Sea," von Ondarza said in an interview, referring to the body of water in northern Europe surrounded by Denmark, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Poland, and Germany -- all NATO member states -- in addition to Finland, Sweden, and Russia.</p> <p> "I also think we will see a policy shift when it comes to foreign and military policy that will shift from crisis management to territorial defense," he said.</p> <p> According to LUISS University's Sciso, there could be impacts of the move far beyond Europe. She noted that the Arctic Sea -- a nearly unpopulated region without major land mass thought to contain 160 billion barrels of oil and as much as 30 percent of the planet's natural gas is currently administered by eight countries that border it, five of which are members of NATO: Canada, Denmark, Iceland, Norway, and the United States. Once Finland and Sweden join NATO, that number will be seven of eight, with only Russia outside the alliance.</p> <p> "It's significant because the states that govern the area will be dominated by NATO," Sciso said. "The countries involved are obligated to respect rules agreed to for the region on things ranging from fishing rights to nuclear testing, but they remain sovereign states and two of them are the world's largest nuclear powers."&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Feature: Baby formula shortage worsening in U.S. prompts federal intervention ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096750</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096750.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 16:09:25 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> DENVER, the United States, May 13 (Xinhua) -- Grocery store shelves were bare of baby formula around Denver and other cities in the United States Friday as the federal government continued unprecedented steps toward accelerating production and distribution of the vital supplement.</p> <p> U.S. President Joe Biden defended his response to the crisis Friday as Republicans and conservative media attacked his administration's actions.</p> <p> "If we'd been better mind readers I guess we could have (reacted faster)," he told CNN at a press conference.</p> <p> Across the country, mothers took to social media and drove up to 50 miles to look around amid baby food formula shortage, People, an American weekly magazine that specializes in celebrity news and human-interest stories, said Friday, calling the situation "very, very scary."</p> <p> One mother also told the Denver Channel that "my entire family just goes and finds the formula when we they can."</p> <p> "My sister picked me up some in Arvada yesterday, my dad up in Thornton the other day," Ashlee Lane, the mother of a 7-month-old, said of her family's efforts scouring the Denver area for baby formula.</p> <p> Data released this week by Datasembly, which tracks baby formula stock at more than 11,000 stores, showed that 43 percent of the top-selling baby formula products were out of stock as of the week ending May 8, and in five states, more than half of the top-selling formula products were missing from stores.</p> <p> At busy retail giant Target in Boulder, 50 km northwest of Denver, baby formula supplies were scarce and most store shelves were empty on Friday.</p> <p> "Usually they tell us when more is coming in," a store inventory clerk told Xinhua, pointing to her hand-held computer. "But this says zero are coming in and zero are expected soon."</p> <p> Nearby, at high-end grocer Whole Foods, the story was the same, even with non-traditional formula products that catered to mothers with money seeking organic baby food solutions.</p> <p> "We really noticed it in the past week," customer service representative Julian Bell said, "although our stock has been dwindling for several weeks."</p> <p> On Friday, the Department of Health and Human Service's (HHS) website posted that "manufacturers have ramped up production 30-50 percent," and that "yesterday, President Biden spoke with retailers and manufacturers, including Walmart, Target, Reckitt, and Gerber, to discuss ways to get more formula quickly and safely onto store shelves."</p> <p> HHS pointed to the January recall of "certain powdered infant formulas" by industry leader Abbott Nutrition as a catalyst for the shortages, a federal response to four Michigan babies getting sick from the formula and two infant deaths between September and February.</p> <p> "The reason we're here is because the FDA (Food and Drug Administration) took the steps to ensure that babies were taking safe formula," White House press secretary Jen Psaki said at a press conference Thursday.</p> <p> "There were babies who died from taking this formula, so they were doing their jobs," Psaki said.</p> <p> Psaki announced a series of measures to alleviate the shortage, including efforts to speed up production and crack down on price gouging, as reports surfaced of individuals buying out store supplies and re-selling them on Ebay for huge profits.</p> <p> The Justice Department is now working with state attorney generals to monitor price-gouging in the formula market, and Biden said Thursday he had asked the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to investigate reports of price-gouging.</p> <p> The Biden administration is also working to increase imports of formula, a new solution as the United States produces 98 percent of its formula supply, according to an administration fact sheet.</p> <p> On Friday, Biden also called for cutting red tape on the types of formula parents can buy, calling on the FTC and state attorneys general to crack down on price gouging and unfair market practices, and increase the supply of formula through increased imports.</p> <p> Congressional Democrats joined the president in demanding answers from baby formula manufacturers.</p> <p> In letters to the heads of four baby formula companies, Democratic Reps. Carolyn Maloney of New York and Raja Krishnamoorthi of Illinois demanded documents and details about the shortage.</p> <p> "The national formula shortage poses a threat to the health and economic security of infants and families in communities throughout the country -- particularly those with less income who have historically experienced health inequities, including food insecurity," they wrote in letters sent to Mead Johnson Nutrition, Nestle USA, Perrigo Company and Abbott Nutrition.</p> <p> These companies control nearly 90 percent of the U.S. market for baby formula, the lawmakers said, requesting certain documents submitted by June 2.</p> <p> REPUBLICANS EXPLOIT THE CRISIS</p> <p> Republican leaders were quick to exploit the baby food crisis for their own political gain, slamming Biden on several fronts.</p> <p> "This is absolutely UNACCEPTABLE in America," Elise Stefanik, a New York House Republican, wrote on Twitter. "Sadly, this has become the norm because of Joe Biden's radical agenda."</p> <p> "Unsurprisingly, when I reached out in February from my office to the FDA we received no substantive response. Joe Biden simply has no plan," Stefanik told the media at a press conference Thursday.</p> <p> "Instead, bare shelves. Biden has continued to pass the buck. This is not a Third World country. This should never happen in the United States of America. We're unified in demanding action to address this crisis," she added.</p> <p> Rep. Ann Wagner, a Missouri Republican, joined in: "This is sadly Joe Biden's America."</p> <p> "Working families are already struggling to put food on the table due to the skyrocketing costs of every day items, and now they are facing a crisis that is threatening the very lives of their newborn children," Wagner said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Tomato fever grips India's Kerala, neighboring states sound alert ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096751</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096751.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 16:09:25 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NEW DELHI, May 14 (Xinhua) -- A viral fever has caused panic in the southern Indian state of Kerala, where at least 80 cases of what is locally known as tomato fever were reported, officials said Saturday.</p> <p> The viral disease, which gets its name "tomato fever" because of the red blister it causes, has raised concern in Kerala and the neighboring states of Tamil Nadu and Karnataka.</p> <p> Doctors say tomato flu comes with red rashes, skin irritation, and dehydration.</p> <p> The illness that experts say is contagious can also cause tiredness, joint pain, stomach cramps, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, coughing, sneezing, runny nose, high fever, or body ache. In some cases, it may also change the skin color of legs and hands, according to reports.</p> <p> In Kerala, the disease has been detected in children under five years of age.</p> <p> Tamil Nadu's Health Secretary J. Radhakrishnan on Friday urged the local residents not to panic as health authorities were monitoring the situation across the state.</p> <p> The Karnataka state government has sounded high alert in the districts bordering Kerala.</p> <p> Health officials in these districts have been directed to step up surveillance measures and maintain a constant vigilance on outpatient services at both private and public health institutions.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 2023 AFC Asia Cup to be relocated from China ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096748</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096748.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 16:09:25 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0514/FOREIGN202205141521000535461869918.jpg" style="width: 634px; height: 357px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>File Photo</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) -- The 2023 Asian Cup football tournament will be relocated from China to a new host, the Asian Football Confederation (AFC) and the tournament's Local Organizing Committee announced on Saturday.</p> <p> "Due to the COVID-19 pandemic, the Chinese Organizing Committee cannot pledge at this moment to hold next year's Asian Cup competition under a fully open model. After negotiations between the AFC, the Chinese Football Association (CFA) and the Local Organizing Committee, a joint decision has been made to remove the 2023 Asian Cup from China to a new host which is to be confirmed soon," read a statement published by the Chinese Organizing Committee.</p> <p> "The Organizing Committee hereby expresses sincere gratitude to the AFC, all host cities and the whole society for their great support during the tournament's preparations," the statement added.</p> <p> The AFC said in a separate statement that it appreciates that China, the CFA and the Local Organizing Committee have made "this very difficult but necessary decision in the collective interests of the AFC Asian Cup 2023, which has also provided the AFC the required time to assess the situation regarding the hosting of the AFC Asian Cup 2023."</p> <p> "The AFC worked closely with the CFA and the AFC Asian Cup China 2023 Local Organizing Committee during the preparations and several milestones were achieved, including the launch of the tournament logo and the unveiling of the newly completed Shanghai Pudong Football Stadium last year," the Asian football governing body added.</p> <p> Details about the next steps related to the hosting of the Asian Cup will be announced in due course, the AFC said.</p> <p> China was awarded the hosting right of the 2023 Asian Cup in June 2019. The 24-team competition was scheduled to be hosted across 10 Chinese cities.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ India records 2,858 new COVID-19 cases, 11 more deaths ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096749</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096749.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 15:32:21 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NEW DELHI, May 14 (Xinhua) -- India's COVID-19 tally rose to 43,119,112 on Saturday, with 2,858 new cases registered in the past 24 hours across the South Asian country, showed the federal health ministry's latest data.</p> <p> Besides, 11 deaths from the pandemic were registered across the country since Friday morning, taking the death toll to 524,201.</p> <p> Currently there are 18,096 active COVID-19 cases recorded in India, a fall of 508 in the past 24 hours.</p> <p> So far, 42,576,815 COVID-19 cases have been cured and discharged from hospitals in the country, including 3,355 discharged in the past 24 hours.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 626 families receive cash assistance in central Afghan province ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096747</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096747.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 15:22:19 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> KABUL, May 14 (Xinhua) -- A total of 626 families have received cash assistance in Afghanistan's central Bamyan province, the Afghan Ministry of Refugees and Repatriation said on Saturday.</p> <p> The displaced and most vulnerable families identified by surveys in Shibar and Yakawlang districts of the province received 400 U.S. dollars each in cash assistance on Wednesday, the ministry said in a statement.</p> <p> The assistance was provided by the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR), according to the statement.</p> <p> It added that more humanitarian assistance would be provided to needy families in Afghanistan's far-flung provinces in the coming days or weeks.</p> <p> Following the U.S. forces' pullout from Afghanistan last August, Washington has imposed sanctions on the Taliban-run administration and frozen assets of more than 9 billion U.S. dollars of Afghanistan's central bank in a move weighing heavily on the battered economy in the war-torn Asian country.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ People participate in Feel Accessibility 2022 event in Tel Aviv, Israel ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096745</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096745.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 15:06:23 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/53/8126417460637092625.jpg" /></p> <p> Citizens experience wheelchair basketball during the Feel Accessibility 2022 event in Tel Aviv, Israel on May 13, 2022. Citizens take part in the Feel Accessibility 2022, an annual event aiming at boosting people's awareness of accessibility for disabled people at Tel Aviv Port. This year's event includes a combination of Paralympic sports, such as wheelchair basketball and sitting volleyball, as well as fun activities. (Photo by Gil Cohen Magen/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/27/15708327646680666783.jpg" /></p> <p> Students experience sitting volleyball during the Feel Accessibility 2022 event in Tel Aviv, Israel on May 13, 2022. Citizens take part in the Feel Accessibility 2022, an annual event aiming at boosting people's awareness of accessibility for disabled people at Tel Aviv Port. This year's event includes a combination of Paralympic sports, such as wheelchair basketball and sitting volleyball, as well as fun activities. (Photo by Gil Cohen Magen/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/83/13955366791849113955.jpg" /></p> <p> Boys play wheelchair tennis during the Feel Accessibility 2022 event in Tel Aviv, Israel on May 13, 2022. Citizens take part in the Feel Accessibility 2022, an annual event aiming at boosting people's awareness of accessibility for disabled people at Tel Aviv Port. This year's event includes a combination of Paralympic sports, such as wheelchair basketball and sitting volleyball, as well as fun activities. (Photo by Gil Cohen Magen/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ India overcomes Denmark to make Thomas Cup final for 1st time ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096744</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096744.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 15:06:23 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BANGKOK, May 14 (Xinhua) -- India's men's badminton team made history by defeating Denmark 3-2 in the Thomas Cup semifinals here on Friday and will vie for the trophy against the reigning champions Indonesia.</p> <p> Although India's first singles Lakshya Sen could not challenge world No. 1 Viktor Axelsen, his team took a 2-1 lead after three matches.</p> <p> As the semifinal entered the deciding match after Denmark tied the score in the second doubles, India's remarkable run at the tournament seemed to come to an end when H.S. Prannoy twisted his ankle early in the first set. But he bounced back to win the match 13-21, 21-9, 21-12 against Rasmus Gemke.</p> <p> In the other semifinal, Indonesia cruised into the final again after Anthony Sinisuka Ginting, as well as Mohammad Ahsan/Kevin Sanjaya Sukamuljo, secured a 2-0 lead before Japan put up a tough fight to force a tie. In the third singles match, Shesar Hiren Rhustavito fended off Kodai Naraoka to take the victory for Indonesia.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Shanghai's COVID-19 battle sees big progress ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096746</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096746.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 15:06:23 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/25/12757223949248409973.jpg" style="height: 608px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Residents shop at a bakery store in Xuhui district of Shanghai, on May 10, 2022. [Photo/Xinhua]</em></p> <p> Shanghai is expected to achieve zero-COVID beyond areas under closed-loop management in mid-May, and will by then ease COVID-19 restrictions while implementing a tiered management system for communities based on their risk levels, local authorities said on Friday.</p> <p> According to Shanghai's Vice-Mayor Wu Qing, efforts to control the current COVID-19 wave have started to show good results. Despite small fluctuations in daily new infection numbers, over 99 percent of new infections have been identified through testing in closed-loop management zones. In the past three days, only six cases were found in other areas.</p> <p> "The city now faces a critical transition from epidemic emergency response to a normalized prevention and control mode," Wu said.</p> <p> Further efforts will be made in epidemic control and prevention in key areas, including old neighborhoods and villages at risk of a resurgence, he added.</p> <p> "We're drafting an outline to consolidate the results of the prevention and control efforts so far and to prepare for the resumption of work, business and on-campus education and a return to normalcy," Wu said.</p> <p> Cars will be allowed back on the roads gradually while supermarkets, convenience stores and other types of businesses such as hairdressing will gradually be allowed to operate.</p> <p> "Students who need to sit exams, especially ninth, 11th and 12th graders in high schools, will be given priority to return to school. More healthcare institutions and government service windows will also be reopened gradually," he added.</p> <p> Over 9,900 nucleic acid testing sites have been set up and more than 5,700 of them were operational across the city as of Thursday, mainly providing services for residents in precautionary zones and people who have resumed work, Wu said.</p> <p> Shanghai reported 227 new locally transmitted COVID-19 confirmed cases, 1,869 asymptomatic infections and two deaths on Thursday. The two who died were aged 88 and 89.</p> <p> "Given the large aging population that is vulnerable to the virus, vaccination acts as one of the most effective means to protect the elderly and we must promptly accelerate the vaccination of this group of people," said Zhao Dandan, deputy director of the Shanghai Municipal Health Commission.</p> <p> Shanghai administered around 100,000 doses of COVID-19 vaccines between May 1 and 11, with about half of these given to people aged 60 and above, according to Zhao.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China greenlights two ChiNext IPOs ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096734</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096734.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:53:28 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) -- China's securities regulator has approved the initial public offering (IPO) registration of two companies on the country's NASDAQ-style ChiNext board.</p> <p> ChinaEtek Service &amp;Technology Co., Ltd., a Beijing-based IT services provider, and Shanghai Menon Animal Nutrition Technology Co., Ltd. will be listed on the Shenzhen Stock Exchange's board of growth enterprises, the ChiNext board, according to the China Securities Regulatory Commission.</p> <p> The companies should strictly follow the prospectuses as well as the issuance and underwriting plans while issuing stocks, said the commission.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Feature: 2 years on, anti-Asian hatred persists in New York ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096731</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096731.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:51:36 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NEW YORK, May 13 (Xinhua) -- About two and a half years into the COVID-19 pandemic, the United States has seen not only an increase in infections and deaths, but also an orgy of racism and hate crimes against minority groups, particularly the Asian-American community.</p> <p> Following an apparently random yet violent murder of a young Korean-American woman in a Chinatown apartment here in February, mourners placed flowers, candles, photos, and cardboard signs condemning anti-Asian hatred around a tree outside the residential building where Christina Yuna Lee was stabbed to death.</p> <p> While the shock of Lee's death had yet to wear off, mourners were outraged that the makeshift memorial for Lee had been repeatedly vandalized.</p> <p> The temporary memorial was first vandalized in the middle of the night just three days after Lee's death, and it continued to be vandalized even in broad daylight.</p> <p> "So five times last month, and it just keeps increasing. It is very sad," Brian Chin, Lee's former landlord, told Xinhua.</p> <p> According to video clips from a surveillance camera shared by Chin, a man kicked at the flowers, candles, and signs in the early morning on March 2, and another pedestrian pulled down a cardboard sign about a week later.</p> <p> Every attack on the memorial is pretty much anti-Asian and "it is very scary right now," said Chin, whose family came to the United States from China over 60 years ago.</p> <p> "They're doing it with hate. They see her picture. They see the flowers and candles," Chin added.</p> <p> Lee's tragic death followed the fatal shoving of Asian American Michelle Alyssa Go onto subway tracks by a man at Times Square station on Jan. 15 and the death of Yaopan Ma in January in a racially motivated attack in East Harlem.</p> <p> "Her (Lee's) death is part of an alarming pattern of unchecked, hateful violence against women, namely women of Asian descent and women of color that can no longer stand without consequence," said one of Lee's relatives in an appeal on Gofundme.com.</p> <p> For Chin, a middle-aged man, the continued anti-Asian hate crimes had brought about unprecedented depression.</p> <p> "I think everyone is terrified right now that they will be attacked on the subways, on the streets, and then the guy will be out on the same day," he said.</p> <p> According to Chin, this wave of anti-Asian hatred began with very vitriolic language which claims COVID-19 as the so-called "Chinese flu" or "Wuhan flu."</p> <p> Kathleen Flynn-hui, whose husband originally came from Hong Kong, said that anti-Asian prejudice affects her family on a daily basis.</p> <p> "We've kind of always felt it, but not as strongly as now," said Flynn-hui, adding that she "dealt with discrimination against my husband because he was Asian the whole time."</p> <p> Chin said the situation is deteriorating due to a combination of politics, the impact of new laws, and the new Manhattan District Attorney's lenient stance on crime.</p> <p> "The cops are doing their job, but they arrest them, and they're free the next day due to the laws," said Chin.</p> <p> Right now, much stronger laws are needed to protect the Asian community, Chin said, calling on lawmakers, the city council, and the mayor to take stronger and more enforceable action.</p> <p> The Committee of 100, a non-profit leadership organization of prominent Chinese Americans, recently called on U.S. elected officials, law enforcement, and responsible media to address racism, discrimination, and violence against Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders immediately with actionable and concrete results.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Exhibition on Ishtar Gate held in Pergamon Museum in Berlin ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096732</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096732.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:51:36 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/63/13345661598134279747.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows the Ishtar Gate at the Pergamon Museum in Berlin, capital of Germany. (Xinhua/Ren Pengfei)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/61/8934235986071663501.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows an Ishtar Gate fridge sticker at the Pergamon Museum in Berlin, capital of Germany. (Xinhua/Ren Pengfei)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/0/15312264108420997368.png" /></p> <p> A visitor takes photos of the Ishtar Gate at the Pergamon Museum in Berlin, capital of Germany, May 13, 2022. (Xinhua/Ren Pengfei)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/86/16567293318077846022.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows Ishtar Gate postcards at the Pergamon Museum in Berlin, capital of Germany. (Xinhua/Ren Pengfei)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/35/9937261294720875963.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows an Ishtar Gate keychain at the Pergamon Museum in Berlin, capital of Germany. (Xinhua/Ren Pengfei)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/96/6024056643312435856.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows the Ishtar Gate at the Pergamon Museum in Berlin, capital of Germany. (Xinhua/Ren Pengfei)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/23/18168216836158965743.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows part of the Ishtar Gate at the Pergamon Museum in Berlin, capital of Germany. (Xinhua/Ren Pengfei)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/60/18429475470191263620.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows cultural and creative products of the Ishtar Gate at the Pergamon Museum in Berlin, capital of Germany. (Xinhua/Ren Pengfei)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/88/11093793161277262780.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows an Ishtar Gate fridge sticker at the Pergamon Museum in Berlin, capital of Germany. (Xinhua/Ren Pengfei)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/66/10048026233024462306.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows Ishtar Gate mugs at the Pergamon Museum in Berlin, capital of Germany. (Xinhua/Ren Pengfei)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Creative products featuring "She-Wolf" exhibited in Rome ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096733</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096733.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:51:36 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/12/10757951812586647536.png" /></p> <p> A souvenir featuring "She-Wolf" is seen in the Capitoline Museums in Rome, Italy, May 13, 2022. One of the prestigious collections of the Capitoline Museums is the "She-Wolf", a masterpiece of bronze sculpture based on the legend that contributed the city's origin to the twins Romulus and Remus, who in their infancy had been saved and suckled by a wolf. (Xinhua/Jin Mamengni)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/57/8081357471347205413.png" /></p> <p> Magnets featuring "She-Wolf" are seen in the Capitoline Museums in Rome, Italy, May 13, 2022. One of the prestigious collections of the Capitoline Museums is the "She-Wolf", a masterpiece of bronze sculpture based on the legend that contributed the city's origin to the twins Romulus and Remus, who in their infancy had been saved and suckled by a wolf. (Xinhua/Jin Mamengni)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/46/10791290629578261074.png" /></p> <p> Magnets featuring "She-Wolf" are seen in the Capitoline Museums in Rome, Italy, May 13, 2022. One of the prestigious collections of the Capitoline Museums is the "She-Wolf", a masterpiece of bronze sculpture based on the legend that contributed the city's origin to the twins Romulus and Remus, who in their infancy had been saved and suckled by a wolf. (Xinhua/Jin Mamengni)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/44/13676865392017486356.png" /></p> <p> A visitor displays a postcard featuring "She-Wolf" in the Capitoline Museums in Rome, Italy, May 13, 2022. One of the prestigious collections of the Capitoline Museums is the "She-Wolf", a masterpiece of bronze sculpture based on the legend that contributed the city's origin to the twins Romulus and Remus, who in their infancy had been saved and suckled by a wolf. (Xinhua/Jin Mamengni)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/90/7338720063394676730.png" /></p> <p> Souvenirs featuring "She-Wolf" are seen in the Capitoline Museums in Rome, Italy, May 13, 2022. One of the prestigious collections of the Capitoline Museums is the "She-Wolf", a masterpiece of bronze sculpture based on the legend that contributed the city's origin to the twins Romulus and Remus, who in their infancy had been saved and suckled by a wolf. (Xinhua/Jin Mamengni)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/85/2400420801012573805.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 18, 2021 shows the "She-Wolf" in the Capitoline Museums in Rome, Italy. One of the prestigious collections of the Capitoline Museums is the "She-Wolf", a masterpiece of bronze sculpture based on the legend that contributed the city's origin to the twins Romulus and Remus, who in their infancy had been saved and suckled by a wolf. (Xinhua/Cheng Tingting)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/35/16673783597915717567.png" /></p> <p> A jewelry featuring "She-Wolf" is seen in the Capitoline Museums in Rome, Italy, May 13, 2022. One of the prestigious collections of the Capitoline Museums is the "She-Wolf", a masterpiece of bronze sculpture based on the legend that contributed the city's origin to the twins Romulus and Remus, who in their infancy had been saved and suckled by a wolf. (Xinhua/Jin Mamengni)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/9/5229360191103181813.png" /></p> <p> A magnet featuring "She-Wolf" is seen in the Capitoline Museums in Rome, Italy, May 13, 2022. One of the prestigious collections of the Capitoline Museums is the "She-Wolf", a masterpiece of bronze sculpture based on the legend that contributed the city's origin to the twins Romulus and Remus, who in their infancy had been saved and suckled by a wolf. (Xinhua/Jin Mamengni)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 27 elks released to Daqingshan Nature Reserve in Hohhot ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096730</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096730.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:43:50 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/21/4445449586826564169.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows elks at the Daqingshan Nature Reserve in Hohhot, north China's Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region. A total of 27 elks (or milu) were released to the Daqingshan Nature Reserve on Sept. 29, 2021. Since April 3 this year, the group has given birth to nine fawns. (Photo by Wang Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/10/7237787415262814402.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows elks at the Daqingshan Nature Reserve in Hohhot, north China's Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region. A total of 27 elks (or milu) were released to the Daqingshan Nature Reserve on Sept. 29, 2021. Since April 3 this year, the group has given birth to nine fawns. (Photo by Wang Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/57/5267416113729464821.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows elks at the Daqingshan Nature Reserve in Hohhot, north China's Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region. A total of 27 elks (or milu) were released to the Daqingshan Nature Reserve on Sept. 29, 2021. Since April 3 this year, the group has given birth to nine fawns. (Photo by Wang Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/38/6608404956790826522.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows elks at the Daqingshan Nature Reserve in Hohhot, north China's Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region. A total of 27 elks (or milu) were released to the Daqingshan Nature Reserve on Sept. 29, 2021. Since April 3 this year, the group has given birth to nine fawns. (Photo by Wang Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/3/1060299404122308235.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows elks at the Daqingshan Nature Reserve in Hohhot, north China's Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region. A total of 27 elks (or milu) were released to the Daqingshan Nature Reserve on Sept. 29, 2021. Since April 3 this year, the group has given birth to nine fawns. (Photo by Wang Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/91/4570683457552986007.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows elks at the Daqingshan Nature Reserve in Hohhot, north China's Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region. A total of 27 elks (or milu) were released to the Daqingshan Nature Reserve on Sept. 29, 2021. Since April 3 this year, the group has given birth to nine fawns. (Photo by Wang Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/70/4906318185815451686.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows elks at the Daqingshan Nature Reserve in Hohhot, north China's Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region. A total of 27 elks (or milu) were released to the Daqingshan Nature Reserve on Sept. 29, 2021. Since April 3 this year, the group has given birth to nine fawns. (Photo by Wang Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/53/4417832945415543601.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows elks at the Daqingshan Nature Reserve in Hohhot, north China's Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region. A total of 27 elks (or milu) were released to the Daqingshan Nature Reserve on Sept. 29, 2021. Since April 3 this year, the group has given birth to nine fawns. (Photo by Wang Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Australian opposition party maintains polling lead ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096729</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096729.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:43:50 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> CANBERRA, May 14 (Xinhua) -- Australia's opposition the Labor Party still maintains the lead as the federal election campaign entered its final week.</p> <p> According to the latest edition of Newspoll published on Friday night, the Labor Party holds a comfortable 54-46 lead over the Coalition on a two-party preferred basis.</p> <p> It marks the 20th consecutive Newspoll where the Coalition has trailed the Labor since November 2020.</p> <p> Significantly, the Coalition has not been able to make any inroads since Prime Minister Scott Morrison called the election on April 10.</p> <p> Newspoll found that 43 percent of voters identified Morrison as their preferred prime minister and 42 percent as Labor leader Anthony Albanese.</p> <p> It represents a major swing in Albanese's favor from a 46-37 lead for Morrison at the end of April.</p> <p> In a major shift of tone, Morrison promised to change his leadership style if re-elected.</p> <p> Admitting he can be "a bit of a bulldozer", Morrison promised to empathize more with Australians if given another term as the prime minister.</p> <p> "I will seek to explain motives and my concerns and empathize a lot more. But I tell you what, at the end of the day, what matters most is I get the job done," he told reporters.</p> <p> In response, Albanese, who on Saturday announced a Labor government would boost health spending by 970 million Australian dollars (673 million U.S. dollars), promised to unite the country.</p> <p> "A bulldozer wrecks things. A bulldozer knocks things over. I'm a builder, that's what I am," he said. "I will build things in this country."&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ U.S. urged not to rope in Southeast Asian countries out of geopolitical interests ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096718</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096718.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:28:13 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) -- The just-concluded U.S.-ASEAN summit will not draw regional countries closer to the U.S. side, and the U.S. attempt to court support among ASEAN in pursuit of its geopolitical interests is unlikely to gain traction, experts have said.</p> <p> U.S. President Joe Biden met leaders of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) countries at the White House during a summit held on Thursday and Friday, a move widely seen as an attempt by the world's sole superpower to pull members of the bloc into its camp against a rising China.</p> <p> U.S. ATTEMPTS SHALL FAIL</p> <p> Against the backdrop of escalating tensions between Russia and Ukraine, the U.S.-initiated summit was widely viewed as a signal to highlight the importance of what America calls the "Indo-Pacific" region out of strategic concerns, and to counter the rising influence of China in the region.</p> <p> Lee Pei May, a political expert at the International Islamic University Malaysia, said while the summit occurred amid the tougher Russia-Ukraine conflict, the primary concern of the Biden administration is not about Russia, but more about ensuring a so-called "free and open" Indo-Pacific.</p> <p> "For the Biden administration to advance this vision, they have to get ASEAN countries on the American side and potentially for the U.S. to play a role in managing the disputes in the South China Sea," she said. "Such moves can be interpreted as challenging China's position in the region and hindering peaceful progress between China and ASEAN countries."</p> <p> The summit's significance lies in its timing, reported Foreign Affairs magazine on Wednesday. "It is being held as war rages in Ukraine, demonstrating that the United States has not lost its focus on the Indo-Pacific," the report said, adding "U.S. President Joe Biden seeks to better position his country in the wider geopolitical competition with China."</p> <p> Yet, the United States "shall fail in attempts to counter China, because most ASEAN countries want to expand economic exchanges and other cooperation with (their) regional neighbor China," Wilson Lee Flores, a columnist for the English daily The Philippine Star, told Xinhua.</p> <p> Flores noted that Washington was also aimed at convincing ASEAN countries to take tougher public positions and join its sanctions against Russia, which, likewise, shall fail. "Most of ASEAN seek to promote dialogue, diplomacy and stability in crisis areas due to ASEAN's traditional position of non-interference and upholding consensus."</p> <p> Joseph Matthews, a senior professor at the BELTEI International University in Phnom Penh, said that the United States should not use the summit to coerce and pressure ASEAN into submitting to its will and approach against Russia and China.</p> <p> Commenting on the Western sanctions and illegal embargoes on Russia, Ky Sereyvath, director general of the Institute of China Studies at the Royal Academy of Cambodia, said these sanctions will harm the global economy.</p> <p> "I think the rise in fuel prices will not slow down if the Ukraine crisis still continues and the U.S. still push this war forward," Sereyvath added.</p> <p> As the United States is scrambling to combat a sluggish economy and simmering social disorder amid COVID-19, its capability to fulfill promises to other countries has come under question.</p> <p> "The U.S. now has limited capacities to deliver on its promises, due to its own political and economic challenges, especially with the upcoming midterm elections in November," Flores cautioned.</p> <p> "The U.S. can still lobby to export its weapons to ASEAN. It can still attempt (to carry out) political or diplomatic initiatives. It can also attempt to pursue security alliances. But its waning economic activities and influence in Asia will weaken its strategic presence and leverage," the columnist noted.</p> <p> From the "Pivot to Asia" to the "Indo-Pacific Strategy," the United States has been teaming up its allies and regional countries to contain China. Washington never stops hyping up the concept of "Indo-Pacific" to peddle the targeted strategy at economic, political and military levels.</p> <p> A recent report by the U.S. Center for Strategic and International Studies showed that many ASEAN members have expressed concerns that the so-called "Indo-Pacific Economic Framework" is "primarily a political endeavor meant to counter China, rather than a sincere and thoughtful economic policy integration initiative."</p> <p> This viewpoint was echoed by Veronika Saraswati, researcher at Indonesia's the Center for Strategic and International Studies. "It is not hard to see that although the United States wants to strengthen its influence in ASEAN, it has not built cooperation with ASEAN countries in a more concrete level, only symbolic."</p> <p> ASEAN NATIONS WON'T TAKE SIDE</p> <p> Many believe that ASEAN members, now with a primary focus on post-pandemic economic recovery, will maintain neutrality at the forefront and neglect the attempts to pressure them into a U.S. sphere of influence.</p> <p> With China rising "sharply out of expectation," the United States "is afraid of losing its control" in Southeast Asia and found it necessary to hold tighter their hegemonic power, Saraswati pointed out.</p> <p> The Indonesian researcher stressed that Southeast Asian countries, including Indonesia, certainly do not want to be dragged into the competition between major powers.</p> <p> "Powerful countries should never use coercive measures to force other countries to choose side," she noted. "For a long time, the exercise of hegemonic power by the U.S. and its allies has had a deep impact on the survival and development of many countries."</p> <p> The United States will find itself unable to make any headway among ASEAN members, especially after Malaysia and Indonesia voiced concerns over the AUKUS trilateral security partnership involving Australia and Britain, said Azmi Hassan, a senior research fellow at Nusantara Academy for Strategic Research.</p> <p> Hassan gave the persuasive example that the United States has been unable to exert pressure on ASEAN over the Russia-Ukraine conflict, with most of the 10-member bloc abstaining from voting in favor of a resolution to suspend Russia from the United Nations Human Rights Council last month.</p> <p> "Bringing up controversial issues, forcing and coercing ASEAN member states to support its approach and agenda in the region, and trying to divide ASEAN on any issues will undermine the credibility and authenticity of the whole summit. The U.S. should be mindful of it," Matthews told Xinhua.</p> <p> Rather than pressing the bloc to follow its scenarios or agendas against other countries, Washington should use the meeting to express support for ASEAN's post-COVID-19 socioeconomic recovery, Kin Phea, director-general of the International Relations Institute at the Royal Academy of Cambodia, told Xinhua.</p> <p> "What the U.S. should do is encouraging ASEAN to adhere to its principle of centrality, solidarity and unity," he said, adding the United States should also respect ASEAN's rights in making decisions and refrain from using economic, political or security pressure to bargain with ASEAN or to force ASEAN to make decisions in its favor.</p> <p> "The U.S. must respect the common interests of the ASEAN, the region and the world, and should not put forward any scenarios or agendas that lead to ASEAN's rift and instability in the region," he said.</p> <p> VIGILANCE, UNITY URGED IN ASEAN</p> <p> It is essential for the 10-member bloc to stand in solidarity against the U.S. interference for the sake of regional peace, stability, development and prosperity, Phea said.</p> <p> Matthews also urged ASEAN leaders to be vigilant about the Quadrilateral Security Dialogue among the United States, Japan, Australia and India, and the Australia-U.K.-U.S. pact, saying both military-cum-security alliances are posing a major security threat to ASEAN and the whole Asia region.</p> <p> "These alliances will trigger a conventional and nuclear arms race in the region, and thus destabilize peace and security, undermine economic development and destroy the ASEAN's centrality," he said.</p> <p> Unless it can demonstrate unity, ASEAN may find itself in a position where different members pursue different paths, which could compromise its cohesiveness, Lee cautioned. "This can be remedied by member states forging a consensus when dealing with the United States."</p> <p> "Having a consensus on key issues is not easy, but it is crucial as it would allow the members to speak with one united voice at the summit," the Malaysian expert noted. "The members can send a signal to the U.S. that ASEAN would remain neutral in whatever circumstances."&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 7 found, 6 remain missing after unauthorized trip to SW China mountain ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096717</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096717.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:23:38 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0514/FOREIGN202205141422000375699823008.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Rescuers search for missing people on Cangshan Mountain in Dali in southwest China's Yunnan Province, May 14, 2022. /CMG</em></p> <p> Seven people were found by rescuers and are in good condition after they went missing in Cangshan Mountain in Dali in southwest China's Yunnan Province on Thursday, China Media Group (CMG) has learned.</p> <p> The seven are among a group of 13 people who visited the famous Chinese mountain area, a renowned tourist spot, without permission, bypassing a guarded checkpoint.</p> <p> The search operation for the remaining six continues.</p> <p> Cangshan Mountain Reserve in Yangbi Yi Autonomous County has been under closed-off management since March 29, 2020, due to safety work and anti-epidemic prevention.</p> <p> Local conservation authorities said they received tips from the public about the unauthorized trip on Thursday afternoon.</p> <p> Ten other people in the group were found on Friday morning and removed from the area.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0514/FOREIGN202205141422000514778203836.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Rescuers search for missing people on Cangshan Mountain in Dali in southwest China's Yunnan Province, May 14, 2022. /CMG</em></p> <p> Rescuers at the site told CMG on Saturday that the missing group consists of six guides, five non-locals, and two members of China's Blue Sky Rescue Team, the country's largest non-governmental humanitarian organization.</p> <p> Some of them have extensive wilderness survival experience and were equipped with professional hiking sets, including two satellite phones, as well as food and water.</p> <p> But steep slopes, dense forests and rain are hampering the search.</p> <p> Authorities said they're trying to find out the reason for the trip, but The Paper, a Chinese media outlet, reported that the visitors were attempting to locate the crash site of a plane that went down on a Hump Route mission in the early 1940s.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: CGTN</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Jen Psaki leaves role as White House press secretary ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096716</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096716.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:13:43 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> WASHINGTON, May 13 (Xinhua) -- Jen Psaki left her role as the White House press secretary on Friday.</p> <p> "I want to say thank you to the president and the first lady. They entrusted me in serving in this role for the last 15 months," Psaki said during her last briefing at the White House.</p> <p> She also extended appreciation to the White House's press team, as well as to reporters in the James S. Brady Press Briefing Room.</p> <p> The appearance was Psaki's 224th White House briefing over her tenure that began the day Joe Biden was sworn in as U.S. president in January 2021.</p> <p> Karine Jean-Pierre is the new White House press secretary, becoming both the first African American and openly LGBTQ person to hold the position.</p> <p> As an assistant to the U.S. president, the White House press secretary provides daily briefings for the media on the administration's activities and agenda.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's SMEs Development Index retreats in April ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096714</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096714.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:13:36 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) -- China's Small and Medium Enterprises (SMEs) Development Index, based on a survey of 3,000 SMEs, edged down 0.3 points from the previous month to 88.3 in April, the latest industry data showed.</p> <p> This is the third consecutive month of decline for the gauge, which is lower than that of the same period last year, said the China Association of Small and Medium Enterprises.</p> <p> Halted production due to domestic COVID-19 outbreaks, coupled with industry chain disruptions and high commodity prices, has made it more difficult for some companies to cover costs, said the association.</p> <p> The sub-indexes for industry, construction, transportation and postal services, wholesale and retail, as well as hospitality and catering retreated from a month ago, while that for real estate increased.</p> <p> The industry group calls for targeted support to virus-hit small businesses in the service sector, implementation of policies like tax and fee cuts, as well as efforts to keep prices and employment stable.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ U.S. uses democracy as pretext for interference -- experts ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096713</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096713.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:10:46 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> CAIRO, May 14 (Xinhua) -- The United States has been exploiting democracy, human rights and aid as tools and weapons to incite division around the world and meddle in other countries' internal affairs, say political experts.</p> <p> "To influence domestic policies in recipient countries ... the U.S. has provided assistance to serve its goals and achieve its interests," Ayman Okeil, general manager of the Cairo-based Maat for Peace, Development, and Human Rights, told Xinhua in a recent interview.</p> <p> THE NED AS A PROXY</p> <p> Among all the proxies Washington uses to serve its political agenda in other countries, the National Endowment for Democracy (NED), which was founded in 1983 as a bipartisan, non-profit institution by the U.S. government, is one of the most active.</p> <p> Nominally a non-governmental organization that provides support for democracy abroad, the NED in fact relies on continuous financial support from the White House and the U.S. Congress, and takes orders from the U.S. government.</p> <p> Okeil described the NED as one of Washington's "soldiers" for interfering in other countries' decision-making process.</p> <p> The NED has worked as a substitute for the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) in cultivating pro-U.S. opposition activists for subverting lawful governments and provoking uprisings in the Arab countries under the pretext of promoting democracy, he said.</p> <p> According to Saeb Rawashdeh, a political analyst at the Jordan Press Foundation, the NED was founded as a tool for projecting political influence in different sovereign states that the U.S. government has labeled as "non-democratic, totalitarian, authoritarian and anti-American."</p> <p> The NED supported opposition groups in other countries, which were trained to represent Washington's interest, rather than the vital interests of their own nations and states, Rawashdeh pointed out.</p> <p> Echoing Rawashdeh's point, Okeil said that the NED has spent millions of U.S. dollars to support political parties, labor unions, dissident movements, and media in dozens of countries.</p> <p> The organization has been employed as the "mastermind" behind separatist riots, color revolutions, and political crises around the world, with the aim of toppling legitimate governments and creating U.S. puppets in targeted countries, said Ahmad Ashqar, a Syrian journalist and political expert.</p> <p> The NED makes sure that nations across the globe do what the United States wants them to do and in no way feel confident and capable of pursuing their own political/ideological agendas, Rawashdeh said. "And this is also what the U.S. foreign policy is doing for decades."</p> <p> A NEW TYPE OF IMPERIALISM</p> <p> The United States, unfortunately, has created a new type of imperialism, by occupying foreign countries with money and forces and interfering in their choice of leaders and party compositions, Okeil told Xinhua.</p> <p> Unlike the funds that came from some countries like China, which help improve health, education and development sectors, the U.S. economic aid is always with conditions attached, he noted</p> <p> Okeil's words are not groundless. According to a study by the American University in Cairo in November 2021, the NED has allocated more than 606 million dollars in "democracy assistance" to Egypt in the period between 1990 and 2003. In 2008, the U.S. government provided 415 million dollars in economic assistance to Egypt, which includes 55 million dollars to support programs for promoting democracy.</p> <p> However, as Tariq Fahmy, a political science professor at the Cairo University, noted, the U.S. mode of democracy has not been successful in the Middle East, and it contradicts many countries' unique conditions.</p> <p> "We all saw the disgraceful role in provoking the Arab Spring via funding the protesters" under the cover of democracy and human rights, Fahmy said, explaining that such kind of imposed democracy couldn't breed stability.</p> <p> After the Arab Spring, many people in the Middle East have started to see the real objectives behind the U.S. aid when knowing that Washington had a role in inciting the Arab Spring uprisings via supporting, training and funding young protesters, Okeil noted.</p> <p> The U.S. model of democracy is not suitable for the world, and based on that model, the U.S. policies led to real crimes, Fahmy said.</p> <p> It's a fact that the United States has distorted the positive meaning of democracy and emptied such a notion of anything useful and beneficial for other countries, Ashqar argued.</p> <p> "We have seen several examples like in Syria, where the United States used democracy as a pretext to support separatist forces and radical ones to destabilize the legitimate government," he said. "The U.S. presence in Syria has achieved all but the so-called democracy."</p> <p> "Under the pretext of fighting terrorism and spreading democracy, the U.S. has stolen key areas in Syria rich with oil and gas, do you call that democracy?" asked the Syrian journalist.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 27 killed, 12 injured in Indian capital building fire ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096712</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096712.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 13:57:02 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NEW DELHI, May 14 (Xinhua) -- At least 27 people were killed and 12 others suffered burn injuries after a massive fire broke out in a three-storey commercial building in the Indian capital, senior police officer Sameer Sharma said Saturday.</p> <p> The fire broke out inside the building on Friday evening at 4:40 p.m. (local time) near the city's Mundka metro station, and the death toll became clear only by night.</p> <p> Reports said the fire started from the first floor of the building at an office of a CCTV cameras and router manufacturing company.</p> <p> Officials said the firefighting and rescue operations continued until early morning on Saturday. Police are yet to identify the deceased, and the injured have been admitted to Sanjay Gandhi Memorial Hospital.</p> <p> Firefighters used heavy cranes to reach the top floor of the building, and 27 fire tenders were sent to contain the blaze when smoke surrounded the entire building.</p> <p> Video clips showed people trying to escape the building using a rope and hanging from broken windows. Many people could be seen trying to jump to another building.</p> <p> "There was only one staircase and because of that people could not go out. I think the building did not have a proper no objection certificate (NOC) from the fire department," Satpal Bhardwaj, divisional officer of the Delhi fire department told media.</p> <p> Police said they have arrested the owners of the company, but the owner of the building who did not have safety clearance from the fire department is on the run.</p> <p> Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi has expressed grief over the deaths in the fire.</p> <p> "Extremely saddened by the loss of lives due to a tragic fire in Delhi. My thoughts are with the bereaved families. I wish the injured a speedy recovery," Modi wrote on social media.</p> <p> Chances of fire in Indian buildings are usually high as people often ignore safety standards vis-a-vis fire.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xiconomics: How Xi's economic philosophy promotes global governance ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096711</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096711.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 13:56:59 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) -- "The right way forward for humanity is peaceful development and win-win cooperation," Chinese President Xi Jinping told the 2022 World Economic Forum (WEF) virtual session in mid-January, offering China's solutions to global challenges, including the COVID-19 pandemic.</p> <p> "Different countries and civilizations may prosper together on the basis of respect for each other, and seek common ground and win-win outcomes by setting aside differences," he added.</p> <p> Xi's remarks elaborated on "Xiconomics," or the economics philosophy of the Chinese president, demonstrating China's commitment to building a harmonious world, promoting common development and enhancing the common interests of mankind.</p> <p> OPENING WIDER</p> <p> "We need to learn from comparing long history cycles, and see the change in things through the subtle and minute. We need to foster new opportunities amidst crises, open up new horizons on a shifting landscape, and pool great strength to go through difficulties and challenges," Xi said in his special address, giving insight into a world battered by both the COVID-19 pandemic and sluggish economic growth.</p> <p> In the past two years, under the guidance of Xi's economic thought, China has struck a fine balance between pandemic control and economic development.</p> <p> In 2020, China has emerged as the only major economy with positive growth. In 2021, its gross domestic product saw a year-on-year increase of 8.1 percent, contributing around a quarter to world economic growth and beating most market expectations. The country has also played a crucial and irreplaceable role in supporting the global supply chains.</p> <p> Alexander Petrov, a professor at St. Petersburg State University, said China's success has proved that in a socialist market economy, it is possible to coordinate the efficiency of economic development and social governance, which is needed for global economic recovery in the post-pandemic era.</p> <p> China has once again become one "driving force of the global economy," said Jochen Goller, president and CEO of BMW China, who spoke highly of China's concerted efforts and strong resilience in both successfully fighting against COVID-19 and boosting economic recovery.</p> <p> China's steady growth has served as a stabilizer for the world economy amid the pandemic. It has been implementing a development philosophy featuring openness and cooperation, which helped strengthen global solidarity for economic recovery.</p> <p> "Countries around the world should uphold true multilateralism. We should remove barriers, not erect walls. We should open up, not close off. We should seek integration, not decoupling. This is the way to build an open world economy," Xi said, urging countries worldwide to "make economic globalization more open, inclusive, balanced and beneficial for all, and to fully unleash the vitality of the world economy."</p> <p> Humphrey Moshi, director of the Center for Chinese Studies at the University of Dar es Salaam of Tanzania, said that "China has been on the front line of encouraging multilateralism among global countries, and it has been doing that through cooperation on the principles of a win-win situation."</p> <p> "As a staunch supporter of globalization, China has been actively participating in and promoting international cooperation against COVID-19, providing medical equipment and COVID-19 vaccines to many countries," Moshi said.</p> <p> "China stands ready to work with all countries to build an open world economy so that the spring breeze of openness will bring warmth to all parts of the world," Xi said at the opening ceremony of the fourth China International Import Expo in November 2021, reiterating China's resolve to open wider and with a high standard.</p> <p> From shortening the negative list for foreign investment and improving the business environment to expanding institutional opening-up, China has honored its commitments by offering more opportunities to other countries, which injected fresh momentum into global economic recovery.</p> <p> Honson To, chairman of KPMG China and Asia Pacific, said China has kept opening wider to the world, upheld and acted on multilateralism, as well as actively pushed for a more inclusive global cooperation, sending a positive signal that China is willing to work together with other countries for a better future.</p> <p> BENEFIT FOR ALL</p> <p> At a time when the international community is struggling to reduce the development gap and secure equal opportunities for all, China has offered its solution to the problem by underlining the people's desire for a happy life.</p> <p> "No matter what difficulties may come our way, we must adhere to a people-centered philosophy of development, place development and livelihoods front and center in global macro-policies, realize the UN's 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development, and build greater synergy among existing mechanisms of development cooperation to promote balanced development worldwide," Xi said at January's forum.</p> <p> In the eyes of Raphael Tuju, secretary-general of Kenya's ruling Jubilee Party, this people-centered philosophy of development Xi emphasized is well manifested in the Chinese president's famous remarks that "for the good of my people, I will put aside my own well-being."</p> <p> By the end of 2020, China had lifted out of poverty all rural residents living below the current poverty line and met the poverty eradication target set out in the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development 10 years ahead of schedule.</p> <p> Its own people's well-being is not the only thing China cares about. As Xi noted, "on the road to the well-being of all mankind, no country or nation should be left behind."</p> <p> From China's growth to inclusive and common development of countries worldwide, Xi's economic thought addresses the need of the development of mankind through a variety of cooperation frameworks, such as the Belt and Road Initiative (BRI).</p> <p> The Mombasa-Nairobi Railway is a mega project under the BRI. It boosted Kenya's economy by significantly improving freight transportation, brought substantial benefits to local people, and at the same time protected the local ecological environment.</p> <p> This is the beginning of the transformation, which will create jobs, hope, opportunities and prosperity for all Kenyans, Kenyan President Uhuru Kenyatta said during a test ride of the railway.</p> <p> Another landmark project of Belt and Road cooperation is the 1,035-km China-Laos Railway, which has opened the landlocked country in Southeast Asia and connected it to markets as far away as in Europe since the railway's operation on Dec. 3, 2021.</p> <p> Sommad Pholsena, vice president of the National Assembly of Laos, said while China was not the first country to express a willingness to build a railway in Laos, it was the only one to turn it into reality.</p> <p> Xi's proposal to enhance interconnectivity and promote common development provides an opportunity for cooperation among developing countries, Pholsena said.</p> <p> According to the World Bank, BRI transport projects could, by 2030, help lift 7.6 million people out of extreme poverty and 32 million people out of moderate poverty globally.</p> <p> "The more we study the BRI and witness its continuous advancement, the more we can appreciate the vision and the wisdom of President Xi's economic thought on world development," said former Egyptian Prime Minister Essam Sharaf.</p> <p> DEVELOPMENT FOR GOOD</p> <p> To tackle global challenges and seek sustainable development, the Chinese president has been promoting the building of a community with a shared future for mankind.</p> <p> Mankind was presented with two choices -- one is vicious competition or even armed conflict for power and self-interest, which may well lead to a disastrous crisis, Xi said when addressing the CPC (the Communist Party of China) in Dialogue with the World Political Parties High-Level Meeting in 2017.</p> <p> "The other is for us to go along with the tide of the times and rise to challenges through global collaboration," he said. "This, in turn, will create favorable conditions for building a community with a shared future for mankind."</p> <p> For Khalid Taimur Akram, executive director of the Center for Global and Strategic Studies in Islamabad, the notion of building a community with a shared future for mankind bears significance for today's global development.</p> <p> China has provided a platform for all to turn this vision into reality, as the international community is searching for ways to advance cooperation and resolve differences, Akram said.</p> <p> In his speech in September 2021 at the general debate of the 76th session of the United Nations General Assembly via video, Xi said "we must revitalize the economy and pursue more robust, greener and more balanced global development. Development holds the key to people's well-being."</p> <p> He then urged countries around the world to "work together to steer global development toward a new stage of balanced, coordinated and inclusive growth," and proposed the Global Development Initiative (GDI) to this end.</p> <p> Speaking highly of the GDI, Tanzanian Minister of Foreign Affairs and East African Cooperation Liberata Mulamula said the pandemic serves as a reminder that the world is a community and no country should be left behind.</p> <p> Since Xi brought up the concept of building a community with a shared future for mankind in 2013, China has been enriching it to reflect the hope of people from all countries for a better world.</p> <p> "We should follow the trend of history, work for a stable international order, advocate common values of humanity, and build a community with a shared future for mankind. We should choose dialogue over confrontation, inclusiveness over exclusion, and stand against all forms of unilateralism, protectionism, hegemony or power politics," Xi said at the WEF meeting in January.</p> <p> The notion of a community with a shared future is the right path for human development, which could help reduce global inequality, said Ronnie Lins, director of the China-Brazil Center for Research and Business.</p> <p> The Chinese president's philosophy is of profound theoretical significance, said Maxim Rybachuk, leading researcher at the Central Economic Mathematical Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences.</p> <p> "We are talking about development concepts such as inclusive growth and dual circulation that have benefited both the Chinese people and people in other countries," Rybachuk said.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Russian, U.S. defense chiefs discuss Ukraine situation over phone ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096695</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096695.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 13:38:51 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) --The following are the latest developments in the conflict between Russia and Ukraine:</p> <p> More than 6.4 million people have been reached with vital humanitarian assistance in Ukraine since the country's military conflict with Russia started on Feb. 24, said UN humanitarians on Friday.</p> <p> This includes more than 5.7 million people who have been able to put food on their table. Cash assistance has been provided to over 655,000 people, allowing them to cover some of their most basic needs, said the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA).</p> <p> - - - -</p> <p> Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu and U.S. Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin held a phone conversation on Friday to discuss the situation in Ukraine.</p> <p> During the call initiated by the American side, the defense chiefs discussed topical issues of international security, including the situation in Ukraine, the Russian Defense Ministry said in a brief statement.</p> <p> - - - -</p> <p> Ukraine is entering a new long-lasting phase of the military conflict with Russia, Ukrainian Defense Minister Olexiy Reznikov said on Friday.</p> <p> Russia has more resources than Ukraine, but Ukraine is receiving heavy weapons from its partners, Reznikov said, adding that some 1,500 Ukrainian soldiers will soon be trained to work with modern military equipment.</p> <p> - - - -</p> <p> Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said that he stands ready for direct talks with Russian President Vladimir Putin, Zelensky's press service reported Friday.</p> <p> "I am ready to talk with Putin. But only with him. Without his mediators of any kind," Zelensky said in a video interview with Italian RAI TV, published on the official presidential Telegram account.</p> <p> - - - -</p> <p> Russian President Vladimir Putin and German Chancellor Olaf Scholz held a phone conversation on Friday to discuss the situation in Ukraine with an emphasis on the humanitarian aspect.</p> <p> Putin outlined in detail the logic and main objectives of Russia's special military operation and spoke about measures being taken by the Russian side to ensure the safety of civilians, the Kremlin said in a statement.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese mainland reports 253 new local COVID-19 cases ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096703</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096703.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 13:38:51 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0514/FOREIGN202205141132000191831888288.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Medical worker Yan Xu collects swab samples for nucleic acid testing in Chaoyang District of Beijing, capital of China, May 8, 2022. Chaoyang District started further district-wide nucleic acid testing from May 7 to 9 on. (Xinhua/Ju Huanzong)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) -- The Chinese mainland Friday reported 253 locally-transmitted confirmed COVID-19 cases, of which 194 were in Shanghai, according to the National Health Commission's report Saturday.</p> <p> Apart from Shanghai, 12 other provincial-level regions on the mainland saw new local COVID-19 cases, including 32 in Beijing.</p> <p> Shanghai also reported 1,487 locally-transmitted asymptomatic infections of the novel coronavirus Friday, out of a total of 1,726 local asymptomatic carriers newly identified on the mainland.</p> <p> A total of 866 COVID-19 patients were discharged from hospitals after recovery on the Chinese mainland on Friday, the NHC said.</p> <p> That brought the mainland's total number of COVID-19 patients discharged from hospitals after recovery to 210,006 as of Friday.</p> <p> One new death from COVID-19 was reported in Shanghai, according to the NHC.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Slain Palestinian journalist buried in Jerusalem ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096687</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096687.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:50:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> JERUSALEM, May 13 (Xinhua) -- Shireen Abu Akleh, a Palestinian-American journalist who was killed while covering clashes in the occupied West Bank, was buried on Friday in Jerusalem.</p> <p> Thousands of Palestinians attended the burial, which started with a church service in east Jerusalem in the morning. Last respects were paid in the Old City, said her employer Al Jazeera TV, where she was laid to rest in a nearby cemetery.</p> <p> The Palestinian Health Ministry said Abu Akleh, 51, was shot by the Israeli troops in the northern West Bank city of Jenin on Wednesday morning while covering an Israeli military raid, and she died shortly after.</p> <p> Officials from the Al Jazeera network also accused Israel of deliberately killing the veteran journalist, while Israeli authorities initially claimed she was hit by indiscriminate gunfire from Palestinian militants.</p> <p> Also on Friday, the Israeli military issued initial findings of its probe, saying the gunfire was heavy in the vicinity of Abu Akleh and her team during the incident, and "it is not possible to unequivocally determine the source of the gunfire which hit and killed" her.</p> <p> "At the end of the initial investigation, a number of details requiring further clarification remained," the military added.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese political advisors discuss capacity building for patriots in Hong Kong, Macao ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096690</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096690.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:50:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/64/12336189369519913520.png" /></p> <p> <em>Wang Yang, a member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the Communist Party of China (CPC) Central Committee and chairman of the Chinese People's Political Consultative Conference (CPPCC) National Committee, presides over the 62nd biweekly consultation session of the 13th CPPCC National Committee in Beijing, capital of China, May 13, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhang Ling)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- China's top political advisory body convened a biweekly consultation session on Friday at which attendees contributed their suggestions on further improving capacity building for those who love the country, and love Hong Kong and Macao special administrative regions (SARs).</p> <p> The session of the National Committee of the Chinese People's Political Consultative Conference (CPPCC) was presided over by Wang Yang, chairman of the CPPCC National Committee and a Standing Committee member of the Political Bureau of the Communist Party of China Central Committee.</p> <p> Highlighting the necessity and urgency of enhancing capacity building for the ranks of patriots who love the country, Hong Kong and Macao, Wang underscored the importance of adhering to the fundamental principles of "patriots administering Hong Kong" and "patriots administering Macao."</p> <p> He urged efforts to unite the patriots and help them improve capabilities including enhancing political consciousness, forging close ties with the people and solving problems, so as to contribute to the realization of good governance in the SARs and ensuring the steady practice of "one country, two systems."</p> <p> Ten political advisors and an invited representative spoke at the session, while over 90 political advisors voiced their opinions via an online platform.</p> <p> They extended congratulations on John Lee's election as the six-term chief executive designate of the Hong Kong SAR with an overwhelming majority of votes and expressed confidence in Hong Kong's harmony, stability, prosperity and development.</p> <p> The political advisors noted that, since the return of Hong Kong and Macao to the motherland, those who love the country, and love Hong Kong and Macao have done a lot of work and played an important role, and have withstood tests and shouldered responsibilities.</p> <p> The political advisors suggested that high priority should be given to enhancing political integrity and capability in governance among the governing teams of the SARs.</p> <p> For those in political and social organizations in the SARs who love the country and love Hong Kong and Macao, the political advisors suggested that efforts should be made to further strengthen their political stand, promote self-reform and strengthen internal management.</p> <p> The political advisors also suggested attaching importance to uniting those from professional sectors, expanding the reserve force of those who love the country, and love Hong Kong and Macao, improving the composition of CPPCC members from the SARs, and strengthening patriotic education for young people in the SARs.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 866 COVID-19 patients discharged from hospitals on Chinese mainland ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096676</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096676.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:50:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) -- A total of 866 COVID-19 patients were discharged from hospitals after recovery on the Chinese mainland on Friday, the National Health Commission said in its Saturday report.</p> <p> That brought the mainland's total number of COVID-19 patients discharged from hospitals after recovery to 210,006 as of Friday.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Humanitarian aid reaches 6.4 mln people in Ukraine: UN ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096679</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096679.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:50:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> UNITED NATIONS, May 13 (Xinhua) -- More than 6.4 million people have been reached with vital humanitarian assistance in Ukraine since the country's military conflict with Russia started on Feb. 24, said UN humanitarians on Friday.</p> <p> This includes more than 5.7 million people who have been able to put food on their table. Cash assistance has been provided to over 655,000 people, allowing them to cover some of their most basic needs, said the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA).</p> <p> More than 1.5 million people have received health care support, and around 352,000 people have been provided with clean water and hygiene products. Nearly 430,000 people have received protection services, psychosocial support and critical legal services, including support to internally displaced persons, it said.</p> <p> Despite this remarkable scale-up, many more people urgently need support, including those living in areas experiencing heavy fighting. The United Nations urges parties to the conflict to remove any barriers to the movement of humanitarian staff to ensure the continued delivery of life-saving assistance across Ukraine, said OCHA.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese-built expressway to boost Kenya's tourism sector: official ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096685</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096685.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:50:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NAIROBI, May 13 (Xinhua) -- The Chinese-built Nairobi expressway is expected to boost the tourism sector in Kenya, a senior government official said.</p> <p> Najib Balala, the cabinet secretary of the Ministry for Tourism and Wildlife, told journalists in Nairobi, Kenya's capital, that trial runs by motorists are expected to commence on the facility from Saturday.</p> <p> "The future is bright for the tourism sector because the Nairobi expressway is expected to reduce travel time from the airport to various tourism destinations across the city," Balala said Thursday evening during the fifth-anniversary celebration of Park Inn Hotel, Nairobi.</p> <p> He observed that tourists have been facing delays in moving between the Jomo Kenyatta International Airport and Nairobi's central business district.</p> <p> "With the expressway, tourists will take about ten minutes from arrival at the airport to the city center, instead of taking more than two hours currently," he added.</p> <p> The 27.1-km Nairobi Expressway was financed and built by China Road and Bridge Corporation under a public-private partnership model and consists of four-lane and six-lane dual carriageways.</p> <p> The Kenyan official said the Nairobi expressway will ensure tourists can enjoy the city's beautiful scenery due to seamless connectivity. "We want tourists to enjoy a seamless travel experience from their arrival so as to enhance their tourism experience in Kenya."</p> <p> According to the Ministry for Tourism and Wildlife, the Nairobi expressway will also attract more international hotel brands to set up operations in Kenya's capital city as the level of traffic congestion reduces.</p> <p> A trial run of the expressway will be launched Saturday.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ UN chief mourns death of UAE president ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096659</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096659.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:34:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> UNITED NATIONS, May 13 (Xinhua) -- UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres on Friday mourned the death of United Arab Emirates (UAE) President Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan, who died at the age of 73.</p> <p> Guterres extended his condolences to the royal family and the government and people of the UAE, said Farhan Haq, deputy spokesman for the secretary-general, in a statement.</p> <p> Sheikh Khalifa led the UAE since 2004, succeeding his father, Sheikh Zayed bin Sultan Al Nahyan, the country's founder. Sheikh Khalifa also led the UAE through a significant period of its development, marked by great economic advances and a surge in its regional and global influence, said the statement.</p> <p> "The secretary-general reiterates the commitment of the United Nations to its close cooperation with the United Arab Emirates, including on humanitarian issues and interfaith dialogue, as well as on regional and global peace, security and sustainable development," it said.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Israeli missile attack kills 5 in central Syria ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096660</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096660.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:34:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> DAMASCUS, May 13 (Xinhua) -- Five people were killed and seven others injured after Israel attacked military sites in central Syria on Friday, state news agency SANA reported.</p> <p> Several missiles fired by Israel hit targets near the Masyaf area of Hama province, SANA reported, citing a military statement.</p> <p> The attack also caused property damage and set fire to the forest of Masyaf, according to the report.</p> <p> In an earlier report, SANA said that Syria has intercepted Israeli missiles in its central coast region.</p> <p> Explosions were heard in the Syrian coast cities of Banyas, Tartous, and Jableh, according to the report, adding most of the missiles were intercepted before reaching their targets.</p> <p> Israel frequently bombed Syria's military facilities while claiming it was striking pro-Iran militia bases.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Jurassic Quest exhibition draws visitors in Vancouver, Canada ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096655</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096655.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:34:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/96/11318789443180609872.png" /></p> <p> A life-size dinosaur model is displayed at the Jurassic Quest exhibition at Vancouver Convention Centre in Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada, on May 13, 2022. Featuring life-size animatronic dinosaurs, fossil displays and interactive shows, the exhibition will be held from May 13 to May 15 in Vancouver. (Photo by Liang Sen/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/53/18412532781454499321.png" /></p> <p> People watch a raptor show at the Jurassic Quest exhibition at Vancouver Convention Centre in Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada, on May 13, 2022. Featuring life-size animatronic dinosaurs, fossil displays and interactive shows, the exhibition will be held from May 13 to May 15 in Vancouver. (Photo by Liang Sen/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/47/283643187523998447.png" /></p> <p> Life-size dinosaur models are displayed at the Jurassic Quest exhibition at Vancouver Convention Centre in Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada, on May 13, 2022. Featuring life-size animatronic dinosaurs, fossil displays and interactive shows, the exhibition will be held from May 13 to May 15 in Vancouver. (Photo by Liang Sen/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/89/9379509974076702313.png" /></p> <p> Life-size dinosaur models are displayed at the Jurassic Quest exhibition at Vancouver Convention Centre in Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada, on May 13, 2022. Featuring life-size animatronic dinosaurs, fossil displays and interactive shows, the exhibition will be held from May 13 to May 15 in Vancouver. (Photo by Liang Sen/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/22/3760443277364876510.png" /></p> <p> People look at a life-size dinosaur model at the Jurassic Quest exhibition at Vancouver Convention Centre in Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada, on May 13, 2022. Featuring life-size animatronic dinosaurs, fossil displays and interactive shows, the exhibition will be held from May 13 to May 15 in Vancouver. (Photo by Liang Sen/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ ExpoRose festival kicks off in Grasse, southern France ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096656</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096656.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:34:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/73/4939312892036353277.png" /></p> <p> Roses and pink umbrellas are seen during the 50th ExpoRose in Grasse, southern France, on May 13, 2022. The city center of Grasse was turned into rose gardens during the three-day ExpoRose festival which kicked off here on Friday. (Photo by Serge Haouzi/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/94/8647621282805103078.png" /></p> <p> A street is decorated with pink umbrellas during the 50th ExpoRose in Grasse, southern France, on May 13, 2022. The city center of Grasse was turned into rose gardens during the three-day ExpoRose festival which kicked off here on Friday. (Photo by Serge Haouzi/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/76/13158293269313841612.png" /></p> <p> Visitors look at flowers during the 50th ExpoRose in Grasse, southern France, on May 13, 2022. The city center of Grasse was turned into rose gardens during the three-day ExpoRose festival which kicked off here on Friday. (Photo by Serge Haouzi/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/70/13931290822712344234.png" /></p> <p> Roses and a pink umbrella are seen during the 50th ExpoRose in Grasse, southern France, on May 13, 2022. The city center of Grasse was turned into rose gardens during the three-day ExpoRose festival which kicked off here on Friday. (Photo by Serge Haouzi/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/40/6740824784059135548.png" /></p> <p> A child poses with roses during the 50th ExpoRose in Grasse, southern France, on May 13, 2022. The city center of Grasse was turned into rose gardens during the three-day ExpoRose festival which kicked off here on Friday. (Photo by Serge Haouzi/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/60/8498441066768848248.png" /></p> <p> Roses and pink umbrellas are seen during the 50th ExpoRose in Grasse, southern France, on May 13, 2022. The city center of Grasse was turned into rose gardens during the three-day ExpoRose festival which kicked off here on Friday. (Photo by Serge Haouzi/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Oil prices rise as supply concerns persist ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096657</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096657.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:34:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NEW YORK, May 13 (Xinhua) -- Oil prices advanced on Friday as concerns over tighter supplies remain on the market.</p> <p> The West Texas Intermediate for June delivery added 4.36 U.S. dollars, or 4.1 percent, to settle at 110.49 dollars a barrel on the New York Mercantile Exchange. Brent crude for July delivery increased 4.1 dollars, or 3.8 percent, to close at 111.55 dollars a barrel on the London ICE Futures Exchange.</p> <p> The rally came despite data released Friday by Houston-based oilfield services company Baker Hughes showing that the number of total active drilling rigs in the United States rose by nine to 714 this week.</p> <p> Oil rigs in the United States rose by six to 563 this week , gas rigs rose by three to 149, and miscellaneous rigs stayed unchanged at two, showed the data.</p> <p> Concerns over supply risks lingered as the European Union (EU) worked on gaining support for an oil embargo against Russia.</p> <p> Last week, the EU unveiled a plan to phase out Russian crude oil within six months and refined products by the end of the year, as part of its sixth sanction package aimed against Moscow.</p> <p> Hungary and other Eastern European countries, whose economies are largely reliant on Russian oil, are not ready yet to accept the sanction package in its current form.</p> <p> Traders also weighed risks to the demand side.</p> <p> In its monthly report released on Thursday, the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries revised down its forecast for world oil demand growth in 2022, citing impacts from geopolitical tensions and the COVID-19 pandemic.</p> <p> For the week, the U.S. crude standard rose 0.7 percent, while Brent declined 0.7 percent, based on the front-month contracts.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Shanghai reports 194 confirmed, 1,487 asymptomatic local COVID-19 cases ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096654</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096654.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:34:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> SHANGHAI, May 14 (Xinhua) -- China's Shanghai reported 194 confirmed locally transmitted COVID-19 cases and 1,487 local asymptomatic cases on Friday, the municipal health commission said Saturday.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 16 killed in massive building fire in Indian capital ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096658</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096658.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:34:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NEW DELHI, May 13 (Xinhua) -- At least 16 people were killed Friday in a devastating fire inside a commercial building in the Indian capital, officials said.</p> <p> The fire broke out at around 4:40 p.m. local time in the building located near the Mundka metro station in outer Delhi.</p> <p> "A total of 16 bodies were recovered from the three-storey commercial building which had caught fire this evening near Delhi's Mundka metro station," Atul Garg, director of the Delhi fire service, told local media.</p> <p> According to Garg, the third floor of the building was yet to be searched.</p> <p> Police officials said the death toll was likely to rise as many people were feared trapped in the building.</p> <p> "Rescue operation is underway in the building," a police official said.</p> <p> Officials said 24 fire tenders were at the spot to contain the blaze.</p> <p> "It's a massive fire and heavy cranes are being used to go up and douse the fire," a fire service official said.</p> <p> The cause of the fire is not immediately known. However, reports said the fire started from the first floor of the building which hosts an office of a CCTV camera and router manufacturing company.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Highlights of 1,500m race at 2022 diamond league Doha ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096651</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096651.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:21:29 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/80/7485744791392352268.png" /></p> <p> Abel Kipsang (R) of Kenya competes during the men's 1,500m race of the Diamond League athletics meeting of 2022 diamond league Doha in Doha, capital of Qatar, May 13, 2022. (Photo by Nikku/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/96/930258374624281572.png" /></p> <p> Abel Kipsang of Kenya celebrates after winning the men's 1,500m race of the Diamond League athletics meeting of 2022 diamond league Doha in Doha, capital of Qatar, May 13, 2022. (Photo by Nikku/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/28/99988124130226732.png" /></p> <p> Abel Kipsang of Kenya celebrates after winning the men's 1,500m race of the Diamond League athletics meeting of 2022 diamond league Doha in Doha, capital of Qatar, May 13, 2022. (Photo by Nikku/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/9/7188753046711988317.png" /></p> <p> Abel Kipsang (R) of Kenya competes during the men's 1,500m race of the Diamond League athletics meeting of 2022 diamond league Doha in Doha, capital of Qatar, May 13, 2022. (Photo by Nikku/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ New Zealand PM tests positive for COVID-19 ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096653</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096653.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:21:29 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> WELLINGTON, May 14 (Xinhua) -- New Zealand Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern confirmed on Saturday that she had tested positive for COVID-19.</p> <p> "Despite best efforts, unfortunately, I've joined the rest of my family and tested positive for COVID-19," Ardern posted on social media on Saturday morning.</p> <p> Ardern has been isolating at home with her family since Sunday when her fiance Clarke Gayford tested positive.</p> <p> "We've been isolating since Sunday when Clarke first tested positive. Neve (Ardern's daughter) tested positive on Wednesday, and I returned a weak positive last night and a strong one this morning," said Ardern.</p> <p> "To anyone else out there, isolating or dealing with COVID, I hope you take good care of yourselves," said Ardern.</p> <p> New Zealand recorded 7,441 new community cases of COVID-19, 2,503 of which were reported in the largest city Auckland, the ministry of health said on Friday.</p> <p> To date, the country has reported 1,026,715 confirmed cases of COVID-19 since the beginning of the pandemic.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xiplomacy: Xi calls for solidarity, collaboration in global fight against COVID-19 ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096648</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096648.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:21:24 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/81/9743114531998611073.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Staff members work at an inflatable COVID-19 testing lab in Shunyi District of Beijing, capital of China, May 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Ren Chao)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- As of Friday, the worldwide count of COVID-19 cases has exceeded 520 million, with over 6 million related deaths.</p> <p> As the world is plagued by major challenges, not least a pandemic unseen in a century, Chinese President Xi Jinping has on multiple occasions called on the international community to take concerted actions against the virus.</p> <p> The following are some highlights of his remarks on how cooperation can help the world survive.</p> <p> April 21, 2022</p> <p> In his keynote speech at the opening ceremony of the Boao Forum for Asia Annual Conference 2022, Xi stressed that we need to work together to defend people's lives and health.</p> <p> For humanity to clinch a final victory against the COVID-19 pandemic, more hard efforts are needed. It is essential that countries support each other, better coordinate response measures and improve global public health governance, so as to form strong international synergy against the pandemic, said Xi.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/27/4304448240757922511.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Cargos containing China's Sinovac vaccines are seen in Pasay City, the Philippines on Oct. 24, 2021. (Rouelle Umali/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> Jan. 17, 2022</p> <p> At the virtual session of the 2022 World Economic Forum, Xi pledged to embrace cooperation on jointly overcoming the pandemic and champion economic globalization.</p> <p> As COVID-19 is resurging with more variants and spreading faster than before, Xi stressed the importance of fully leveraging vaccines as a powerful weapon and ensuring the equitable distribution of vaccines to close the global immunization gap.</p> <p> Xi called on countries to strengthen international cooperation against COVID-19, carry out active cooperation on the research and development of medicines, jointly build multiple lines of defense against the coronavirus, and speed up efforts to build a global community of health for all.</p> <p> Dec. 31, 2021</p> <p> China has provided 2 billion doses of COVID-19 vaccines to more than 120 countries and international organizations for the global COVID response, Xi said in his 2022 New Year Address.</p> <p> "Only through unity, solidarity and cooperation can countries around the world write a new chapter in building a community with a shared future for mankind," he said.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/65/1885335616284998845.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Local students at the Obaay Primary School receive the food items donated by fellow Chinese school children through the China Foundation for Poverty Alleviation (CFPA) in Dukem town of Ethiopia's Oromia regional state, on June 9, 2021. (Xinhua/Wang Ping)</em></p> <p> Nov. 29, 2021</p> <p> China and Africa should fight COVID-19 with solidarity, deepen practical cooperation, promote green development, and uphold equity and justice, Xi said at the opening ceremony of the Eighth Ministerial Conference of the Forum on China-Africa Cooperation via video link.</p> <p> On fighting COVID-19 with solidarity, Xi stressed the need to truly ensure the accessibility and affordability of vaccines in Africa.</p> <p> Oct. 31, 2021</p> <p> While addressing the 16th G20 Leaders' Summit via video link, Xi said that at present, the spread of the COVID-19 pandemic has triggered multiple crises.</p> <p> The development achievements made by the international community over the years have been seriously eroded and developing countries are facing unprecedented challenges and tests, Xi pointed out.</p> <p> The COVID-19 pandemic has once again shown that all countries, with high stakes in each other's future and converging interests, form a community with a shared future for mankind, Xi said, noting that promoting sustainable development in developing countries will benefit the people of the countries concerned, and also affect the future and destiny of the whole mankind and the Earth.</p> <p> Sept. 24, 2021</p> <p> While delivering a speech via video at the opening ceremony of the 2021 Zhongguancun Forum, Xi called on all countries to strengthen openness and cooperation in science and technology.</p> <p> Xi noted that nowadays profound changes unseen in a century are evolving rapidly in the world and the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic is far-reaching, presenting severe challenges for the recovery of the global economy.</p> <p> All countries in the world need to strengthen openness and cooperation in science and technology, explore ways and means of jointly solving important global issues through sci-tech innovation, address the challenges of the times together, and promote the noble cause of peace and development for all, said Xi.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Farmers busy with summer farming across China ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096646</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096646.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 09:54:21 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/18/14566088204506571450.png" /></p> <p> Farmers take care of seedlings in the field in Lijiagang Village of Wulingyuan District in Zhangjiajie, central China's Hunan Province, May 13, 2022. (Photo by Wu Yongbing/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/5/7106632666382180477.png" /></p> <p> Aerial photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows farmers reaping rices in Beishan Village of Boao Township in Qionghai, south China's Hainan Province. (Photo by Meng Zhongde/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/99/9851107739337131079.png" /></p> <p> A farmer carries harvested vegetable in the field in Yangpai Village of Danzhai County, southwest China's Guizhou Province, May 13, 2022. (Photo by Huang Xiaohai/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/19/10063637746440022303.png" /></p> <p> Aerial photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows villagers farming in the field in Liangtian Village of Congjiang County in Qiandongnan Miao and Dong Autonomous Prefecture, southwest China's Guizhou Province. (Photo by Luo Jinglai/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/21/5310454787162588197.png" /></p> <p> Aerial photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows a farmer transplanting rice seedlings in the field in Chahe Township of Fengnan District in Tangshan, north China's Hebei Province. (Photo by Li Xiuqing/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/41/3674675481519466313.png" /></p> <p> Aerial photo taken on May 11, 2022 shows a harvester reaping rapeseeds in Chongyang Village in Maliang Township of Xiangyang, central China's Hubei Province. (Photo by Chen Quanlin/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/90/5979975458375418650.png" /></p> <p> Farmers are busy in the corn field in Quanshuitou Village of Zunhua, north China's Hebei Province, May 13, 2022. (Photo by Liu Mancang/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/57/11564410933552729693.png" /></p> <p> Aerial photo taken on May 13, 2022 shows farmers transplanting rice seedlings in the field in Dongma Village of Xiangxi Tujia and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, central China's Hunan Province. (Photo by Long Enze/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/90/17248780899382569354.png" /></p> <p> A farmer transplants rice seedlings in the field in Chahe Township of Fengnan District in Tangshan, north China's Hebei Province, May 13, 2022. (Photo by Li Xiuqing/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/86/6569334383101423478.png" /></p> <p> Farmers take care of peanut seedlings in the field in Quanshuitou Village of Zunhua, north China's Hebei Province, May 13, 2022. (Photo by Liu Mancang/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/13/13167919044982928749.png" /></p> <p> Villagers walk in the fields in Jiaye Village of Congjiang County in Qiandongnan Miao and Dong Autonomous Prefecture, southwest China's Guizhou Province, May 13, 2022. (Photo by Lu Zhongnan/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ "The Kiss" by Gustav Klimt exhibited at Upper Belvedere in Vienna ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096644</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096644.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 09:54:21 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/1/12533990455236815841.png" /></p> <p> Visitors view "The Kiss" by Gustav Klimt at the Upper Belvedere in Vienna, Austria, May 12, 2022.</p> <p> The Upper Belvedere in Vienna houses one of Austria's most valuable art collections - with key works by Gustav Klimt, Egon Schiele and Oskar Kokoschka. The heart of the Belvedere collection is formed by the 24 paintings of Gustav Klimt with his golden images "The Kiss" and "Judith". "The Kiss" in particular is world-famous. (Xinhua/Guo Chen)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/23/6419066052012865303.png" /></p> <p> Souvenirs featuring "The Kiss" by Gustav Klimt are seen at the Upper Belvedere in Vienna, Austria, May 12, 2022.</p> <p> The Upper Belvedere in Vienna houses one of Austria's most valuable art collections - with key works by Gustav Klimt, Egon Schiele and Oskar Kokoschka. The heart of the Belvedere collection is formed by the 24 paintings of Gustav Klimt with his golden images "The Kiss" and "Judith". "The Kiss" in particular is world-famous. (Xinhua/Guo Chen)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/8/13577536838927793044.png" /></p> <p> A visitor views "The Kiss" by Gustav Klimt at the Upper Belvedere in Vienna, Austria, May 12, 2022.</p> <p> The Upper Belvedere in Vienna houses one of Austria's most valuable art collections - with key works by Gustav Klimt, Egon Schiele and Oskar Kokoschka. The heart of the Belvedere collection is formed by the 24 paintings of Gustav Klimt with his golden images "The Kiss" and "Judith". "The Kiss" in particular is world-famous. (Xinhua/Guo Chen)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/55/4928488091747044239.png" /></p> <p> Souvenirs featuring "The Kiss" by Gustav Klimt are seen at the Upper Belvedere in Vienna, Austria, May 12, 2022.</p> <p> The Upper Belvedere in Vienna houses one of Austria's most valuable art collections - with key works by Gustav Klimt, Egon Schiele and Oskar Kokoschka. The heart of the Belvedere collection is formed by the 24 paintings of Gustav Klimt with his golden images "The Kiss" and "Judith". "The Kiss" in particular is world-famous. (Xinhua/Guo Chen)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/34/17729873749989152066.png" /></p> <p> Visitors view "The Kiss" by Gustav Klimt at the Upper Belvedere in Vienna, Austria, May 12, 2022.</p> <p> The Upper Belvedere in Vienna houses one of Austria's most valuable art collections - with key works by Gustav Klimt, Egon Schiele and Oskar Kokoschka. The heart of the Belvedere collection is formed by the 24 paintings of Gustav Klimt with his golden images "The Kiss" and "Judith". "The Kiss" in particular is world-famous. (Xinhua/Guo Chen)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/72/10816976296705593860.png" /></p> <p> Souvenirs featuring "The Kiss" by Gustav Klimt are seen at the Upper Belvedere in Vienna, Austria, May 12, 2022.</p> <p> The Upper Belvedere in Vienna houses one of Austria's most valuable art collections - with key works by Gustav Klimt, Egon Schiele and Oskar Kokoschka. The heart of the Belvedere collection is formed by the 24 paintings of Gustav Klimt with his golden images "The Kiss" and "Judith". "The Kiss" in particular is world-famous. (Xinhua/Guo Chen)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/14/129449815318563482.png" /></p> <p> Souvenirs featuring "The Kiss" by Gustav Klimt are seen at the Upper Belvedere in Vienna, Austria, May 12, 2022.</p> <p> The Upper Belvedere in Vienna houses one of Austria's most valuable art collections - with key works by Gustav Klimt, Egon Schiele and Oskar Kokoschka. The heart of the Belvedere collection is formed by the 24 paintings of Gustav Klimt with his golden images "The Kiss" and "Judith". "The Kiss" in particular is world-famous. (Xinhua/Guo Chen)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/38/1930003040869070338.png" /></p> <p> A souvenir featuring "The Kiss" by Gustav Klimt is seen at the Upper Belvedere in Vienna, Austria, May 12, 2022.</p> <p> The Upper Belvedere in Vienna houses one of Austria's most valuable art collections - with key works by Gustav Klimt, Egon Schiele and Oskar Kokoschka. The heart of the Belvedere collection is formed by the 24 paintings of Gustav Klimt with his golden images "The Kiss" and "Judith". "The Kiss" in particular is world-famous. (Xinhua/Guo Chen)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/12/2765238622779205060.png" /></p> <p> Souvenirs featuring "The Kiss" by Gustav Klimt are seen at the Upper Belvedere in Vienna, Austria, May 12, 2022.</p> <p> The Upper Belvedere in Vienna houses one of Austria's most valuable art collections - with key works by Gustav Klimt, Egon Schiele and Oskar Kokoschka. The heart of the Belvedere collection is formed by the 24 paintings of Gustav Klimt with his golden images "The Kiss" and "Judith". "The Kiss" in particular is world-famous. (Xinhua/Guo Chen)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Commentary: Washington's small-clique politics won't fool SE Asia ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096638</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096638.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 09:49:33 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/18/4223263417608477262.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on Nov. 23, 2021 shows the White House in Washington, D.C., the United States. (Photo by Ting Shen/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> <strong>*The U.S. administration has long taken pleasure in organizing destructive meetings under the guise of constructive engagements. </strong></p> <p> <strong>*The so-called "Indo-Pacific Strategy" it is selling at this summit, for example, claims to maintain regional freedom and openness and respect ASEAN centrality in regional affairs, but in reality incites confrontation, undermines unity, and threatens cooperation and development in the region through such exclusive geopolitical blocs as AUKUS and Quad.</strong></p> <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- The White House is peddling its so-called "Indo-Pacific Strategy" against China and ramping up its pressure campaign of the Russia-Ukraine conflict during a two-day summit in Washington with leaders of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN).</p> <p> But its hope to pull ASEAN members into its camp will shrivel, as ASEAN countries have already woken up to Washington's typical hegemony, hypocrisy and egomania.</p> <p> The arrangement of the summit itself has laid bare Washington's double-dealing nature. Its disrespect for ASEAN members concerning scheduling issues despite its pledge of "enduring commitment" has sparked a wave of complaints among ASEAN members, resulting in a postponement of the summit from late March to May.</p> <p> Cambodian Minister attached to the Prime Minister Kao Kim Hourn said before the summit that if Washington was serious about improving its ties with ASEAN, it should have arranged bilateral meetings between the United States and ASEAN countries. ASEAN leaders "should be treated with respect and equality," he noted.</p> <p> The U.S. administration has long taken pleasure in organizing destructive meetings under the guise of constructive engagements. The so-called "Indo-Pacific Strategy" it is selling at this summit, for example, claims to maintain regional freedom and openness and respect ASEAN centrality in regional affairs, but in reality incites confrontation, undermines unity, and threatens cooperation and development in the region through such exclusive geopolitical blocs as AUKUS and Quad.</p> <p> Many sober minds in ASEAN have seen through this duplicity and bullying. Indonesia and Malaysia warned that AUKUS could lead to a major arms race in the region. A recent report by the U.S. Center for Strategic and International Studies showed that many ASEAN members have expressed concerns that the so-called "Indo-Pacific Economic Framework" is "primarily a political endeavor meant to counter China, rather than a sincere and thoughtful economic policy integration initiative."</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/71/5892171399547127135.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on March 24, 2022 shows the U.S. national flag (R) on the U.S. Embassy building in Moscow, Russia. (Xinhua/Bai Xueqi)</em></p> <p> Meanwhile, the White House will attempt in vain during this summit to talk ASEAN into imposing sanctions against Russia. Ever since the escalation of the current Ukraine crisis, Washington has been trying to exert pressure on ASEAN to take sides, but most of ASEAN members did not follow suit.</p> <p> On April 7, six of the 10-member bloc abstained from voting in favor of a resolution to remove Russia from the United Nations Human Rights Council, and two voted against it. Long adhering to an independent foreign policy, ASEAN members have urged solving the crisis through negotiation and dialogue.</p> <p> Moreover, some ASEAN members have been well aware of Washington's unspoken calculations to turn bloody sufferings of others into golden opportunities for profits in the Russia-Ukraine conflict. For example, during his visit to China in early April, Thai Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Don Pramudwinai said he appreciates China's objective and fair position on the Ukraine issue, that "Asian countries should maintain peace and stability in the region, jointly resist unilateral sanctions and long-arm jurisdiction that have no basis in international law, and prevent attempts to create tensions and replicate crises in the region."</p> <p> Playing small clique politics and forcing others to take sides -- Washington's old tricks to gain geopolitical interests -- work against ASEAN's will to uphold regional peace and stability and to realize sustainable economic development. Launching trade wars and breaking pacts -- Washington's classical acts of unilateralism -- severely disrupt normal trade exchanges and supply chains in the region and deal a heavy blow to ASEAN's economy. All those wrongdoings have tarnished Washington's credit and influence as the world's sole superpower, and driven it further apart from ASEAN members.</p> <p> The long arc of history teaches each and every country that acting without scruples almost always results in the reverse of what one desires. It is time for Washington to learn this lesson, abandon its old dream of Cold War hegemony, uphold an open and inclusive mindset, and play its due role in maintaining regional and global peace, stability and development.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Parliamentary analysis on increased security as NATO member questioned in Sweden ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096640</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096640.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 09:49:33 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/66/2114264619436768198.png" /></p> <p> <em>Swedish Foreign Minister Ann Linde (6th L), Minister of Defense Peter Hultqvist (5th L) and other parliamentary party representatives present the result of a security analysis at a press conference in Stockholm, Sweden, on May 13, 2022. A security analysis presented by the Swedish parliament on Friday that says a NATO membership would increase security for the Nordic country was questioned by several parties ahead of Sweden's historic decision on whether to be a new member of the trans-Atlantic military bloc. (Ninni Andersson/Government Offices of Sweden/Handout via Xinhua)</em></p> <p> STOCKHOLM, May 13 (Xinhua) -- A security analysis presented by the Swedish parliament on Friday that says a NATO membership would increase security for the Nordic country was questioned by several parties ahead of Sweden's historic decision on whether to be a new member of the trans-Atlantic military bloc.</p> <p> The security analysis, which serves as an important basis for Sweden's upcoming NATO membership decisions, has been prepared by all eight parliamentary parties, of which, the Left Party and the Green Party, however, do not support the report's conclusions as a whole.</p> <p> Although the analysis listed a number of advantages of possible Swedish membership in NATO, with an "increased security" as the main conclusion, it does not provide a recommendation on whether Sweden should join.</p> <p> However, the analysis is widely understood to serve as an important basis for the ruling Social Democrats' and the government's NATO decision, to be presented on Sunday and Monday respectively.</p> <p> "The main conclusion of a possible membership in NATO is that Sweden would become part of NATO's collective security," said Foreign Minister Ann Linde at a press conference on Friday.</p> <p> While the analysis assesses that Sweden will not be exposed to a conventional military attack as a reaction to a possible Swedish NATO application, Linde said that "an armed attack on Sweden can not be ruled out."</p> <p> "We see a democratic decline in several countries today, even among countries that are members of NATO, which is not clearly mentioned. The Green Party's basic attitude towards NATO has not changed." Maria Ferm, member of the Green Party, told Swedish Television, emphasizing her party's opposition to joining NATO.</p> <p> "We have therefore submitted a special opinion about this issue and about this analysis, because we do not agree with all the wording about NATO this analysis contains," Ferm emphasized.</p> <p> "I think there is no analysis of the risks that a Swedish NATO membership entails." Hakan Svenneling, a member of the Left Party told Swedish Television, "We are making the biggest change in Swedish security policy in a very long time. And freedom of alliance has been very important and served Sweden well for a long time, and could do so for a long time to come."</p> <p> "I am worried that every major conflict for a long time to come, for decades, will take place at Sweden's borders or in Sweden. This is something I do not want to be a part of, which is why I oppose Swedish NATO membership," Svenneling said.&nbsp;</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/6/691044886501688306.png" /></p> <p> Swedish Foreign Minister Ann Linde (R) and Minister of Defense Peter Hultqvist attend a press conference on a security analysis in Stockholm, Sweden, on May 13, 2022. A security analysis presented by the Swedish parliament on Friday that says a NATO membership would increase security for the Nordic country was questioned by several parties ahead of Sweden's historic decision on whether to be a new member of the trans-Atlantic military bloc. (Ninni Andersson/Government Offices of Sweden/Handout via Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Commentary: Reasons to remain confident in Chinese economy amid pandemic ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096634</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096634.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 09:49:33 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/49/1150674847762861189.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Photo shows customers check out at a Sam's Club warehouse store at Beicai Town in Pudong New Area, east China's Shanghai, May 2, 2022. Large retail companies in Shanghai have started to reopen their supermarkets amid the recent COVID-19 resurgence. (Xinhua/Chen Jianli)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- The surge of the Omicron variant of the coronavirus has exerted downward pressure on the Chinese economy. With an array of pro-growth policies to produce their intended effects, the risk is manageable and the sound fundamentals of the world's second-largest economy in the medium-to-long term will not change.</p> <p> To cope with the pandemic, China has applied a stringent dynamic zero-COVID policy. As the pandemic is still raging across the world and coronavirus continues to mutate, there is a great deal of uncertainty concerning how the situation will develop. The country has warned against any slackening in its efforts to control the virus.</p> <p> China's stance has been firm and clear -- unswervingly adhering to the dynamic zero-COVID policy while shoring up the economy and ensuring people's lives are affected as little as possible.</p> <p> Giving proper consideration to all these aspects is a difficult task. The earnest implementation of this policy is a major test for all regions and departments.</p> <p> A string of pro-growth policies is in the pipeline. China has already adopted multi-pronged fiscal measures in tax and fee cuts, public budget expenditure and bond issuance to stabilize the economy and ensure its people's wellbeing.</p> <p> Moreover, China has accelerated the establishment of a unified domestic market, comprehensively strengthened infrastructure construction, and deepened reform and opening-up across the board.</p> <p> The State Council and relevant departments are also rolling out detailed policies and measures to help industries, individually owned businesses and micro, small and medium-sized enterprises hit hard by the pandemic, and to stabilize market entities.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/78/15009916851255006974.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Photo shows staff members work in a workshop at Songz Automobile Air Conditioning Co. Ltd in Shanghai, east China, April 29, 2022. A total of 251 automakers and auto parts and components enterprises were included in the first batch of 666 companies on the city's "white list" designed to support firms to resume production amid COVID-19 control. (Xinhua/Zhang Jiansong)</em></p> <p> Chinese authorities have ample space and diversified tools for fiscal, monetary and other policies. They have rich experience in responding to downward pressure on the economy and will further strengthen regulatory control, and will do so when the time is right.</p> <p> The Chinese economy is off to a steady start this year, with its GDP up 4.8 percent year on year in the first three months. Despite the downward pressure, the fundamentals of the Chinese economy, including its strong resilience, enormous potential, vast room for maneuver and long-term sustainability, remain unchanged. After pro-growth policies gradually produce their intended effects, China's economic performance will improve.</p> <p> By contributing approximately 30 percent to world economic growth, the Chinese economy is the largest engine driving global economic growth. The Chinese economy is at a critical moment in overcoming its difficulties. It is only by remaining confident and rising to the challenges that China can turn adverse situations into opportunities, embrace its bright prospects, continue to inject dynamism into the stability and recovery of the global economy and bring broader market opportunities for all countries.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China voices opposition to smearing remarks by Japan, EU ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096635</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096635.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 09:49:33 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- China on Friday expressed firm opposition to recent smearing remarks and interference in China's internal affairs by Japan and the European Union (EU), urging them to abandon the zero-sum game mindset.</p> <p> Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Zhao Lijian made the remarks at a daily press briefing in response to a query about a joint statement issued by Japan and the EU at a summit on Thursday, which expressed "concerns" over the situation of the Diaoyu Islands, East China Sea, South China Sea and Taiwan Strait, as well as so-called human rights issues in Hong Kong and Xinjiang.</p> <p> Japan and the EU have hyped up China-related issues, made smearing remarks against China, interfered in China's internal affairs and instigated regional confrontation, Zhao said. "China is firmly opposed to such practice, and has lodged stern representation with relevant parties."</p> <p> Zhao said the Diaoyu Island and its affiliated islands have always been an inherent part of the Chinese territory, adding no matter what is said or done, the fact can never be altered that the islands belong to China.</p> <p> Regarding maritime issues, Zhao said China will firmly safeguard its territorial sovereignty and maritime rights and interests, and at the same time is ready to settle differences with relevant countries via consultations.</p> <p> As for issues related to Taiwan, Hong Kong and Xinjiang, Zhao said they all fall within China's internal affairs, which brook no interference by any external forces. "We urge relevant countries to focus on putting their own house in order."</p> <p> China's development means important opportunities for the world, Zhao said, citing facts that China's economy has contributed 30 percent to the world economic growth, and China's achievements in COVID-19 response have helped stabilize the global supply chain. The Belt and Road Initiative has benefited more than 180 countries and international organizations.</p> <p> "The so-called China threat theory has gone bankrupt in face of facts," Zhao said.</p> <p> Noting the world needs unity and cooperation more than ever before in face of challenges such as the resurgences of COVID-19 and lackluster economic recovery, Zhao urged Japan and the EU to abandon seeking ideological confrontation and a zero-sum game mindset, to practice real multilateralism and inject more positive energy into the world.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinas trade in services moves onto fast lane of development ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096600</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096600.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 09:01:35 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0514/FOREIGN202205140850000325097852849.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 601px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on Sept. 7, 2021 shows the exhibition area of the 2021 China International Fair for Trade in Services (CIFTIS) at the China National Convention Center in Beijing. (Photo by Fan Jiashan/Peoples Daily Online)</em></p> <p> Chinas services trade has maintained fast growth. Data from the countrys Ministry of Commerce (MOFCOM) showed that Chinas imports and exports of services totaled over 1.45 trillion yuan ($214.6 billion) in the first quarter of 2022, rising 25.8 percent year on year.</p> <p> Its exports of services grew 30.8 percent to 713.98 billion yuan and imports of services reached 743.01 billion yuan with a year-on-year increase of 21.3 percent. The growth of services exports outpaced import growth by 9.5 percentage points, resulting in a 56.4-percent drop in the countrys services trade deficit to 29.03 billion yuan from the same period last year.</p> <p> Zhao Zhonghui, director of the translation center of BERIS Engineering and Research Corporation in Qingdao city, east Chinas Shandong province, has been busy dubbing a program of Shandong TV into Lao with her colleagues.</p> <p> This is a new service export project we launched this year. Weve so far finished translating the Chinese subtitles into Lao, English and Romanian, and basically accomplished the dubbing work, said Zhao, adding that the program will be aired on Lao National Television and Romanian public television TVR in a few days.</p> <p> According to Zhao, the company completed the multilingual dubbing and subtitle translation of more than 10,000 standard episodes of TV programs in 2021. The programs it exported last year, which were 450,000 minutes in total length, have been broadcast on TV stations and online video platforms in 195 countries and regions and received over 10 billion hits globally, bringing the company an export value of several billion yuan.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0514/FOREIGN202205140851000026691279557.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 675px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on Sept. 7, 2021 shows the exhibition area of the 2021 China International Fair for Trade in Services (CIFTIS) at the China National Convention Center in Beijing. (Photo by Fan Jiashan/Peoples Daily Online)</em></p> <p> During the rapid development of trade in services, knowledge-intensive service industry, as a key field, made remarkable progress and showed stronger export competitiveness, noted Zhang Jianping, head of the Center for Regional Economic Cooperation under the Chinese Academy of International Trade and Economic Cooperation.</p> <p> Chinas trade in knowledge-intensive services climbed 14.1 percent to 615.66 billion yuan in the first quarter of the year, according to an official with the Department of Trade in Services and Commercial Services of the MOFCOM.</p> <p> Knowledge-intensive services exports expanded 16.3 percent to 350.06 billion yuan, among which exports of such fields as telecommunications, computer and information services, other business services, as well as intellectual property royalties registered fast growth, rising 22.1 percent, 14.6 percent and 11.2 percent, respectively.</p> <p> Imports of knowledge-intensive services grew 11.4 percent to 265.6 billion yuan during the period.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0514/FOREIGN202205140851000585875901609.jpg" style="width: 828px; height: 552px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>A busy container terminal of Haikou Port, south Chinas Hainan province, August 29, 2021.</em></p> <p> The sound performance of Chinas trade in services is attributed to Chinese enterprises increasing competitiveness and the governments policies and measures.</p> <p> On August 26, 2021, China officially began to implement a negative list for cross-border trade in services in the southern island province of Hainan. The introduction and implementation of the negative list represented a major breakthrough in the management model of trade in services and signaled further opening-up in cross-border trade in services.</p> <p> An MOFCOM official recently disclosed that the country plans to formulate a negative list for cross-border trade in services that is applicable to all of its 21 pilot free trade zones (FTZs) this year, and will promote the introduction of a national negative list for cross-border services trade in due course.</p> <p> In March, the general office of the MOFCOM issued a circular on making good use of the guidance funds for the innovative development of services trade to support the development of new trade forms and models, encouraging leveraging new ways of financing to stimulate new trade forms and models.</p> <p> The MOFCOM and six other government departments lately approved a new batch of 40 specialized bases for featured services export. China is now home to 112 bases for featured services export, which cover seven fields including culture, traditional Chinese medicine, digital services, human resources, geographic information, intellectual property and language services.</p> <p> The 2022 China International Fair for Trade in Services (CIFTIS), which is scheduled to be held both online and offline in September, will focus on trends in services trade, highlight digitalization and green development, and add a thematic exhibition of environment services.</p> <p> Six kinds of activities will be held during this years CIFTIS, including the Global Trade in Services Summit, exhibition, conference and forum, promotion and negotiation, achievement release as well as supporting activities.</p> <p> The exhibition will cover an area of no less than 126,000 square meters, and over 100 conferences, forums, promotion and negotiation activities will be held.</p> <p> As an important part of international trade and a major field of international economic and trade cooperation, services trade plays a key role in building a new development pattern.</p> <p> Last year, the value added of Chinas service sector accounted for 53.3 percent of the countrys GDP, and the countrys total trade in services reached 5.3 trillion yuan, ranking second in the world for eight consecutive years.</p> <p> On the whole, Chinas trade in services is characterized by constantly expanding scale, steadily increasing added value and continuously growing competitiveness, and still has huge potential for growth and great market opportunities.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinas Tianzhou-4 cargo spacecraft successfully docks with space station combination ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096603</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096603.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 09:01:30 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0514/FOREIGN202205140859000082034995198.jpg" style="width: 700px; height: 396px;" /></p> <p> <em>Chinas Long March-7 Y5 carrier rocket, carrying the countrys Tianzhou-4 cargo spacecraft, blasts off from the Wenchang Spacecraft Launch Site in south Chinas Hainan province. (Photo/Courtesy of China Academy of Launch Vehicle Technology)</em></p> <p> Chinas Long March-7 Y5 carrier rocket launched the countrys Tianzhou-4 cargo spacecraft from the Wenchang Spacecraft Launch Site in south Chinas Hainan province at 1:56 a.m. on May 10, Beijing time, according to the China Manned Space Agency (CMSA), which declared the launch a complete success.</p> <p> The launch was the 22nd launch mission of Chinas manned space program, the first launch mission since the construction of the countrys space station shifted from the key technology verification phase to the in-orbit construction phase, and the 420th flight mission of the Long March carrier rocket series.</p> <p> The Tianzhou-4 cargo spacecraft successfully completed status setting after entering orbit. At 8:54 a.m. on May 10, Tianzhou-4 conducted a fast automated rendezvous and docking at the rear docking port of the Tianhe core module of Chinas space station, delivering goods to its destination within few hours after launch.</p> <p> All the food, clothing, equipment and other supplies astronauts need for long-term stay in space must be carried to space station in time by cargo spacecraft, as well as the fuel the space station requires to maintain its orbit.</p> <p> Last year, Long March-7 Y3 and Long March-7 Y4 carrier rockets sent the Tianzhou-2 and Tianzhou-3 cargo spacecraft, respectively, into space, delivering supplies for the construction of the countrys space station.</p> <p> This time, before the arrival of the three crew members, the Tianzhou-4 cargo ship carried the necessary supplies for the forthcoming six-month Shenzhou-14 crewed mission to the space station. The cargo vessel brought more than 200 sets of items into orbit, including consumables for the Shenzhou-14 crew, propellants, gadgets, equipment, and samples for application experiments and testing, as well as replacement components and payloads.</p> <p> Tianzhou-4, after rendezvous and docking with the combination of the space station core module Tianhe and the Tianzhou-3 cargo craft, joined the combination.</p> <p> In order to ensure supplies can be delivered to the space accommodations safely, the Tianzhou-4 cargo spacecraft has used cargo bags, racks, and storage tanks to carry goods. The categories and quantities of the transported goods vary according to the needs of the space station.</p> <p> Simultaneously, the cargo craft can also undertake tasks including controlling the attitude and orbital trajectory of the space station and supporting space science experiment.</p> <p> According to a designer with Shanghai Academy of Spaceflight Technology, the construction of Chinas space station is like putting together building blocks, and the docking mechanism is the joint that connects various modules with each other.</p> <p> Since Chinas first-ever rendezvous and docking of two spacecraft in 2011, the country has successfully carried out rendezvous and docking of spacecraft for 19 times, which laid a solid technological foundation for the construction of its space station.</p> <p> The docking mechanism is going to face bigger tests this year as it will need to connect the Wentian and Mengtian lab modules with the space station combination.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0514/FOREIGN202205140859000355364753074.jpg" style="width: 700px; height: 441px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo shows Chinas Long March-7 Y5 carrier rocket. (Photo/Courtesy of China Academy of Launch Vehicle Technology)</em></p> <p> During the construction of the space station, the docking mechanism needs to handle various ways of docking of spacecraft whose weights range from 8 to 180 tons. Besides, huge docking energy can be generated during the process, which poses high requirements on the docking mechanisms buffering and energy dissipation capacity.</p> <p> To make sure two heavyweight spacecraft can dock with each other successfully, designers have carried out massive studies and research on relevant plans and finally mastered the key technology.</p> <p> The launch of the Tianzhou-4 cargo spacecraft is expected to be followed by the launch of the Shenzhou-14 crewed mission in June, the Wentian lab module in July, and the Mengtian lab module in October. The two lab modules and the Tianhe core module will form a T-shaped structure, with the core module at the center and the two lab modules attached to each side of it. The formation of the basic structure will signal the completion of the space station.</p> <p> Hao Chun, director of the CMSA, says that upon the completion of the in-orbit construction of the space station this year, it will enter a phase of application and development that is expected to span over 10 years.</p> <p> The initial plan is to launch two manned spacecraft and two cargo spacecraft each year. Astronauts will stay in the space station for a long time to carry out space science experiments and to maintain the space station, Hao said.</p> <p> As the first launch mission of the space station missions in 2022, the launch of the Tianzhou-4 cargo spacecraft marked the beginning of the in-orbit construction of the space station and made people start counting down to the completion of a new home in space that will benefit all humanity.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
	</channel>
</rss>