<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title> Life_Culture </title>
		<image>
			<title>People's Daily Online</title>
			<link>http://english.people.com.cn/</link>
			<url>http://english.people.com.cn/images/en/top_logo_e.gif</url>
		</image>
		<description>People's Daily Online</description>
		<link>http://english.people.com.cn/90782</link>
		<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Museums across China gather pace in going digital ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096602</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096602.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 09:01:26 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0514/FOREIGN202205140855000465153378561.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>The scene of an exhibition held both online and offline by Zhejiang Provincial Museum. The exhibition showcased more than 1,000 images of ancient Chinese women from 32 museums. (Photo/Zhejiang Provincial Museum)</em></p> <p> Many Chinese museums, art galleries and other cultural and art institutions have ramped up efforts to leverage digital technologies for better development. Based on their characteristic resources, they have rolled out online exhibitions, courses, and other online services, allowing netizens to take virtual tours and enjoy splendid art feasts online.</p> <p> Zhejiang Provincial Museum launched an online exhibition that showcased more than 1,000 images of ancient Chinese women from 32 museums. Meanwhile, it carried out an online interaction activity, attracting active participation of netizens.</p> <p> “You can also take part in our photography collection activity during this online exhibition. We are looking forward to your sharing photos of yourselves in traditional Chinese clothes like Hanfu and Qipao on social media platforms,” said a manager of the museum.</p> <p> Excellent online exhibitions couldn’t have been possible without strong technological support. As 5G, virtual reality (VR), 360-degree panoramic tour and other digital technologies are widely employed in cultural property exhibitions, museums have explored more diversified and interesting forms in interacting with the public.</p> <p> “Art exhibitions have embraced dramatic changes thanks to Internet technologies. They bring new experiences featuring high-definition, three-dimension and interactive products and services to the public, and help show exhibits clearly to people with detailed display, voice introduction and three-dimensional methods,” said Yu Kailiang, professor at the aesthetics teaching and research office under the School of Philosophy, Renmin University of China.</p> <p> The Yungang Grottoes located in Datong city, north China’s Shanxi province, are famous in the world for their magnificence, exquisite craftsmanship and unique charm.</p> <p> Thanks to digital technologies, visitors are able to appreciate the Yungang Grottoes remotely by wearing VR headset, which can help vividly present the grottoes and statues.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0514/FOREIGN202205140856000157214315721.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 534px;" /></p> <p> <em>Visitors watch a replica of the Cave No. 57 of the Mogao Grottoes restored with 3D printing technology at the Zhejiang University Museum of Art and Archaeology, Nov. 2, 2021. (Photo by Long Wei/People’s Daily Online)</em></p> <p> Digitalization offers a new solution to cultural heritage conservation and communication.</p> <p> The Yungang Grottoes Research Institute has completed a project for the digital collection of typical grottoes in the Yungang Grottoes. Through cooperation with colleges and universities including Zhejiang University and Wuhan University, the institute has also used 3D printing, VR and other high technologies to introduce the Yungang Grottoes cultural relics to the world.</p> <p> Based on augmented reality (AR) and VR technologies, the National Museum of China held an online exhibition and built virtual exhibition halls to reproduce historical occasions in Chinese history along the road to rejuvenation, expanding the exhibition space for viewers.</p> <p> The China (Hainan) Museum of the South China Sea allows visitors to enjoy beautiful sunrise and sunset in the island province Hainan through livestreaming empowered by 5G and VR.</p> <p> The Shanxi Museum provided online 360-degree panoramic tours, e-books, high-definition pictures and audio tours of its exquisite exhibitions over the years to meet the diverse needs of the audience.</p> <p> On Digital Dunhuang, a digital platform for the exhibition of the Mogao Grottoes, the exquisite pictures of the grottoes can be magnified, allowing netizens to see clearly even the mottled cracks on the wall. Detailed descriptions are added to introduce the story and artistic value of each grotto, painted sculpture and mural. “The murals seem so real and clear that I feel like I can almost touch them,” a netizen commented.</p> <p> Online exhibition is not only about moving physical exhibitions onto online platforms, but about innovating exhibitions forms with online resources.</p> <p> In recent years, China has rolled out a series of targeted measures to promote the development of online exhibitions.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0514/FOREIGN202205140856000413683089226.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 532px;" /></p> <p> <em>Citizens paint peonies on an interactive device at a peony-themed museum in Luoyang city, central China’s Henan province, May 1, 2022. (Photo by Huang Zhengwei/People’s Daily Online)</em></p> <p> In April 2021, the Ministry of Culture and Tourism issued a development plan for culture and tourism during the country’s 14th Five-Year Plan (2021-2025) period, stating that it would advance the digital construction of art museums and vigorously develop online exhibitions.</p> <p> One month later, nine government departments in China, including the Publicity Department of the Communist Party of China Central Committee, the National Development and Reform Commission, the Ministry of Education and the Ministry of Science and Technology, jointly issued guidelines on driving the reform and development of museums, which stressed that the country would support joint exhibitions, online display and increase exposure of collections.</p> <p> In December last year, the State Council issued a development plan for digital economy during the 14th Five-Year Plan period, which encouraged scenic spots and museums to develop online digital experience products as well as new cultural tourism services such as online exhibitions and immersive experiences.</p> <p> By connecting the organization, participation, sharing and communication of online exhibitions links, resources in the museum industry will be integrated to a high limit, which gives the public more opportunities to enjoy the charm of culture.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chef makes exquisite Japanese cuisine despite having no interest in cooking ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096598</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096598.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 18:28:54 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <script src="http://tv.people.com.cn/img/player/v.js"></script><script>showPlayer({id:"/pvservice/xml/2022/5/13/eb9cf567-45fa-4270-abd5-1957ea45976e.xml",width:830,height:550});</script></p> <p> “I’m a chef but I don’t like cooking that much.”</p> <p> This is how Ryuya Nagase, a chef working for a restaurant specializing in creative Japanese cuisine in Beijing, has described himself.</p> <p> Despite his lack of interest in cooking, Nagase is no newcomer when it comes to serving up his various gourmet delicacies featuring exquisite textures and flavors to his many customers, inspired by his constant stream of culinary ideas. His diligence and sense of pride, driven by an unwillingness to lose business to any of his rival competitors, has put him ahead of the pack among restauranters operating in Beijing’s fine dining scene.</p> <p> Nagase has already lived in China for six years. For him, everything here is still filled with a sense of novelty. “China has become like my second home,” he said.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ City in China’s Hubei revitalizes ancient Chu-style lacquer decoration technique ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096209</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096209.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:23:27 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205131001000432392430218.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Photo shows lacquer artifacts from the Warring States Period (475 – 221 B.C.). (Photo courtesy of Jingzhou Museum)</em></p> <p> Jingzhou city in central China’s Hubei Province has revitalized its time-honored Chu-style lacquer decoration technique, which was listed as a national intangible cultural heritage (ICH) item in 2011, by applying innovative approaches to the craft in recent years, making it even more charming.</p> <p> For thousands of years, the Chu-style lacquer decoration technique has been passed down from generation to generation in Hubei, which was part of the Chu State during the Spring and Autumn Period (770 – 476 B.C.) and the ensuing Warring States Period (475 – 221 B.C.) in ancient China.</p> <p> In 2012, an institute dedicated to passing Jingchu intangible cultural heritage craftsmanship down was established. The institute encompasses workshops dedicated to the protection, inheritance and learning of ICH, as well as the production of relevant products, covering 18 national ICH items, including the Chu-style lacquer decoration technique, and 12 provincial-level items, according to Zhou Jing, director of the intangible cultural heritage protection center of the city.</p> <p> At the institute, people can appreciate exquisite lacquerware items and witness the process for making lacquerware. The institute has served as a platform for ICH demonstration and inheritance, as well as for the production of ICH-related products, with many craftsmen making ICH works there, said Xu Xiaolan, president of the institute.</p> <p> Meanwhile, the institute, affiliated to Changjiang Polytechnic of Art and Engineering, has hired ICH inheritors to teach students, replacing the traditional master-apprentice model with a modern apprenticeship program. In 2013, the polytechnic opened a major related to traditional crafts to cultivate inheritors of ICH items and traditional crafts.</p> <p> The polytechnic has trained close to 1,000 students in this way in recent years, about 200 of whom have started their own businesses or have become partners of the institute.</p> <p> Ma Guangbo, born after 2000, is a student majoring in the Chu-style lacquer decoration technique at the polytechnic. Ma won the first prize for making lacquerware during a national vocational skills competition in 2020.</p> <p> Zou Dexiang, a national-level inheritor of the Chu-style lacquer decoration technique, is also a teacher at the polytechnic. According to Zou, making a piece of lacquerware involves about 20 steps, including choosing the proper materials, carving, polishing, lacquering, and tracing a design in gold. Zou spends about 200 hours teaching students at the polytechnic every year.</p> <p> In 2017, a traditional craft workstation was set up in Jingzhou, aiming to revitalize traditional crafts represented by the Chu-style lacquer decoration technique. By introducing new technologies, designs and academic resources, the workstation has developed its own raw lacquer deep-processing technology, as well as green, cultural and innovative products that combine the lacquer technique with modern life.</p> <p> Two years later, the workstation and the institute built a lacquer culture brand. “Our cultural and innovative products should be both practical and of artistic value,” said Xu.</p> <p> By applying the Chu-style lacquer decoration technique, teachers and students from the institute, ICH inheritors and designers from universities including Tsinghua University have developed a variety of lacquerware products and innovative products with Chu-style cultural elements, including tablewares, tea wares, pens, and decorations.</p> <p> In recent years, the institute has continued to expand its sales channels for ICH-related products. The institute’s annual sales volume for lacquered guqin, a traditional Chinese musical instrument, has reached about 20 million yuan (about $2.95 million), and that of lacquerware and cultural products has hit about 10 million yuan. The institute’s annual volume of orders for customized lacquerware has now approached 20 million yuan.</p> <p> Besides, a whole industry chain that integrates lacquerware making, culture, tourism and lacquer processing has been taking shape in Jingzhou.</p> <p> The institute began to launch experiential courses on handicrafts and lacquer art in 2015, attracting over 50,000 students and tourists each year.</p> <p> The inheritance and development of the traditional lacquer technique has also driven the development of the lacquer tree-planting industry and the raw lacquer processing industry in Hubei. In 2018, the traditional craft workstation established a lacquer tree planting base in the province’s Zhuxi county, Shiyan city. Moreover, the workstation started the construction of a workshop that processes raw lacquer and colored lacquer in Badong county in 2019.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Public-interest library in rural Fujian warms hearts of villagers ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096121</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096121.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:03:14 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Before 7 a.m., a three-story house in Makeng village, Baisha township, Minhou county, Fuzhou city, east China’s Fujian province, is already bustling with people. The house looks just like an ordinary rural house, only it has a library in it.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205130856000556704399540.jpg" style="width: 819px; height: 547px;" /></p> <p> <em>Lin Yuekeng, owner of a public-interest library in Makeng village, Baisha township, Minhou county, Fuzhou city, east China’s Fujian province, arranges books on a bookshelf. (Photo/WeChat account of the publicity department of the Communist Party of China Minhou county committee)</em></p> <p> A sign hanging at the door of the house reads “Baishawan Library”. The sign has faded a bit, but the name of library is well-known to locals.</p> <p> Baishawan Library was started by Lin Lixing, father of a local villager named Lin Yuekeng. In 2011, Lin Lixing visited a library in a neighboring township, and saw villagers read and study there. Deeply inspired by what he saw, he quickly transformed the first floor of his house into the public-interest library after he returned home.</p> <p> As the first library in Baisha township, Baishawan Library has been popular since it opened. According to Lin Yuekeng, visitors crowded the library on its first day.</p> <p> It greatly gratified Lin Lixing, who was in his seventies then, to see that the library was full of students between 12 p.m. and 2 p.m. every day. Taking delight in helping children enjoy books, he was busy working in the library all day and didn’t have time to take a noon break. At night, after the last reader left, he started to rearrange books.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205130857000076457920419.jpg" style="width: 830px; height: 504px;" /></p> <p> <em>Lin Yuekeng (first from right) helps villagers look up information in books. (Photo/WeChat account of the publicity department of the Communist Party of China Minhou county committee)</em></p> <p> In the third year after the opening of the library, Lin Lixing passed away. After his father’s death, Lin Yuekeng hesitated about continuing to run the library. “The library is completely non-profit and requires a lot of manpower and material resources,” explained Lin Yuekeng.</p> <p> But he finally decided to keep it running, considering his fellow villagers’ thirst for knowledge and his father’s last wish.</p> <p> “With this library, we don’t have to go to the urban areas of Fuzhou city to read books or buy books ourselves, because we can read here to increase our knowledge for free,” said Chen Meifang, a villager who is a regular of the library.</p> <p> Now is the busiest time of the year for citrus growers, including Chen. After spraying her fruit trees with pesticide in the morning, Chen, still in her sun hat and muddy shoes and clothes, went straight to the library eagerly. She found a book on green measures to prevent and control citrus diseases and insect pests and started reading.</p> <p> “The book has everything I need to know. For example, what&nbsp;fertilizer should be applied, what pesticide should be used, and what precautions should be taken at each stage, from sprouting and blooming to fruiting, are clearly written in it,” Chen said.</p> <p> In 2006, Chen planted only dozens of mu (one mu equals about 666 square meters) of navel orange trees. As her knowledge of and experience in navel orange tree planting increase, she has become a major grower and an expert in the field in Makeng village.</p> <p> Her “business” could not have flourished so well without Baishawan Library, according to Chen.</p> <p> “I’ll take this book home to read. Could you get me a book on growing peach trees? I got the use right of more than 100 mu of farmlands this year, and I’m going to plant peach trees,” Chen said to Lin Yuekeng.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205130857000240766268772.jpg" style="width: 863px; height: 531px;" /></p> <p> <em>Villagers read at Baishawan Library, a public-interest library run by a local family in Makeng village, Baisha township, Minhou county, Fuzhou city, east China’s Fujian province. (Photo/WeChat account of the publicity department of the Communist Party of China Minhou county committee)</em></p> <p> “No problem. Just come and take it next week,” Lin replied.</p> <p> The library purchases books based on the requirements of residents. Villagers tell the library what books they need, and the library then help get the books for them.</p> <p> Over the past 11 years, the number of bookshelves in the library has increased from one to more than 20, and the number of books has risen from 2,000 to over 30,000 in 18 categories, making the public-interest rural library with the largest collection of books in Minhou county.</p> <p> Almost every family of the nearly 400 households in Makeng village has the phone number of Lin Yuekeng. Villagers give him a call anytime they need new books. Lin works in Baisha township from Monday to Friday. He buys the books his fellow villagers need in the township and takes them to the library every Friday after work.</p> <p> “My trunk is often stuffed with books. Sometimes I also buy books online,” Lin told People’s Daily.</p> <p> Today, besides residents of Makeng village, many construction workers nearby also read and borrow books from Baishawan Library, which has brought knowledge and companionship to nearly 10,000 people living in the three or four surrounding villages.</p> <p> The small library has received support from many people, according to Lin, who disclosed that many villagers and college students living nearby have worked as volunteers in the library, and many people, public institutions, and enterprises have donated books and bookshelves to the library.</p> <p> The popular reading parties and sharing activities held regularly at the library have attracted and benefited many participants.</p> <p> Though the library requires a lot of efforts, Lin and his family will stick to the rewarding cause so as to attract more people to reading, according to him.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Yungang Research Institute strives to create digital versions of grottoes relics ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096103</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096103.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 08:54:53 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/23/5519049531792372607.png" /></p> <p> A technician collects information of relics in Cave 17 of the Yungang Grottoes in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province, May 11, 2022.</p> <p> A group of technicians of the Yungang Research Institute are striving to create digital versions of Cave 17 of the Yungang Grottoes in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province.</p> <p> The institute is dedicated to protection, research and management of the Yungang Grottoes. In recent years, working staff of the institute have been engaged in collecting and digitalizing information of the grottoes relics for the purpose of facilitating digital archives of them.</p> <p> The digitalization of the information is meant to explore new feasible methods of researching on the relics and to keep them in reliable and lasting protection.</p> <p> The Yungang Grottoes, with 45 major caves and more than 59,000 statues, were inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage List in 2001.</p> <p> To date, one-third of the overall information collection and digitalization work has been completed. (Xinhua/Yang Chenguang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/34/3192597354463298450.png" /></p> <p> Technicians collect information of relics in Cave 17 of the Yungang Grottoes in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province, May 11, 2022.</p> <p> A group of technicians of the Yungang Research Institute are striving to create digital versions of Cave 17 of the Yungang Grottoes in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province.</p> <p> The institute is dedicated to protection, research and management of the Yungang Grottoes. In recent years, working staff of the institute have been engaged in collecting and digitalizing information of the grottoes relics for the purpose of facilitating digital archives of them.</p> <p> The digitalization of the information is meant to explore new feasible methods of researching on the relics and to keep them in reliable and lasting protection.</p> <p> The Yungang Grottoes, with 45 major caves and more than 59,000 statues, were inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage List in 2001.</p> <p> To date, one-third of the overall information collection and digitalization work has been completed. (Xinhua/Yang Chenguang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/19/3748680326435585607.png" /></p> <p> A technician collects information of relics in Cave 17 of the Yungang Grottoes in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province, May 11, 2022.</p> <p> A group of technicians of the Yungang Research Institute are striving to create digital versions of Cave 17 of the Yungang Grottoes in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province.</p> <p> The institute is dedicated to protection, research and management of the Yungang Grottoes. In recent years, working staff of the institute have been engaged in collecting and digitalizing information of the grottoes relics for the purpose of facilitating digital archives of them.</p> <p> The digitalization of the information is meant to explore new feasible methods of researching on the relics and to keep them in reliable and lasting protection.</p> <p> The Yungang Grottoes, with 45 major caves and more than 59,000 statues, were inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage List in 2001.</p> <p> To date, one-third of the overall information collection and digitalization work has been completed. (Xinhua/Yang Chenguang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/77/5867781412283020985.png" /></p> <p> A staff member restores the wall of Cave 1 of the Yungang Grottoes in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province, May 11, 2022.</p> <p> A group of technicians of the Yungang Research Institute are striving to create digital versions of Cave 17 of the Yungang Grottoes in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province.</p> <p> The institute is dedicated to protection, research and management of the Yungang Grottoes. In recent years, working staff of the institute have been engaged in collecting and digitalizing information of the grottoes relics for the purpose of facilitating digital archives of them.</p> <p> The digitalization of the information is meant to explore new feasible methods of researching on the relics and to keep them in reliable and lasting protection.</p> <p> The Yungang Grottoes, with 45 major caves and more than 59,000 statues, were inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage List in 2001.</p> <p> To date, one-third of the overall information collection and digitalization work has been completed. (Xinhua/Yang Chenguang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/64/13149116187307958324.png" /></p> <p> A staff member restores the wall of Cave 1 of the Yungang Grottoes in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province, May 11, 2022.</p> <p> A group of technicians of the Yungang Research Institute are striving to create digital versions of Cave 17 of the Yungang Grottoes in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province.</p> <p> The institute is dedicated to protection, research and management of the Yungang Grottoes. In recent years, working staff of the institute have been engaged in collecting and digitalizing information of the grottoes relics for the purpose of facilitating digital archives of them.</p> <p> The digitalization of the information is meant to explore new feasible methods of researching on the relics and to keep them in reliable and lasting protection.</p> <p> The Yungang Grottoes, with 45 major caves and more than 59,000 statues, were inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage List in 2001.</p> <p> To date, one-third of the overall information collection and digitalization work has been completed. (Xinhua/Yang Chenguang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/63/12890320510005571079.png" /></p> <p> Technicians collect information of relics in Cave 17 of the Yungang Grottoes in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province, May 11, 2022.</p> <p> A group of technicians of the Yungang Research Institute are striving to create digital versions of Cave 17 of the Yungang Grottoes in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province.</p> <p> The institute is dedicated to protection, research and management of the Yungang Grottoes. In recent years, working staff of the institute have been engaged in collecting and digitalizing information of the grottoes relics for the purpose of facilitating digital archives of them.</p> <p> The digitalization of the information is meant to explore new feasible methods of researching on the relics and to keep them in reliable and lasting protection.</p> <p> The Yungang Grottoes, with 45 major caves and more than 59,000 statues, were inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage List in 2001.</p> <p> To date, one-third of the overall information collection and digitalization work has been completed. (Xinhua/Yang Chenguang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/80/6405798170017520336.png" /></p> <p> A three-dimensional image of a Buddha statue in Cave 17 of the Yungang Grottoes is seen on a screen in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province, May 11, 2022.</p> <p> A group of technicians of the Yungang Research Institute are striving to create digital versions of Cave 17 of the Yungang Grottoes in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province.</p> <p> The institute is dedicated to protection, research and management of the Yungang Grottoes. In recent years, working staff of the institute have been engaged in collecting and digitalizing information of the grottoes relics for the purpose of facilitating digital archives of them.</p> <p> The digitalization of the information is meant to explore new feasible methods of researching on the relics and to keep them in reliable and lasting protection.</p> <p> The Yungang Grottoes, with 45 major caves and more than 59,000 statues, were inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage List in 2001.</p> <p> To date, one-third of the overall information collection and digitalization work has been completed. (Xinhua/Yang Chenguang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/15/18223314236066472183.png" /></p> <p> Technicians collect information of relics in Cave 17 of the Yungang Grottoes in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province, May 11, 2022.</p> <p> A group of technicians of the Yungang Research Institute are striving to collect digital data of Cave 17 of the Yungang Grottoes in Datong.</p> <p> The institute is dedicated to protection, research and management of the Yungang Grottoes. In recent years, staff of the institute have been engaged in collecting and digitalizing information of the grottoes relics for the purpose of facilitating digital archives of them.</p> <p> The digitalization of the information is meant to explore new feasible methods of researching on the relics and to keep them in reliable and lasting protection.</p> <p> The Yungang Grottoes, with 45 major caves and more than 59,000 statues, were inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage List in 2001.</p> <p> To date, one-third of the overall information collection and digitalization work has been completed. (Xinhua/Yang Chenguang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/20/8670864922091044880.png" /></p> <p> People visit the Yungang Grottoes in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province, May 11, 2022.</p> <p> A group of technicians of the Yungang Research Institute are striving to create digital versions of Cave 17 of the Yungang Grottoes in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province.</p> <p> The institute is dedicated to protection, research and management of the Yungang Grottoes. In recent years, working staff of the institute have been engaged in collecting and digitalizing information of the grottoes relics for the purpose of facilitating digital archives of them.</p> <p> The digitalization of the information is meant to explore new feasible methods of researching on the relics and to keep them in reliable and lasting protection.</p> <p> The Yungang Grottoes, with 45 major caves and more than 59,000 statues, were inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage List in 2001.</p> <p> To date, one-third of the overall information collection and digitalization work has been completed. (Xinhua/Yang Chenguang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/74/7814816880205351098.png" /></p> <p> A technician collects information of relics in Cave 17 of the Yungang Grottoes in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province, May 11, 2022.</p> <p> A group of technicians of the Yungang Research Institute are striving to create digital versions of Cave 17 of the Yungang Grottoes in Datong, north China's Shanxi Province.</p> <p> The institute is dedicated to protection, research and management of the Yungang Grottoes. In recent years, working staff of the institute have been engaged in collecting and digitalizing information of the grottoes relics for the purpose of facilitating digital archives of them.</p> <p> The digitalization of the information is meant to explore new feasible methods of researching on the relics and to keep them in reliable and lasting protection.</p> <p> The Yungang Grottoes, with 45 major caves and more than 59,000 statues, were inscribed on the UNESCO World Heritage List in 2001.</p> <p> To date, one-third of the overall information collection and digitalization work has been completed. (Xinhua/Yang Chenguang)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Exhibition featured Bronze Age civilization held in SE China ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096043</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096043.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 08:19:30 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/16/17096544475901618100.png" /></p> <p> An exhibit is displayed at an exhibition named "Share the Same River: Bronze Age Civilization in the Yangtze River Valley" at Fujian Museum in Fuzhou City, southeast China's Fujian Province, May 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Wei Peiquan)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/56/15217422338653539108.png" /></p> <p> An exhibit is displayed at an exhibition named "Share the Same River: Bronze Age Civilization in the Yangtze River Valley" at Fujian Museum in Fuzhou City, southeast China's Fujian Province, May 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Wei Peiquan)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/73/10341953392024235717.png" /></p> <p> Visitors take photos of exhibits at an exhibition named "Share the Same River: Bronze Age Civilization in the Yangtze River Valley" at Fujian Museum in Fuzhou City, southeast China's Fujian Province, May 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Wei Peiquan)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/18/17583191173004033346.png" /></p> <p> Visitors view an exhibit at an exhibition named "Share the Same River: Bronze Age Civilization in the Yangtze River Valley" at Fujian Museum in Fuzhou City, southeast China's Fujian Province, May 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Wei Peiquan)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Influencer revives Tang Dynasty beauty ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095812</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095812.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 15:17:23 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <center> <video controls="controls" poster=" http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/5/12/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_67a8452c6b907983f649336c0eeaa355.jpeg" src=" http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/5/12/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_d53b681a2928b2caecd90328204a9620.mp4" style=" width: 830px; height:550px;"> <p> &nbsp;</p> </video> </center> <p> Wang Yu achieved internet fame dressing up as the legendary Tang Dynasty beauty Yang Guifei at a cultural block in Xi'an, Northwest China's Shaanxi Province.</p> <p> Wang, 28, said she was once the victim of body shaming. Few knew her shape was the side effect of her medication.</p> <p> "It's the most wonderful thing in the world to be recognized for what you do," Wang said of her dressing up.</p> <p> <em>(Produced by Teng Jiade and Bai Yujie)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily App</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Archaeology museum offers public closer look at history ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095535</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095535.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:22:03 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/1/1010773458817893861.png" /></p> <p> A visitor takes photos of an exhibit at the Shaanxi Archaeology Museum in Xi'an, northwest China's Shaanxi Province, April 28, 2022. (Xinhua/Li Yibo)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/48/13874049922462050456.png" /></p> <p> People visit the Shaanxi Archaeology Museum in Xi'an, northwest China's Shaanxi Province, April 28, 2022. (Xinhua/Li Yibo)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/72/6909751993241059056.png" /></p> <p> People view a mobile lab in the Shaanxi Archaeology Museum in Xi'an, northwest China's Shaanxi Province, April 28, 2022. (Xinhua/Li Yibo)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Ancient port city in Guangxi rebranded based on its contribution to historical Maritime Silk Road ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095371</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095371.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 17:41:55 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205111703000077260463039.jpeg" style="width: 850px; height: 566px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo shows an exhibit displayed at the Hepu Han Dynasty Museum in Beihai City, southwest China’s Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region. (People's Daily Online/Qin Xin)</em></p> <p> An ancient port located in Hepu county of Beihai, southwest China’s Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, is one of the three ports of departure for the Maritime Silk Road, which dates back to the Han Dynasty (202 BC – 220 AD).</p> <p> The port city has been a place known for its burgeoning traffic and thriving businesses throughout Chinese history. Its prosperity is recorded in over 20,000 relics, 1,300 antiques and 1,200 ancient tombs discovered in the locality.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205111703000555637398678.jpeg" style="width: 850px; height: 566px;" /></p> <p> <em>A visitor looks at exhibits at the Hepu Han Dynasty Museum in Beihai City, southwest China’s Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region. (Photo/Courtesy of Publicity Department of the Beihai Municipal Committee)</em></p> <p> The Hepu Han Dynasty Museum in Beihai City collects and studies the excavated artefacts and local heirlooms, ranging across a large variety and covering different eras.</p> <p> The museum has since gone online as well. Nowadays, citizens can fully appreciate the delicate beauty of 362 exhibits and 41 highlights in the display, just by visiting its official platform on WeChat, a commonly used social media app in China.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205111705000296867516368.jpeg" style="width: 850px; height: 566px;" /></p> <p> <em>A visitor takes photos of an exhibit at the Hepu Han Dynasty Museum in Beihai City,&nbsp;southwest China’s Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region. (People's Daily Online/Qin Xin)</em></p> <p> Visitors can not only learn about the inherited culture of the Maritime Silk Road, but can also dive into the local history of the city as well, as one local citizen commented.</p> <p> Over the years, Beihai City has worked towards building a distinctive style of tourism, all by tapping into its profound cultural heritage based on the Maritime Silk Road, local fishing customs and its pearl business. Seaside resorts, leisure cruise marinas and tourist towns have flourished and fueled the local tourism industry.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205111704000365459697820.jpeg" style="width: 850px; height: 566px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>During the nights, an interactive show can be seen performed on stage along the seaside. (People's Daily Online/Qin Xin)</em></p> <p> During the nights, an interactive show can be seen performed on stage along the seaside, which tells the story of a pearl fisher’s life and the emergence of the Maritime Silk Road in historical times. More than 100 actors have fully committed themselves to the performance, inviting audiences from near and far to participate in a vivid dialogue with the locality’s own ancient history.&nbsp;</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205111704000495152890539.jpeg" style="width: 850px; height: 566px;" /></p> <p> <em>Actors have fully committed themselves to the performance, inviting audiences from near and far to participate in a vivid dialogue with the locality’s own ancient history. (Photo/Courtesy of Publicity Department of the Beihai Municipal Committee)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's Palace Museum to be closed temporarily over COVID-19 ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095347</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095347.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 17:12:57 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- China's Palace Museum, also known as the Forbidden City, will be temporarily closed from Thursday, the museum said Wednesday.</p> <p> The move is based on Beijing's current COVID-19 situation and aims to further reduce the risk of virus transmission caused by the movement of people.</p> <p> The closure will last until further notice, the museum said.</p> <p> A total of 302 confirmed local COVID-19 cases were reported on the Chinese mainland on Tuesday, of which 24 were in Beijing, new data showed.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Traditional Chinese Medicine: What You Need To Know ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095260</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095260.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 15:46:09 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/6/2072633731137404126.jpg" /></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Ecns.cn</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Miniature models: A tiny recreation of the real world ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095249</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095249.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 15:39:59 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <center> <video controls="controls" poster=" http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/5/11/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_0b17fb481885f2ad442269f94c675c45.png" src=" http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/5/11/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_61bfa369a72e6c1dd5b65004a470b50f.mp4" style=" width: 830px; height:550px;"> <p> &nbsp;</p> </video> </center> <p> A simple and warm countryside courtyard home or the mysterious and spectacular Loulan ancient city… Both can be restored by a creator of models through a pair of skillful hands. Even details down to a small tree or a string of red peppers are presented. Let's take a look at the exquisite works of modelers!</p> <p> <em>(Compiled by Liang Yuting)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily App</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Gen Z performer livestreams Peking Opera ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095223</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095223.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 15:17:33 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <center> <video controls="controls" poster=" http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/5/11/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_b3fac841b450cddb13b271fdb5388981.jpg" src=" http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/5/11/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_937d5dbf90a581801633343f4e696b9f.mp4" style=" width: 830px; height:550px;"> <p> &nbsp;</p> </video> </center> <p style="margin: 0px 0px 20px; padding: 0px; border: 0px; font-size: 18px; vertical-align: baseline; box-sizing: border-box; line-height: 25px; max-width: 100%;"> Peking Opera artist Guo Yu'ang, a member of Generation Z, shares his love for traditional opera through livestreaming every day.<br style="box-sizing: border-box; color: rgb(51, 51, 51); font-family: HelveticaNeue, Helvetica, HelveticaNeue-new; font-size: 18px; font-style: normal; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; font-weight: 400; letter-spacing: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: start; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; text-decoration-thickness: initial; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial;" /> &nbsp;</p> <p> &nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily App</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Hong Kong Palace Museum ready to open ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095129</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095129.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 11:12:39 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/18/12459005438616570298.jpg" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 10, 2022 shows the Hong Kong Palace Museum during a media preview, the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. Located in the west Kowloon cultural district, the construction is almost completed and expected to open this summer. (Photo: China News Service/Li Zhihua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/11/9140431734412154499.jpg" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 10, 2022 shows an interior view of the completed main structure of the Hong Kong Palace Museum building, the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. (Photo: China News Service/Li Zhihua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/28/4765254158773540160.jpg" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 10, 2022 shows an exterior view of the Hong Kong Palace Museum, the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. (Photo: China News Service/Li Zhihua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/81/12787196405934200105.jpg" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 10, 2022 shows the atrium ceiling comprised of 3D, curved, and perforated aluminum tiles at the Hong Kong Palace Museum, the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. (Photo: China News Service/Li Zhihua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/9/13098454252694808773.jpg" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 10, 2022 shows the Hong Kong Palace Museum during a media preview, the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. (Photo: China News Service/Li Zhihua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/27/8925549286365561287.jpg" /></p> <p> Journalists take photo during a media preview at the Hong Kong Palace Museum, the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. (Photo: China News Service/Li Zhihua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/22/10446763701951159758.jpg" /></p> <p> A journalist takes photo during a media preview at the Hong Kong Palace Museum, the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. (Photo: China News Service/Li Zhihua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Ecns.cn</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese museums, galleries regale netizens with cultural feast through online exhibitions ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094699</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094699.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 16:10:18 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0510/FOREIGN202205101545000112119040142.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>A staff member of the&nbsp;Yungang Grottoes Research Institute collects data in&nbsp;Yungang Grottoes in Datong, Shanxi Province. (Photo/Xinhua)&nbsp;</em></p> <p> Chinese museums and galleries have accelerated their digital transformation and have rolled out online exhibitions through the application of digital technologies while exploring innovative ways to display their exhibits, regaling visitors with a cultural feast both online and offline.</p> <p> An exhibition featuring about 1,000 ancient female-themed paintings from 32 museums across China was held both offline and online at the Zhejiang Provincial Museum in Hangzhou, capital city of east China’s Zhejiang Province between March 8 and May 8. The museum encouraged Internet users to post photos of themselves wearing traditional Chinese clothes on social media platforms such as Weibo and Xiaohongshu, engaging in active interactions with them online.</p> <p> “You can tour the digital exhibition hall and find the traditional clothes you like,” a netizen commented.</p> <p> Chinese museums have also offered online services such as online courses so that visitors can learn more about cultural relics. For example, a guide of the Shanghai Museum took visitors on a virtual tour of the museum’s exhibition of 100 donated cultural relics, through which they could not only enjoy these relics but also learn about the historical and the cultural connotations behind them.</p> <p> Digital technologies bring cultural relics back to life virtually. With the help of virtual reality (VR) devices, people now can virtually visit the Yungang Grottoes in Datong city, north China’s Shanxi Province, a UNESCO World Cultural Heritage site.</p> <p> Besides, the Yungang Grottoes Research Institute has cooperated with universities including Zhejiang University in Zhejiang and Wuhan University in central China’s Hubei Province to bring the cultural relics of the grottoes to a wider audience by applying 3D printing technology and VR technology.</p> <p> Online exhibitions will be able to free cultural relics housed at museums from constraints based on time and space, while providing added convenience for attracting more viewers, according to Wang Yanlong, director of the center for cultural communication studies of Sichuan University in Chengdu, capital of southwest China’s Sichuan Province.</p> <p> Internet technologies have brought a tremendous change to art exhibitions, bringing high-definition, three-dimensional, and interactive experiences for people, said Yu Kailiang, a professor at the School of Philosophy at Renmin University of China.</p> <p> China has rolled out measures to encourage more online exhibitions. According to a plan for the development of culture and tourism between 2021 and 2025 released by the Ministry of Culture and Tourism in April 2021, China intends to continually promote the digital transformation of art galleries and online exhibitions.</p> <p> One month later, nine government authorities that included the Ministry of Science and Technology issued a guideline to advance the reform and development of museums, encouraging online exhibitions and cooperation among museums.</p> <p> China will boost the development of online digital products for scenic spots and museums and develop new cultural and tourism services such as online exhibitions and immersive experiences, according to a plan issued by China’s State Council in December 2021 to facilitate the development of the digital economy during the 14th Five-Year Plan period (2021-2025).&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Man from Hebei carves pencil tip into art works ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094668</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094668.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 15:06:13 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <center> <video controls="controls" poster=" http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/5/10/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_453a5cd81dc649c32b6dd6cc7f148697.jpg" src="http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/5/10/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_01ff5d9f8044c522c1f728b2ccb1fc4a.mp4" style=" width: 830px; height:550px;"> <p> &nbsp;</p> </video> </center> <p> Li Mingjun, from Laishui of Hebei Province, likes to create microscopic carvings on pencil lead in his leisure time. With a diameter of three to five millimeters, pencil lead is turned into exquisite art works in Li’s hands.</p> <p> <em>(Video source: Kuaishou)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily App</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese culture show staged in Ghana university to boost friendly ties ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094080</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0509/c90000-10094080.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 14:15:11 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> ACCRA, May 8 (Xinhua) -- The Confucius Institute at the University of Ghana on Sunday staged a Chinese culture show to the Ghanaian audience to promote cultural links between the two peoples.</p> <p> Some students and staffers of the Confucius Institute put up performances, including sword dance, Sichuan Opera and Chinese songs.</p> <p> The institute also organized some games such as using Chinese chopsticks to pick up beans. Those who won the games received Chinese knots as rewards.</p> <p> Chu Beijuan, the Chinese dean of the Confucius Institute, said the event was part of the efforts to deepen the friendly ties between China and Ghana.</p> <p> "We will include calligraphy, martial arts, and other forms of Chinese culture in our Chinese language courses, because we want more people to understand the Chinese language and culture," she added.</p> <p> Henry Nii Adjiri Quarcoopome, a student from the Confucius Institute at the University of Ghana, told Xinhua that learning Chinese has become an imperative for students who seek employment in the labor market after school.</p> <p> "Gradually, we will be interacting with Chinese people for our construction and other economic activities," Quarcoopome said.</p> <p> Pascalina Arthur, another student, said the Confucius Institute has been bridging the cultural gap between Ghana and China.</p> <p> "The friendly attitude of the Chinese language teachers deepens the interest of students in the language and makes them develop a love for the Chinese language," she said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Highlights of Fashion Art Toronto ]]></title>
	<news_id>10093991</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0509/c90000-10093991.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 11:26:34 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220509/65/15807986356343442313.png" /></p> <p> A model presents a creation of Flors Fashion during the Fashion Art Toronto in Toronto, Canada, on May 8, 2022. (Photo by Zou Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220509/86/5077071478280722106.png" /></p> <p> A model presents a creation of Kohmontreal By. Juan Iskandar during the Fashion Art Toronto in Toronto, Canada, on May 8, 2022. (Photo by Zou Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220509/12/11186383714811501332.png" /></p> <p> A model presents a creation of Kohmontreal By. Juan Iskandar during the Fashion Art Toronto in Toronto, Canada, on May 8, 2022. (Photo by Zou Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220509/57/16776460764678952725.png" /></p> <p> A model presents a creation of Kohmontreal By. Juan Iskandar during the Fashion Art Toronto in Toronto, Canada, on May 8, 2022. (Photo by Zou Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Qichun-- Hometown of Li Shizhen ]]></title>
	<news_id>10093849</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0509/c90000-10093849.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 09:01:49 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220509/1/548911384993857537.jpg" /></p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220509/45/14265344357392458613.jpg" /></p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220509/37/2282249456933914097.jpg" /></p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220509/80/2029180442043126228.jpg" /></p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220509/58/9793649412026575374.jpg" /></p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220509/30/11079873619879513706.jpg" /></p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220509/23/1087274405920071327.jpg" /></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Ecns.cn</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Archaeology museum offers public closer look at history ]]></title>
	<news_id>10093745</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0508/c90000-10093745.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 18:19:13 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> 　　XI'AN, May 2 (Xinhua) -- Yang Bin, a university student in northwest China's Shaanxi Province, didn't expect that he could touch the fragments of prehistoric pottery displayed in a museum.</p> <p> 　　Visitors, including Yang, to the newly opened Shaanxi Archaeology Museum, located in Xi'an, the capital of Shaanxi, were amazed by the different experiences of feeling the texture of actual cultural relics like archaeologists.</p> <p> 　　Featuring China's modern archaeology, the museum is built based on achievements of field archaeological excavation projects and research on relic preservation technologies made by the Shaanxi Academy of Archaeology over the past six decades.</p> <p> 　　The museum provides visitors a glimpse of technology-assisted archaeological work via the restoration of excavation sites, carefully-placed interpretations, and interactive devices. It offers a closer look at these treasures and a deeper understanding of history.</p> <p> 　　Among the over 5,200 pieces of relics on display, most are exhibited to the public for the first time.</p> <p> 　　An exquisite headgear dating to the Tang Dynasty (618-907) decorated with gold, silver, pearls, and jade has hogged the limelight. It is the first headgear in that dynasty successfully restored in China.</p> <p> 　　Next to it, four pictures show the scenes when it was first discovered. The headgear was scattered beside a skeleton and broken into hundreds of pieces overlaid with each other. Archaeologists brought them all into the laboratory.</p> <p> 　　With the help of micrographs, archaeologists located the original position of each fragment and restored them layer by layer. The whole process is elaborated to visitors in words and pictures. Excavation tools and a microscope for the restored headgear are also on display.</p> <p> 　　This headgear is also the first to be restored through laboratory microscopic technologies in China.</p> <p> 　　Another eye-catching exhibit is a bronze chariot dating from the Western Zhou Dynasty (1046-771 B.C.).</p> <p> 　　Unearthed in the Zhouyuan site, Baoji City, the bronze chariot was a luxurious vehicle for dignitaries. The wheels are bronze, and the carriage is decorated with hundreds of bronze components inlaid with turquoise.</p> <p> 　　Archaeologists "packaged" the whole excavation site to the laboratory and spent three years cleaning and restoring the chariot. The entire site is now on display in the museum.</p> <p> 　　"3D models, touch screens, and other interactive devices in the museum can demonstrate extensive information about the archaeological research, the history, and the arduous work done by archaeologists," said Hu Xiaoyu, director of the exhibition department of the museum.</p> <p> 　　"The museum gathers archaeological excavations, relics preservation, exhibitions, and public education together to offer the public a closer look at archaeological research and our achievements in the field," said Sun Zhouyong, curator of the museum.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Giant karst sinkhole discovered in China's Guangxi ]]></title>
	<news_id>10093743</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0508/c90000-10093743.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 18:18:44 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/77/7544388819329017061.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>　　Aerial Photo taken on April 19, 2020 shows a Tiankeng, or giant karst sinkhole, at Leye-Fengshan Global Geopark, south China's Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region. (Xinhua/Zhou Hua)</em></p> <p> 　　NANNING, May 7 (Xinhua) -- A cave exploration team has discovered a giant karst sinkhole in Leye County, south China's Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, bringing Leye's number of such sinkholes to 30.</p> <p> 　　Zhang Yuanhai, a senior engineer with the Institute of Karst Geology of China Geological Survey, said the sinkhole, located near Ping'e village under Luoxi township, measures 306 m in length, 150 m in width and 192 m in depth, with its volume exceeding 5 million cubic meters, and can be categorized as a large sinkhole.</p> <p> 　　Zhang said that there are three big caves in the wall, which are presumed to be the remains of the early evolution of the sinkhole. The bottom of the sinkhole has a well-preserved primitive forest.</p> <p> 　　Chen Lixin, leader of the Guangxi 702 cave expedition team, said the ancient trees growing at the bottom are nearly 40 meters high, and the dense shade plants are up to one's shoulders.</p> <p> 　　The expedition was completed on Friday, after the team members abseiled down more than 100 meters and trekked several hours to reach the pit's bottom. They returned to the ground safely on Friday evening.</p> <p> 　　Giant sinkholes, also known as Tiankeng (heavenly pit) in Chinese, are dolines, or giant pits, with special geological features found in karst regions formed by repeated cave-ins. They are mainly found in China, Mexico and Papua New Guinea.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China calls for more efforts to protect revolutionary cultural relics ]]></title>
	<news_id>10093747</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0508/c90000-10093747.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 18:18:18 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> 　　BEIJING, May 3 (Xinhua) -- China has issued a circular calling for various departments and localities across the country to enhance efforts to protect revolutionary cultural relics, according to the National Cultural Heritage Administration.</p> <p> 　　The circular, jointly released by the administration and the Publicity Department of the Communist Party of China Central Committee, noted that revolutionary cultural relics are precious wealth of the Party and the country.</p> <p> 　　Localities need to systematically comb through cultural relics resources and include those qualified on the list of revolutionary cultural relics, the circular said.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ People enjoy food at Athens Street Food Festival ]]></title>
	<news_id>10093700</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0508/c90000-10093700.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 16:04:47 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/87/10576190308191887703.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　An employee shows a sandwich at the Athens Street Food Festival in Athens, Greece, on May 7, 2022. (Xinhua/Marios Lolos)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/21/13794185862707846229.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　People take part in the Athens Street Food Festival in Athens, Greece, on May 7, 2022. (Xinhua/Marios Lolos)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/25/10133377534313068673.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　An employee prepares food at the Athens Street Food Festival in Athens, Greece, on May 7, 2022. (Xinhua/Marios Lolos)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/15/5235248548027460759.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　A visitor takes her oder at the Athens Street Food Festival in Athens, Greece, on May 7, 2022. (Xinhua/Marios Lolos)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/33/3937103742688079041.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　People enjoy food at the Athens Street Food Festival in Athens, Greece, on May 7, 2022. (Xinhua/Marios Lolos)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/93/12422331531678753209.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　A woman enjoys food at the Athens Street Food Festival in Athens, Greece, on May 7, 2022. (Xinhua/Marios Lolos)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China-aided borehole project boosts water access in eastern Rwanda ]]></title>
	<news_id>10093644</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0507/c90000-10093644.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 17:06:50 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220507/28/15142840903750254452.png" /></p> <p> <em>Chinese staff members check the water quality of a borehole in Gatsibo district, Eastern Province, Rwanda, on April 11, 2022. (Photo by Huang Wanqing/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> KIGALI, May 6 (Xinhua) -- Thousands of residents in eastern Rwanda once did not have easy access to clean and safe water due to recurrent drought.</p> <p> In the Rwinkwavu area in Kayonza district, Eastern Province, for instance, residents were forced to walk long distances to reach the nearest clean water source.</p> <p> Water woes are now a thing of the past, thanks to a China-funded 200-borehole drilling project mostly focused on addressing water scarcity in the province. The drilling project, contracted by construction and engineering giant China Geo-Engineering Corporation (CGC), has been tested and commissioned following its recent completion, benefiting 110,000 people.</p> <p> Residents in several districts in the province said in separate interviews with Xinhua that potable water needs are no longer a problem in their localities.</p> <p> Residents in the above-mentioned Rwinkwavu area in Kayonza district, Eastern Province, now have access to a solar-powered borehole, which provides clean and safe water.</p> <p> At GS Rwinkwavu school, also one of the beneficiaries, administrators said the newly installed borehole will help them achieve their education goals.</p> <p> "This project came at the right time to address a serious water problem. Besides being free, the water flows easily unlike the hand borehole. It has helped students as well as teachers and neighbors. We are excited about it," said Magnifique Habimana, the head teacher of GS Rwinkwavu.</p> <p> He recalled that bathing, washing clothes and general hygiene maintenance were challenging at school before the solar-driven borehole was drilled.</p> <p> "It was a very big inconvenience to the school in terms of sanitation and running costs," said Habimana. "Our only option was to hire people to fetch water for cooking and drinking. But this was not sustainable, it was a costly option."</p> <p> The school's sanitation and hygiene standards have now improved with the new water source, which has a designed capacity of serving 600 people, said Habimana. "We thank the Chinese government for maintaining cooperation with Rwanda which enabled the implementation of this water project. With this water, we can do farming activities for all seasons because we have water to irrigate the crops."</p> <p> Prosper Manikuze, the standards and quality control specialist in Rwanda's Water and Sanitation Corporation (WASAC), who has closely followed the project, said the contractors have delivered quality work.</p> <p> "I appreciate the quality of this project because the contractors took an initiative to install standard borehole handles and heads. The mixing of cement ratio was also good for concrete works. It was built with strong materials," he said.</p> <p> Manikuze said GS Rwinkwavu previously had no water as a manual borehole in place was not functional, but even though it was working it would not satisfy the high water demand. "With the solar-powered borehole facility at the school, there will be no students missing school anymore to go and fetch water which we hope will boost education standards," he said.</p> <p> Clarisse Uwera, a resident of Murambi in Gatsibo district, also in East Province, said getting water for drinking, cooking and washing clothes at her home has been eased. "Before it was a challenge. The newly installed water source benefits many people, about 300 people in this village. I'm very thankful to have access to this borehole. There is no need to worry anymore about water."</p> <p> Jean Damascene Harelimana, the vice mayor of Kayonza district in charge of social affairs, said the newly installed boreholes will positively impact the health and wellbeing of many people.</p> <p> "We are all happy about the water project. We are also happy about the cooperation of Rwanda and China which leads to an extension of services to people," he said.</p> <p> Lack of access to clean water increases the risk of outbreaks of waterborne disease, including acute watery diarrhea and diseases such as cholera.</p> <p> Diarrheal disease, often caused by bacteria ingested through contaminated food or water, is the second leading cause of death in children under five, according to the World Health Organization (WHO).</p> <p> Chen Jinke, the manager of the Chinese borehole drilling project, said the boreholes are well protected and the impact is good.</p> <p> The wells are installed with chlorination systems to keep the water clean and ready to drink, and solar wells are built in places with a high concentration of people such as markets and schools, according to Chen.</p> <p> "The boreholes using solar energy are good since Rwanda has good sunshine intensity which can meet the conditions of using solar wells. Compared with the manual system, the solar borehole can ensure reliable water supply to the surrounding villages," he explained.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220507/87/1631801105474860283.png" /></p> <p> Reisdents fetch water from a borehole in Gatsibo district, Eastern Province, Rwanda, on April 11, 2022. Thousands of residents in eastern Rwanda once did not have easy access to clean and safe water due to recurrent drought. In the Rwinkwavu area in Kayonza district, Eastern Province, for instance, residents were forced to walk long distances to reach the nearest clean water source. Water woes are now a thing of the past, thanks to a China-funded 200-borehole drilling project mostly focused on addressing water scarcity in the province. The drilling project, contracted by construction and engineering giant China Geo-Engineering Corporation (CGC), has been tested and commissioned following its recent completion, benefiting 110,000 people. (Photo by Huang Wanqing/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220507/87/14757671766435509723.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on April 28, 2022 shows a solar powered borehole in Kayonza district, Eastern Province, Rwanda. Thousands of residents in eastern Rwanda once did not have easy access to clean and safe water due to recurrent drought. In the Rwinkwavu area in Kayonza district, Eastern Province, for instance, residents were forced to walk long distances to reach the nearest clean water source. Water woes are now a thing of the past, thanks to a China-funded 200-borehole drilling project mostly focused on addressing water scarcity in the province. The drilling project, contracted by construction and engineering giant China Geo-Engineering Corporation (CGC), has been tested and commissioned following its recent completion, benefiting 110,000 people. (Photo by Huang Wanqing/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220507/64/915060240706464308.png" /></p> <p> Students fetch water from a solar powered borehole in Kayonza district, Eastern Province, Rwanda, on April 28, 2022. Thousands of residents in eastern Rwanda once did not have easy access to clean and safe water due to recurrent drought. In the Rwinkwavu area in Kayonza district, Eastern Province, for instance, residents were forced to walk long distances to reach the nearest clean water source. Water woes are now a thing of the past, thanks to a China-funded 200-borehole drilling project mostly focused on addressing water scarcity in the province. The drilling project, contracted by construction and engineering giant China Geo-Engineering Corporation (CGC), has been tested and commissioned following its recent completion, benefiting 110,000 people. (Photo by Huang Wanqing/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220507/80/6750749596808612788.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on April 28, 2022 shows a solar panel of a solar powered borehole in Kayonza district, Eastern Province, Rwanda. Thousands of residents in eastern Rwanda once did not have easy access to clean and safe water due to recurrent drought. In the Rwinkwavu area in Kayonza district, Eastern Province, for instance, residents were forced to walk long distances to reach the nearest clean water source. Water woes are now a thing of the past, thanks to a China-funded 200-borehole drilling project mostly focused on addressing water scarcity in the province. The drilling project, contracted by construction and engineering giant China Geo-Engineering Corporation (CGC), has been tested and commissioned following its recent completion, benefiting 110,000 people. (Photo by Huang Wanqing/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ People visit "L.A. Underwater" exhibition in Los Angeles ]]></title>
	<news_id>10093641</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0507/c90000-10093641.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 17:05:09 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220507/77/18249805334892498789.png" /></p> <p> A boy visits "L.A. Underwater" exhibition at the Natural History Museum in Los Angeles, the United States, on May 6, 2022. An exhibition opened this week at the Natural History Museum (NHM) of Los Angeles County, in the western U.S. state of California, uncovering the city's submerged prehistory through fossils. (Photo by Zeng Hui/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220507/28/6334500057400151228.png" /></p> <p> People visit "L.A. Underwater" exhibition at the Natural History Museum in Los Angeles, the United States, on May 6, 2022. An exhibition opened this week at the Natural History Museum (NHM) of Los Angeles County, in the western U.S. state of California, uncovering the city's submerged prehistory through fossils. (Photo by Zeng Hui/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220507/95/2410679353840694695.png" /></p> <p> People visit "L.A. Underwater" exhibition at the Natural History Museum in Los Angeles, the United States, on May 6, 2022. An exhibition opened this week at the Natural History Museum (NHM) of Los Angeles County, in the western U.S. state of California, uncovering the city's submerged prehistory through fossils. (Photo by Zeng Hui/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220507/47/7255204188461473903.png" /></p> <p> People visit "L.A. Underwater" exhibition at the Natural History Museum in Los Angeles, the United States, on May 6, 2022. An exhibition opened this week at the Natural History Museum (NHM) of Los Angeles County, in the western U.S. state of California, uncovering the city's submerged prehistory through fossils. (Photo by Zeng Hui/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ BiH capital marks 50th anniversary of its cult WWII movie ]]></title>
	<news_id>10093609</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0507/c90000-10093609.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 16:46:07 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220507/11/16664229806675630307.png" /></p> <p> <em>A couple sitting in a car watch the movie Valter (Walter) Defends Sarajevo at a drive-in movie theatre in Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina (BiH) on May 6, 2022. Bosnian capital Sarajevo made its cult WWII movie Valter (Walter) Defends Sarajevo back to audience by organizing a free screening in a drive-in movie theatre on Friday, a move marking the 50th anniversary of this once worldwide popular movie. (Photo by Nedim Grabovica/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> SARAJEVO, May 7 (Xinhua) -- Bosnian capital Sarajevo made its cult WWII movie Valter (Walter) Defends Sarajevo back to audience by organizing a free screening in a drive-in movie theatre on Friday, a move marking the 50th anniversary of this once worldwide popular movie.</p> <p> The Municipality Center organized the screening at the parking lot of the Kosevo football stadium as a part of its annual Days of Youth celebration, which traditionally lasts from May 2 to 9.</p> <p> The movie narrative follows Vladimir Peric Valter, a World War II iconic member of the anti-fascist resistance movement, taking on Nazi occupation forces in Sarajevo.</p> <p> First screened in April 1972, the movie has become one of the most watched movies in history, and has been screened in more than 40 countries across the world including China, where it was very popular in the 1970s.</p> <p> Given the international popularity of the movie, Sarajevo dedicated a small museum to it. The museum was opened in April 2019, and has since become an important sight for Chinese tourists.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220507/46/11554554953233706282.png" /></p> <p> A photo of director Hajrudin Siba Krvavac is seen on the screen at the beginning of the movie Valter (Walter) Defends Sarajevo at a drive-in movie theatre in Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina (BiH) on May 6, 2022. Bosnian capital Sarajevo made its cult WWII movie Valter (Walter) Defends Sarajevo back to audience by organizing a free screening in a drive-in movie theatre on Friday, a move marking the 50th anniversary of this once worldwide popular movie. (Photo by Nedim Grabovica/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220507/79/4367794504461972259.png" /></p> <p> People watch movie Valter (Walter) Defends Sarajevo at a drive-in movie theatre in Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina (BiH) on May 6, 2022. Bosnian capital Sarajevo made its cult WWII movie Valter (Walter) Defends Sarajevo back to audience by organizing a free screening in a drive-in movie theatre on Friday, a move marking the 50th anniversary of this once worldwide popular movie. (Photo by Nedim Grabovica/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220507/46/6604949565493428914.png" /></p> <p> A scene from the movie Valter (Walter) Defends Sarajevo is seen at a drive-in movie theatre in Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina (BiH) on May 6, 2022. Bosnian capital Sarajevo made its cult WWII movie Valter (Walter) Defends Sarajevo back to audience by organizing a free screening in a drive-in movie theatre on Friday, a move marking the 50th anniversary of this once worldwide popular movie. (Photo by Nedim Grabovica/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's box office gets holiday boost, warm-up for summer movie season ]]></title>
	<news_id>10093370</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0507/c90000-10093370.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 10:00:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 6 (Xinhua) -- China's movie box office enjoyed a bounce over the May Day holiday, amassing 297 million yuan (44.77 million U.S. dollars) over the five-day period ending Wednesday.</p> <p> The nearly 300-million-yuan revenue, though much lower than the 1.67 billion yuan generated during the holiday last year, is "no easy feat," according to experts reached by Xinhua.</p> <p> It is meaningful considering that the current wave of COVID-19 infections has caused the postponement of release dates by multiple major domestic titles and mounting cinema closures, especially in Shanghai and Beijing -- two box office powerhouses.</p> <p> The achievement somehow signals hope for further film market recovery and serves as a warm-up for the summer movie season, usually a busy moviegoing period, they said.</p> <p> "BETTER-THAN-EXPECTED"</p> <p> China's box office performance during the holiday has been regarded as "better than expected" by a China Film News report quoting industry insiders.</p> <p> Daily ticket sales peaked at 81 million yuan on May 1, a huge jump from a low of less than 10 million yuan that continued for many working days in April, according to box office tracker Maoyan and the China Movie Data Information Network.</p> <p> Nearly 8.7 million people went to movie theaters during the holiday when a daily average of around 68 percent of cinemas remained open nationwide, up from 56 percent on April 28.</p> <p> Topping the sales chart was the romantic comedy "Stay With Me" from Enlight Pictures with 88 million yuan, immediately followed by DreamWorks Animation's animated comedy "The Bad Guys" with 71.55 million yuan.</p> <p> Coming in third place was Warner Bros. Pictures' "Fantastic Beasts: The Secrets of Dumbledore." It grossed nearly 33 million yuan during the holiday.</p> <p> Rao Shuguang, president of the China Film Critics Association, said in the May Day holiday box office figures people can see "hope and vitality" amid the COVID-19 pandemic.</p> <p> "The 'fundamentals' of China's film market are still there, holding on and waiting (for the pandemic to wane)," commented the critic. He said some of the cinemas are struggling to survive the impact of the pandemic and they need support.</p> <p> WARM-UP FOR SUMMER MOVIE SEASON</p> <p> China's summer movie season spanning three months until Aug. 31 is usually a busy moviegoing period for young people.</p> <p> It generated an average of 17 billion yuan in box office revenue in each of the three years through 2019, before the pandemic struck.</p> <p> The amount for the same period dropped to just 7.4 billion yuan in 2021, even lower than the 7.8 billion yuan recorded for the same year's seven-day Spring Festival holiday.</p> <p> As the output imbalance among different movie seasons is becoming an outstanding issue, experts are calling for greater efforts to meet young moviegoers' need for quality films and boost summer box office sales.</p> <p> Rao called the upcoming summer movie season "a big test" for China's film market, stressing the need to increase the market supply of high-quality, major films to solidify and explore the moviegoer base that is being diverted online partly due to the COVID-19.</p> <p> His remarks echoed surging worries among cinema chain managers that young people are increasingly accustomed to going online for films and dramas, rather than attending theaters.</p> <p> Confident about film's status as an industry, Yin Hong, vice chairman of the China Film Association and a professor at Tsinghua University, said as long as there are great movies and demands for them still exist, a fully-recovered film industry will be foreseeable.</p> <p> Comparing cinemas to "the first window to showcase a film's influence, popularity, and appeal," Yin said only when cinemas flourish can films flourish on streaming platforms.</p> <p> "Without the support of cinemas, it's almost impossible for a movie to become a huge hit that is widely known among the public," he said.</p> <p> That said, Yin stressed that an orderly film market, wider range of film themes, more diverse film genres, professional talent, and the promotion of shared values are crucial to the Chinese movie industry's high-quality development.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 7th cross-Strait ceremony to worship Emperor Yan to be held in China’s Shanxi ]]></title>
	<news_id>10092464</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0505/c90000-10092464.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 14:22:01 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0505/FOREIGN202205051411000373533407844.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 531px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo show a press conference on the 7th cross-Strait ceremony to worship Emperor Yan, a legendary ancestor of the Chinese nation, held on April 30, 2022 in Gaoping, a county-level city where the mausoleum of Emperor Yan is located in north China’s Shanxi Province. (Photo courtesy of Publicity Department of the Communist Party of China Gaoping Municipal Committee)</em></p> <p> The 7th cross-Strait ceremony to worship Emperor Yan, a legendary ancestor of the Chinese nation, will take place on May 8 in Gaoping, a county-level city in north China’s Shanxi Province, where the mausoleum of Emperor Yan is located, its organizers revealed at a recent press conference.</p> <p> Gaoping, administered by Jincheng city, is best known for its unique culture of Emperor Yan. Since 2016, Gaoping has hosted six cross-Strait ceremonies to worship Emperor Yan, providing excellent opportunities for people on both sides of the Taiwan Strait to strengthen and celebrate ties of kinship and culture.</p> <p> At the press conference, Wu Jianpeng, deputy mayor of Jincheng, called on people on both sides of the Taiwan Strait and the Chinese diaspora to pay homage to Emperor Yan, and pray for blessings.</p> <p> Yuan Jian, mayor of Gaoping, announced the 7th cross-Strait ceremony at the press conference while inviting members of the Chinese diaspora and friends from all over the globe to visit and invest in the city.</p> <p> The event will be held both online and offline after implementing COVID-19 prevention and control measures.</p> <p> The event will feature a wide range of activities, including soliciting 100 stories about Emperor Yan from around the world, to promote the history and culture of Emperor Yan, and the cultural heritage of Gaoping and Jincheng.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Calendar for Chinese 24 Solar Terms: Start of Summer ]]></title>
	<news_id>10092288</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0505/c90000-10092288.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 10:54:01 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> The Start of Summer (Lixia) is the seventh of the 24 solar terms, succeeding Grain Rain (Guyu). As the name indicates, this solar term indicates the arrival of summer. The term came into being near the end of the Warring States Period (475-221BC).</p> <p> From the Start of Summer, the days lengthen, temperatures rise and rainfall increases.</p> <center> <video controls="controls" poster="http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/5/5/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-XianJiangNan_6530cc3312dff8942f78723e93453d31.png" src="http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/5/5/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-XianJiangNan_2596fd713ff58bfe26ff44fbe2382ac2.mp4" style="width:80%;margin:20px auto;"> &nbsp;</video> </center> <p> <strong>Traditions:</strong></p> <p> Weighing:</p> <p> People believe that weighing themselves can ease the heat of summer, keep people healthy and bring good luck to children. As a result, the saying goes that on the Start of Summer you'd better weigh yourself to avoid bad luck.</p> <p> Egg competition:</p> <p> On the Start of Summer, parents put eggs into handmade colorful net bags. Children wear the bag around their necks and take part in a game with their friends. Both competitors try to hit the other person's egg, like conkers, and the egg that stays intact wins. The process continues until the only one left whole becomes the "king of eggs" while children who lose eat their eggs. It's believed that by eating eggs, children can enjoy an untroubled summer.</p> <p> <strong>Food and drinks:</strong></p> <p> Taste fresh food on the Start of Summer:</p> <p> In the southern part of the Yangtze River, it is said that three kinds of fresh food are to be eaten. Traditionally, these are cherry, plum and Reeves' shad. There are other variations of this rule: bamboo shoots, cherry and plum; cherry, plum and wheat berry; and bamboo shoot, cherry and broad beans. The gist of the different categories is that people should enjoy fresh food during this solar term.</p> <p> In Jiangxi, people drink tea during the Start of Summer. Green tea is one of their favorites because it dispels heat.&nbsp;</p> <p> Start of Summer Rice:</p> <p> It is popular in Guangxi to cook five different beans with rice. The beans are red, yellow, black and green while the rice is white. Thus, Start of Summer rice is also called Five-Colored Rice.</p> <p> During the Start of Summer, it is essential to maintain a light diet. Vegetables and fruits are good choices while spicy and salty food should be avoided. People should remain calm and enjoy a variety of activities like painting, fishing and playing chess.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0505/FOREIGN202205050944000306890780557.jpg" style="width: 700px; height: 1244px;" /></p> <p> <strong>Related:&nbsp;</strong></p> <p> <a href="http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0420/c90000-10086143.html" target="_blank"><strong>Calendar for Chinese 24 Solar Terms: Grain Rain</strong></a></p> <p> <strong><a href="http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0405/c90000-10080028.html" target="_blank">Calendar for Chinese 24 Solar Terms: Qingming</a></strong></p> <p> <a href="http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0320/c98389-9973540.html" target="_blank"><strong>Calendar for Chinese 24 Solar Terms: Spring Equinox</strong></a></p> <p> <strong><a href="http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0305/c90000-9966323.html" target="_blank">Calendar for Chinese 24 Solar Terms: Awakening of Insects</a></strong></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Emerging young talents carry forward traditional Chinese culture ]]></title>
	<news_id>10092277</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0505/c90000-10092277.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 08:49:43 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> <strong>* On April 21, China released its first white paper centered on its youth, "Youth of China in the New Era." This year also marks the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC).</strong></p> <p> <strong>* Nowadays, young Chinese identify more and more with the splendors of Chinese civilization. They are deeply proud of the Chinese nation, and are more active in promoting traditional Chinese culture and boosting cultural confidence across society.</strong></p> <p> <strong>* China has pledged to go all out to preserve and develop its excellent traditional culture, eyeing a "marked boost" in the international influence of Chinese culture by 2025.</strong></p> <p> TAIYUAN/LHASA, May 4 (Xinhua) -- Sitting in a self-designed, ancient-style courtyard, Liu Kai, 30, draws Chongfu Temple, a cultural structure steeped in history and now under state protection in north China's Shanxi Province.</p> <p> Hailing from a farming family in Zhuge Village, Shanxi's Linfen City, Liu has a passion for ancient China's awe-inspiring architecture, especially the buildings in the culture-rich province.</p> <p> Over the past eight years, he has recorded over 50 historic structures on paper, depicting himself in front of each old building. "It is me, like countless others who have looked up to the heritage through the ages," Liu said.</p> <p> On April 21, China released its first white paper centered on its youth, "Youth of China in the New Era." This year also marks the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC).</p> <p> China's youth draw nutrients from the best of China's traditional culture, revolutionary culture, and advanced socialist culture, and gain strength from the time-honored Chinese civilization, said the document.</p> <p> Young Chinese identify more and more with the splendors of Chinese civilization. They are deeply proud of the Chinese nation, and are more active in promoting traditional Chinese culture and boosting cultural confidence across society, according to the white paper.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220505/59/9368318024412831199.jpg" style="height: 900px; width: 605px;" /></p> <p> <em>File photo provided by Liu Kai shows a painting of his depicting a view of the Tayuan Temple on Mount Wutai in north China's Shanxi Province. (Xinhua)</em></p> <p> Over the years, China has placed great emphasis on the passing on and promotion of its culture, with a raft of guidelines and proposals launched to fuel the nationwide protection, innovation and spread of its invaluable culture.</p> <p> Liu is not alone in his passion for China's past. After posting his paintings online, his artworks have wowed netizens and attracted collectors across the country.</p> <p> China has pledged to go all out to preserve and develop its excellent traditional culture, eyeing a "marked boost" in the international influence of Chinese culture by 2025.</p> <p> According to the guidelines issued by the central government in 2017, major achievements are expected to be registered in traditional culture-related research, education, protection, inheritance, innovation and exchanges by 2025.</p> <p> China's top design to rejuvenate its fine culture has received an enthusiastic echo from the public.</p> <p> At a Virtual Reality (VR) exhibition hall in Xigaze City, southwest China's Tibet Autonomous Region, an eight-minute video introduces visitors to the history and development of Zhentang Sherpa dance, a form of national intangible cultural heritage.</p> <p> The videography and translation involved the efforts of 23-year-old Sidar, who is of Sherpa descent. His hometown Zhentang, deep in the Himalayas and bordering Nepal, is home to more than 2,600 Sherpa people.</p> <p> The young man's mother is a practitioner of Zhentang Sherpa dance. When Sidar was a child, he used to watch his mother teach locals of all ages the ancient steps of the dance.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220505/62/11586495174384594446.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>File photo taken by Sidar shows Sherpa villagers enjoying liquor made from Eleusine Coracana in Zhentang of Xigaze, southwest China's Tibet Autonomous Region, on July 16, 2019. (Photo by Sidar/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> Scholars have frequently visited the sleepy town to conduct studies of the unique local culture. "The Sherpa culture is diverse and rich. Scholars make academic achievements, but the responsibility of real cultural inheritance falls on the shoulders of local youths like Sidar," said Tarring Namgel, an associate professor at the College of Art of Tibet University. He traveled to the region to research Mani Drama, another time-honored form of Sherpa cultural heritage.</p> <p> Increasing participation in such trips inspired Sidar to record local culture through his lens. Old gadgets of the Sherpa people, dancing and vibrant festival celebrations have since become the subjects of his videos.</p> <p> "Our culture is like an ancient river that flows inside us from history to today," Sidar said. It is his dream to make a documentary and establish a museum of Sherpa folk culture.</p> <p> More and more young Chinese people have joined efforts to preserve cultural heritage thanks to China's blockbuster documentaries and television shows such as "Masters in the Forbidden City" and "National Treasure."</p> <p> When Zhu Xiaocong, now an ancient calligraphy and painting conservator, landed his job at Shanxi Museum seven years ago, he only had three or four colleagues. But now, the team has expanded to about 30 people, with its members mostly born after 1990.</p> <p> Zhu's studio may seem like a kitchen to the untrained eye, as a variety of brushes hang on the walls, knives rest in drawers and pots of different sizes litter the counter. Lying on his workbench is a piece of calligraphy dating back to the Qing Dynasty (1644-1911), spoiled by faint stains and cracks.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220505/16/6412638164361081032.jpg" style="height: 675px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Zhu Xiaocong, a restorer for painting and calligraphy, works on an artwork at the Shanxi Museum in Taiyuan, north China's Shanxi Province, April 27, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Xuetao)</em></p> <p> Zhu is "performing surgery" on the delicate artwork. He scrapes off the stains with a knife and sticks thin white strips to the back of the paper on damaged areas.</p> <p> "It can take days to merely open the frames of articrafts using tweezers, as ancient Chinese people used to write and draw on fragile materials," Zhu explained.</p> <p> "Young people are energetic, but they can lack experience when it comes to artifact restoration," said Guo Zhiyong, deputy director of the museum's cultural artifact conservation and research department. "However, their techniques can be greatly improved through training, teaching guides from their seniors, and field trips."</p> <p> Over the past seven years, Zhu has single-handedly restored over 100 ancient paintings and calligraphy works. "All my efforts are worthwhile when I see the artifacts restored to their former glory and appreciated by museum visitors," he said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Mass wedding held in Bhopal, India ]]></title>
	<news_id>10092124</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0504/c90000-10092124.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 16:01:19 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220504/5/2656869638146956237.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> 　　Brides take part in a mass wedding in Bhopal, capital of India's Madhya Pradesh state, May 3, 2022. More than 52 couples on Tuesday tied the nuptial knot during the mass wedding in Bhopal. (Str/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220504/28/2115068060503857100.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> 　　Bridegrooms on camels take part in a mass wedding in Bhopal, capital of India's Madhya Pradesh state, May 3, 2022. More than 52 couples on Tuesday tied the nuptial knot during the mass wedding in Bhopal. (Str/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220504/1/794977637096566085.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> 　　Brides take part in a mass wedding in Bhopal, capital of India's Madhya Pradesh state, May 3, 2022. More than 52 couples on Tuesday tied the nuptial knot during the mass wedding in Bhopal. (Str/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220504/10/2967581405301632658.jpg" style="height: 655px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> 　　A bride talks on a phone as she takes part in a mass wedding in Bhopal, capital of India's Madhya Pradesh state, May 3, 2022. More than 52 couples on Tuesday tied the nuptial knot during the mass wedding in Bhopal. (Str/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220504/92/1976511363442079144.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> 　　Brides take part in a mass wedding in Bhopal, capital of India's Madhya Pradesh state, May 3, 2022. More than 52 couples on Tuesday tied the nuptial knot during the mass wedding in Bhopal. (Str/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220504/82/8662592380523219046.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> 　　Bridegrooms on camels take part in a mass wedding in Bhopal, capital of India's Madhya Pradesh state, May 3, 2022. More than 52 couples on Tuesday tied the nuptial knot during the mass wedding in Bhopal. (Str/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220504/15/12480182360576460151.jpg" style="height: 516px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> 　　Brides and bridegrooms take part in a mass wedding in Bhopal, capital of India's Madhya Pradesh state, May 3, 2022. More than 52 couples on Tuesday tied the nuptial knot during the mass wedding in Bhopal. (Str/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China calls for more efforts to protect revolutionary cultural relics ]]></title>
	<news_id>10092077</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0504/c90000-10092077.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 14:43:27 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> 　　BEIJING, May 3 (Xinhua) -- China has issued a circular calling for various departments and localities across the country to enhance efforts to protect revolutionary cultural relics, according to the National Cultural Heritage Administration.</p> <p> 　　The circular, jointly released by the administration and the Publicity Department of the Communist Party of China Central Committee, noted that revolutionary cultural relics are precious wealth of the Party and the country.</p> <p> 　　Localities need to systematically comb through cultural relics resources and include those qualified on the list of revolutionary cultural relics, the circular said.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Pic story: national intangible inheritor of Chagaanyidee in Inner Mongolia ]]></title>
	<news_id>10091697</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0502/c90000-10091697.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 10:31:03 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/32/11881883537509408268.png" /></p> <p> Tao Gao milks a cow in Zhenglan Banner of Xilingol League, north China's Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, April 27, 2022. Tao Gao is the national intangible inheritor of Chagaanyidee (dairy product) in Inner Mongolia. She combines modern techniques with traditional crafts and trains herders in pastoral areas to make dairy products. In recent years, the local government has boosted the development of traditional dairy food industry to increase the income of herdsmen. The average annual sales of dairy food in the whole banner reached about 60 million yuan (about 9 million U.S. dollars) in the past two years. (Xinhua/Lian Zhen)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/24/1504811182332493300.png" /></p> <p> Tao Gao filters whey in Zhenglan Banner of Xilingol League, north China's Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, April 27, 2022. Tao Gao is the national intangible inheritor of Chagaanyidee (dairy product) in Inner Mongolia. She combines modern techniques with traditional crafts and trains herders in pastoral areas to make dairy products. In recent years, the local government has boosted the development of traditional dairy food industry to increase the income of herdsmen. The average annual sales of dairy food in the whole banner reached about 60 million yuan (about 9 million U.S. dollars) in the past two years. (Xinhua/Lian Zhen)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/43/2703741178787512051.png" /></p> <p> Tao Gao (L) and Altenzagas make dairy product in Zhenglan Banner of Xilingol League, north China's Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, April 27, 2022. Tao Gao is the national intangible inheritor of Chagaanyidee (dairy product) in Inner Mongolia. She combines modern techniques with traditional crafts and trains herders in pastoral areas to make dairy products. In recent years, the local government has boosted the development of traditional dairy food industry to increase the income of herdsmen. The average annual sales of dairy food in the whole banner reached about 60 million yuan (about 9 million U.S. dollars) in the past two years. (Xinhua/Lian Zhen)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/66/9325997632891790742.png" /></p> <p> Tao Gao makes dairy product in Zhenglan Banner of Xilingol League, north China's Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, April 27, 2022. Tao Gao is the national intangible inheritor of Chagaanyidee (dairy product) in Inner Mongolia. She combines modern techniques with traditional crafts and trains herders in pastoral areas to make dairy products. In recent years, the local government has boosted the development of traditional dairy food industry to increase the income of herdsmen. The average annual sales of dairy food in the whole banner reached about 60 million yuan (about 9 million U.S. dollars) in the past two years. (Xinhua/Lian Zhen)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/42/627367344273673074.png" /></p> <p> Tao Gao dries a new dairy product at her workshop in Zhenglan Banner of Xilingol League, north China's Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, April 27, 2022. Tao Gao is the national intangible inheritor of Chagaanyidee (dairy product) in Inner Mongolia. She combines modern techniques with traditional crafts and trains herders in pastoral areas to make dairy products. In recent years, the local government has boosted the development of traditional dairy food industry to increase the income of herdsmen. The average annual sales of dairy food in the whole banner reached about 60 million yuan (about 9 million U.S. dollars) in the past two years. (Xinhua/Lian Zhen)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/30/9626664766457760518.png" /></p> <p> Tao Gao makes dairy product at her workshop in Zhenglan Banner of Xilingol League, north China's Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, April 27, 2022. Tao Gao is the national intangible inheritor of Chagaanyidee (dairy product) in Inner Mongolia. She combines modern techniques with traditional crafts and trains herders in pastoral areas to make dairy products. In recent years, the local government has boosted the development of traditional dairy food industry to increase the income of herdsmen. The average annual sales of dairy food in the whole banner reached about 60 million yuan (about 9 million U.S. dollars) in the past two years. (Xinhua/Lian Zhen)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/11/7005577882537246283.png" /></p> <p> Tao Gao makes dairy product at her workshop in Zhenglan Banner of Xilingol League, north China's Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, April 27, 2022. Tao Gao is the national intangible inheritor of Chagaanyidee (dairy product) in Inner Mongolia. She combines modern techniques with traditional crafts and trains herders in pastoral areas to make dairy products. In recent years, the local government has boosted the development of traditional dairy food industry to increase the income of herdsmen. The average annual sales of dairy food in the whole banner reached about 60 million yuan (about 9 million U.S. dollars) in the past two years. (Xinhua/Lian Zhen)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/63/13842838438614055131.png" /></p> <p> Tao Gao (L) and Altenzagas make dairy product in Zhenglan Banner of Xilingol League, north China's Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, April 27, 2022. Tao Gao is the national intangible inheritor of Chagaanyidee (dairy product) in Inner Mongolia. She combines modern techniques with traditional crafts and trains herders in pastoral areas to make dairy products. In recent years, the local government has boosted the development of traditional dairy food industry to increase the income of herdsmen. The average annual sales of dairy food in the whole banner reached about 60 million yuan (about 9 million U.S. dollars) in the past two years. (Xinhua/Lian Zhen)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ People visit spring fair in Batroun, Lebanon ]]></title>
	<news_id>10091684</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0502/c90000-10091684.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 09:41:25 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/10/16837439310218142082.png" /></p> <p> People visit a spring fair in Batroun, northern Lebanon, on April 30, 2022. (Xinhua/Liu Zongya)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/1/11753595986118344729.png" /></p> <p> People visit a spring fair in Batroun, northern Lebanon, on April 30, 2022. (Xinhua/Liu Zongya)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/24/6351439683483739968.png" /></p> <p> People visit a spring fair in Batroun, northern Lebanon, on April 30, 2022. (Xinhua/Liu Zongya)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/60/2836478539677709664.png" /></p> <p> People visit a spring fair in Batroun, northern Lebanon, on April 30, 2022. (Xinhua/Liu Zongya)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/93/18077225478909730821.png" /></p> <p> A stone painting stand is seen at a spring fair in Batroun, northern Lebanon, on April 30, 2022. (Xinhua/Liu Zongya)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's cultural industry recovers steadily in Q1 ]]></title>
	<news_id>10091263</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0429/c90000-10091263.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:57:11 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, April 29 (Xinhua) -- China's cultural sector sustained recovery momentum in the first quarter despite COVID-19 shocks, official data showed Friday.</p> <p> The combined operating revenues of major companies in the sector amounted to about 2.7 trillion yuan (about 408 billion U.S. dollars) during the period, up 5 percent year on year, according to the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS).</p> <p> Among the sub-sectors, the revenue of cultural content creation logged a year-on-year growth of 10.1 percent in the first three months of the year, the data showed.</p> <p> The country's central region led the growth with the revenue of the sector expanding 12 percent year on year, followed by the eastern and western regions.</p> <p> The NBS data came from a survey of cultural companies with annual revenue of more than 20 million yuan or those meeting other standards set by the NBS.</p> <p> Looking forward, with more policies implemented to help enterprises tide over difficulties, the cultural sector is expected to maintain stable and healthy development, the NBS said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ "East-West Fusion" erhu concerts held in Sydney, Australia ]]></title>
	<news_id>10091073</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0429/c90000-10091073.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:04:00 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Sydney, April 27 (People's Daily Online) - From April 22 to April 25, Phoenix Collective's erhu concerts "East-West Fusion" were presented to audiences in Canberra, Sydney and the Central Coast, Australia.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0429/FOREIGN202204291447000482798376473.jpg" style="width: 550px; height: 413px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Phoenix Collective performs at Sydney Mosman Art Gallery on April 23, 2022. (Photo /Jiayi Wang)</em></p> <p> This was the first time that Phoenix Collective combined Western string quartets with the traditional Chinese erhu. It revealed the unique charm of Chinese and Western music fusion by exploring traditional Chinese folk music, winning wide praise from audiences.</p> <p> Chinese erhu performer Ying Liu and four famous Australian performers from the Phoenix Collective performed the concert together and jointly arranged Chinese and Australian classical music works.</p> <p> Dan Russell, artistic director of the concert, said that the concept of combining Western string quartets and erhu was formed by exchanging musical ideas with Ying and the orchestra's cellist Andrew Wilson. “The uniqueness of the erhu sound, for me, represents the different soundscape that I was looking for,” he said.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0429/FOREIGN202204291448000012141468214.jpg" style="width: 550px; height: 413px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Performers' group photo (Photo/Jiayi Wang)</em></p> <p> &nbsp;He also said that although the ensemble of violin and erhu put forward higher requirements for the selection of repertoire, the erhu and string quartet cooperated perfectly.</p> <p> Ying also agreed. “The sound of the violin and the erhu are very well integrated.</p> <p> &nbsp;“Now many composers have begun to compose music focusing on the fusion of Chinese and Western music.”</p> <p> &nbsp;Liu also affirmed the significance of this tour concert. She said, “Chinese culture has been subtly integrated into Western artistic creation.”</p> <p> &nbsp;Russell also added that films with traditional Chinese culture also inspired him.&nbsp;</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0429/FOREIGN202204291448000123888789040.jpg" style="width: 550px; height: 346px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Dan Russell, the artistic director of the concert (Photo/Xueyi Zhao)</em></p> <p> “I've kind of grown up listening to the music used in movies such as&nbsp;Hero, Crouching Tiger Hidden Dragon,&nbsp;and&nbsp;House of Flying Daggers, the music used in these movies is exquisite,” Russell said.</p> <p> The whole concert mainly explored traditional Chinese folk music, improvisation and modern experimental techniques. The concert opened with an excerpt from the classic Chinese music piece&nbsp;Ode to Yellow River&nbsp;by cellist Andrew Wilson.</p> <p> The repertoire also includes many classic pieces adapted from the fusion of Chinese and Western musical elements, such as&nbsp;Left Bank Waltz&nbsp;by Australian composer Peter Schuthorpe, specially arranged by Australian arranger Julie Symonds for the erhu and quartet.</p> <p> The adapted Chinese traditional folk songs&nbsp;Jasmine Flower,&nbsp;Beautiful Night,&nbsp;Lan Hua-Hua, and other works were also performed for audience, one after another. More improvised songs, such as the music from Oscar-winning film Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon, attracted applause from the audience.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0429/FOREIGN202204291448000240865270167.jpg" style="width: 550px; height: 355px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Chinese erhu performer Ying Liu (Photo/Xueyi Zhao)</em></p> <p> The Australian audience also showed great enthusiasm for the concert.</p> <p> Russell said that music is a sound that anyone can understand.</p> <p> “Music is a universal language, and so in that respect, anyone can enjoy and understand it,” he noted</p> <p> Ying also said that most people listening to the concert were Westerners. "Everyone likes and enjoys it, and completely indulges in it," she said.</p> <p> Ying also emphasized that the exchange of music between China and the West shows China's national culture and self-confidence, and music is the commonwealth of all humanity.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Luxor, ancient Egyptian city, becomes tourist destination ]]></title>
	<news_id>10090961</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0429/c90000-10090961.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 09:52:20 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220429/50/10197732038761708194.png" /></p> <p align="center" class="pictext"> 　　Tourists visit the Karnak Temple Complex in Luxor, Egypt, April 27, 2022.</p> <p> Luxor, a capital of ancient Upper Egypt known as Thebes, is now a tourist destination famous for the historic temple buildings and other relics. (Xinhua/Sui Xiankai)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220429/75/10541028247572407211.png" /></p> <p align="center" class="pictext"> 　　Tourists visit the Colossi of Memnon in Luxor, Egypt, April 26, 2022.</p> <p> Luxor, a capital of ancient Upper Egypt known as Thebes, is now a tourist destination famous for the historic temple buildings and other relics. (Xinhua/Sui Xiankai)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220429/51/4161301577518775755.png" /></p> <p align="center" class="pictext"> 　　Tourists visit the Temple of Hatshepsut in Luxor, Egypt, April 26, 2022.</p> <p> Luxor, a capital of ancient Upper Egypt known as Thebes, is now a tourist destination famous for the historic temple buildings and other relics. (Xinhua/Sui Xiankai)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220429/7/10457282443503787299.png" /></p> <p> Tourists visit huge columns at the Karnak Temple Complex in Luxor, Egypt, April 27, 2022.</p> <p> Luxor, a capital of ancient Upper Egypt known as Thebes, is now a tourist destination famous for the historic temple buildings and other relics. (Xinhua/Sui Xiankai)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220429/79/13629276466510134031.png" /></p> <p> Tourists visit huge columns at the Karnak Temple Complex in Luxor, Egypt, April 27, 2022.</p> <p> Luxor, a capital of ancient Upper Egypt known as Thebes, is now a tourist destination famous for the historic temple buildings and other relics. (Xinhua/Sui Xiankai)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220429/87/2688395843501545651.png" /></p> <p align="center" class="pictext"> 　　Tourists visit the Temple of Hatshepsut in Luxor, Egypt, April 26, 2022.</p> <p> Luxor, a capital of ancient Upper Egypt known as Thebes, is now a tourist destination famous for the historic temple buildings and other relics. (Xinhua/Sui Xiankai)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220429/64/17559816784465252788.png" /></p> <p> Tourists visit huge columns at the Karnak Temple Complex in Luxor, Egypt, April 27, 2022.</p> <p> Luxor, a capital of ancient Upper Egypt known as Thebes, is now a tourist destination famous for the historic temple buildings and other relics. (Xinhua/Sui Xiankai)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220429/99/3202009003022751031.png" /></p> <p align="center" class="pictext"> 　　Tourists visit the Colossi of Memnon in Luxor, Egypt, April 26, 2022.</p> <p> Luxor, a capital of ancient Upper Egypt known as Thebes, is now a tourist destination famous for the historic temple buildings and other relics. (Xinhua/Sui Xiankai)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220429/5/13674116516335480509.png" /></p> <p> Photo shows huge columns at the Karnak Temple Complex in Luxor, Egypt, April 27, 2022.</p> <p> Luxor, a capital of ancient Upper Egypt known as Thebes, is now a tourist destination famous for the historic temple buildings and other relics. (Xinhua/Sui Xiankai)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220429/52/10490946507045876044.png" /></p> <p align="center" class="pictext"> 　　Tourists visit the Temple of Hatshepsut in Luxor, Egypt, April 26, 2022.</p> <p> Luxor, a capital of ancient Upper Egypt known as Thebes, is now a tourist destination famous for the historic temple buildings and other relics. (Xinhua/Sui Xiankai)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220429/9/10295775889792965401.png" /></p> <p> Tourists visit huge columns at the Karnak Temple Complex in Luxor, Egypt, April 27, 2022.</p> <p> Luxor, a capital of ancient Upper Egypt known as Thebes, is now a tourist destination famous for the historic temple buildings and other relics. (Xinhua/Sui Xiankai)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Influencer tours the world wearing traditional Chinese clothes ]]></title>
	<news_id>10090682</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0428/c90000-10090682.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 16:21:46 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <center> <video controls="controls" poster=" http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/4/28/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_b8ec41f138b43e8156ebc2ccbddaef14.jpeg" src="http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/4/28/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_73c7b7d5977d751e36bd7871de08edda.mp4" style=" width: 830px; height:550px;"> <p> &nbsp;</p> <p> &nbsp;</p> </video> </center> <p> Her innovative fashion ideas have earned her 12 million followers on China's popular video sharing platform Bilibili.</p> <p> Influencer Lian Yuxin, better known by the online pseudonym Xiao Doukou'er, is instrumental in an ongoing fashion revival of traditional clothing of China's Han ethnic majority, known as hanfu among Chinese.</p> <p> Born in 1994 in Fujian Province, Lian has boosted her reputation through hanfu cosplay and by combining elements from different dynasties into her design.</p> <p> Lian has also modernized the clothing to make it more suitable for daily life.</p> <p> <em>(Source: The Global People magazine)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily App</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Hainan's boat-shaped houses tell stories of rich ethnic culture ]]></title>
	<news_id>10090665</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0428/c90000-10090665.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 16:17:11 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> HAIKOU, April 28 (Xinhua) -- In the island province of Hainan, the village of Chubao boasts something unique: dozens of boat-shaped thatch cottages lined up surrounded by coconut trees.</p> <p> Tucked away in the boundless lush mountains in south China, the cottages feature walls made of wood or mud, and triangular thatch roofs, giving them the appearance of an overturned boat.</p> <p> The boat-shaped houses were built by the local ethnic Li people in Chubao Village. For thousands of years, the local Li people have lived in these houses in the rainforest.</p> <p> "We lived here for generations," said local villager Wang Shiqi.</p> <p> In recent years, locals have gradually moved into modern new houses. But as the traditional dwellings bear testimony to the Li culture, they are now well preserved.</p> <p> Authorities are applying for the houses to be included in the World Heritage List, hoping to draw more attention to the distinctive values of the Li culture.</p> <p> Recently, the Hainan tropical rainforest and the traditional settlement of Li ethnic group have become part of the tentative list to qualify for inclusion in the World Heritage List.</p> <p> The Li people have developed a distinctive culture over many years of development. Their colorful culture includes Li brocade, bamboo dancing, face tattoos, and boat-shaped houses, among others.</p> <p> Legend has it that the ancestors of the Li people arrived in Hainan by boats. When they arrived, they turned the boats upside down as houses for shelter. Their descendants built the boat-shaped houses in memory of their ancestors.</p> <p> In the late 1980s, about 800,000 Li people were still living in boat-shaped dwellings in Hainan.</p> <p> But the houses were not that easy to live in, as they were made of thatch or mud, making them susceptible to the damage from wind and rain.</p> <p> "In the summertime, it was cool in the houses, but in winter, the biting wind sneaked in through the cracks," recalled Wang Shiqi.</p> <p> As people's living conditions improved, they began to move out of the houses.</p> <p> Though villagers no longer live in the houses, they have unique feelings attached to them.</p> <p> "After all, we have lived here for a long time," Wang said.</p> <p> Authorities have made efforts to preserve the traditional houses by putting them on the provincial-level list of cultural heritage under protection.</p> <p> "The thatched houses reflected the Li people's wisdom for house location and layout and their architecture skills," said Li Jilong, with the provincial department of tourism, culture, radio, television and sports.</p> <p> The houses should be preserved as cultural relics so that the younger generation will know the stories of their ancestors, said Chen Rongchuan, curator of the cultural museum in the city of Dongfang, which administers Baicha Village, home to more than 80 such houses.</p> <p> "The traditional houses are of great value, and they should be well preserved," said Liu Baodang, with the National Forestry and Grassland Administration.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Digitalization helps more people in China discover joy of reading ]]></title>
	<news_id>10090625</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0428/c90000-10090625.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 15:09:38 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220428/32/16179279548352756748.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; width: 600px; height: 800px;" /></p> <p> <em>A board displaying new forms of reading is pictured during the first National Conference on Reading in Beijing, capital of China, April 23, 2022. (Xinhua/Luo Xin)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, April 27 (Xinhua) -- Cheng Zhiwu, a 70-year-old from central China's Hubei Province, has downloaded some 600 digital books on a reading App on his tablet computer.</p> <p> "I've found so much joy in reading or listening to digital books as a way to keep up with the times and enrich my golden years," said Chen, adding that he spends some four to five hours a day on the reading App.</p> <p> The first National Conference on Reading concluded in Beijing on Monday with digital reading taking the spotlight. With advances in technology and the popularization of the mobile internet, digital reading has become a new driving force to encourage people of all ages in China to read.</p> <p> According to the China digital readership report 2021 released during the conference, the number of digital book readers in China reached 506 million in 2021, up 2.43 percent year on year.</p> <p> The overall scale of China's digital reading market reached 41.57 billion yuan (about 6.3 billion U.S. dollars) last year, marking a year-on-year growth of 18.23 percent, according to the report mainly compiled by the China Audio-video and Digital Publishing Association.</p> <p> As a growing trend, audio reading attracted over 800 million active users in China last year, an increase of 230 million over 2020, said Fan Weiping, president of the China Federation of Radio and Television Associations.</p> <p> Noticeably, audio reading functions as a bridge over the "digital gap" for elderly readers like Cheng, and a number of e-book platforms have focused on optimizing the audio reading experience.</p> <p> "We provide personalized book lists for aged members, and the AI technologies we utilize can convert text into audio content in real-time without the need for human voice recording," said Liu Xin, general manager of Migu Culture Technology Co., Ltd while introducing a tailored version of their reading App for elderly.</p> <p> Industry insiders pointed out that audio reading products, such as audiovisual novels, interactive picture books, and short dramas, have become an important resource for cultural IP development and formed a mature IP incubation system.</p> <p> Meanwhile, young people still dominate China's digital reading market. Over 70 percent of digital book readers were under the age of 25 in 2021, the aforementioned report shows.</p> <p> Digital reading has also helped with the popularization of classic books among the young. Cheng Wu, CEO of China Literature, said that last year, the Analects of Confucius was the most popular e-book on its platform with nearly 30 million views, and more than 80 percent of its readers were under 30 years old.</p> <p> China's digital reading products, especially online literature, have become more and more popular in overseas markets. Over 400,000 Chinese digital books were released abroad last year, with fantasy and martial arts among the most popular themes, according to the industry report.</p> <p> "In the future, the digital reading experience will be further transformed," said Liu with Migu. "A book will no longer be just a book. It will be a constant flow of thinking, writing, sharing, socializing, marketing, and other activities."</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220428/63/16011729198943458203.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 675px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>People visit a hall showcasing holographic reading technologies for children during the first National Conference on Reading in Beijing, capital of China, April 23, 2022. (Xinhua/Luo Xin)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ People's support vital for state governance ]]></title>
	<news_id>10090586</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0428/c90000-10090586.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 14:47:09 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, April 27 (Xinhua) -- The Chinese idiom "De Ren Zhe Xing" emphasizes the importance of winning people's hearts and attracting talents to a country or government.</p> <p> "Ren" stands for people's hearts as well as talents. The saying, which comes from Shiji, or Records of the Grand Historian, a monumental history book of ancient China compiled about 2,000 years ago, has two connotations.</p> <p> Only by winning people's hearts and responding to their wishes can a country or government continue to thrive. This is in accord with the philosophy that "people's will is the foundation of the state" and "people are the foundation of the state."</p> <p> Moreover, talents are critical to the rise and fall of a country or government. Only by identifying and recruiting the most capable and upright people and suitably employing them can a great cause be completed and a country and its government remain stable and secure.</p> <p> Winning people's hearts is closely related to attracting the talented. Winning people's hearts will eventually draw in the talented, and recruiting the talented will eventually help win people's hearts.</p> <p> Under the leadership of the Communist Party of China, China adopts a people-centered development philosophy. This is best illustrated by China's massive poverty-alleviation campaign and its handling of the COVID-19 epidemic, where such concepts and practices as "no one should be left behind" and "people first, life first" have been demonstrated.</p> <p> China emphasizes the development of professional talent to improve the country's workforce, and education to nurture a new generation of capable young people who are well-prepared to join the socialist cause.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Online opera performances help popularize refined art among wider audience ]]></title>
	<news_id>10090558</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0428/c90000-10090558.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 14:32:58 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> By holding evening galas or live-streaming performances of Chinese operas, known as gems of traditional Chinese culture, multiple online platforms in China have injected new vitality into the popularization of the refined art and have helped to create a craze for art forms featuring opera elements.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0428/FOREIGN202204281416000318823005414.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 178px;" /></p> <p> <em>A visitor watches a video featuring Huizhou Opera in a museum in east China’s Anhui Province. (Photo/Shi Yalei)</em></p> <p> “I have performed Huangmei Opera for 30 years. But I never expected that I would attract so many new fans through live-streaming shows,” said Liu Lihua, head of the Huangmei Opera troupe in Huaining county, Anqing city, east China’s Anhui Province.</p> <p> Liu said that the troupe has moved its performances online in recent two years due to the negative effects of the COVID-19 epidemic and has held live-streaming sessions on Douyin, a popular short-video sharing platform in China. To her surprise, the troupe’s live-streaming account on the platform garnered 600,000 followers and 3 million likes in just three months.</p> <p> The popularity of Huangmei Opera on the platform epitomizes the appeal of traditional Chinese opera to an increasing number of people.</p> <p> Statistics showed that by February of this year, performances of over 300 Chinese opera types had been presented on Douyin, 231 types of which had also been performed through live-streaming sessions. Last year, over 800,000 live-streaming shows on Chinese operas were held on the platform, with each attracting an average of more than 3,200 viewers. The top five most popular operas on Douyin were Peking Opera, Qinqiang Opera, Yue Opera, Huangmei Opera, and Henan Yu Opera.</p> <p> “Online platforms offer viewers easy access to traditional Chinese operas,” said Wan Quan, a fan of Peking Opera who was born in the 1990s.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0428/FOREIGN202204281416000452178202483.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 210px;" /></p> <p> <em>Performers stage a Pingju Opera show in Fengrun district, Tangshan city, north China’s Hebei Province. (Photo/Zhu Dayong)</em></p> <p> The biggest perk of watching online videos featuring Peking Opera is that young fans can acquire knowledge of the art, something which is necessary to truly appreciate the art form, through comments from other internet users, according to Wan.</p> <p> He explained that when viewers find resonance with operas through online interaction, they will be more willing to continue to learn about opera and enjoy opera performances offline.</p> <p> Meanwhile, internet platforms have also helped popularize some art forms featuring opera elements.</p> <p> On China’s popular video-streaming platform Bilibili, Bian Jingting, a vlogger who graduated from the Shanghai Theatre Academy, has garnered about 800,000 followers by uploading videos featuring herself performing Chinese “gufeng” songs in a Peking Opera style. “Gufeng” music is a particular type of music with lyrical, musical, and symbolic references to ancient China that is often produced, consumed, and circulated within online fan communities.</p> <p> Many viewers commented that they went on to learn more about traditional operas after watching her videos.</p> <p> Now Bian introduces shows of traditional Chinese operas and related knowledge to her audiences during live-streaming sessions, popularizing Chinese opera culture.</p> <p> “The reason why songs featuring elements of traditional Chinese operas have become popular among young people, is that young creators are more familiar with new media and make innovations by blending elements of traditional Chinese operas into songs,” said Lin Ling, an associate researcher with the China Institute of Fudan University.</p> <p> Lin pointed out to better inherit traditional Chinese operas, the industry will continue to attract more audiences and continue to make these operas fun through innovations.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ In pics: tomb of Ramesses VI in Valley of Kings in Egypt ]]></title>
	<news_id>10090356</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0428/c90000-10090356.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 09:24:10 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220428/4/7984314432913692932.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on April 26, 2022 shows colorful reliefs and murals inside the tomb of Ramesses VI in the Valley of the Kings in Luxor, Egypt. The tomb of Ramesses VI, a ruler of the 20th Dynasty in ancient Egypt, is one of the most beautiful and well-preserved tombs in the Valley of the Kings. (Xinhua/Sui Xiankai)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220428/18/6145608600898073994.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on April 26, 2022 shows colorful reliefs inside the tomb of Ramesses VI in the Valley of the Kings in Luxor, Egypt. The tomb of Ramesses VI, a ruler of the 20th Dynasty in ancient Egypt, is one of the most beautiful and well-preserved tombs in the Valley of the Kings. (Xinhua/Sui Xiankai)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220428/95/13134943355902230835.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on April 26, 2022 shows colorful reliefs and murals inside the tomb of Ramesses VI in the Valley of the Kings in Luxor, Egypt. The tomb of Ramesses VI, a ruler of the 20th Dynasty in ancient Egypt, is one of the most beautiful and well-preserved tombs in the Valley of the Kings. (Xinhua/Sui Xiankai)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220428/43/2532805681935545235.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on April 26, 2022 shows colorful reliefs and murals inside the tomb of Ramesses VI in the Valley of the Kings in Luxor, Egypt. The tomb of Ramesses VI, a ruler of the 20th Dynasty in ancient Egypt, is one of the most beautiful and well-preserved tombs in the Valley of the Kings. (Xinhua/Sui Xiankai)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220428/35/15481115944892522379.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on April 26, 2022 shows colorful reliefs and murals inside the tomb of Ramesses VI in the Valley of the Kings in Luxor, Egypt. The tomb of Ramesses VI, a ruler of the 20th Dynasty in ancient Egypt, is one of the most beautiful and well-preserved tombs in the Valley of the Kings. (Xinhua/Sui Xiankai)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220428/79/3207424235637919583.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on April 26, 2022 shows colorful reliefs and murals inside the tomb of Ramesses VI in the Valley of the Kings in Luxor, Egypt. The tomb of Ramesses VI, a ruler of the 20th Dynasty in ancient Egypt, is one of the most beautiful and well-preserved tombs in the Valley of the Kings. (Xinhua/Sui Xiankai)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ King's Day celebrated in Amsterdam ]]></title>
	<news_id>10090343</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0428/c90000-10090343.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 09:06:34 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220428/42/14310876874458247450.png" /></p> <p> People attend celebrations on King's Day in Amsterdam, the Netherlands, on April 27, 2022. King's Day (Koningsdag in Dutch) is a national holiday in the Kingdom of the Netherlands, celebrated on April 27, King Willem-Alexander's birthday. (Photo by Sylvia Lederer/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220428/33/2409061176140584477.png" /></p> <p> People celebrate King's Day on boats on a canal in Amsterdam, the Netherlands, on April 27, 2022. King's Day (Koningsdag in Dutch) is a national holiday in the Kingdom of the Netherlands, celebrated on April 27, King Willem-Alexander's birthday. (Photo by Sylvia Lederer/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220428/77/10726013187764356761.png" /></p> <p> People attend celebrations on King's Day in Amsterdam, the Netherlands, on April 27, 2022. King's Day (Koningsdag in Dutch) is a national holiday in the Kingdom of the Netherlands, celebrated on April 27, King Willem-Alexander's birthday. (Photo by Sylvia Lederer/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Mandarin-Speaking Australian Tour Guide: “Chinese history and culture need to be known by more people” ]]></title>
	<news_id>10090046</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0427/c90000-10090046.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 17:54:51 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <center> <video controls="controls" poster="http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/4/27/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-PengYuKai_fe47a3736d44db0e9f394c2fa3ff7f6d.png" src=" http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/4/27/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-PengYuKai_1fc628b7309abcc152bbd7a77f4f6359.mp4" style=" width: 830px; height:550px;"> <p> &nbsp;</p> </video> </center> <p> As an Australian citizen, Justin Steele has long served as a tour guide who has kept a strong connection with China, Chinese tourists and Chinese culture.&nbsp;“It was a choice in following my destiny to select Chinese as second language because I expected to help more people learn about China's rich history and its diverse cuisines,” he said.</p> <p> Steele, who also has a Chinese name, Hailin Wen, has been a tour guide in Sydney for many years now. The Australian man, who speaks fluent Chinese, has a great passion for Chinese culture and offers guide services for tourists in Mandarin Chinese. Through the years, he has helped many Chinese visitors to enjoy a wonderful journey in Sydney, Australia, by offering his Mandarin-speaking tours.</p> <p> “There are a lot of people in Sydney and in Australia with a Chinese background, and I think those people are really important in building relationships. So this Chinatown tour that I’ve launched is focused on telling the story of Chinese-Australians and to celebrate the contributions that the Chinese people have made to Australia over the last 200 years,” said Steele.&nbsp;</p> <p> Steele used to work as a corporate lawyer until one day he finally decided to quit his job and pursue a happier career as a tour guide and travel consultant. He noted that the most exciting thing about this job is to show people different places and bring people together to experience historical stories.</p> <p> In 2018, Steele founded AussieYou Travel (now called Local Sauce), a travel agency that offers small group tour services for tourists worldwide. Its Walking Sydney's Chinatown tour has been among the most popular options for Chinese tourists. This tour was designed to give visitors a chance to learn more about the Chinese communities residing in Australia. During the two-hour tour, Steele usually takes the visitors to Chinatown, tasting authentic Chinese snacks and exploring the early history and development of the community.</p> <p> “When people talk about Chinese food, they may only know Sichuan, Shanghai and Cantonese cuisine, but they don't know what Rou Jia Mo and lamb kebabs are, so I want more people to taste special snacks from different parts of China,” said the man.</p> <p> Actually, Steele personally knows many of the Chinese restaurant owners there. He would always give them a warm hello every time he passes by. “These restaurants have lost so much business over the past two years because of COVID. So I want to help them in this way,” he said.</p> <p> Other than Chinese cuisine, Steele also takes the time to introduce the history behind some of the different Chinese communities in Australia. He takes the visitors to places such as the&nbsp;Australian Chinese&nbsp;Ex-Services&nbsp;Monument and the Golden Water Mouth Tree, a feng shui-stylized treasure tree covered in 23-karat gold leaf at the entranceway to the local Chinatown.&nbsp;</p> <p> To encourage the tourists to learn more about how the local Chinese community has contributed to the development of Sydney, Steele even designed an educational game, where participants are divided into different teams and then compete to find nine Chinese-Australians and list their contributions to society.&nbsp;</p> <p> Steele’s interest in China began all the way back when he was in primary school. At that time, he was living with his family whose home was located in the Chinese community of Brisbane. With the influence of many Chinese and Asian classmates, he chose Chinese as a second language to study as a young pupil. This learning experience then accompanied him through his high school and university years.&nbsp;</p> <p> “China has been a big part of my life and I made many Chinese friends both in Australia and China,” he said.</p> <p> At the age of 16, Steele went to Guilin for an exchange study trip where he received a Chinese name from his host family. During this exchange trip, he visited Shanghai, Beijing, and many other places in China. After graduating from high school, the young man went on to study at Nanjing University, where he spent a great deal of vocational time traveling everywhere around the country as a student. No matter where he went, he would always do his best to taste the local food and learn about local culture, “this is the best way to understand the diversity of China.”</p> <p> Nowadays, Chinese tourists have become an important group for Steele’s business in Australia. More than 50 percent of his clients are Chinese, having seen overall a 40 percent increase in his total number of clients from 2018 to 2019. This number was expected to double by 2020, but the business was met with its most severe challenge to date over the last two years due to the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp;</p> <p> Even so, Steele remains optimistic about his career. He never regretted entering into the tourism industry. He is also really looking forward to welcoming more tourists to Australia after the pandemic is over. “I hope my little tours can play a part to help in improving relations and improving people’s knowledge in recognition of the importance of the China-Australia relationship through tourism,” he said.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China key contributor to safeguarding Cambodia's famed Angkor Archaeological Park ]]></title>
	<news_id>10090198</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0427/c90000-10090198.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 17:12:29 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> PHNOM PENH, April 27 (Xinhua) -- China has been one of the key contributors to safeguarding, preserving and developing the famed Angkor Archaeological Park in northwest Cambodia's Siem Reap province, officials said on Wednesday.</p> <p> The Angkor Archaeological Park, inscribed on the World Heritage List of the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) in 1992, is the most popular tourist destination in the Southeast Asian nation.</p> <p> Covering an area of 401-square kilometers, the Angkor site contains the magnificent remains of the different capitals of the Khmer Empire from the ninth to the 15th century, and it consists of scores of key temples such as the Angkor Wat, Angkor Thom, Bayon, Chau Say Tevoda and Ta Keo, among others.</p> <p> Long Kosal, deputy director-general and spokesman for the Apsara National Authority, which is the government agency responsible for managing, safeguarding and preserving the site, said China has helped restore ruined temples there since 1997, restoring the Chau Say Tevoda temple and the Ta Keo temple successfully.</p> <p> He said the restoration work on the Chau Say Tevoda was completed in 2008 and on the Ta Keo, which started in late 2010, was concluded in 2018.</p> <p> "And since 2019, the Chinese experts have begun working on the 11-year restoration project of the Phimeanakas temple located inside the walled enclosure of the Royal Palace of the Angkor Thom," he told Xinhua.</p> <p> Built in the middle of the 10th century, the Phimeanakas temple was considered a place of worship in the Royal Palace, which covered an area of 581 meters long and 242 meters wide.</p> <p> Kosal said that despite the COVID-19 pandemic, the restoration work is still going on smoothly.</p> <p> "We highly value China's active contribution to the protection, preservation and development of the Angkor," he said. "China's assistance has not only contributed to ensuring the sustainable development of our cultural heritage, but also helped train Cambodian experts on restoration and preservation work."</p> <p> Meanwhile, Kosal said that during the pandemic when few tourists visited the site, the Apsara National Authority had taken the opportunity to do renovation work, maintenance and gardening at the site in order to improve its beauty.</p> <p> "Now, the Angkor Archaeological Park is ready to welcome all tourists from around the world," he said. "As our country has reopened its borders to fully vaccinated travelers without quarantine, I believe that more international tourists will spend their holidays visiting the Angkor in the near future."</p> <p> Prior to the pandemic, the Angkor attracted up to 2.2 million international visitors in 2019, earning 99 million U.S. dollars in revenue from ticket sales.</p> <p> Tourism ministry's secretary of state and spokesman Top Sopheak said the number of foreign tourists to the Angkor has gradually recovered in the first quarter of 2022, adding that it received 19,840 foreign tourists during the January-March period this year, up 342 percent from 4,482 over the same period last year.</p> <p> "Now, the Angkor attracts about 400 foreign tourists a day, a gradual increase from only 70 per day during the pandemic in the past two years," he told Xinhua.</p> <p> Sopheak recalled that prior to the pandemic, the site received up to 9,000 international visitors a day.</p> <p> Chhay Sivlin, president of the Cambodia Association of Travel Agents, said some tour and travel operators have restarted their businesses after the country has fully resumed its socioeconomic activities and reopened its borders to vaccinated travelers without quarantine, buoyed by high vaccination rates.</p> <p> "We hope that international visitors will gradually return to Cambodia, especially to the Angkor, because several flights between Cambodia and other countries have been resumed," she said.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Exquisite meticulous painting brings creations to life ]]></title>
	<news_id>10090073</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0427/c90000-10090073.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 15:18:15 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <center> <video controls="controls" poster=" http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/4/27/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_0a1052a0d52770f3f4685a5b7cfa8c83.jpeg" src=" http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/4/27/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_22c130ddbed62dd85f168f64d25c873d.mp4" style=" width: 830px; height:550px;"> <p> &nbsp;</p> </video> </center> <p> Have you ever seen such a vivid kitten or delicious-looking grapes on paper? Meticulous painting is a Chinese painting technique that uses bamboo brushes for very detailed work on a special treated paper.</p> <p> Click to learn about this exquisite style of painting.</p> <p> <em>(Video source: Kuaishou)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily App</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Israel's national annual Holocaust remembrance day to be marked ]]></title>
	<news_id>10090051</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0427/c90000-10090051.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 14:52:19 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220427/72/2156339946236228704.png" /></p> <p> People visit Yad Vashem, the World Holocaust Remembrance Center, in Jerusalem on April 26, 2022. Israel's national annual Holocaust remembrance day will be marked on Wednesday and Thursday, in remembering the 6 million Jews who perished in the Holocaust during the Second World War. (Photo by Gil Cohen Magen/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220427/9/5370206829493997561.png" /></p> <p> People visit Yad Vashem, the World Holocaust Remembrance Center, in Jerusalem on April 26, 2022. Israel's national annual Holocaust remembrance day will be marked on Wednesday and Thursday, in remembering the 6 million Jews who perished in the Holocaust during the Second World War. (Xinhua/Wang Zhuolun)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220427/23/11652073601145464839.png" /></p> <p> People visit Yad Vashem, the World Holocaust Remembrance Center, in Jerusalem on April 26, 2022. Israel's national annual Holocaust remembrance day will be marked on Wednesday and Thursday, in remembering the 6 million Jews who perished in the Holocaust during the Second World War. (Xinhua/Wang Zhuolun)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220427/27/11233125648793970927.png" /></p> <p> People visit Yad Vashem, the World Holocaust Remembrance Center, in Jerusalem on April 26, 2022. Israel's national annual Holocaust remembrance day will be marked on Wednesday and Thursday, in remembering the 6 million Jews who perished in the Holocaust during the Second World War. (Xinhua/Wang Zhuolun)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220427/57/8672824982910720665.png" /></p> <p> People visit Yad Vashem, the World Holocaust Remembrance Center, in Jerusalem on April 26, 2022. Israel's national annual Holocaust remembrance day will be marked on Wednesday and Thursday, in remembering the 6 million Jews who perished in the Holocaust during the Second World War. (Photo by Gil Cohen Magen/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China steps up weather protection for cultural heritage sites, artifacts ]]></title>
	<news_id>10089980</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0427/c90000-10089980.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 11:19:26 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, April 26 (Xinhua) -- China's National Cultural Heritage Administration on Tuesday urged extra protection against extreme weather for cultural artifacts and historical sites.</p> <p> Cultural heritage authorities and museums across the country should keep track of extreme weather and respond in a timely manner, the administration said in an emergency notice.</p> <p> Ancient constructions and affiliated museums, as well as heritage conservation and excavation sites, must be checked for potential risks, the notice said.</p> <p> It also called for responsive measures and supplies to cope with damage to constructions and the falling of historically significant and ancient trees.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Beijing theatre offers 18 consecutive shows “Poetic dance: The Journey of a Legendary Landscape Painting” ]]></title>
	<news_id>10089846</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0427/c90000-10089846.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 09:59:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0427/FOREIGN202204270946000006417888057.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>A stage photo of the dance show “Poetic Dance: The Journey of a Legendary Landscape Painting.” (Photo courtesy of the China Oriental Performing Arts Group)</em></p> <p> Between April 8 and 24, a total of 18 performances of the dance show “Poetic Dance: The Journey of a Legendary Landscape Painting” were staged consecutively at the Poly Theater in Beijing, capital of China.</p> <p> After making its debut at the National Centre for the Performing Arts in Beijing in August 2021, the show went on a nationwide tour, performing in 16 cities across the country, totaling 50 performances, winning wide praise from audiences.</p> <p> According to the Poly Theater in Beijing, tickets for the dance show sold out instantly after being available for reservations, with the theatre eventually adding three more shows in order to meet audiences’ needs.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0427/FOREIGN202204270946000166368843655.jpeg" style="width: 902px; height: 601px;" /></p> <p> <em>A stage photo of the dance show “Poetic Dance: The Journey of a Legendary Landscape Painting.” (Photo courtesy of the China Oriental Performing Arts Group)</em></p> <p> A total of 19,000 people watched the 18 shows, with the seat occupancy rate for each show being as high as 98 percent, said Yao Rui, general manager of the Beijing Poly Theater Management Co., Ltd. The show broke the record for most consecutive performances of a Chinese dance show in one city.</p> <p> Cultural and creative products related to the dance show, such as masks, thermals, post cards, notebooks, hair bands and bags, were popular purchases for audience members while waiting for the performances to begin at the Poly Theater in Beijing.</p> <p> Jing Xiaoyong, head of the China Oriental Performing Arts Group, stated that the dance show has eyed diverse and mature partnerships with cultural and creative brands. “This fully proves that dance shows have been integrated into daily life, and their influence can be found in every aspect of society,” Jing said.&nbsp;</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0427/FOREIGN202204270946000337718433203.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 571px;" /></p> <p> <em>A stage photo of the dance show “Poetic Dance: The Journey of a Legendary Landscape Painting.” (Photo courtesy of the China Oriental Performing Arts Group)</em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0427/FOREIGN202204270946000485974311621.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 378px;" /></p> <p> <em>A stage photo of the dance show “Poetic Dance: The Journey of a Legendary Landscape Painting.” (Photo courtesy of the China Oriental Performing Arts Group)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
	</channel>
</rss>