<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title> Sports </title>
		<image>
			<title>People's Daily Online</title>
			<link>http://english.people.com.cn/</link>
			<url>http://english.people.com.cn/images/en/top_logo_e.gif</url>
		</image>
		<description>People's Daily Online</description>
		<link>http://english.people.com.cn/90779</link>
		<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 2023 AFC Asia Cup to be relocated from China ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096748</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096748.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 16:09:25 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0514/FOREIGN202205141521000535461869918.jpg" style="width: 634px; height: 357px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>File Photo</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) -- The 2023 Asian Cup football tournament will be relocated from China to a new host, the Asian Football Confederation (AFC) and the tournament's Local Organizing Committee announced on Saturday.</p> <p> "Due to the COVID-19 pandemic, the Chinese Organizing Committee cannot pledge at this moment to hold next year's Asian Cup competition under a fully open model. After negotiations between the AFC, the Chinese Football Association (CFA) and the Local Organizing Committee, a joint decision has been made to remove the 2023 Asian Cup from China to a new host which is to be confirmed soon," read a statement published by the Chinese Organizing Committee.</p> <p> "The Organizing Committee hereby expresses sincere gratitude to the AFC, all host cities and the whole society for their great support during the tournament's preparations," the statement added.</p> <p> The AFC said in a separate statement that it appreciates that China, the CFA and the Local Organizing Committee have made "this very difficult but necessary decision in the collective interests of the AFC Asian Cup 2023, which has also provided the AFC the required time to assess the situation regarding the hosting of the AFC Asian Cup 2023."</p> <p> "The AFC worked closely with the CFA and the AFC Asian Cup China 2023 Local Organizing Committee during the preparations and several milestones were achieved, including the launch of the tournament logo and the unveiling of the newly completed Shanghai Pudong Football Stadium last year," the Asian football governing body added.</p> <p> Details about the next steps related to the hosting of the Asian Cup will be announced in due course, the AFC said.</p> <p> China was awarded the hosting right of the 2023 Asian Cup in June 2019. The 24-team competition was scheduled to be hosted across 10 Chinese cities.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ India overcomes Denmark to make Thomas Cup final for 1st time ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096744</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096744.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 15:06:23 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BANGKOK, May 14 (Xinhua) -- India's men's badminton team made history by defeating Denmark 3-2 in the Thomas Cup semifinals here on Friday and will vie for the trophy against the reigning champions Indonesia.</p> <p> Although India's first singles Lakshya Sen could not challenge world No. 1 Viktor Axelsen, his team took a 2-1 lead after three matches.</p> <p> As the semifinal entered the deciding match after Denmark tied the score in the second doubles, India's remarkable run at the tournament seemed to come to an end when H.S. Prannoy twisted his ankle early in the first set. But he bounced back to win the match 13-21, 21-9, 21-12 against Rasmus Gemke.</p> <p> In the other semifinal, Indonesia cruised into the final again after Anthony Sinisuka Ginting, as well as Mohammad Ahsan/Kevin Sanjaya Sukamuljo, secured a 2-0 lead before Japan put up a tough fight to force a tie. In the third singles match, Shesar Hiren Rhustavito fended off Kodai Naraoka to take the victory for Indonesia.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China out of Thomas Cup after being swept by Indonesia in quarters ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096207</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096207.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:16:39 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BANGKOK, May 13 (Xinhua) -- Chinese men's badminton team suffered a disheartening 3-0 defeat against defending champions Indonesia at the Thomas Cup quarterfinals here on Thursday, which tied China's previous worst result at the tournament.</p> <p> In a repeat of the Thomas Cup final last year, in which Indonesia swept China to claim the trophy, both teams made changes to their line-ups this time.</p> <p> China sent Zhao Junpeng instead of top-ranking Lu Guangzu against Indonesia's Anthony Sinisuka Ginting. Zhao put on an epic struggle in the second set to tie the match but his last-ditch efforts fell short in the third and lost by 21-12, 25-27 and 21-17.</p> <p> In the following doubles match, the combination of Kevin Sanjaya Sukamuljo and Mohammad Ahsan, ranked top and second respectively in the world, proved too good for the Chinese duo Liu Yuchen/Ou Xuanyi to handle as Indonesia extended its lead.</p> <p> In the following singles, China's Li Shifeng couldn't improve from his defeat by Jonatan Christie in the last Thomas Cup final and went down in straight sets (21-13, 21-18) that saw Indonesia advancing to the semifinals.</p> <p> The defeat also marked only the second time in 40 years that the Chinese men's team failed to reach the Thomas Cup semifinals following an early exit in 2016.</p> <p> Indonesia will continue its quest for a back-to-back championship with a semifinal clash against Japan, while India and Denmark meet in the other semifinal.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese men's and women's rosters for Volleyball Nations League unveiled ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095898</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095898.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 16:35:55 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- China's volleyball teams (both men and women) will compete in the upcoming Volleyball Nations League (VNL) 2022 within a month as FIVB announced the squads on Wednesday.</p> <p> Led by new head coach Cai Bin, the Chinese women's team includes 24 players with Yuan Xinyue as the captain. Key players such as Gong Xiangyu, Ding Xia, Diao Linyu and Li Yingying all made the list.</p> <p> The new names include Wu Mengjie and Wang Yizhu, as well as Jin Ye, Wang Yunlu and Xu Jianan.</p> <p> Star spikers Zhu Ting and Zhang Changning, who both played pivotal roles in China's success at the Rio Olympics in 2016 and World championship in 2019, will miss the tournament due to injury.</p> <p> The women's VNL will begin on May 31, with the finals in Ankara, Turkey to be played from July 13 to 17.</p> <p> The following is the Chinese women's squad:</p> <p> Outside spikers: Jin Ye, Wang Yunlu, Wang Yizhu, Li Yingying, Wu Mengjie, Wang Yifan, Zhong Hui</p> <p> Middle blockers: Yuan Xinyue, Yang Hanyu, Gao Yi, Wang Yuanyuan, Zheng Yixin, Wang Wenhan</p> <p> Opposite hitters: Gong Xiangyu, Miao Yiwen, Chen Peiyan, Du Qingqing</p> <p> Setters: Diao Linyu, Cai Yaqian, Ding Xia</p> <p> Liberos: Wang Weiyi, Ni Feifan, Xu Jianan, Wang Mengjie</p> <p> For men's team, which skipped the VNL 2021 due to the COVID-19 pandemic, is trying to go all out for Paris 2024 place. Star players such as Jiang Chuan, Yu Yaochen and Dai Qingyao are on the 25-man list.</p> <p> "We will try our best in the VNL and the World Championships so that we can earn enough points to qualify for the Olympic Qualification tournaments," said Wu Sheng, who was appointed head coach of China's men's team in October 2020.</p> <p> The men's VNL gets underway on June 7, with the finals in Bologna, Italy to be played from July 20 through 24.</p> <p> The following is the Chinese men's squad:</p> <p> Outside spikers: Dai Qingyao, Zhang Binglong, Yu Yuantai, Yuan Dangyi, Zhang Jingyin, Zhai Dejun</p> <p> Middle blockers: Li Yongzhen, Jiang Zhengyang, Zhang Zhejia, Wang Dongchen, Peng Shikun, Dai Haibo, Miao Ruantong</p> <p> Opposite hitters: Jiang Chuan, Wang Jingyi, Zhang Guanhua, Wu Pengzhi</p> <p> Setters: Yu Yaochen, Liu Meng, Chen Leiyang, Wang Hebin</p> <p> Liberos: Qu Zongshuai, Yang Yiming, Yang Tianyuan, Qi Jiahao</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China to send 35 athletes to Gymnasiade 2022 ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095834</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095834.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 16:27:05 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- China will send a contingent of 35 student athletes to compete at the Gymnasiade Normandy 2022 in France, the China School Sports Federation said on Thursday.</p> <p> They will compete in nine sports including athletics, swimming and table tennis.</p> <p> Wang Dengfeng, a senior official with the Ministry of Education, said the biennial event is a good opportunity to showcase the mentality and sports level of contemporary middle school students in China.</p> <p> "We will go all out for the goal of staying safe and showing excellence and harmony," said Wang.</p> <p> Known as the largest international multi-sport event for school students aged between 16 and 18, the Gymnasiade was initiated in Germany in 1974.</p> <p> Gymnasiade Normandy 2022, which will run from May 14 to 22, will draw an estimated 3,500 participants from about 70 countries and regions competing in 20 disciplines.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Thomas Cup: China vs. Denmark ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095715</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095715.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 11:21:45 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/69/16533346896873381473.png" /></p> <p> Li Shifeng of China reacts against Anders Antonsen of Denmark during a group B singles match at the Thomas Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 11, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/65/17109921103629360293.png" /></p> <p> Li Shifeng (L) of China greets Anders Antonsen of Denmark after a group B singles match at the Thomas Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 11, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/18/3612875918872175518.png" /></p> <p> He Jiting (L)/Zhou Haodong of China compete against Anders Skaarup Rasmussen/Frederik Sogaard of Denmark during a group B doubles match at the Thomas Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 11, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/74/5353431284683310670.png" /></p> <p> Anders Antonsen of Denmark competes against Li Shifeng of China during a group B singles match at the Thomas Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 11, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/66/6755892532820440642.png" /></p> <p> Liu Yuchen (front)/Ou Xuanyi of China compete against Kim Astrup/Mathias Christiansen of Denmark during a group B doubles match at the Thomas Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 11, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/75/14914955196034150903.png" /></p> <p> Weng Hongyang of China competes against Hans-Kristian Solberg Vittinghus of Denmark during a group B singles match at the Thomas Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 11, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/38/4205498331766102706.png" /></p> <p> Anders Antonsen of Denmark competes against Li Shifeng of China during a group B singles match at the Thomas Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 11, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Young Chinese men's volleyball team to go all out for Paris 2024 place ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095591</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095591.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:43:55 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- China's men's volleyball team is set to embark on its qualifying campaign for the 2024 Paris Olympics when the 2022 Volleyball Nations League (VNL) kicks off in June.</p> <p> "Our only chance to qualify for Paris 2024 is to earn as many ranking points as possible in the next couple of events," China head coach Wu Sheng told Xinhua on Tuesday.</p> <p> At Paris 2024, world rankings will play a bigger role in the definition of quotas, as a result of FIVB's change to the sport's Olympic qualification system.</p> <p> As host nation, France is entitled to one quota for both men's and women's tournaments. For the remaining 11 quotas for each gender, six will be defined by three Olympic qualification tournaments, to be played in September and October 2023.</p> <p> The three Olympic qualification tournaments will feature eight teams each - 24 total - defined by the FIVB rankings of September 12, 2022 (men) and October 17, 2022 (women). The top two teams in each tournament will qualify for Paris 2024. The five remaining Olympic places will be decided using the FIVB rankings in June 2024, prioritizing countries from continents that do not yet have qualified teams in the Olympic tournament.</p> <p> China's national team is currently training in Jiangmen, Guangdong Province, for the opening VNL game against Iran.</p> <p> "We will try our best in the VNL and the World Championships so that we can earn enough points to qualify for the Olympic Qualification tournaments," said Wu.</p> <p> Wu, who was appointed head coach of China's men's team in October 2020, has handpicked a young squad made up of players mainly born after 1999. Despite a lack of international experience, he is full of praise for his players' physical conditions.</p> <p> "Our height is not inferior to that of the world's top teams, and many of our players have great bounce," Wu said.</p> <p> "Zhang Jingyin, for instance, has a vertical jumping height of 3.70 meters."</p> <p> "Unlike women's games, which focus more on tactics, the trend of men's volleyball lies in a higher, faster, more powerful and all-round attacking line," he added.</p> <p> Wu said that after studies on other elite teams, the coaching staff found that improving the team's serving and receiving is the top priority for the Chinese team.</p> <p> "One can only apply enough strength when he serves and receives right. We have been training our players with the help of additional equipment so that they learn and improve in real-time," said Wu.</p> <p> Besides working on skills, another concern for Wu is the difficulty in knowing at what level China currently stands in the world after skipping many international events over the past two years due to COVID-19. Nevertheless, Wu is determined to qualify for the Paris Olympics.</p> <p> "The players do well in training, and the young players like to play football and basketball in their spare time to reduce pressure. The goal of advancing to the Olympic qualifiers remains unchanged. We will try to seize this opportunity," Wu said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China cruises into Uber Cup quarterfinals with perfect record in group stage ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095238</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095238.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 15:17:49 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/15/12556809364709545491.png" /></p> <p> <em>Chen Qingchen (L)/Jia Yifan of China react in the doubles match against Lee Chia-Hsin/Teng Chun-Hsun of Chinese Taipei during a group B match at the Uber Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 10, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</em></p> <p> BANGKOK, May 11 (Xinhua) -- Defending champion China closed up the Uber Cup group stage with its third victory and cruised into the quarterfinals after strolling past Chinese Taipei 5-0 here on Tuesday.</p> <p> A potential top-level clash in the opening singles didn't materialize as former world no.1 Tai Tzu Ying was absent from Chinese Taipei's lineup. Her teammate Hsu Wen Chi could not stop Olympic champion Chen Yufei who won 21-15 and 21-13.</p> <p> China went on to win the four remaining matches with the only surprise coming from Sung Shuo Yun who snatched the opening set against He Bingjiao, who then staged a rally to take the match 2-1.</p> <p> The three victories in the group stage allowed China to top the group and advance into the quarterfinals. A draw will decide China's opponent in the quarterfinals after all group matches conclude on Wednesday.</p> <p> Rio Olympic gold medalist Carolina Marin made her first appearance in the Uber Cup as Spain beat Australia 4-1. But the efforts fell short as Chinese Taipei secured the other place in the group to qualify for the quarterfinals.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/39/8251802810314579103.png" /></p> <p> Huang Dongping (front)/Li Wenmei of China compete in the doubles match against Chang Ching-Hui/Lee Chih-Chen of Chinese Taipei during a group B match at the Uber Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 10, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/59/3707705455652042371.png" /></p> <p> Wang Zhiyi of China competes in the singles match against Chen Su-Yu of Chinese Taipei during a group B match at the Uber Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 10, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/53/321714531858869549.png" /></p> <p> He Bingjiao of China competes against Sung Shuo-Yun of Chinese Taipei during a group B match at the Uber Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 10, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/15/7300075892044870043.png" /></p> <p> Chen Su-Yu of Chinese Taipei competes in the singles match against Wang Zhiyi of China during a group B match at the Uber Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 10, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/19/116110264107386611.png" /></p> <p> He Bingjiao of China reacts in the singles match against Sung Shuo-Yun of Chinese Taipei during a group B match at the Uber Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 10, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Immense pressure during World Cup qualifying defeat to Vietnam, says Chinese midfielder ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094796</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094796.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 17:21:24 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Chinese midfielder Xu Xin said huge psychological pressure played a destructive role in China's humiliating 3-1 loss to Vietnam during their FIFA 2022 World Cup qualifying campaign.</p> <p> The Chinese side were under constant pressure throughout their failed World Cup qualification and it took a heavy toll on their away game against Vietnam in early February, according to Xu.</p> <p> "Before that game all of us were preoccupied with one thought: we cannot afford to lose the game, we cannot afford any hiccup during the game," he said.</p> <p> "This brought huge pressure to us, which badly affected our performance. Admittedly, we were not good enough to be completely sure of beating Vietnam."</p> <p> "Vietnam made impressive progress over the past few years, they were probably determined to beat us in that game," he added.</p> <p> The defeat to Vietnam meant the Chinese side's slim chance to qualify for the World Cup finals was shattered with two more games left.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ In pics: Chen Yufei at Uber Cup badminton tournament ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094345</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094345.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 08:36:39 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ Chen Yufei of China competes against Clara Azurmendi of Spain during the women's singles match of Gr ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220510/98/802542109201410318.png" /></p> <p> Chen Yufei of China competes against Clara Azurmendi of Spain during the women's singles match of Group B at the Uber Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 9, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220510/49/5574599144842385821.png" /></p> <p> Chen Yufei of China competes against Clara Azurmendi of Spain during the women's singles match of Group B at the Uber Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 9, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220510/65/9157043574682279569.png" /></p> <p> Chen Yufei of China competes against Clara Azurmendi of Spain during the women's singles match of Group B at the Uber Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 9, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220510/1/6054952170329687857.png" /></p> <p> Chen Yufei of China competes against Clara Azurmendi of Spain during the women's singles match of Group B at the Uber Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 9, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220510/57/18027680405986842129.png" /></p> <p> Chen Yufei of China competes against Clara Azurmendi of Spain during the women's singles match of Group B at the Uber Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 9, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220510/95/6994162368420751891.png" /></p> <p> Chen Yufei of China serves during the women's singles match of Group B against Clara Azurmendi of Spain at the Uber Cup badminton tournament in Bangkok, Thailand, May 9, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Teng)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Li Ke included in Beijing Guoan team list for new CSL season ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094078</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0509/c90000-10094078.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 14:15:06 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 9 (Xinhua) -- Li Ke appeared on the Beijing Guoan team list unveiled on Sunday for the 2022 Chinese Super League campaign amid worries about his fitness.</p> <p> The fitness level of the naturalized player, also known as Nico Yennaris, has been a concern for Chinese media and Beijing Guoan supporters as he has been out of action since late November when he received an ankle operation in England.</p> <p> Li Ming, general manager of the Beijing club, said in early April that Beijing Guoan already had a well-equipped squad and he was not sure if Li could be included in the team list for the first half of this season's Chinese Super League campaign.</p> <p> "I cannot guarantee he will be on the list for the first half of the season," he then said.</p> <p> The Beijing side has been greatly reinforced after the arrival of Nigerian striker Samuel Adegbenro, Croatian forward Marko Dabro, South Korean defender Kang Sang-Woo and Bosnia and Herzegovina defender Samir Memisevic.</p> <p> The kickoff date of the 2022 Chinese Super League season remains undecided due to the latest wave of COVID-19 cases.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Highlights of Nairobi City Marathon in Kenya ]]></title>
	<news_id>10093761</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0508/c90000-10093761.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 19:55:40 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/65/1066499929992458005.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　Runners participate in the Nairobi City Marathon in Nairobi, Kenya, May 8, 2022. (Photo by John Okoyo/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/87/2313631360393372275.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　Chinese contestants pose for a group photo before the Nairobi City Marathon in Nairobi, Kenya, May 8, 2022. (Xinhua/Long Lei)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/97/11837403126030676241.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　Runners participate in the half marathon during the Nairobi City Marathon in Nairobi, Kenya, May 8, 2022. (Xinhua/Long Lei)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/0/2902112099464318088.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　Runners participate in the Nairobi City Marathon in Nairobi, Kenya, May 8, 2022. (Xinhua/Long Lei)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/14/10612611141688477786.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　Runners participate in the half marathon during the Nairobi City Marathon in Nairobi, Kenya, May 8, 2022. (Xinhua/Long Lei)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/66/6267515356171595130.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　Runners participate in the Nairobi City Marathon in Nairobi, Kenya, May 8, 2022. (Photo by John Okoyo/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/26/12754237032444437758.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　Runners take a group photo before the Nairobi City Marathon in Nairobi, Kenya, May 8, 2022. (Xinhua/Long Lei)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/14/9174510692552905998.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　Brimin Misoi, the marathon winner, crosses the finish line during the Nairobi City Marathon in Nairobi, Kenya, May 8, 2022. (Xinhua/Li Zhuoqun)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/12/10393458765758630436.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　Runners participate in the Nairobi City Marathon in Nairobi, Kenya, May 8, 2022. (Photo by John Okoyo/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/59/11193682792235179083.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　Runners participate in the Nairobi City Marathon in Nairobi, Kenya, May 8, 2022. (Xinhua/Long Lei)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/62/1558935290151905434.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　Runners pose for photos while participating in the Nairobi City Marathon in Nairobi, Kenya, May 8, 2022. (Photo by John Okoyo/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ In pics: Formula One Grand Prix of Miami qualifying session ]]></title>
	<news_id>10093753</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0508/c90000-10093753.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 18:56:36 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/94/15078700488292062434.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　Ferrari's Carlos Sainz of Spain competes during the qualifying session for the Formula One Grand Prix of Miami at the Miami International Autodrome in Miami Gardens, Florida, the United States, May 7, 2022. (QIAN JUN M via Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/42/487723685708869466.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　Ferrari's Charles Leclerc (R) of Monaco speaks with Red Bull's Max Verstappen of the Netherlands following the qualifying session for the Formula One Grand Prix of Miami at the Miami International Autodrome in Miami Gardens, Florida, the United States, May 7, 2022. (QIAN JUN M via Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/73/5313629458999341105.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　Alfa Romeo's Zhou Guanyu of China competes during the qualifying session for the Formula One Grand Prix of Miami at the Miami International Autodrome in Miami Gardens, Florida, the United States, May 7, 2022. (QIAN JUN M via Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/95/12142449386492935971.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　Red Bull's Max Verstappen of the Netherlands competes during the qualifying session for the Formula One Grand Prix of Miami at the Miami International Autodrome in Miami Gardens, Florida, the United States, May 7, 2022. (QIAN JUN M via Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/49/16303797590829548801.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　Alfa Romeo's Zhou Guanyu of China reacts before the qualifying session for the Formula One Grand Prix of Miami at the Miami International Autodrome in Miami Gardens, Florida, the United States, May 7, 2022. (QIAN JUN M via Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/14/17130270313371406062.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　Ferrari's Charles Leclerc of Monaco competes during the qualifying session for the Formula One Grand Prix of Miami at the Miami International Autodrome in Miami Gardens, Florida, the United States, May 7, 2022. (QIAN JUN M via Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220508/84/7332719476974615304.jpg" /></p> <p> 　　Mercedes' Lewis Hamilton of Britain competes during the qualifying session for the Formula One Grand Prix of Miami at the Miami International Autodrome in Miami Gardens, Florida, the United States, May 7, 2022. (QIAN JUN M via Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China aims to win Thomas &Uber Cup in Bangkok ]]></title>
	<news_id>10093689</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0508/c90000-10093689.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 16:04:47 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> 　　BANGKOK, May 7 (Xinhua) -- China's badminton coach Xia Xuanze vowed on Saturday that the Chinese team aims to win the Thomas and Uber Cup titles.</p> <p> 　　Set to run from May 8 to 15, the tournament features a number of the world's top players. Tokyo Olympic champion Chen Yufei leads Chinese women's squad which includes veteran players Chen Qingchen and Jia Yifan, as well as young faces like Wang Zhiyi, who had a stunning record recently.</p> <p> 　　The Chinese women's team lost to Thailand in the same venue in 2018. Despite a stronger line-up this time, "all of us should be prepared for a tough battle and strive for every victory," Xia said after Saturday's training session.</p> <p> 　　The men's team includes 22-year-old Wen Hongyang, who won the men's singles title at the BWF South Korea Open last month.</p> <p> 　　Major tournament experience is precious for training the athletes' will and cultivating the spirit of unity and cooperation, Xia said.</p> <p> 　　China has been drawn in Group B in Thomas Cup with Algeria, Denmark and France, and Group B in Uber Cup with Chinese Taipei, Spain and Australia.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese snowboarder Zhang Jiahao: Do what you want to do ]]></title>
	<news_id>10093615</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0507/c90000-10093615.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 17:03:46 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <center> <video controls="controls" poster=" http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/5/7/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_d19836ade84ad162dfcf046d3a534391.jpg" src=" http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/5/7/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_72d9688a4521c9b5b3e3db72c470d3bc.mp4" style=" width: 830px; height:550px;"> <p> &nbsp;</p> </video> </center> <p> Chinese snowboarder Zhang Jiahao, who once trained as a baker, shares his story of pursuing his dream of competing at the Beijing 2022 Winter Olympics.</p> <p> Zhang, now 27, has exceeded his wildest expectations. “Do what you want to do,” advises Zhang.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily App</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chengdu World University Games rescheduled for 2023 ]]></title>
	<news_id>10093143</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0506/c90000-10093143.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 17:02:39 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> CHENGDU, China, May 6 (Xinhua) -- The Chengdu 2021 World University Games has been postponed until 2023, the International University Sports Federation (FISU) announced on Friday.</p> <p> The FISU said in a news release that the decision was made following extensive discussions between FISU, the Chengdu 2021 Organizing Committee and other stakeholders.</p> <p> The FISU Games had initially been scheduled for the summer of 2021 but were rescheduled for June this year following the postponement of the Olympic Games in Tokyo 2020.</p> <p> "The decision to reschedule Chengdu 2021 is not one that was made easily, but it is the right decision for university athletes. Their welfare is always our number one priority. Continued uncertainty over conditions has made rescheduling the sensible choice - a number of National University Sports Federations had already changed their plans," said Acting FISU President Leonz Eder.</p> <p> "Taking a team to the FISU World University Games is a great responsibility and FISU is confident that this decision will enable the greatest possible number of university athletes to attend next year."</p> <p> Despite the postponement, Eder paid tributes to the Chengdu organizers for their preparatory work over the past three years.</p> <p> "The Chengdu organizing committee has made great efforts for the preparatory work since its successful bid. FISU thanks the Chengdu Organizing Committee for its hard work," said Eder.</p> <p> Chengdu will be the third Chinese city to host the Universiade, after Beijing and Shenzhen in 2001 and 2011 respectively.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ OCA announces decision to postpone 19th Asian Games ]]></title>
	<news_id>10093134</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0506/c90000-10093134.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 16:59:21 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220506/48/12847183860463735200.jpg" /></p> <p> <strong>The Olympic Council of Asia (OCA) decided to postpone the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou, China.</strong></p> <p> TASHKENT, May 6 (Xinhua) -- Following detailed discussions with the Chinese Olympic Committee (COC) and the Hangzhou Asian Games Organising Committee (HAGOC), the Olympic Council of Asia (OCA) Executive Board Friday decided to postpone the 19th Asian Games, which were scheduled to be held in Hangzhou, China, from 10 to 25 September 2022.</p> <p> The new dates will be agreed between the OCA, the COC and the HAGOC and announced in the near future, it said.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Hangzhou dressed up for upcoming Asian Games ]]></title>
	<news_id>10092962</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0506/c90000-10092962.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 14:00:58 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220506/39/4691157366125828683.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Mascots for the Hangzhou 2022 Asian Games attract visitors in Hangzhou, east China's Zhejiang Province, May 5, 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Wang Gang)</em></p> <p> Hangzhou is ready for the upcoming Asian Games which will be held from Sept 10 to 25, 2022 in Hangzhou.</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220506/97/3438453234426906081.jpg" /></p> <p> Mascots for the Hangzhou 2022 Asian Games are displayed in the West Lake scenic area, Hangzhou, east China's Zhejiang Province, May 5, 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Wang Gang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220506/95/17150849603780710787.jpg" /></p> <p> A tourists watches 3D naked eye video featuring the mascots for the Hangzhou 2022 Asian Games by the West Lake, Hangzhou, east China's Zhejiang Province, May 5, 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Wang Gang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220506/18/17176697381889623490.jpg" /></p> <p> Mascots for the Hangzhou 2022 Asian Games are displayed along the West Lake Walkway in Hangzhou, east China's Zhejiang Province, May 5, 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Wang Gang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220506/20/7904141465260997344.jpg" /></p> <p> Photo shows beautiful street view to welcome the upcoming Hangzhou 2022 Asian Games in Hangzhou, east China's Zhejiang Province, May 5, 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Wang Gang)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Ecns.cn</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ UEFA Champions League: Real Madrid vs. Manchester City ]]></title>
	<news_id>10092431</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0505/c90000-10092431.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 13:20:23 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220505/16/3565193109263121192.png" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's Luka Modric (R) vies with Manchester City's Kevin De Bruyne during the UEFA Champions League semifinal second leg football match between Real Madrid of Spain and Manchester City of England in Madrid, Spain, May 4, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220505/21/9947274139941943861.png" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's Karim Benzema competes during the UEFA Champions League semifinal second leg football match between Real Madrid of Spain and Manchester City of England in Madrid, Spain, May 4, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220505/98/4675627436834288818.png" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's Dani Carvajal (R) vies with Manchester City's Jack Grealish (2nd R) during the UEFA Champions League semifinal second leg football match between Real Madrid of Spain and Manchester City of England in Madrid, Spain, May 4, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220505/61/4438618672284233893.png" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's Vinicius Junior (R) vies with Manchester City's Kyle Walker during the UEFA Champions League semifinal second leg football match between Real Madrid of Spain and Manchester City of England in Madrid, Spain, May 4, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220505/61/9651414361090294093.png" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's Vinicius Junior (R) vies with Manchester City's Kyle Walker during the UEFA Champions League semifinal second leg football match between Real Madrid of Spain and Manchester City of England in Madrid, Spain, May 4, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220505/89/9519683613802397437.png" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's players celebrate the victory after the UEFA Champions League semifinal second leg football match between Real Madrid of Spain and Manchester City of England in Madrid, Spain, May 4, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220505/86/2259220318178132106.png" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's Casemiro (R) vies with Manchester City's Bernardo Silva during the UEFA Champions League semifinal second leg football match between Real Madrid of Spain and Manchester City of England in Madrid, Spain, May 4, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220505/50/1554730504606663134.png" style="width: 900px; height: 703px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's Vinicius Junior (2nd R) conflicts with Manchester City's Aymeric Laporte (bottom) during the UEFA Champions League semifinal second leg football match between Real Madrid of Spain and Manchester City of England in Madrid, Spain, May 4, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220505/5/16801241307818182197.png" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's Rodrygo (front L) shoots the ball during the UEFA Champions League semifinal second leg football match between Real Madrid of Spain and Manchester City of England in Madrid, Spain, May 4, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220505/92/16949369436924501912.png" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's Luka Modric (C) vies with Manchester City's Bernardo Silva (R) during the UEFA Champions League semifinal second leg football match between Real Madrid of Spain and Manchester City of England in Madrid, Spain, May 4, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220505/69/13753625207205371233.png" style="width: 900px; height: 596px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's Casemiro (C) celebrates the victory after the UEFA Champions League semifinal second leg football match between Real Madrid of Spain and Manchester City of England in Madrid, Spain, May 4, 2022. (Photo by Pablo Morano/Xinhua)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220505/40/17654560012736903456.png" style="width: 900px; height: 617px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's players celebrate the victory after the UEFA Champions League semifinal second leg football match between Real Madrid of Spain and Manchester City of England in Madrid, Spain, May 4, 2022. (Photo by Pablo Morano/Xinhua)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220505/56/3316447580107842160.png" style="width: 900px; height: 592px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's Rodrygo celebrates the victory after the UEFA Champions League semifinal second leg football match between Real Madrid of Spain and Manchester City of England in Madrid, Spain, May 4, 2022. (Photo by Pablo Morano/Xinhua)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220505/30/2609467481367509058.png" style="width: 900px; height: 662px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's Luka Modric celebrates the victory after the UEFA Champions League semifinal second leg football match between Real Madrid of Spain and Manchester City of England in Madrid, Spain, May 4, 2022. (Photo by Pablo Morano/Xinhua)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220505/51/9926503627199116439.png" style="width: 900px; height: 623px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's Karim Benzema celebrates his goal during the UEFA Champions League semifinal second leg football match between Real Madrid of Spain and Manchester City of England in Madrid, Spain, May 4, 2022. (Photo by Pablo Morano/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ I won the AFC Women's Asian Cup 16 years ago and my football lives on ]]></title>
	<news_id>10092073</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0504/c90000-10092073.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 13:02:16 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <center> <video controls="controls" poster=" http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/5/4/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-PengYuKai_573c33b5d3cbe71b810a27fdb6e254a1.jpg " src=" http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/5/4/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-PengYuKai_f564807b15ec6b75730f6db475f75995.mp4 " style=" width: 830px; height:550px;"> &nbsp;</video> </center> <p> “May I join you guys on the field?”, shouted Zhang Tong, a former player on the Chinese national women's football team, to a group of men playing football after work for fun. “Sure!” the amateur footballers shouted back. She was playing right midfield and made some accurate diagonal passes toward her fellow forward players before they completed promising shots on the goal.</p> <p> Few of the men on the pitch, however, realized that this woman playing among them was a member of the winning team that took home the AFC Women's Asian Cup back in 2006.</p> <p> Her shiny medal in her trophy room refreshes the memory for many football fans, men or women, as China was crowned the same title once again 16 years later after defeating South Korea on February 6.</p> <p> Though she is no longer capable of running, dribbling, passing and shooting like she could on the pitch 16 years ago, her football story and experience lives on.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0504/FOREIGN202205041139000435047419040.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 534px;" /></p> <p> <em>Zhang Tong high fives a youth player during a training session on February 26, 2022 (People’s Daily Online/Peng Yukai)</em></p> <p> <strong>Past glory</strong></p> <p> “It was a long time ago, but the glory still remains in our hearts,” said Zhang as she looks back to the championship journey in 2006. Having been benched during all three games during the group stage, Zhang was substituted during the semi-final and played a crucial role in the 1-0 win against DPRK. While people still have high expectations for the team, Zhang still remembers the stress that spread among the players and coaches before the final.</p> <p> “The atmosphere in the team was really stressful,” said Zhang. “Coach Ma Liangxing asked me if I was ready the day before the game, and I said yes even though I wasn’t 100 percent ready.” However, Zhang quickly adjusted herself and she was substituted in the 31st minute during the final against Australia, when China was then down by two goals.</p> <p> “I was really pumped when I ran onto the field, and all the stress was gone.” Playing as the central midfielder, Zhang kept the pressure on the opponent’s defense, which helped China equalize the game in the second half, as well as eventually winning the penalty shoot-out.&nbsp;</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0504/FOREIGN202205041140000441599708675.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on March 23, 2022, shows all the metals that Zhang Tong has won in her career. (People’s Daily Online/Peng Yukai)</em></p> <p> “When you look back on what you’ve done, you still feel a sense of pride,” said Zhang. “Playing for our national team and watching the national flag rise is the utmost honor for every professional football player, and winning the championship makes this glory even precious.”</p> <p> <strong>Start over from the grassroot</strong></p> <p> After a 16-year professional career, Zhang decided to hang up her boots in 2012. However, life after retirement was not as easy as Zhang originally thought.</p> <p> “(I was) really puzzled and confused. I didn’t know what I could do or what I should do,” said Zhang. Luckily, the uncertainty of being unemployed didn’t last too long, and Zhang started working for a professional football club in Beijing. At the same time, Zhang also started to apply for coaching credentials to prepare for her coaching career.</p> <p> “The reason why I applied for coaching credentials is because coaching is what I am aimed to do, and I hope I can utilize my past experience and pass them along to those younger players, especially to all the kids.”</p> <p> After working for a professional football club for a few years, Zhang gradually turned her focus to youth training. Eventually, she became the youth training director at Jujia Football Club, a club focuses on youth football training based in Daxing District in Beijing.</p> <p> Compared to coaching players at other age levels, Zhang has a special fondness for coaching children. In her opinion, coaching children is challenging, yet interesting. “There are a lot of factors that you need to put into consideration before coaching a group of children, (such as) their physical and psychological conditions, as well as their level of understanding,” said Zhang. However, Zhang also felt a sense of relief when the kids come up with some bizarre questions, which added some humor and laughter to her routine job.&nbsp;</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0504/FOREIGN202205041142000517376010619.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 533px;" /></p> <p> <em>Zhang Tong consoles a youth player after a training session at a practice field on February 26, 2022. (People’s Daily Online/Peng Yukai)</em></p> <p> <strong>One step at a time</strong></p> <p> With China having won the Women’s Asian Cup again after 16 years, the expectations and enthusiasm for Chinese football has once again been ignited among the public. While people are curious about when China will have its next super football star, Zhang instead keeps calm about the vague future of Chinese football as well as youth football training.</p> <p> “We need to take one step at a time,” said Zhang. “The meaning of being a youth football coach is to guide our children to get involved in football, and we as coaches should teach them the right value instead of expecting them to reach a certain result. Throwing apart all the result, we must make sure that we are teaching the right things to our kids.”&nbsp;</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0504/FOREIGN202205041143000574266010765.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 534px;" /></p> <p> <em>Youth players in the middle of a training session at a practice pitch on February 26, 2022. (People’s Daily Online/Peng Yukai)</em></p> <p> In terms of what she wants her students to achieve, the very first word that comes up to her mind is happiness. “I hope every one of the kids who come here to play football is happy, and this is what football is all about.”</p> <p> Having stepped away from the spotlight and applause for almost a decade, Zhang has never felt lonely about her current life. Instead, she holds a strong sense of responsibility. “I just want to live my everyday life,” said Zhang. “Football is the greatest asset of my life, and I want to contribute all my effort to football at no matter how old I am.”</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ O'Sullivan seizes seventh title at Snooker Worlds ]]></title>
	<news_id>10091897</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0503/c90000-10091897.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:05:05 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0503/FOREIGN202205031100000193185312114.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>England's Ronnie O'Sullivan celebrates with the trophy during the awarding ceremony after the final over England's Judd Trump at the Betfred World Snooker Championship in Sheffield, England, May 2, 2022. (Photo by Zhai Zheng/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> LONDON, May 2 (Xinhua) -- Ronnie O'Sullivan beat Judd Trump 18-13 on Monday to win the World Snooker Championship title for the seventh time, equaling the record held by Stephen Hendry.</p> <p> The world number one returned to the table on Monday with a 12-5 lead from Sunday, but the 2019 world champion Trump fought hard to close the gap within three frames at 14-11.</p> <p> In the final session, the Rocket dominated the table again, winning the world title at the age of 46 to become the oldest champion in the season-ending tournament.</p> <p> "That's probably the greatest result I've ever had," O'Sullivan told the World Snooker Tour website after clinching his 39th ranking title. "As far as I'm concerned, Judd is already an all-time great. The way he plays the game, he plays such dynamic snooker."</p> <p> O'Sullivan took his first world title in 2001 by beating John Higgins in the final. After more than two decades, these two great players are still in their top forms as they met in the semifinals at the Crucible Theatre this year with O'Sullivan outplaying his long-time rival 17-11.&nbsp;</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/20220503/88/3184300623319109836.jpg" style="height: 599px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> England's Ronnie O'Sullivan celebrates with the trophy during the awarding ceremony after the final over England's Judd Trump at the Betfred World Snooker Championship in Sheffield, England, May 2, 2022. (Photo by Zhai Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Zheng Zhi leaves Guangzhou FC after almost 12 years ]]></title>
	<news_id>10091806</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0502/c90000-10091806.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 16:05:44 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING May 2 (Xinhua) -- Zheng Zhi is noticeably absent from the team list Guangzhou FC unveiled on Monday for the new season of the Chinese Super League.</p> <p> The 41-year-old reportedly chose not to stay on after his contract with the financially stricken Guangzhou side expired at the end of last year.</p> <p> The next destination of the former Charlton midfielder remains unknown.</p> <p> Zheng joined the Guangzhou club, then known as Guangzhou Evergrande, in late June 2010.</p> <p> He won the Chinese Super League title eight times and the Asian Champions League trophy twice with the Guangzhou side.</p> <p> The kickoff date of the 2022 Chinese Super League campaign remains undecided due to the COVID-19 pandemic.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 2022 Outdoor Adventure Show held in Canada ]]></title>
	<news_id>10091686</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0502/c90000-10091686.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 09:44:58 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/2/13152775361485036690.png" /></p> <p> People look at rooftop tents during the 2022 Outdoor Adventure Show in Mississauga, the Greater Toronto Area, Canada, on May 1, 2022. Featuring the latest camping gear, paddle sports, outdoor clothing, scuba diving and ultimate adventure travel destinations, this annual event was held here from Friday to Sunday. (Photo by Zou Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/5/2401159813604436169.png" /></p> <p> A man looks at a hydrofoil ebike during the 2022 Outdoor Adventure Show in Mississauga, the Greater Toronto Area, Canada, on May 1, 2022. Featuring the latest camping gear, paddle sports, outdoor clothing, scuba diving and ultimate adventure travel destinations, this annual event was held here from Friday to Sunday. (Photo by Zou Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/12/1725925269997984748.png" /></p> <p> A coach shows the basics of stand up paddle boarding during the 2022 Outdoor Adventure Show in Mississauga, the Greater Toronto Area, Canada, on May 1, 2022. Featuring the latest camping gear, paddle sports, outdoor clothing, scuba diving and ultimate adventure travel destinations, this annual event was held here from Friday to Sunday. (Photo by Zou Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/31/3760950905777731051.png" /></p> <p> People experience an ATV during the 2022 Outdoor Adventure Show in Mississauga, the Greater Toronto Area, Canada, on May 1, 2022. Featuring the latest camping gear, paddle sports, outdoor clothing, scuba diving and ultimate adventure travel destinations, this annual event was held here from Friday to Sunday. (Photo by Zou Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/81/9220654513107378181.png" /></p> <p> A coach shows boating skills during a Greenland paddle techniques and rolling class at the 2022 Outdoor Adventure Show in Mississauga, the Greater Toronto Area, Canada, on May 1, 2022. Featuring the latest camping gear, paddle sports, outdoor clothing, scuba diving and ultimate adventure travel destinations, this annual event was held here from Friday to Sunday. (Photo by Zou Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China wins three golds at Badminton Asia Championships 2022 ]]></title>
	<news_id>10091664</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0502/c90000-10091664.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 09:15:05 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/68/1045177624070429856.png" /></p> <p> Wang Zhiyi of China poses on the podium after the women's singles final against Yamaguchi Akane of Japan at the Badminton Asia Championships 2022 in Manila, the Philippines, April 30, 2022. (Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/79/6542593243340976495.png" /></p> <p> Wang Zhiyi of China hits a return during the women's singles final against Yamaguchi Akane of Japan at the Badminton Asia Championships 2022 in Manila, the Philippines, April 30, 2022. (Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/24/3848360622668708004.png" /></p> <p> Wang Zhiyi of China reacts during the women's singles final against Yamaguchi Akane of Japan at the Badminton Asia Championships 2022 in Manila, the Philippines, April 30, 2022. (Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/60/17099177630054546028.png" /></p> <p> Wang Zhiyi of China hits a return during the women's singles final against Yamaguchi Akane of Japan at the Badminton Asia Championships 2022 in Manila, the Philippines, April 30, 2022. (Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/54/14338475126284595986.png" /></p> <p> Wang Zhiyi of China hits a return during the women's singles final against Yamaguchi Akane of Japan at the Badminton Asia Championships 2022 in Manila, the Philippines, April 30, 2022. (Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/62/6946789245599931518.png" /></p> <p> Yamaguchi Akane of Japan hits a return during the women's singles final against Wang Zhiyi of China at the Badminton Asia Championships 2022 in Manila, the Philippines, April 30, 2022. (Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/82/10822436373003221778.png" /></p> <p> Wang Zhiyi of China hits a return during the women's singles final against Yamaguchi Akane of Japan at the Badminton Asia Championships 2022 in Manila, the Philippines, April 30, 2022. (Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/46/9993659135942419290.png" /></p> <p> Yamaguchi Akane of Japan hits a return during the women's singles final against Wang Zhiyi of China at the Badminton Asia Championships 2022 in Manila, the Philippines, April 30, 2022. (Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/31/10940024308799799727.png" /></p> <p> Chen Qingchen (1st L)/Jia Yifan (2nd L) and Du Yue (2nd R)/Li Wen of China react during the awarding ceremony for the women's doubles at the Badminton Asia Championships 2022 in Manila, the Philippines, May 1, 2022. (Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/56/3584343164680382752.png" /></p> <p> Chen Qingchen (L)/Jia Yifan of China react during the awarding ceremony for the women's doubles at the Badminton Asia Championships 2022 in Manila, the Philippines, May 1, 2022. (Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/55/12812551172321307411.png" /></p> <p> Chen Qingchen/Jia Yifan (R) of China compete during the women's doubles final against Iwanaga Rin/Nakanish Kie of Japan at the Badminton Asia Championships 2022 in Manila, the Philippines, May 1, 2022. (Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/43/6935411902426922275.png" /></p> <p> Zheng Siwei (L)/Huang Yaqiong of China compete during the mixed doubles final against their compatriots Wang Yilyu/Huang Dongping at the Badminton Asia Championships 2022 in Manila, the Philippines, May 1, 2022. (Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/31/1116289859792933587.png" /></p> <p> Wang Yilyu/Huang Dongping (2nd R) of China greet each other during the mixed doubles final against their compatriots Zheng Siwei/Huang Yaqiong at the Badminton Asia Championships 2022 in Manila, the Philippines, May 1, 2022. (Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Real Madrid claims its 35th LaLiga title, Alaves grab lifeline ]]></title>
	<news_id>10091598</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0501/c90000-10091598.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 14:54:32 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0501/FOREIGN202205011433000535048041388.jpg" style="width: 1023px; height: 682px;" /></p> <p> <em>Real Madrid's Karim Benzema (L) and Marcelo celebrate the victory after a Spanish La Liga football match between RCD Espanyol and Real Madrid in Madrid, Spain, on April 30, 2022. Real Madrid won 4-0 and claimed 35th La Liga title. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</em></p> <p> MADRID, April 30 (Xinhua) -- Real Madrid sealed its 35th La Liga title thanks to a 4-0 win over Espanyol on Saturday afternoon.</p> <p> Two first half goals from Rodrygo and further strikes from Marco Asensio and Karim Benzema saw Carlo Ancelotti's men to an easy win against a rival that looked like an uninvited guest at the celebrations.</p> <p> Ancelotti has now won league titles in Spain, England, France, Germany and Italy.</p> <p> Sevilla's hopes of finishing second suffered a setback when they were held 1-1 at home to struggling Cadiz on Friday night.</p> <p> Youssef En-Neysri's first half header for just his fourth league goal of the season, put Sevilla ahead, but a dogged Cadiz got their reward in the second half thanks to Lucas Perez's excellent free kick.</p> <p> Atletico Madrid's fourth place also looks in doubt as they were beaten 2-0 away to Athletic Club Bilbao, who keep their hopes of playing in Europe next season alive with an impressive win.</p> <p> Inaki Williams' eighth minute cross was deflected into his own net by Atletico defender Mario Hermoso as Athletic dominated the first 25 minutes.</p> <p> Atletico began the second half brightly, but after Antoine Griezmann had rattled the crossbar with a free kick, Williams netted Athletic's second from the penalty spot after Iker Muniain had been fouled.</p> <p> Although Angel Correa saw a deflected shot rebound off the post in injury time, Atletico never looked like recovering from the second goal.</p> <p> The result leaves Athletic a point behind seventh place Villarreal, who suffered a hangover from their Champions League semi-final against Liverpool with a 2-1 defeat away to Alaves.</p> <p> First half goals from Victor Laguardia and Gonzalo Escalante gave Alaves a 2-goal cushion and the side from Vitoria held on to climb above Levante after Samuel Chukwueze pulled a goal back for Villarreal two minutes into the second half.</p> <p> Oscar Duarte scored an 81st minute equalizer for Levante to cancel out Hugo Duro's first half opening goal for Valencia in the city derby.</p> <p> Levante slipped back to bottom of the table after missing chances to win the game after Valencia defender Jose Luis Gaya was sent off for a direct red card after 31 minutes.</p> <p> Levante made 24 shots in the game but collected only one goal from Duarte on 81 minutes. Duro caught the only chance on target for Valencia in the 27th minute.&nbsp;</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0501/FOREIGN202205011434000167275479466.jpg" style="width: 1023px; height: 682px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's players celebrate the victory after a Spanish La Liga football match between RCD Espanyol and Real Madrid in Madrid, Spain, on April 30, 2022. Real Madrid won 4-0 and claimed 35th La Liga title. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0501/FOREIGN202205011434000313762641129.jpg" style="width: 1023px; height: 682px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's Karim Benzema (2nd L), Toni Kroos (2nd R) and Isco (1st R) prepare to play during a Spanish La Liga football match between RCD Espanyol and Real Madrid in Madrid, Spain, on April 30, 2022. Real Madrid won 4-0 and claimed 35th La Liga title. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0501/FOREIGN202205011434000461575544097.jpg" style="width: 1023px; height: 682px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's Carlo Ancelotti (R) communicates with Espanyol's Vicente Moreno Peris before a Spanish La Liga football match between RCD Espanyol and Real Madrid in Madrid, Spain, on April 30, 2022. Real Madrid won 4-0 and claimed 35th La Liga title. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0501/FOREIGN202205011435000015650383723.jpg" style="width: 682px; height: 1023px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's Luka Modric celebrates the victory after a Spanish La Liga football match between RCD Espanyol and Real Madrid in Madrid, Spain, on April 30, 2022. Real Madrid won 4-0 and claimed 35th La Liga title. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0501/FOREIGN202205011435000185813305584.jpg" style="width: 1023px; height: 682px;" /></p> <p> Rafael Nadal greets spectators before a Spanish La Liga football match between RCD Espanyol and Real Madrid in Madrid, Spain, on April 30, 2022. Real Madrid won 4-0 and claimed 35th La Liga title. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0501/FOREIGN202205011435000378178579069.jpg" style="width: 1023px; height: 682px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's players celebrate the victory after a Spanish La Liga football match between RCD Espanyol and Real Madrid in Madrid, Spain, on April 30, 2022. Real Madrid won 4-0 and claimed 35th La Liga title. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0501/FOREIGN202205011435000550944915809.jpg" style="width: 1024px; height: 1024px;" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's Nacho perfoms a bullfight with his children to celebrate the victory after a Spanish La Liga football match between RCD Espanyol and Real Madrid in Madrid, Spain, on April 30, 2022. Real Madrid won 4-0 and claimed 35th La Liga title. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0501/FOREIGN202205011448000158514197884.jpg" /></p> <p> Rafael Nadal (2nd L) kicks off for a Spanish La Liga football match between RCD Espanyol and Real Madrid in Madrid, Spain, on April 30, 2022. Real Madrid won 4-0 and claimed 35th La Liga title. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p> &nbsp;</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0501/FOREIGN202205011448000334666954118.jpg" /></p> <p> Real Madrid's Mariano Diaz (top) heads the ball during a Spanish La Liga football match between RCD Espanyol and Real Madrid in Madrid, Spain, on April 30, 2022. Real Madrid won 4-0 and claimed 35th La Liga title. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ O'Sullivan to face Trump in World Snooker Championship final ]]></title>
	<news_id>10091583</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0501/c90000-10091583.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 13:59:34 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> LONDON, April 30 (Xinhua) -- Ronnie O'Sullivan and Judd Trump will lock horns in the final at the World Snooker Championship after beating John Higgins and Mark Williams respectively on Saturday.</p> <p> O'Sullivan, 46, reached the final in the Crucible Theatre for the eighth time as the world number one beat long-time rival Higgins 17-11.</p> <p> If the Rocket beats Trump on Monday, he will equal Stephen Hendry's record of seven world titles.</p> <p> "I am not focused on titles, what I have won and haven't won," O'Sullivan told the World Snooker Tour website. "It's more about the experience and enjoying it. When I won this title in 2020 it didn't change my life. If I win it again I'm not sure I will feel overly elated. But it would still be nice to have."</p> <p> The 32-year-old Trump held off a sizzling Williams as the 47-year-old fought hard from seven frames behind to lead at 16-15. But the 2019 world champion Trump held his nerve to win the last two frames, reaching the final for the third time.</p> <p> "I said it in every round that it is a free shot and I don't expect anything of myself," said Trump. "I felt a lot better yesterday, like I did against John in 2019. I feel like I am close to being at my best."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China issues commemorative coins for 19th Asian Games ]]></title>
	<news_id>10091127</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0429/c90000-10091127.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 14:33:10 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220429/10/16692581115293773790.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Photo shows the whole set of gold and silver commemorative coins for the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou, east China’s Zhejiang Province issued on April 28. (Photo: China News Service/Wang Gang)</em></p> <p> A set of gold and silver commemorative coins was issued on April 28.</p> <p> The 19th Asian Games Hangzhou 2022 will be held from Sept 10 to 25, 2022 in Hangzhou, east China’s Zhejiang Province.</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220429/43/15960095655544673467.jpg" /></p> <p> Photo shows the front side and the reverse side of the 5-gram gold coin. (Photo: China News Service/Wang Gang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220429/60/9032219325291168104.jpg" /></p> <p> Photo shows the front side and the reverse side of the 5-gram silver commemorative coin for the 19th Asian Games Hangzhou 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Wang Gang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220429/64/16217116508153019168.jpg" /></p> <p> Photo shows the front side and the reverse side of the 30-gram silver coin. (Photo: China News Service/Wang Gang)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Ecns.cn</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Yanqing Olympic Zone to open to public soon as Beijing 2022's continued commitment to ensure a lasting legacy ]]></title>
	<news_id>10090564</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0428/c90000-10090564.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 14:36:49 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, April 27 (Xinhua) -- The Yanqing Olympic Zone, which hosted alpine skiing, bobsleigh, skeleton and luge competitions during the Beijing 2022 Winter Olympics, will open to the general public from Friday, operators said.</p> <p> The Yanqing competition zone, the third area in Beijing titled "Olympic" after the city's Olympic Park and Winter Olympic Park, includes the National Sliding Center and the National Alpine Skiing Center.</p> <p> At the National Sliding Center, visitors can walk along the path on the roof of the venue to enjoy both the full view of the Olympic Village and mountain scenery. Visitors can also take a 30-minute ride on the cable car from the Olympic Village to the National Alpine Skiing Center.</p> <p> "We hope to offer the public a real Winter Olympic experience, so the Games-time features and settings of the venues have been maintained as much as possible," said Li Xin, deputy manager of Beijing Olympic venues operation company.</p> <p> The signature wall of athletes and staff, souvenir shops as well as remote-controlled smart beds all remain to provide an authentic atmosphere for visitors. The food menu designed for the Olympic and Paralympic athletes at Beijing 2022 will also be available.</p> <p> These venues will not only stage winter sports competitions in the future but also become a base camp for mountain activities like rock climbing, hiking and camping, according to Li.</p> <p> Opening its venues to the public represents Beijing 2022's continued commitment to ensure a lasting legacy for the Games.</p> <p> The National Aquatics Center, better known as the "Ice Cube" venue at the Beijing 2022 Games, has already opened to the public.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Highlights of Badminton Asia Championships 2022 doubles 1st round matches ]]></title>
	<news_id>10090109</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0427/c90000-10090109.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 15:54:45 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220427/48/1432555067218957476.png" /></p> <p> Satwiksairaj Rankireddy/Chirag Shetty of India compete during the men's doubles 1st round match against Apiluk Gaterahong/Natchanon Tulamok of Thailand at the Badminton Asia Championships 2022 in Manila, the Philippines, April 26, 2022. (Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220427/72/7593508634437183064.png" /></p> <p> Chen Qingchen (L)/Jia Yifan of China react during their women's doubles first round match against Jeong Na Eun/Kim Hye Jeong of South Korea at the Badminton Asia Championships 2022 in Manila, the Philippines on April 27, 2022. (Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220427/82/6045887869000598330.png" /></p> <p> Lu Ching Yao (R)/Yang Po Han of Chinese Taipei compete during the men's doubles first round match against Hoki Takuro/Kobayashi Yugo of Japan at the Badminton Asia Championships 2022 in Manila, the Philippines on April 26, 2022. (Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220427/25/8981641864845489401.png" /></p> <p> Liu Yuchen (L)/Ou Xuanyi of China compete during the men's doubles first round match against Law Cheuk Him/Lee Chun Hei Reginald of China's Hong Kong at the Badminton Asia Championships 2022 in Manila, the Philippines on April 26, 2022. (Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220427/95/6322408275759277343.png" /></p> <p> Taichi Saito (R)/Akira Koga of Japan compete during the men's doubles first round match against Muhammad Shohibul Fikri/Bagas Maulana of Indonesia at the Badminton Asia Championships 2022 in Manila, the Philippines on April 26, 2022. (Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Serie A football match: Sassuolo vs. FC Juventus ]]></title>
	<news_id>10089572</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0426/c90000-10089572.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 16:45:04 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220426/83/15706559501047113051.png" /></p> <p> Juventus' Dusan Vlahovic (front L) controls the ball during a Serie A football match between Sassuolo and FC Juventus in Reggio Emilia, Italy, on April 25, 2022. (Photo by Federico Tardito/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220426/69/12493162153293600529.png" /></p> <p> Juventus' Leonardo Bonucci (front) vies with Sassuolo's Gianluca Scamacca during their Serie A football match in Reggio Emilia, Italy, on April 25, 2022. (Photo by Federico Tardito/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220426/2/5885821751044233638.png" /></p> <p> Juventus' Paulo Dybala (2nd R) shoots and scores during a Serie A football match between Sassuolo and FC Juventus in Reggio Emilia, Italy, on April 25, 2022. (Photo by Federico Tardito/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220426/32/11270480587389198636.png" /></p> <p> Juventus' Denis Zakaria (R) vies with Sassuolo's Hamed Junior Traore during their Serie A football match in Reggio Emilia, Italy, on April 25, 2022. (Photo by Federico Tardito/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220426/79/11249953016971339171.png" /></p> <p> Juventus' Federico Bernardeschi (R) vies with Sassuolo's Maxime Lopez during their Serie A football match in Reggio Emilia, Italy, on April 25, 2022. (Photo by Federico Tardito/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220426/50/12879369278570138098.png" /></p> <p> Juventus' Dusan Vlahovic (L) vies with Sassuolo's Kaan Ayhan during their Serie A football match in Reggio Emilia, Italy, on April 25, 2022. (Photo by Federico Tardito/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220426/5/16534097510995814645.png" /></p> <p> Juventus' Dusan Vlahovic (back) vies with Sassuolo's Kaan Ayhan during their Serie A football match in Reggio Emilia, Italy, on April 25, 2022. (Photo by Federico Tardito/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220426/23/9765115782038906855.png" /></p> <p> Juventus' Moise Kean (R) shoots and scores during a Serie A football match between Sassuolo and FC Juventus in Reggio Emilia, Italy, on April 25, 2022. (Photo by Federico Tardito/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220426/41/6412743917629386269.png" /></p> <p> Juventus' players celebrate a goal by Moise Kean during a Serie A football match between Sassuolo and FC Juventus in Reggio Emilia, Italy, on April 25, 2022. (Photo by Federico Tardito/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Southwest China’s Chengdu to host green, low-carbon Summer World University Games ]]></title>
	<news_id>10088881</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0425/c90000-10088881.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 13:22:38 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Chengdu, capital of southwest China's Sichuan Province, where the 31st Summer World University Games will take place starting on June 26, 2022, has worked to make the event a green and low-carbon one.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0425/FOREIGN202204251316000277446419586.jpg" style="width: 850px; height: 478px;" /></p> <p> <em>The athletes’ village for the Chengdu 2021 FISU World University Games (Photo courtesy of the Executive Committee of the Chengdu 2021 FISU World University Games)</em></p> <p> “The University Games will be a grand event for youth. The gathering of youth from all over the globe will be a great opportunity to spread the concept of green and low-carbon development,” introduced an official from the Executive Committee of the Chengdu 2021 FISU World University Games Summer.</p> <p> The city, the first one in western China to hold an international multi-sporting event, has made the best use of its existing venues. Only 13 out of the total 49 venues are newly built. Energy conservation measures and green construction materials were used in the construction process, while all the venues will remain in use after the games come to a close.</p> <p> Clean energy, such as wind power and hydrogen power from the Ganzi Tibetan Autonomous Prefecture and Liangshan Yi Autonomous Prefecture in the province, will be consumed at the venues, the main media center as well as the Universiade Village.</p> <p> Moreover, the number of new-energy vehicles (NEV) to be used during the event, such as hydrogen fuel cell vehicles and battery-powered electric vehicles, will hit a record high. Chengdu Public Transport Group Co., Ltd has allocated 1,380 new-energy buses for the transportation of athletes and technical staff, and is working to improve charging infrastructure to further increase the usage of NEVs during the games.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Night view of Hangzhou Esports Center ]]></title>
	<news_id>10088865</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0425/c90000-10088865.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 11:26:20 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220425/2/7339537224999718898.jpg" /></p> <p> Aerial photo shows night view of China Hangzhou Esports Center, a venue of the 19th Asian Games Hangzhou 2022 in Hangzhou, east China's Zhejiang Province, April 24, 2022. The 19th Asian Games will be held in Hangzhou from September 10 to 25. (Photo: China News Service/Wang Gang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220425/75/5639865577762324147.jpg" /></p> <p> Aerial photo shows night view of China Hangzhou Esports Center, a venue of the 19th Asian Games Hangzhou 2022 in Hangzhou, east China's Zhejiang Province, April 24, 2022. The 19th Asian Games will be held in Hangzhou from September 10 to 25. (Photo: China News Service/Wang Gang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220425/97/13643585857280541893.jpg" /></p> <p> Aerial photo shows night view of China Hangzhou Esports Center, a venue of the 19th Asian Games Hangzhou 2022 in Hangzhou, east China's Zhejiang Province, April 24, 2022. The 19th Asian Games will be held in Hangzhou from September 10 to 25. (Photo: China News Service/Wang Gang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220425/19/12903769239782201531.jpg" /></p> <p> Aerial photo shows night view of China Hangzhou Esports Center, a venue of the 19th Asian Games Hangzhou 2022 in Hangzhou, east China's Zhejiang Province, April 24, 2022. The 19th Asian Games will be held in Hangzhou from September 10 to 25. (Photo: China News Service/Wang Gang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220425/46/9799759476592326122.jpg" /></p> <p> Aerial photo shows night view of China Hangzhou Esports Center, a venue of the 19th Asian Games Hangzhou 2022 in Hangzhou, east China's Zhejiang Province, April 24, 2022. The 19th Asian Games will be held in Hangzhou from September 10 to 25. (Photo: China News Service/Wang Gang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220425/71/12221304976069704059.jpg" /></p> <p> Aerial photo shows night view of China Hangzhou Esports Center, a venue of the 19th Asian Games Hangzhou 2022 in Hangzhou, east China's Zhejiang Province, April 24, 2022. The 19th Asian Games will be held in Hangzhou from September 10 to 25. (Photo: China News Service/Wang Gang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220425/27/328901556630147983.jpg" /></p> <p> Aerial photo shows night view of China Hangzhou Esports Center, a venue of the 19th Asian Games Hangzhou 2022 in Hangzhou, east China's Zhejiang Province, April 24, 2022. The 19th Asian Games will be held in Hangzhou from September 10 to 25. (Photo: China News Service/Wang Gang)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Ecns.cn</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Betfred World Snooker Championships 2022: Yan Bingtao vs. Mark Selby ]]></title>
	<news_id>10088431</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0424/c90000-10088431.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 11:24:53 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220424/34/10607073694530249054.png" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Yan Bingtao of China reacts during the 2nd round match against Mark Selby of England at the Betfred World Snooker Championships 2022 in Sheffield, Britain, April 23, 2022. (Photo by Zhai Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220424/60/9534007730343821736.png" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Yan Bingtao (L) of China celebrates after winning the 2nd round match against Mark Selby of England at the Betfred World Snooker Championships 2022 in Sheffield, Britain, April 23, 2022. (Photo by Zhai Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220424/63/8277541237907385147.png" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Yan Bingtao of China competes during the 2nd round match against Mark Selby of England at the Betfred World Snooker Championships 2022 in Sheffield, Britain, April 23, 2022. (Photo by Zhai Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220424/45/13663271106398843821.png" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Yan Bingtao (L) of China reacts during the 2nd round match against Mark Selby of England at the Betfred World Snooker Championships 2022 in Sheffield, Britain, April 23, 2022. (Photo by Zhai Zheng/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's Yan outplays reigning champion Selby at World Snooker Championship ]]></title>
	<news_id>10088411</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0424/c90000-10088411.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 11:24:25 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> LONDON, April 23 (Xinhua) -- Chinese hopeful Yan Bingtao saw off defending champion Mark Selby 13-10 on Saturday to reach the quarterfinals at the World Snooker Championship for the first time.</p> <p> Yan, 22, is making his fourth appearance in Crucible Theater, Sheffield as he booked his place in the year-ending tournament with a world ranking of 16.</p> <p> The 2021 Masters champion showed great composure and patience, winning the longest ever frame in the history of the World Championship after more than 85 minutes to take a 12-10 lead before finishing the last frame with a break of 112.</p> <p> "I just felt very very tired after the long frame," said Yan. "Too many safeties from both of us...He just missed the best chance to back to tie at 11 each."</p> <p> Yan is going to meet three-time world champion Mark Williams as the 47-year-old stormed to the round of last eight by outclassing Jackson Page 13-3 on Friday.</p> <p> "He has been playing very well at this year's World Championship. He's very confident, very strong. But I'm the same, confident and strong," said Yan.</p> <p> Earlier, Yan's compatriot Zhao Xintong lost to Stephen Maguire 13-9 in the second round. The other Chinese players Ding Junhui and Lyu Haotian both failed to pass the opening round.</p> <p> Maguire will face six-time world champion Ronnie O'Sullivan as the world No. 1 reached the quarterfinals at the World Championship for the 20th time after sweeping Mark Allen 13-4.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Highlights of skateboard Vert Final at X Games Chiba 2022 in Japan ]]></title>
	<news_id>10088012</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0423/c90000-10088012.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 14:14:09 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220423/5/306417477528942193.png" /></p> <p> Silver medalist Shibata Moto of Japan competes during the skateboard Vert Final of X Games Chiba 2022 in Chiba, Japan, April 22, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhang Xiaoyu)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220423/5/7898319418540947429.png" /></p> <p> Gold medalist Jimmy Wilkins of the United States reacts during the ceremony after the skateboard Vert Final of X Games Chiba 2022 in Chiba, Japan, April 22, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhang Xiaoyu)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220423/6/11098614537016782542.png" /></p> <p> Bronze medalist Gui Khury of Brazil celebrates during the awarding ceremony after the skateboard Vert Final of X Games Chiba 2022 in Chiba, Japan, April 22, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhang Xiaoyu)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220423/8/16504837070958652856.png" /></p> <p> Bronze medalist Gui Khury (front) of Brazil rests while other contestants pratice for the skateboard Vert Final of X Games Chiba 2022 in Chiba, Japan, April 22, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhang Xiaoyu)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220423/73/12950604380267662361.png" /></p> <p> Bronze medalist Gui Khury of Brazil competes during the skateboard Vert Final of X Games Chiba 2022 in Chiba, Japan, April 22, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhang Xiaoyu)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220423/91/6783246094352543575.png" /></p> <p> Silver medalist Shibata Moto of Japan, gold medalist Jimmy Wilkins of the United States and bronze medalist Gui Khury of Brazil (L to R) pose for photos during the ceremony after the skateboard Vert Final of X Games Chiba 2022 in Chiba, Japan, April 22, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhang Xiaoyu)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220423/72/13879155268167044456.png" /></p> <p> Silver medalist Shibata Moto of Japan competes during the skateboard Vert Final of X Games Chiba 2022 in Chiba, Japan, April 22, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhang Xiaoyu)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220423/89/1106922363005674405.png" /></p> <p> Silver medalist Shibata Moto of Japan reacts during the ceremony after the skateboard Vert Final of X Games Chiba 2022 in Chiba, Japan, April 22, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhang Xiaoyu)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220423/36/14147192066595038800.png" /></p> <p> Gold medalist Jimmy Wilkins of the United States competes during the skateboard Vert Final of X Games Chiba 2022 in Chiba, Japan, April 22, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhang Xiaoyu)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220423/11/17135684576270291635.png" /></p> <p> Bronze medalist Gui Khury of Brazil reacts after the skateboard Vert Final of X Games Chiba 2022 in Chiba, Japan, April 22, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhang Xiaoyu)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220423/75/16226171808106827871.png" /></p> <p> Bronze medalist Gui Khury (R) of Brazil takes a selfie with a supporter during the skateboard Vert Final of X Games Chiba 2022 in Chiba, Japan, April 22, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhang Xiaoyu)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220423/40/12886731941511631772.png" /></p> <p> Bronze medalist Gui Khury of Brazil reacts after the skateboard Vert Final of X Games Chiba 2022 in Chiba, Japan, April 22, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhang Xiaoyu)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220423/14/14732975301751162226.png" /></p> <p> Gold medalist Jimmy Wilkins of the United States competes during the skateboard Vert Final of X Games Chiba 2022 in Chiba, Japan, April 22, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhang Xiaoyu)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Highlights of Serbia Tennis Open ATP 250 series tournament ]]></title>
	<news_id>10087059</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0421/c90000-10087059.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 14:26:43 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220421/41/12004105409532153789.jpg" /></p> <p> Serbia's Novak Djokovic returns the ball during a men's singles match against Serbia's Laslo Djere at Serbia Tennis Open ATP 250 series tournament in Belgrade, Serbia on April 20, 2022. (Photo by Predrag Milosavljevic/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220421/19/18013742374580763795.jpg" /></p> <p> Serbia's Novak Djokovic serves the ball during a men's singles match against Serbia's Laslo Djere at Serbia Tennis Open ATP 250 series tournament in Belgrade, Serbia on April 20, 2022. (Photo by Predrag Milosavljevic/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 2022 Asian Wrestling Championships kick off in Mongolia's capital ]]></title>
	<news_id>10086280</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0420/c90000-10086280.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 09:32:21 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220420/50/5285291396526478462.png" style="height: 691px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Sonoda Arata (L) of Japan competes against Khuderbulga Dorjkhand of Mongolia during the men's Greco-Roman 130kg quarterfinal at the 2022 Asian Wrestling Championships in Ulan Bator, Mongolia, April 19, 2022. (Photo by Suriya/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> ULAN BATOR, April 19 (Xinhua) -- The 2022 Asian Wrestling Championships kicked off in Ulan Bator's Buyant-Ukhaa Sports Complex here on Tuesday.</p> <p> More than 250 Greco-Roman and freestyle wrestlers from 22 countries and regions including Mongolia, Japan, Iran, India, Uzbekistan, Kazakhstan and South Korea are participating in the championships, organizers said, adding that the event is the first to be held in Mongolia in 21 years.</p> <p> The 35th edition of the Asian Wrestling Championships will last until Sunday.&nbsp;</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220420/44/5439771297754755636.png" style="height: 606px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Sakuraba Kodai (L) of Japan competes against Suldkhuu Olonbayar of Mongolia during the men's Greco-Roman 77kg quarterfinal at the 2022 Asian Wrestling Championships in Ulan Bator, Mongolia, April 19, 2022. (Photo by Suriya/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's star spiker Zhu recovers well from wrist surgery ]]></title>
	<news_id>10086017</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0419/c90000-10086017.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 16:29:53 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, April 19 (Xinhua) -- China's women's volleyball star Zhu Ting posted photos of her watching the Barcelona Open tennis tournament on China's Twitter-like Sina Weibo on Tuesday, showing her recovering from wrist surgery.</p> <p> Zhu appears in the photo wearing only a wristband around her injured wrist.</p> <p> Zhu revealed on Weibo two weeks ago that she had undergone wrist surgery. "I need to focus on recovery and hopefully I can make progress," she wrote.</p> <p> Due to her injury, Zhu was not called up to the latest training camp of China's national women's volleyball team.</p> <p> The 27-year-old led China to gold at the Rio Games in 2016 and back-to-back World Cup titles in 2015 and 2019 but struggled with a wrist injury at last year's Tokyo Olympics, where the defending champions failed to advance to the knockout stage.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Guangzhou, Shandong Taishan thrashed by Japanese clubs in AFC Champions League ]]></title>
	<news_id>10085925</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0419/c90000-10085925.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 14:22:11 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220419/84/12753988726153693168.png" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Peng Jiahao (R) of Guangzhou FC vies with Igarashi Taiyo of Kawasaki Frontales during the AFC Champions League 2022 Group I match between Guangzhou FC of China and Kawasaki Frontale of Japan in Johor Bahru, Malaysia, April 18, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhu Wei)</em></p> <p> BANGKOK, April 19 (Xinhua) -- Guangzhou FC and Shandong Taishan FC were both given resounding defeats on Monday in their second matches of the AFC Champions League group stage against Japan's Kawasaki Frontale and Urawa Red Diamonds respectively.</p> <p> Both Chinese teams fielded second-string as clubs are prepare the domestic Chinese Super League whose opening date is yet to be decided.</p> <p> Kawasaki made 10 changes to their starting line-up from their opening 1-1 draw with Ulsan Hyundai of South Korea in Group I, but it took just seven minutes for the J-League champions to open their account, when Kei Chinen headed home from a corner.</p> <p> Guangzhou's defenders could barely keep up with their opponents and Kawasaki were already leading 4-0 after Yu Kobayashi buried his own missed penalty in the 21st minute. The score was 5-0 at half-time. Kawasaki went on to score three more goals in the second half to end the one-sided match 8-0.</p> <p> In Group F, Shandong Taishan held Urawa Red Diamonds until the 26th minute when Takahiro Akimoto broke the deadlock with repeated attempts inside the box. Akimoto then soon won a penalty, which was converted by Alexander Scholz to give the reigning Emperor's Cup champions a 2-0 lead.</p> <p> Urawa kept their dominance into the second half. Two goals by substitute Alex Schalk, including a free-kick from distance, extended the lead to 4-0. A long-range strike in stoppage time confirmed a 5-0 victory for the Japanese side.&nbsp;</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220419/77/9970333212380040681.png" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Tanabe Shuto (C) of Kawasaki Frontales controls the ball during the AFC Champions League 2022 Group I match between Guangzhou FC of China and Kawasaki Frontale of Japan in Johor Bahru, Malaysia, April 18, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhu Wei)</em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220419/26/1228905349073354734.png" style="height: 666px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Peng Jiahao (C) of Guangzhou FC vies with Kobayashi Yu (L) of Kawasaki Frontales during the AFC Champions League 2022 Group I match between Guangzhou FC of China and Kawasaki Frontale of Japan in Johor Bahru, Malaysia, April 18, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhu Wei)</em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220419/87/10075591156636783691.png" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Fan Ruiwei (L) of Guangzhou FC vies with Miyagi Ten of Kawasaki Frontale during the AFC Champions League 2022 Group I match between Guangzhou FC of China and Kawasaki Frontale of Japan in Johor Bahru, Malaysia, April 18, 2022. (Photo by Chong Voon Chung/Xinhua)</em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220419/49/18147902408628030057.png" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Fan Ruiwei (L) of Guangzhou FC competes during the AFC Champions League 2022 Group I match between Guangzhou FC of China and Kawasaki Frontale of Japan in Johor Bahru, Malaysia, April 18, 2022. (Photo by Chong Voon Chung/Xinhua)</em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220419/67/8796282549911090459.png" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Guo Shuai (C) of Guangzhou FC competes during the AFC Champions League 2022 Group I match between Guangzhou FC of China and Kawasaki Frontale of Japan in Johor Bahru, Malaysia, April 18, 2022. (Photo by Chong Voon Chung/Xinhua)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese hopeful Zhao claims first win at World Snooker Championship ]]></title>
	<news_id>10085346</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0418/c90000-10085346.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 12:25:00 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> LONDON, April 17 (Xinhua) -- China's Zhao Xintong won his first match at the World Snooker Championship after seeing off qualifier Jamie Clarke 10-2 on Sunday.</p> <p> Zhao, 25, qualified for the final stages of the year-ending tournament with a highest career ranking of world number seven.</p> <p> After the first session on Saturday, Zhao comfortably led Clarke 7-2. When they returned to the table on Sunday, Zhao took three frames in a row to reach the last 16.</p> <p> "This is my first win at the Crucible so I'm very happy," Zhao was quoted as saying by the World Snooker Tour website. "I need more confidence for the next match, so this win is very important to me."</p> <p> Zhao competed at the 2019 World Championship, but lost to Mark Selby in the opening round. He made a breakthrough this season by winning his maiden ranking title at the UK Championship last December, before adding another trophy in the German Masters.</p> <p> "Even when I was 9-2 up I still felt pressure and I needed to finish the match quickly so that the pressure didn't build," said Zhao.</p> <p> Elsewhere, world number one Ronnie O'Sullivan, who is making his 30th appearance at the Crucible Theatre, defeated David Gilbert 10-5.</p> <p> "Whatever I'm doing now I try to be the best I can be," said the six-time world champion. "30 appearances doesn't really mean anything to me. I want to be a champion and do the business. That's what I'm proud of. I don't care about centuries, I don't care about maximums. I just care about how many majors I've won. It's all about those."</p> <p> The 2022 World Championship will run until May 2.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China wins women's singles, mixed doubles at 2022 South Korea Badminton Masters ]]></title>
	<news_id>10085181</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0418/c90000-10085181.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 09:34:07 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220418/25/1290330665283210049.png" style="height: 697px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>He Bingjiao of China competes during the women's singles final match against her compatriot Chen Yufei at the 2022 Gwangju Yonex Korea Masters in Gwangju, South Korea, April 17, 2022. (Photo by James Lee/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> SEOUL, April 17 (Xinhua) -- China's He Bingjiao claimed the women's singles title, while Wang Yilyu/Huang Dongping took the mixed doubles crown at the 2022 South Korea Badminton Masters held in Gwangju, South Korea on Sunday.</p> <p> Fourth seed He fought hard to overcome Olympic champion Chen Yufei 21-14, 14-21, 21-9 in a final lasting more than one hour.</p> <p> Olympic champions Wang Yilyu and Huang Dongping won against Ou Xuanyi and Olympic mixed silver medalist Huang Yaqiong 21-17, 21-17 in the all-Chinese final.</p> <p> South Korea's veteran players Kim Gi-jung and Kim Sa-rang became the men's doubles champions by overwhelming Tokyo Olympic silver medalists Liu Yuchen and his partner Ou Xuanyi 21-14, 21-16.</p> <p> Second seeds Kim So-yeong and Kong Hee-yong from South Korea won the women's doubles title by smashing their compatriots Baek Ha-na and Lee Yu-lim 21-17, 21-12.</p> <p> Jeon Hyeok-jin ousted Kodai Naraoka of Japan in the men's singles final as the South Korean won in two straight games, 21-17, 21-16.&nbsp;</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220418/25/16568597308190888125.png" style="height: 659px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>He Bingjiao of China competes during the women's singles final match against her compatriot Chen Yufei at the 2022 Gwangju Yonex Korea Masters in Gwangju, South Korea, April 17, 2022. (Photo by James Lee/Xinhua)</em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220418/72/17368772761113421508.png" style="height: 677px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>He Bingjiao of China competes during the women's singles final match against her compatriot Chen Yufei at the 2022 Gwangju Yonex Korea Masters in Gwangju, South Korea, April 17, 2022. (Photo by James Lee/Xinhua)</em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220418/76/6854119632016301436.png" style="height: 669px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>He Bingjiao of China competes during the women's singles final match against her compatriot Chen Yufei at the 2022 Gwangju Yonex Korea Masters in Gwangju, South Korea, April 17, 2022. (Photo by James Lee/Xinhua)</em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220418/47/15591971740612186683.png" style="height: 640px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Chen Yufei of China competes during the women's singles final match against her compatriot He Bingjiao at the 2022 Gwangju Yonex Korea Masters in Gwangju, South Korea, April 17, 2022. (Photo by James Lee/Xinhua)</em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220418/15/16430881939600106547.png" style="width: 647px; height: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>He Bingjiao of China competes during the women's singles final match against her compatriot Chen Yufei at the 2022 Gwangju Yonex Korea Masters in Gwangju, South Korea, April 17, 2022. (Photo by James Lee/Xinhua)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Sun Minghui fuels Zhejiang past Shanghai for CBA final ]]></title>
	<news_id>10085002</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0418/c90000-10085002.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 08:22:02 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220418/75/1876623301500216531.jpg" style="height: 691px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Sun Minghui (R) of Zhejiang Lions breaks through during the semifinal against Shanghai Sharks in the 2021-2022 Chinese Basketball Association (CBA) season in Nanchang, east China's Jiangxi Province, April 17, 2022. (Xinhua/Wan Xiang)</em></p> <p> <strong>Guard Sun Minghui scored 45 points, which equaled his career-high, to power Zhejiang Lions to a 3-0 sweep over Shanghai Sharks in the CBA semifinals. Zhejiang will face Liaoning Flying Leopards in the finals.</strong></p> <p> NANCHANG, China, April 17 (Xinhua) -- Sun Minghui notched a game-high 45 points to help the Zhejiang Lions edge the Shanghai Sharks 103-100, advancing into the finals 3-0 in the best-of-five semifinals of the Chinese Basketball Association (CBA) on Sunday.</p> <p> In addition to Sun, Jahlil Okafor contributed another 13 points, followed by Zhao Yanhao's 12 points. Wang Zhelin grabbed a team-high 26 points and 11 rebounds for Shanghai. Jamaal Franklin added 21 points.</p> <p> Zhejiang center Hu Jinqiu, MVP of the regular season, was absent for a splenic rupture picked up when he vied for a rebound with Shanghai point guard Franklin in Game 2 on Friday.</p> <p> Though Shanghai made a 7-2 opener, Zhejiang quickly fought back after Zhao was put on the court to pocket 12 points in seven minutes. Entering the second quarter 28-21, Sun led Zhejiang to deliver a 10-0 run to end the first half 53-37.</p> <p> However, Zhao was sent to hospital for feeling headache during the interval, marking Zhejiang's loss of another regular starter.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220418/0/12041401101586430328.jpg" style="width: 784px; height: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Sun Minghui (C) of Zhejiang Lions goes up for a layup during the semifinal against Shanghai Sharks in the 2021-2022 Chinese Basketball Association (CBA) season in Nanchang, east China's Jiangxi Province, April 17, 2022. (Xinhua/Wan Xiang)</em></p> <p> During the second half, with Zhejiang lacking momentum in attack, Shanghai made a 13-1 comeback to cut the deficit to 75-73 by the end of the third quarter.</p> <p> Then Sun stood out by keeping Zhejiang's slight advantage until the final second. When Franklin failed his three-pointer attempt before the whistle, Zhejiang locked the ticket for the finals.</p> <p> "It is a pity to lose the game, but all the team members worked hard during the whole season. I think they did a good job by sparing no efforts in the game, and hope that we will have a fresh start next season," said Shanghai head coach Li Chunjiang.</p> <p> Zhejiang will face the Liaoning Flying Leopards in the final.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's shuttlers out of 2022 Korea Masters men's singles ]]></title>
	<news_id>10084930</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0416/c90000-10084930.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 14:23:06 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0416/FOREIGN202204161358000589358050002.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 657px;" /></p> <p> <em>Chen Yufei of China competes during the women's singles quarterfinal match against Takahashi Asuka of Japan at the 2022 Gwangju Yonex Korea Masters in Gwangju, South Korea, April 15, 2022. (Photo by James Lee/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> SEOUL, April 15 (Xinhua) -- Lu Guangzu, the only Chinese player in the men's singles quarterfinals of the 2022 Korea Masters, was edged out of the tournament in Gwangju, South Korea on Friday.</p> <p> Fourth seed Lu was defeated by sixth seed Sitthikom Thammasin of Thailand 16-21, 21-12, 21-15, leaving no remaining Chinese shuttlers in the men's singles draw.</p> <p> In the women's singles, Olympic champion Chen Yufei of China breezed past Japan's Asuka Takahashi 21-14, 21-10. Fourth seed He Bingjiao of China took an easy win over South Korea's Lee Se-yeon 21-9, 21-10, while He's compatriot Wang Zhiyi outplayed Singapore's Yeo Jia Min 21-13, 21-13.</p> <p> Two Chinese pairs advanced into the mixed doubles as Olympic champions Wang Yilyu and Huang Dongping overwhelmed Japanese duo Yujiro Nishikawa and Saori Ozaki 21-4, 21-6, while Ou Xuanyi, paired with Olympic mixed silver medalist Huang Yaqiong, outclassed South Korea's Kang Min-hyuk and Baek Ha-na 21-15, 21-10.</p> <p> In the men's doubles, Tokyo Olympic silver medalist Liu Yuchen, who teamed up with Ou Xuanyi, fought hard to overcome South Korea's second seeds Ko Sung-hyun and Shin Baek-cheol 21-17, 18-21, 21-13.</p> <p> In the women's doubles, China's Du Yue and Li Wenmei defeated their compatriots Zhang Shuxian and Zheng Yu 21-15, 21-19.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chengdu 2021 FISU World University Games unveils a tasty menu of 704 dishes for participants ]]></title>
	<news_id>10084736</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0415/c90000-10084736.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 18:01:54 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> The organizing committee of the Chengdu 2021 FISU World University Games recently announced a menu consisting of 704 dishes to be served during the Games, which is scheduled to be held from June 26 to July 7 in southwest China’s Sichuan Province.</p> <p> Some 480 ingredients in 11 types will be used to cook the different dishes, and food from various countries in Europe, the Mediterranean, and Asia, as well as Sichuan food and food specially prepared for Muslims will be made available for athletes from a variety of backgrounds. Statistics show that 61.29 percent of the ingredients are locally produced, while the rest are sourced from elsewhere.</p> <p> A kitchen crew consisting of 600 staff members will provide catering services during the Games, making sure that the dishes are available 20 hours each day.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ New faces called up for Chinese national women's volleyball team while Zhu Ting missing ]]></title>
	<news_id>10084328</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0415/c90000-10084328.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 09:04:17 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220415/12/9922835015929097260.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Yuan Xinyue of China seen in action during the women's volleyball preliminary round match between China and Italy at the 2020 Olympic Games in Tokyo, Japan, on July 31, 2021. (Xinhua/Xu Zijian)</em></p> <p> <strong>China has named a mixture of youth and experience in its women's volleyball squad.</strong></p> <p> BEIJING, April 14 (Xinhua) -- The Chinese national women's volleyball team revealed its new recruits here on Thursday with several fresh faces first time listed among the legendary side.</p> <p> The new names include young players Wu Mengjie and Wang Yizhu who may be seen as the reinforcement for star spiker Li Yingying, as well as spiker Jin Ye, setter Wang Yunlu and libero Xu Jianan.</p> <p> China's international volleyball stars Zhu Ting and Zhang Changning were both not called up due to injury.</p> <p> But the list also includes some veteran players such as 32-year-old setter Ding Xia.</p> <p> Gong Xiangyu and Yuan Xinyue, who have attended both the Rio 2016 and Tokyo 2020 Olympics, represent "middle-age" players, the main force on the team.</p> <p> After Cai Bin took over the reins from the legendary coach Lang Ping, the national team assembled players from all over China for testing and selecting procedures.</p> <p> "This recruitment aims for preparing the incoming FIVB Women's World Championship and the 2022 Asian Games," according to an announcement from China Volleyball Association (CVA).</p> <p> "We want to assemble players from different age groups when forming the new national team so that the young players can get tested and grow up," Cai said.</p> <p> "Also, we've considered recruiting the middle-years who have potential and the veterans with experience in international competitions.</p> <p> "But the door is still open for the newcomers," he added.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Winter Olympic champion Su Yiming eyes on Grand Slam ]]></title>
	<news_id>10084042</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0414/c90000-10084042.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 15:37:46 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, April 14 (Xinhua) -- Beijing Winter Olympic champion Su Yiming set his next goal of his snowboard career on Grand Slam, the new Chinese sports idol said on Wednesday at a winter sports activity held at the Big Air Shougang and the Beijing Winter Olympic Park.</p> <p> Su, who clinched a silver in slopestyle and the gold medal in Big Air at Beijing 2022, said, "I wish I could win the Grand Slam and hear the national anthem in more events." The Chinese won a World Cup title in the United States in 2021.</p> <p> The 18-year-old snowboarding prodigy considers the Big Air Shougang, where he won his first Winter Olympic gold medal, as a "blessed place".</p> <p> "Three years ago, I competed in my first World Cup here. At that time, I had the goal to get the best result in Beijing," he said.</p> <p> "Hard work pays off," Su said. "When I decided to become a professional, I knew I would be a long way to be the top athlete in the world, but I was always working hard."</p> <p> Many young people regard Su as a role model after his overnight success at the Beijing Winter Olympics. Su noticed teenagers' enthusiasm for winter sports and hoped that his experience would inspire them.</p> <p> Su gave them this advice: "Find what you're passionate about, believe in yourself, and give it your all. One day, your dream will come true."&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China football head coach Li Xiaopeng likely to resign, reports Chinese media ]]></title>
	<news_id>10083833</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0414/c90000-10083833.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 09:34:21 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220414/20/4819696622077800156.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Head coach Li Xiaopeng of China looks on during the Group B match between China and Saudi Arabia of FIFA World Cup Qatar 2022 Qualifier in Sharjah, the United Arab Emirates, March 24, 2022. (Str/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> <strong>Li Xiaopeng is reported likely to resign as China's national team coach.</strong></p> <p> BEIJING, April 13 (Xinhua) -- Li Xiaopeng is likely to resign as head coach of China's national football team following his side's dismal FIFA World Cup qualification campaign, Chinese media reported on Wednesday.</p> <p> China, whose failed World Cup qualification campaign culminated in a 2-0 loss to Oman on March 29, drew once and lost three times under Li, who took over from previous incumbent Li Tie in December.</p> <p> When Li Xiaopeng took the reins with the national team, he treated the final four World Cup qualifiers as a test in which he failed, according to a report in the Guangzhou-based Soccer News.</p> <p> "With circumstances conspiring against him, in all likelihood he will tender his resignation," the report said.</p> <p> Following China's loss to Oman in March, when asked by the media if he had the confidence to transform his team which he accused of being resigned to defeats, Li was evasive in his reply, before conceding that it would be difficult.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Highlights of first round match of Gwangju Yonex Korea Masters ]]></title>
	<news_id>10083830</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0414/c90000-10083830.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 09:27:58 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220414/47/2496803566197956223.png" style="height: 653px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Ou Xuanyi/Huang Yaqiong (R) of China compete during the mixed doubles first round match against Choong Hon Jian/Yap Cheng Wen of Malaysia at the 2022 Gwangju Yonex Korea Masters in Gwangju, South Korea, April 13, 2022. (Photo by James Lee/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220414/29/9118684099411755577.png" style="height: 607px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Ou Xuanyi/Huang Yaqiong (L) of China compete during the mixed doubles first round match against Choong Hon Jian/Yap Cheng Wen of Malaysia at the 2022 Gwangju Yonex Korea Masters in Gwangju, South Korea, April 13, 2022. (Photo by James Lee/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220414/43/14032041053918380343.png" style="width: 700px; height: 800px;" /></p> <p> Lu Guangzu of China hits a return during the men's singles first round match against Lee Dong-keun of South Korea at the 2022 Gwangju Yonex Korea Masters in Gwangju, South Korea, April 13, 2022. (Photo by James Lee/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220414/97/4087852580208624609.png" style="width: 709px; height: 800px;" /></p> <p> Ou Xuanyi/Huang Yaqiong (R) of China compete during the mixed doubles first round match against Choong Hon Jian/Yap Cheng Wen of Malaysia at the 2022 Gwangju Yonex Korea Masters in Gwangju, South Korea, April 13, 2022. (Photo by James Lee/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220414/33/1355182965398902945.png" style="width: 542px; height: 800px;" /></p> <p> Lu Guangzu of China hits a return during the men's singles first round match against Lee Dong-keun of South Korea at the 2022 Gwangju Yonex Korea Masters in Gwangju, South Korea, April 13, 2022. (Photo by James Lee/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220414/82/7071850065121405474.png" style="width: 600px; height: 800px;" /></p> <p> Lu Guangzu of China hits a return during the men's singles first round match against Lee Dong-keun of South Korea at the 2022 Gwangju Yonex Korea Masters in Gwangju, South Korea, April 13, 2022. (Photo by James Lee/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220414/23/14046800763051045475.png" style="width: 600px; height: 800px;" /></p> <p> Lu Guangzu of China hits a return during the men's singles first round match against Lee Dong-keun of South Korea at the 2022 Gwangju Yonex Korea Masters in Gwangju, South Korea, April 13, 2022. (Photo by James Lee/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220414/50/9433562140044167770.png" style="width: 723px; height: 800px;" /></p> <p> Ou Xuanyi/Huang Yaqiong (R) of China have a talk during the mixed doubles first round match against Choong Hon Jian/Yap Cheng Wen of Malaysia at the 2022 Gwangju Yonex Korea Masters in Gwangju, South Korea, April 13, 2022. (Photo by James Lee/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220414/5/12818627418865546817.png" style="height: 677px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Lu Guangzu of China hits a return during the men's singles first round match against Lee Dong-keun of South Korea at the 2022 Gwangju Yonex Korea Masters in Gwangju, South Korea, April 13, 2022. (Photo by James Lee/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Highlights of UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg matches ]]></title>
	<news_id>10083381</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0413/c90000-10083381.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 10:56:39 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/34/1667892939558608990.jpg" style="height: 658px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Thomas Mueller of Bayern Munich controls the ball during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Bayern Munich of Germany and Villarreal CF of Spain in Munich, Germany, April 12, 2022. (Photo by Philippe Ruiz/Xinhua)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/78/6058611339419586770.jpg" style="width: 699px; height: 900px;" /></p> <p> Leroy Sane (top) of Bayern Munich vies for header with Pervis Estupinan of Villarreal during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Bayern Munich of Germany and Villarreal CF of Spain in Munich, Germany, April 12, 2022. (Photo by Philippe Ruiz/Xinhua)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/8/11479693162984523416.jpg" style="height: 587px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Leon Goretzka (R) of Bayern Munich vies with Etienne Capoue of Villarreal during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Bayern Munich of Germany and Villarreal CF of Spain in Munich, Germany, April 12, 2022. (Photo by Philippe Ruiz/Xinhua)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/26/17845616133139366666.jpg" style="height: 685px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Kingsley Coman (R) of Bayern Munich vies with Juan Foyth of Villarreal during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Bayern Munich of Germany and Villarreal CF of Spain in Munich, Germany, April 12, 2022. (Photo by Philippe Ruiz/Xinhua)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/90/1289164969723157354.jpg" style="width: 680px; height: 900px;" /></p> <p> Leon Goretzka (R) of Bayern Munich vies with Pervis Estupinan of Villarreal during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Bayern Munich of Germany and Villarreal CF of Spain in Munich, Germany, April 12, 2022. (Photo by Philippe Ruiz/Xinhua)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/12/9607683493769934588.jpg" style="height: 572px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Thomas Mueller of Bayern Munich reacts after a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Bayern Munich of Germany and Villarreal CF of Spain in Munich, Germany, April 12, 2022. (Photo by Philippe Ruiz/Xinhua)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/33/16068836076403519049.jpg" style="height: 592px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Benjamin Pavard (L) of Bayern Munich tries to shoot during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Bayern Munich of Germany and Villarreal CF of Spain in Munich, Germany, April 12, 2022. (Photo by Philippe Ruiz/Xinhua)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/17/2116393805115139093.jpg" style="height: 669px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Kingsley Coman (R) of Bayern Munich breaks through the defense from Juan Foyth of Villarreal during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Bayern Munich of Germany and Villarreal CF of Spain in Munich, Germany, April 12, 2022. (Photo by Philippe Ruiz/Xinhua)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/55/14191755586503468307.jpg" style="width: 673px; height: 900px;" /></p> <p> Head coach Unai Emery of Villarreal reacts during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Bayern Munich of Germany and Villarreal CF of Spain in Munich, Germany, April 12, 2022. (Photo by Philippe Ruiz/Xinhua)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/52/3377326693424886464.jpg" style="height: 645px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Kingsley Coman of Bayern Munich controls the ball during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Bayern Munich of Germany and Villarreal CF of Spain in Munich, Germany, April 12, 2022. (Photo by Philippe Ruiz/Xinhua)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/85/1233745046540629873.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Antonio Rudiger (top, L) of Chelsea scores during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Real Madrid of Spain and Chelsea FC of England at Santiago Bernabeu Stadium in Madrid, Spain, on April 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/14/12786730929535302046.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Mason Mount (R) of Chelsea celebrates his goal during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Real Madrid of Spain and Chelsea FC of England at Santiago Bernabeu Stadium in Madrid, Spain, on April 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/88/2522549752150673560.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Casemiro (R) of Real Madrid vies with Kai Havertz of Chelsea during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Real Madrid of Spain and Chelsea FC of England at Santiago Bernabeu Stadium in Madrid, Spain, on April 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/96/10311051901443021796.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Marcelo of Real Madrid celebrates the victory after a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Real Madrid of Spain and Chelsea FC of England at Santiago Bernabeu Stadium in Madrid, Spain, on April 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/21/9428888774164665753.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Cesar Azpilicueta (2nd R) of Chelsea receives a yellow card on the bench during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Real Madrid of Spain and Chelsea FC of England at Santiago Bernabeu Stadium in Madrid, Spain, on April 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/26/15807076337049315698.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> David Alaba (R) of Real Madrid vies with Kai Havertz of Chelsea during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Real Madrid of Spain and Chelsea FC of England at Santiago Bernabeu Stadium in Madrid, Spain, on April 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/27/12753884114058272439.jpg" style="width: 599px; height: 899px;" /></p> <p> David Alaba (bottom) of Real Madrid vies with Kai Havertz of Chelsea during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Real Madrid of Spain and Chelsea FC of England at Santiago Bernabeu Stadium in Madrid, Spain, on April 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/19/9305280085839732515.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Casemiro (L) of Real Madrid vies with Mason Mount of Chelsea during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Real Madrid of Spain and Chelsea FC of England at Santiago Bernabeu Stadium in Madrid, Spain, on April 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/6/3551356335836964082.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Karim Benzema of Real Madrid celebrates his goal during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Real Madrid of Spain and Chelsea FC of England at Santiago Bernabeu Stadium in Madrid, Spain, on April 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/84/3249380250412641704.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Toni Kroos (L) of Real Madrid vies with N'Golo Kante of Chelsea during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Real Madrid of Spain and Chelsea FC of England at Santiago Bernabeu Stadium in Madrid, Spain, on April 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/90/9161962800528976910.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Timo Werner of Chelsea reacts before a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Real Madrid of Spain and Chelsea FC of England at Santiago Bernabeu Stadium in Madrid, Spain, on April 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/35/5216680900240819451.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Eduardo Camavinga (R) of Real Madrid vies with Ruben Loftus-Cheek of Chelsea during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Real Madrid of Spain and Chelsea FC of England at Santiago Bernabeu Stadium in Madrid, Spain, on April 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/90/9689140542720648574.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Players of Real Madrid celebrate the victory after a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Real Madrid of Spain and Chelsea FC of England at Santiago Bernabeu Stadium in Madrid, Spain, on April 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/88/9290530945752544192.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Rodrygo (R) of Real Madrid scores during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Real Madrid of Spain and Chelsea FC of England at Santiago Bernabeu Stadium in Madrid, Spain, on April 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/24/1902312931068616748.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Federico Valverde (L) of Real Madrid vies with Marcos Alonso of Chelsea during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Real Madrid of Spain and Chelsea FC of England at Santiago Bernabeu Stadium in Madrid, Spain, on April 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/17/10559590843836193489.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Karim Benzema of Real Madrid celebrates his goal during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Real Madrid of Spain and Chelsea FC of England at Santiago Bernabeu Stadium in Madrid, Spain, on April 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220413/98/18304266870363603950.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 900px;" /></p> <p> Rodrygo (top) of Real Madrid celebrates his goal with Karim Benzema during a UEFA Champions League quarterfinal second leg match between Real Madrid of Spain and Chelsea FC of England at Santiago Bernabeu Stadium in Madrid, Spain, on April 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Meng Dingbo)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Mountaineering flourishes in China’s Tibet autonomous region ]]></title>
	<news_id>10083219</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0413/c90000-10083219.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 09:13:02 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> At 4:20 a.m. on May 25, 1960, Wang Fuzhou, Gonpo, and Qu Yinhua, mountaineers with an average age of 24 years old, ascended to the top of Mount Qomolangma from its northern slope, which is considered so high that even birds can’t fly over. It was the first time that Chinese people had reached the top of the world’s highest peak, and also the first time that mankind had climbed to the summit of Mount Qomolangma from its northern slope.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0413/FOREIGN202204130906000316950557031.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 401px;" /></p> <p> <em>Members of the China Tibet Mountaineering Team pose for a group photo after reaching the summit of Mount Qomolangma in 1999. (Photo/Courtesy of sports bureau of Tibet autonomous region)</em></p> <p> “In those years, our climbing gear was quite rudimentary. Since we didn’t have metal ladder, we built a human ladder to climb the mountain. We thought we must reach the summit, even if only one of us could do it,” said the Tibetan climber Gonpo, who can still vividly recall the feat of great daring.</p> <p> “The first thing we did after reaching the top of the mountain was to erect our national flag. We wanted to show the world that Chinese people can do it,” Gonpo added.</p> <p> On Oct. 1, 1960, Tibet mountaineering camp, which later became the China Tibet Mountaineering Team, was established, with Gonpo and his fellow teammates who took part in the ascent of Mount Qomolangma in 1960 forming the backbone of the camp.</p> <p> After the first successful ascent of the world’s tallest mountain in 1960, generations of Tibetan mountaineers have continued to create new world records for mountaineering: more than 300 people have scaled Mount Qomolangma; over 460 people have reached the tops of mountains that are more than 8,000 meters in height; three people have conquered all the world’s 14 peaks above the altitude of 8,000 meters; and two members of the China Tibet Mountaineering Team have accomplished the magnificent feat of reaching the summits of the highest mountains on each of the world’s seven continents and trekking to the South and North Poles.</p> <p> In 2020, when the 60th anniversary of the China Tibet Mountaineering Team was marked, a Chinese survey team reached the summit of Mount Qomolangma and remeasured the height of the peak, which is 8,848.86 meters. At the same time, the team set a new record for the longest stay on the top of the peak by Chinese people.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0413/FOREIGN202204130906000457438017055.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /></p> <p> <em>Tourists enjoy spectacular scenery at the foot of Mount Qomolangma, August 26, 2020. (People’s Daily Online/Peng Huan)</em></p> <p> “Mountaineers from the China Tibet Mountaineering Team have played a part in all the important activities and major events involving the sport of mountain climbing, including pushing the limits of mountaineering, remeasuring the height of Mount Qomolangma, and the Olympic torch relay at the summit of the peak,” said Sonam, head of the China Tibet Mountaineering Team.</p> <p> The team has also carried out, on behalf of China, joint mountaineering activities with many countries and regions, making mountaineering a major leverage to build China into a country strong on sports and an important bridge for exchanges between China and foreign countries, according to Sonam.</p> <p> As times change, the sport of mountain climbing has also become increasingly rich in content, with rock climbing, ski mountaineering and other events deriving from it gradually.</p> <p> Nevertheless, the spirit of being fearless of danger and difficulty, tenacity, solidarity and cooperation, and scaling new heights has been carried forward by mountaineers in Tibet from generation to generation.</p> <p> “In addition to maintaining our strengths in mountaineering expedition, we also need to strive for better performance in competitions,” said Ngawang Tashi, deputy head of the China Tibet Mountaineering Team.</p> <p> After Beijing and its neighboring city Zhangjiakou in north China’s Hebei province won the bid to host the 2022 Olympic and Paralympic Winter Games, the China Tibet Mountaineering Team took the preparations for the sports event and China’s vision of involving 300 million people in winter sports as an opportunity to boost the development of ice and snow sports in Tibet, and set up the first skiing training team of the region.</p> <p> The team selected outstanding athletes, regardless of their professional backgrounds, for cross-country skiing, snowboarding, and ski mountaineering.</p> <p> “Within less than four to five years, these young athletes who used to be completely new to skiing have gradually developed enthusiasm for these skiing events,” said Ngawang Tashi.</p> <p> What’s particularly exciting was that Tsering Dradul and Yongqing Lhamo finally qualified for Beijing 2022 and became the first Tibetan athletes to compete at Winter Olympics, Ngawang Tashi added.</p> <p> These brilliant achievements couldn’t have been made without the mountaineering team’s talent cultivation system that has matured considerably over the past years.</p> <p> The mountaineering guide school located in the northern suburbs of Lhasa, capital of Tibet, is the only mountaineering school in China and the second one of its kind in the world. Students there are mainly teenagers of the Tibetan ethnic group who are interested in skiing and mountaineering. They are provided with systematic and professional training in the school.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0413/FOREIGN202204130907000466903508794.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo shows Mount Namjagbarwa in Nyingchi, southwest China’s Tibet autonomous region. (People’s Daily Online/Wang Tianhao)</em></p> <p> So far, the school has cultivated more than 300 mountaineering professionals including mountain guides, continuously supplying reserve forces to the China Tibet Mountaineering Team and the industry of high-altitude mountaineering.</p> <p> In an effort to bring mountaineering closer to the public, the China Tibet Mountaineering Team has actively promoted the Tibet mountaineering conference, which has been held for 20 consecutive sessions and attracted many mountaineering enthusiasts to climbing snow-capped mountains in Tibet.</p> <p> The event includes not only splendid skiing and mountaineering competitions, but mountaineering training, ice and snow sports-themed cultural exhibition, and other activities, playing an important role in boosting the integrated development of mountaineering, sports industry and tourism sector.</p> <p> Based on its rich reserve of professional mountaineers, the China Tibet Mountaineering Team has actively engaged in mountain rescue, and taken part in more than 30 major rescue tasks, including the evacuation of mountaineers after a devastating earthquake hit Nepal in 2015. In the climbing season every year, the mountaineering team clears mountain areas of household waste and disposes of it.</p> <p> “We’ve got to protect the lofty mountains, blue skies, and white clouds of the snow-covered Qinghai-Tibet Plateau,” Sonam noted.</p> <p> Looking forward, the China Tibet Mountaineering Team is making active efforts to adapt to changes and make progress in key priorities of its work, including mountaineering industrialization, regular environmental protection activities in mountains, and scientific development of mountain rescue.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
	</channel>
</rss>