<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title> Special_Coverage </title>
		<image>
			<title>People's Daily Online</title>
			<link>http://english.people.com.cn/</link>
			<url>http://english.people.com.cn/images/en/top_logo_e.gif</url>
		</image>
		<description>People's Daily Online</description>
		<link>http://english.people.com.cn/102775</link>
		<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi Focus-Closeup: An exceptional student ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096797</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096797.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 12:10:38 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 15 (Xinhua) -- Lost both arms in an accident at the age of nine; failed twice in the national college entrance exam and the result of the third try was still up in the air -- Huang Daoliang recalled the time in his younger age as the darkest period in life.</p> <p> Now 52, Huang is able to look back with satisfaction at what followed: a place at college and a career that has made good use of his skills and enthusiasm. He says he owes a great debt of thanks to the college principal who decided to enroll him at the time.</p> <p> The principal who gave him "a new lease of life" was Xi Jinping.</p> <p> Born in 1970 in the county of Minqing, east China's Fujian Province, Huang had both of his arms amputated after he accidentally touched a high-voltage wire. He stayed in hospital for over half a year, and after returning home, he felt everything had changed.</p> <p> "All the joy had disappeared along with my arms," he recalled.</p> <p> Huang went on to senior middle school, and officials at a local welfare institution offered him a job after graduation.</p> <p> "However, deep in my heart, I still cherished a dream," he said. "I wanted to go to college and continue my studies."</p> <p> He decided to carry on at school, writing with his feet, a practice that required him to go barefoot. Without shoes or socks, the winters were difficult. His feet turned "as red as carrots" in the cold air.</p> <p> He took the college entrance exam in 1988 and 1989 but failed to gain admission on both occasions. Although Huang got decent scores in the exams, he was rejected due to his physical limitations. At that time, no universities or colleges enrolled students without arms.</p> <p> Huang tried for a third time in 1990, but his past failures hung over him like a dark cloud. What he didn't know was that better times were just around the corner.</p> <p> In that year, Xi took up the position of Communist Party of China (CPC) chief of the city of Fuzhou, Fujian's capital, as well as principal of Minjiang Polytechnic College (now known as Minjiang University). On learning of Huang's story, Xi decided to admit Huang on the basis of exceptional enrollment.</p> <p> Huang thus became the first "armless student" in his college, and in the province.</p> <p> Huang joined the CPC during the college years, and after graduation he became a staff member at the local disabled persons' federation in Minqing, aiming to help more people with disabilities embrace their "rebirth."</p> <p> Over the years, Xi, as the country's top leader, has given "particular care and attention" to disabled people. He has pointed out that people with disabilities are equal members of the community as a whole, and has pushed for society-wide efforts to support them.</p> <p> In 2016, during a visit to a paraplegic rehabilitation center in Tangshan, north China's Hebei Province, Xi talked with residents, saying, "If people with a sound physical condition can have a brilliant life, people with disabilities can do likewise."</p> <p> During the 13th Five-Year Plan period (2016-2020), more than 60,000 students with disabilities were enrolled in higher-education institutions. In 2020, a total of 8.62 million people with disabilities were employed across the country. The government subsidizes over 400,000 handicapped people's vocational training annually.</p> <p> Several years after his graduation, Huang met Xi at a local meeting to commend role models for disabled people and those who have made outstanding contributions in helping the disabled.</p> <p> "I wanted to tell him in person of my gratitude for the college admission," Huang said. However, he was too shy to express his feelings.</p> <p> "I decided instead to keep that thankfulness deep in my mind, and use it to drive the sense of responsibility in my work, and my devotion to the cause of helping disabled people," he said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi Focus-Quotable Quotes: Xi Jinping on family ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096796</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096796.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 12:10:34 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 15 (Xinhua) -- Sunday marks the International Day of Families, an occasion proposed by the United Nations to promote awareness of issues relating to families and to increase the knowledge of the social, economic and demographic processes affecting families.</p> <p> Chinese President Xi Jinping has made various important remarks on that theme. The following are some highlights:</p> <p> -- A family is the smallest unit of a nation while a nation is a myriad of families put together.</p> <p> -- Parents should influence their children by precept and example. They should impart knowledge and foster children's virtues, helping their children establish moral values that steer them forward in their future adult life.</p> <p> -- We should promote filial piety and family harmony, encourage people to take on family responsibilities, cultivate fine family traditions, and take care of the elderly.</p> <p> -- Filial piety at home and loyalty to the country are among the fine traditions of the Chinese nation.</p> <p> -- The prosperity and strength of the country and the rejuvenation of the nation must be ultimately reflected in the happiness of myriads of families and the continuous improvement of the lives of hundreds of millions of people.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Experts denounce U.S. plot to deprive Xinjiang people of development opportunities ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096783</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096783.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 11:33:18 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> URUMQI, May 14 (Xinhua) -- Chinese scholars have slammed anti-China politicians in the United States for plotting to deprive Xinjiang people of development opportunities by fabricating lies of "forced labor" in the region.</p> <p> They made the denouncement at a press briefing held Friday in Urumqi, capital of northwest China's Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region.</p> <p> Cao Wei, an associate professor at Lanzhou University, said that out of fear of sanctions from the United States, some enterprises dare not employ workers of Uygur ethnicity, which will result in rising unemployment rate and declining living standards of the Uygur population.</p> <p> Those anti-China politicians in the United States are the culprits who are depriving Xinjiang residents of their development opportunities under the guise of human rights, said Cao.</p> <p> Ildos Murat, vice chairman of the Federation of Trade Unions of Xinjiang, said that in fact, the United States is the country where forced labor is still deeply rooted in the 21st century, with the immigrants being the main victims, and the U.S. government has evaded its obligations to protect them.</p> <p> "According to research by academic institutions in the U.S., at least 500,000 people in the U.S. are subjected to modern-day slavery and forced labor," said Ildos Murat. "No matter how viciously anti-China forces in the U.S. smear Xinjiang over labor issues, they can never cover up the ironclad proof that the United States has violated labor rights."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi Focus-Closeup: Mother's heart on the needlework ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096782</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096782.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 10:57:38 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) -- In his adolescent years, Xi Jinping was given a simple sewing kit by his mother; a gift that would bestow him the courage to weather through a difficult time and make "the first step of life."</p> <p> In 1969, 15-year-old Xi was sent to Liangjiahe, a small rural village in northwest China's Shaanxi Province, as an "educated youth" -- urban youth sent to remote rural areas to "learn from farmers" during the Cultural Revolution (1966-1976). Upon learning this, his mother, Qi Xin, who was then working at a farm in central China's Henan Province, carefully made a sewing kit for him.</p> <p> On the coarse cloth of the kit bag, Qi used red threads to stitch the words "niang de xin (mother's heart)" on it.</p> <p> "From the threads a mother's hands weaves, a gown for parting son is made. Sown stitch by stitch before he leaves, for fear his return be delayed," Xi once quoted the poem "Song of the Parting Son" by Meng Jiao in Tang Dynasty (618-907) to explain how the Chinese tradition of strong family ties remains unchanged throughout history.</p> <p> Xi kept the gift from his mother throughout the seven years he spent in Liangjiahe, where he overcame numerous challenges -- from the infestation of fleas and strenuous labor to perplexing challenges that required a great deal of thought. Xi learnt to do all kinds of farm work -- reclaiming wasteland, farming, hoeing, herding, hauling coal, mounding, and carrying manure -- and came to understand what reality, seeking truth and the masses meant. In his own words, Liangjiahe is the place where he "stepped out the first step of my life."</p> <p> Meng's poem goes on to say "such kindness is like young grass that receives warmth from the vernal sun and can never be repaid," indicating the immense love the child owes to their parents.</p> <p> As a filial son, Xi has always tried to spend time with his mother when possible. Despite a tight work schedule, he would always find time to go for a walk with her.</p> <p> However, sometimes, for the sake of the greater good -- the interests of the people, he is unable to stay by her side, and Qi, in those cases, has always showed unwavering love and support for her son.</p> <p> A TV documentary recorded a tender moment from 2001, where Xi, serving as the governor of east China's Fujian Province at the time, told his mother over the phone that he might not be able to make the family reunion during that year's Spring Festival.</p> <p> "It doesn't matter if you come or not," Qi told him, "you doing your job well is the greatest piety for your father and mother... Son, I have thousands of thousands of words for you, but in one sentence, I hope you carry your responsibility, heavy as it may be, well."</p> <p> At the end of the call, Qi said to Xi "I'll also give my best wishes to you, and wish you, Liyuan (Xi's wife)... and my little granddaughter a happy Spring Festival, a happy family life... and have all your dreams come true."</p> <p> Xi often recalls a moment from when he was five or six years old, where Qi bought him picture books about Yue Fei, a patriotic military commander of the Southern Song Dynasty (1127-1279). Qi would read to him the story of how Yue's mother tattooed four Chinese characters on Yue's back to remind him of devoting himself to the country: "Jing Zhong Bao Guo," or serving the country with total loyalty.</p> <p> "Jing Zhong Bao Guo: I have long remembered these four characters. It is the pursuit of my entire life," Xi said, reaffirming his commitment to living up to the expectations of his mother, as well as the people of his motherland.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Feature: 2 years on, anti-Asian hatred persists in New York ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096731</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096731.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:51:36 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NEW YORK, May 13 (Xinhua) -- About two and a half years into the COVID-19 pandemic, the United States has seen not only an increase in infections and deaths, but also an orgy of racism and hate crimes against minority groups, particularly the Asian-American community.</p> <p> Following an apparently random yet violent murder of a young Korean-American woman in a Chinatown apartment here in February, mourners placed flowers, candles, photos, and cardboard signs condemning anti-Asian hatred around a tree outside the residential building where Christina Yuna Lee was stabbed to death.</p> <p> While the shock of Lee's death had yet to wear off, mourners were outraged that the makeshift memorial for Lee had been repeatedly vandalized.</p> <p> The temporary memorial was first vandalized in the middle of the night just three days after Lee's death, and it continued to be vandalized even in broad daylight.</p> <p> "So five times last month, and it just keeps increasing. It is very sad," Brian Chin, Lee's former landlord, told Xinhua.</p> <p> According to video clips from a surveillance camera shared by Chin, a man kicked at the flowers, candles, and signs in the early morning on March 2, and another pedestrian pulled down a cardboard sign about a week later.</p> <p> Every attack on the memorial is pretty much anti-Asian and "it is very scary right now," said Chin, whose family came to the United States from China over 60 years ago.</p> <p> "They're doing it with hate. They see her picture. They see the flowers and candles," Chin added.</p> <p> Lee's tragic death followed the fatal shoving of Asian American Michelle Alyssa Go onto subway tracks by a man at Times Square station on Jan. 15 and the death of Yaopan Ma in January in a racially motivated attack in East Harlem.</p> <p> "Her (Lee's) death is part of an alarming pattern of unchecked, hateful violence against women, namely women of Asian descent and women of color that can no longer stand without consequence," said one of Lee's relatives in an appeal on Gofundme.com.</p> <p> For Chin, a middle-aged man, the continued anti-Asian hate crimes had brought about unprecedented depression.</p> <p> "I think everyone is terrified right now that they will be attacked on the subways, on the streets, and then the guy will be out on the same day," he said.</p> <p> According to Chin, this wave of anti-Asian hatred began with very vitriolic language which claims COVID-19 as the so-called "Chinese flu" or "Wuhan flu."</p> <p> Kathleen Flynn-hui, whose husband originally came from Hong Kong, said that anti-Asian prejudice affects her family on a daily basis.</p> <p> "We've kind of always felt it, but not as strongly as now," said Flynn-hui, adding that she "dealt with discrimination against my husband because he was Asian the whole time."</p> <p> Chin said the situation is deteriorating due to a combination of politics, the impact of new laws, and the new Manhattan District Attorney's lenient stance on crime.</p> <p> "The cops are doing their job, but they arrest them, and they're free the next day due to the laws," said Chin.</p> <p> Right now, much stronger laws are needed to protect the Asian community, Chin said, calling on lawmakers, the city council, and the mayor to take stronger and more enforceable action.</p> <p> The Committee of 100, a non-profit leadership organization of prominent Chinese Americans, recently called on U.S. elected officials, law enforcement, and responsible media to address racism, discrimination, and violence against Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders immediately with actionable and concrete results.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ U.S. uses democracy as pretext for interference -- experts ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096713</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096713.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:10:46 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> CAIRO, May 14 (Xinhua) -- The United States has been exploiting democracy, human rights and aid as tools and weapons to incite division around the world and meddle in other countries' internal affairs, say political experts.</p> <p> "To influence domestic policies in recipient countries ... the U.S. has provided assistance to serve its goals and achieve its interests," Ayman Okeil, general manager of the Cairo-based Maat for Peace, Development, and Human Rights, told Xinhua in a recent interview.</p> <p> THE NED AS A PROXY</p> <p> Among all the proxies Washington uses to serve its political agenda in other countries, the National Endowment for Democracy (NED), which was founded in 1983 as a bipartisan, non-profit institution by the U.S. government, is one of the most active.</p> <p> Nominally a non-governmental organization that provides support for democracy abroad, the NED in fact relies on continuous financial support from the White House and the U.S. Congress, and takes orders from the U.S. government.</p> <p> Okeil described the NED as one of Washington's "soldiers" for interfering in other countries' decision-making process.</p> <p> The NED has worked as a substitute for the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) in cultivating pro-U.S. opposition activists for subverting lawful governments and provoking uprisings in the Arab countries under the pretext of promoting democracy, he said.</p> <p> According to Saeb Rawashdeh, a political analyst at the Jordan Press Foundation, the NED was founded as a tool for projecting political influence in different sovereign states that the U.S. government has labeled as "non-democratic, totalitarian, authoritarian and anti-American."</p> <p> The NED supported opposition groups in other countries, which were trained to represent Washington's interest, rather than the vital interests of their own nations and states, Rawashdeh pointed out.</p> <p> Echoing Rawashdeh's point, Okeil said that the NED has spent millions of U.S. dollars to support political parties, labor unions, dissident movements, and media in dozens of countries.</p> <p> The organization has been employed as the "mastermind" behind separatist riots, color revolutions, and political crises around the world, with the aim of toppling legitimate governments and creating U.S. puppets in targeted countries, said Ahmad Ashqar, a Syrian journalist and political expert.</p> <p> The NED makes sure that nations across the globe do what the United States wants them to do and in no way feel confident and capable of pursuing their own political/ideological agendas, Rawashdeh said. "And this is also what the U.S. foreign policy is doing for decades."</p> <p> A NEW TYPE OF IMPERIALISM</p> <p> The United States, unfortunately, has created a new type of imperialism, by occupying foreign countries with money and forces and interfering in their choice of leaders and party compositions, Okeil told Xinhua.</p> <p> Unlike the funds that came from some countries like China, which help improve health, education and development sectors, the U.S. economic aid is always with conditions attached, he noted</p> <p> Okeil's words are not groundless. According to a study by the American University in Cairo in November 2021, the NED has allocated more than 606 million dollars in "democracy assistance" to Egypt in the period between 1990 and 2003. In 2008, the U.S. government provided 415 million dollars in economic assistance to Egypt, which includes 55 million dollars to support programs for promoting democracy.</p> <p> However, as Tariq Fahmy, a political science professor at the Cairo University, noted, the U.S. mode of democracy has not been successful in the Middle East, and it contradicts many countries' unique conditions.</p> <p> "We all saw the disgraceful role in provoking the Arab Spring via funding the protesters" under the cover of democracy and human rights, Fahmy said, explaining that such kind of imposed democracy couldn't breed stability.</p> <p> After the Arab Spring, many people in the Middle East have started to see the real objectives behind the U.S. aid when knowing that Washington had a role in inciting the Arab Spring uprisings via supporting, training and funding young protesters, Okeil noted.</p> <p> The U.S. model of democracy is not suitable for the world, and based on that model, the U.S. policies led to real crimes, Fahmy said.</p> <p> It's a fact that the United States has distorted the positive meaning of democracy and emptied such a notion of anything useful and beneficial for other countries, Ashqar argued.</p> <p> "We have seen several examples like in Syria, where the United States used democracy as a pretext to support separatist forces and radical ones to destabilize the legitimate government," he said. "The U.S. presence in Syria has achieved all but the so-called democracy."</p> <p> "Under the pretext of fighting terrorism and spreading democracy, the U.S. has stolen key areas in Syria rich with oil and gas, do you call that democracy?" asked the Syrian journalist.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 27 killed, 12 injured in Indian capital building fire ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096712</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096712.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 13:57:02 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NEW DELHI, May 14 (Xinhua) -- At least 27 people were killed and 12 others suffered burn injuries after a massive fire broke out in a three-storey commercial building in the Indian capital, senior police officer Sameer Sharma said Saturday.</p> <p> The fire broke out inside the building on Friday evening at 4:40 p.m. (local time) near the city's Mundka metro station, and the death toll became clear only by night.</p> <p> Reports said the fire started from the first floor of the building at an office of a CCTV cameras and router manufacturing company.</p> <p> Officials said the firefighting and rescue operations continued until early morning on Saturday. Police are yet to identify the deceased, and the injured have been admitted to Sanjay Gandhi Memorial Hospital.</p> <p> Firefighters used heavy cranes to reach the top floor of the building, and 27 fire tenders were sent to contain the blaze when smoke surrounded the entire building.</p> <p> Video clips showed people trying to escape the building using a rope and hanging from broken windows. Many people could be seen trying to jump to another building.</p> <p> "There was only one staircase and because of that people could not go out. I think the building did not have a proper no objection certificate (NOC) from the fire department," Satpal Bhardwaj, divisional officer of the Delhi fire department told media.</p> <p> Police said they have arrested the owners of the company, but the owner of the building who did not have safety clearance from the fire department is on the run.</p> <p> Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi has expressed grief over the deaths in the fire.</p> <p> "Extremely saddened by the loss of lives due to a tragic fire in Delhi. My thoughts are with the bereaved families. I wish the injured a speedy recovery," Modi wrote on social media.</p> <p> Chances of fire in Indian buildings are usually high as people often ignore safety standards vis-a-vis fire.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xiconomics: How Xi's economic philosophy promotes global governance ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096711</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096711.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 13:56:59 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) -- "The right way forward for humanity is peaceful development and win-win cooperation," Chinese President Xi Jinping told the 2022 World Economic Forum (WEF) virtual session in mid-January, offering China's solutions to global challenges, including the COVID-19 pandemic.</p> <p> "Different countries and civilizations may prosper together on the basis of respect for each other, and seek common ground and win-win outcomes by setting aside differences," he added.</p> <p> Xi's remarks elaborated on "Xiconomics," or the economics philosophy of the Chinese president, demonstrating China's commitment to building a harmonious world, promoting common development and enhancing the common interests of mankind.</p> <p> OPENING WIDER</p> <p> "We need to learn from comparing long history cycles, and see the change in things through the subtle and minute. We need to foster new opportunities amidst crises, open up new horizons on a shifting landscape, and pool great strength to go through difficulties and challenges," Xi said in his special address, giving insight into a world battered by both the COVID-19 pandemic and sluggish economic growth.</p> <p> In the past two years, under the guidance of Xi's economic thought, China has struck a fine balance between pandemic control and economic development.</p> <p> In 2020, China has emerged as the only major economy with positive growth. In 2021, its gross domestic product saw a year-on-year increase of 8.1 percent, contributing around a quarter to world economic growth and beating most market expectations. The country has also played a crucial and irreplaceable role in supporting the global supply chains.</p> <p> Alexander Petrov, a professor at St. Petersburg State University, said China's success has proved that in a socialist market economy, it is possible to coordinate the efficiency of economic development and social governance, which is needed for global economic recovery in the post-pandemic era.</p> <p> China has once again become one "driving force of the global economy," said Jochen Goller, president and CEO of BMW China, who spoke highly of China's concerted efforts and strong resilience in both successfully fighting against COVID-19 and boosting economic recovery.</p> <p> China's steady growth has served as a stabilizer for the world economy amid the pandemic. It has been implementing a development philosophy featuring openness and cooperation, which helped strengthen global solidarity for economic recovery.</p> <p> "Countries around the world should uphold true multilateralism. We should remove barriers, not erect walls. We should open up, not close off. We should seek integration, not decoupling. This is the way to build an open world economy," Xi said, urging countries worldwide to "make economic globalization more open, inclusive, balanced and beneficial for all, and to fully unleash the vitality of the world economy."</p> <p> Humphrey Moshi, director of the Center for Chinese Studies at the University of Dar es Salaam of Tanzania, said that "China has been on the front line of encouraging multilateralism among global countries, and it has been doing that through cooperation on the principles of a win-win situation."</p> <p> "As a staunch supporter of globalization, China has been actively participating in and promoting international cooperation against COVID-19, providing medical equipment and COVID-19 vaccines to many countries," Moshi said.</p> <p> "China stands ready to work with all countries to build an open world economy so that the spring breeze of openness will bring warmth to all parts of the world," Xi said at the opening ceremony of the fourth China International Import Expo in November 2021, reiterating China's resolve to open wider and with a high standard.</p> <p> From shortening the negative list for foreign investment and improving the business environment to expanding institutional opening-up, China has honored its commitments by offering more opportunities to other countries, which injected fresh momentum into global economic recovery.</p> <p> Honson To, chairman of KPMG China and Asia Pacific, said China has kept opening wider to the world, upheld and acted on multilateralism, as well as actively pushed for a more inclusive global cooperation, sending a positive signal that China is willing to work together with other countries for a better future.</p> <p> BENEFIT FOR ALL</p> <p> At a time when the international community is struggling to reduce the development gap and secure equal opportunities for all, China has offered its solution to the problem by underlining the people's desire for a happy life.</p> <p> "No matter what difficulties may come our way, we must adhere to a people-centered philosophy of development, place development and livelihoods front and center in global macro-policies, realize the UN's 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development, and build greater synergy among existing mechanisms of development cooperation to promote balanced development worldwide," Xi said at January's forum.</p> <p> In the eyes of Raphael Tuju, secretary-general of Kenya's ruling Jubilee Party, this people-centered philosophy of development Xi emphasized is well manifested in the Chinese president's famous remarks that "for the good of my people, I will put aside my own well-being."</p> <p> By the end of 2020, China had lifted out of poverty all rural residents living below the current poverty line and met the poverty eradication target set out in the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development 10 years ahead of schedule.</p> <p> Its own people's well-being is not the only thing China cares about. As Xi noted, "on the road to the well-being of all mankind, no country or nation should be left behind."</p> <p> From China's growth to inclusive and common development of countries worldwide, Xi's economic thought addresses the need of the development of mankind through a variety of cooperation frameworks, such as the Belt and Road Initiative (BRI).</p> <p> The Mombasa-Nairobi Railway is a mega project under the BRI. It boosted Kenya's economy by significantly improving freight transportation, brought substantial benefits to local people, and at the same time protected the local ecological environment.</p> <p> This is the beginning of the transformation, which will create jobs, hope, opportunities and prosperity for all Kenyans, Kenyan President Uhuru Kenyatta said during a test ride of the railway.</p> <p> Another landmark project of Belt and Road cooperation is the 1,035-km China-Laos Railway, which has opened the landlocked country in Southeast Asia and connected it to markets as far away as in Europe since the railway's operation on Dec. 3, 2021.</p> <p> Sommad Pholsena, vice president of the National Assembly of Laos, said while China was not the first country to express a willingness to build a railway in Laos, it was the only one to turn it into reality.</p> <p> Xi's proposal to enhance interconnectivity and promote common development provides an opportunity for cooperation among developing countries, Pholsena said.</p> <p> According to the World Bank, BRI transport projects could, by 2030, help lift 7.6 million people out of extreme poverty and 32 million people out of moderate poverty globally.</p> <p> "The more we study the BRI and witness its continuous advancement, the more we can appreciate the vision and the wisdom of President Xi's economic thought on world development," said former Egyptian Prime Minister Essam Sharaf.</p> <p> DEVELOPMENT FOR GOOD</p> <p> To tackle global challenges and seek sustainable development, the Chinese president has been promoting the building of a community with a shared future for mankind.</p> <p> Mankind was presented with two choices -- one is vicious competition or even armed conflict for power and self-interest, which may well lead to a disastrous crisis, Xi said when addressing the CPC (the Communist Party of China) in Dialogue with the World Political Parties High-Level Meeting in 2017.</p> <p> "The other is for us to go along with the tide of the times and rise to challenges through global collaboration," he said. "This, in turn, will create favorable conditions for building a community with a shared future for mankind."</p> <p> For Khalid Taimur Akram, executive director of the Center for Global and Strategic Studies in Islamabad, the notion of building a community with a shared future for mankind bears significance for today's global development.</p> <p> China has provided a platform for all to turn this vision into reality, as the international community is searching for ways to advance cooperation and resolve differences, Akram said.</p> <p> In his speech in September 2021 at the general debate of the 76th session of the United Nations General Assembly via video, Xi said "we must revitalize the economy and pursue more robust, greener and more balanced global development. Development holds the key to people's well-being."</p> <p> He then urged countries around the world to "work together to steer global development toward a new stage of balanced, coordinated and inclusive growth," and proposed the Global Development Initiative (GDI) to this end.</p> <p> Speaking highly of the GDI, Tanzanian Minister of Foreign Affairs and East African Cooperation Liberata Mulamula said the pandemic serves as a reminder that the world is a community and no country should be left behind.</p> <p> Since Xi brought up the concept of building a community with a shared future for mankind in 2013, China has been enriching it to reflect the hope of people from all countries for a better world.</p> <p> "We should follow the trend of history, work for a stable international order, advocate common values of humanity, and build a community with a shared future for mankind. We should choose dialogue over confrontation, inclusiveness over exclusion, and stand against all forms of unilateralism, protectionism, hegemony or power politics," Xi said at the WEF meeting in January.</p> <p> The notion of a community with a shared future is the right path for human development, which could help reduce global inequality, said Ronnie Lins, director of the China-Brazil Center for Research and Business.</p> <p> The Chinese president's philosophy is of profound theoretical significance, said Maxim Rybachuk, leading researcher at the Central Economic Mathematical Institute of the Russian Academy of Sciences.</p> <p> "We are talking about development concepts such as inclusive growth and dual circulation that have benefited both the Chinese people and people in other countries," Rybachuk said.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 16 killed in massive building fire in Indian capital ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096658</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096658.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:34:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NEW DELHI, May 13 (Xinhua) -- At least 16 people were killed Friday in a devastating fire inside a commercial building in the Indian capital, officials said.</p> <p> The fire broke out at around 4:40 p.m. local time in the building located near the Mundka metro station in outer Delhi.</p> <p> "A total of 16 bodies were recovered from the three-storey commercial building which had caught fire this evening near Delhi's Mundka metro station," Atul Garg, director of the Delhi fire service, told local media.</p> <p> According to Garg, the third floor of the building was yet to be searched.</p> <p> Police officials said the death toll was likely to rise as many people were feared trapped in the building.</p> <p> "Rescue operation is underway in the building," a police official said.</p> <p> Officials said 24 fire tenders were at the spot to contain the blaze.</p> <p> "It's a massive fire and heavy cranes are being used to go up and douse the fire," a fire service official said.</p> <p> The cause of the fire is not immediately known. However, reports said the fire started from the first floor of the building which hosts an office of a CCTV camera and router manufacturing company.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xiplomacy: Xi calls for solidarity, collaboration in global fight against COVID-19 ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096648</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096648.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:21:24 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/81/9743114531998611073.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Staff members work at an inflatable COVID-19 testing lab in Shunyi District of Beijing, capital of China, May 12, 2022. (Xinhua/Ren Chao)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- As of Friday, the worldwide count of COVID-19 cases has exceeded 520 million, with over 6 million related deaths.</p> <p> As the world is plagued by major challenges, not least a pandemic unseen in a century, Chinese President Xi Jinping has on multiple occasions called on the international community to take concerted actions against the virus.</p> <p> The following are some highlights of his remarks on how cooperation can help the world survive.</p> <p> April 21, 2022</p> <p> In his keynote speech at the opening ceremony of the Boao Forum for Asia Annual Conference 2022, Xi stressed that we need to work together to defend people's lives and health.</p> <p> For humanity to clinch a final victory against the COVID-19 pandemic, more hard efforts are needed. It is essential that countries support each other, better coordinate response measures and improve global public health governance, so as to form strong international synergy against the pandemic, said Xi.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/27/4304448240757922511.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Cargos containing China's Sinovac vaccines are seen in Pasay City, the Philippines on Oct. 24, 2021. (Rouelle Umali/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> Jan. 17, 2022</p> <p> At the virtual session of the 2022 World Economic Forum, Xi pledged to embrace cooperation on jointly overcoming the pandemic and champion economic globalization.</p> <p> As COVID-19 is resurging with more variants and spreading faster than before, Xi stressed the importance of fully leveraging vaccines as a powerful weapon and ensuring the equitable distribution of vaccines to close the global immunization gap.</p> <p> Xi called on countries to strengthen international cooperation against COVID-19, carry out active cooperation on the research and development of medicines, jointly build multiple lines of defense against the coronavirus, and speed up efforts to build a global community of health for all.</p> <p> Dec. 31, 2021</p> <p> China has provided 2 billion doses of COVID-19 vaccines to more than 120 countries and international organizations for the global COVID response, Xi said in his 2022 New Year Address.</p> <p> "Only through unity, solidarity and cooperation can countries around the world write a new chapter in building a community with a shared future for mankind," he said.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/65/1885335616284998845.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Local students at the Obaay Primary School receive the food items donated by fellow Chinese school children through the China Foundation for Poverty Alleviation (CFPA) in Dukem town of Ethiopia's Oromia regional state, on June 9, 2021. (Xinhua/Wang Ping)</em></p> <p> Nov. 29, 2021</p> <p> China and Africa should fight COVID-19 with solidarity, deepen practical cooperation, promote green development, and uphold equity and justice, Xi said at the opening ceremony of the Eighth Ministerial Conference of the Forum on China-Africa Cooperation via video link.</p> <p> On fighting COVID-19 with solidarity, Xi stressed the need to truly ensure the accessibility and affordability of vaccines in Africa.</p> <p> Oct. 31, 2021</p> <p> While addressing the 16th G20 Leaders' Summit via video link, Xi said that at present, the spread of the COVID-19 pandemic has triggered multiple crises.</p> <p> The development achievements made by the international community over the years have been seriously eroded and developing countries are facing unprecedented challenges and tests, Xi pointed out.</p> <p> The COVID-19 pandemic has once again shown that all countries, with high stakes in each other's future and converging interests, form a community with a shared future for mankind, Xi said, noting that promoting sustainable development in developing countries will benefit the people of the countries concerned, and also affect the future and destiny of the whole mankind and the Earth.</p> <p> Sept. 24, 2021</p> <p> While delivering a speech via video at the opening ceremony of the 2021 Zhongguancun Forum, Xi called on all countries to strengthen openness and cooperation in science and technology.</p> <p> Xi noted that nowadays profound changes unseen in a century are evolving rapidly in the world and the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic is far-reaching, presenting severe challenges for the recovery of the global economy.</p> <p> All countries in the world need to strengthen openness and cooperation in science and technology, explore ways and means of jointly solving important global issues through sci-tech innovation, address the challenges of the times together, and promote the noble cause of peace and development for all, said Xi.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Commentary: Washington's small-clique politics won't fool SE Asia ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096638</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096638.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 09:49:33 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/18/4223263417608477262.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on Nov. 23, 2021 shows the White House in Washington, D.C., the United States. (Photo by Ting Shen/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> <strong>*The U.S. administration has long taken pleasure in organizing destructive meetings under the guise of constructive engagements. </strong></p> <p> <strong>*The so-called "Indo-Pacific Strategy" it is selling at this summit, for example, claims to maintain regional freedom and openness and respect ASEAN centrality in regional affairs, but in reality incites confrontation, undermines unity, and threatens cooperation and development in the region through such exclusive geopolitical blocs as AUKUS and Quad.</strong></p> <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- The White House is peddling its so-called "Indo-Pacific Strategy" against China and ramping up its pressure campaign of the Russia-Ukraine conflict during a two-day summit in Washington with leaders of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN).</p> <p> But its hope to pull ASEAN members into its camp will shrivel, as ASEAN countries have already woken up to Washington's typical hegemony, hypocrisy and egomania.</p> <p> The arrangement of the summit itself has laid bare Washington's double-dealing nature. Its disrespect for ASEAN members concerning scheduling issues despite its pledge of "enduring commitment" has sparked a wave of complaints among ASEAN members, resulting in a postponement of the summit from late March to May.</p> <p> Cambodian Minister attached to the Prime Minister Kao Kim Hourn said before the summit that if Washington was serious about improving its ties with ASEAN, it should have arranged bilateral meetings between the United States and ASEAN countries. ASEAN leaders "should be treated with respect and equality," he noted.</p> <p> The U.S. administration has long taken pleasure in organizing destructive meetings under the guise of constructive engagements. The so-called "Indo-Pacific Strategy" it is selling at this summit, for example, claims to maintain regional freedom and openness and respect ASEAN centrality in regional affairs, but in reality incites confrontation, undermines unity, and threatens cooperation and development in the region through such exclusive geopolitical blocs as AUKUS and Quad.</p> <p> Many sober minds in ASEAN have seen through this duplicity and bullying. Indonesia and Malaysia warned that AUKUS could lead to a major arms race in the region. A recent report by the U.S. Center for Strategic and International Studies showed that many ASEAN members have expressed concerns that the so-called "Indo-Pacific Economic Framework" is "primarily a political endeavor meant to counter China, rather than a sincere and thoughtful economic policy integration initiative."</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/71/5892171399547127135.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on March 24, 2022 shows the U.S. national flag (R) on the U.S. Embassy building in Moscow, Russia. (Xinhua/Bai Xueqi)</em></p> <p> Meanwhile, the White House will attempt in vain during this summit to talk ASEAN into imposing sanctions against Russia. Ever since the escalation of the current Ukraine crisis, Washington has been trying to exert pressure on ASEAN to take sides, but most of ASEAN members did not follow suit.</p> <p> On April 7, six of the 10-member bloc abstained from voting in favor of a resolution to remove Russia from the United Nations Human Rights Council, and two voted against it. Long adhering to an independent foreign policy, ASEAN members have urged solving the crisis through negotiation and dialogue.</p> <p> Moreover, some ASEAN members have been well aware of Washington's unspoken calculations to turn bloody sufferings of others into golden opportunities for profits in the Russia-Ukraine conflict. For example, during his visit to China in early April, Thai Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Don Pramudwinai said he appreciates China's objective and fair position on the Ukraine issue, that "Asian countries should maintain peace and stability in the region, jointly resist unilateral sanctions and long-arm jurisdiction that have no basis in international law, and prevent attempts to create tensions and replicate crises in the region."</p> <p> Playing small clique politics and forcing others to take sides -- Washington's old tricks to gain geopolitical interests -- work against ASEAN's will to uphold regional peace and stability and to realize sustainable economic development. Launching trade wars and breaking pacts -- Washington's classical acts of unilateralism -- severely disrupt normal trade exchanges and supply chains in the region and deal a heavy blow to ASEAN's economy. All those wrongdoings have tarnished Washington's credit and influence as the world's sole superpower, and driven it further apart from ASEAN members.</p> <p> The long arc of history teaches each and every country that acting without scruples almost always results in the reverse of what one desires. It is time for Washington to learn this lesson, abandon its old dream of Cold War hegemony, uphold an open and inclusive mindset, and play its due role in maintaining regional and global peace, stability and development.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi, Croatian president exchange congratulations on 30th anniversary of diplomatic ties ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096601</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096601.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 09:01:22 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/94/13427338071703457134.jpg" style="height: 563px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on Oct. 20, 2020 shows the Peljesac Bridge under construction near Komarna, Croatia. (Milan Sabic/Pixsell via Xinhua)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping and his counterpart of the Republic of Croatia, Zoran Milanovic, on Friday exchanged congratulatory messages on the 30th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between the two countries.</p> <p> In his message, Xi pointed out that since the establishment of diplomatic ties 30 years ago, China and Croatia have always respected each other and treated each other as equals, adding that bilateral relations have withstood the test of international vicissitudes.</p> <p> Thanks to the concerted efforts of both sides, China and Croatia have enjoyed solid political mutual trust and achieved positive results in their cooperation in jointly building the Belt and Road, bringing benefits to the people of the two countries, he said.</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/37/10305212393747464001.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Airport staff unload medical supplies off a cargo aircraft from Shanghai of China in Zagreb, Croatia, April 12, 2020. (Xinhua/Gao Lei)</em></p> <p> In the face of the challenges caused by COVID-19, China and Croatia have joined hands to fight the pandemic and written a new story of bilateral friendship, Xi added.</p> <p> Noting that he attaches great importance to the development of the bilateral ties, Xi said he is ready to work with President Milanovic to take the 30th anniversary of diplomatic ties as an opportunity to consolidate political mutual trust between the two countries, strengthen the alignment of development strategies, and jointly pilot bilateral relations for greater development, so as to benefit the two countries and their people.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chef makes exquisite Japanese cuisine despite having no interest in cooking ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096598</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096598.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 18:28:54 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <script src="http://tv.people.com.cn/img/player/v.js"></script><script>showPlayer({id:"/pvservice/xml/2022/5/13/eb9cf567-45fa-4270-abd5-1957ea45976e.xml",width:830,height:550});</script></p> <p> Im a chef but I dont like cooking that much.</p> <p> This is how Ryuya Nagase, a chef working for a restaurant specializing in creative Japanese cuisine in Beijing, has described himself.</p> <p> Despite his lack of interest in cooking, Nagase is no newcomer when it comes to serving up his various gourmet delicacies featuring exquisite textures and flavors to his many customers, inspired by his constant stream of culinary ideas. His diligence and sense of pride, driven by an unwillingness to lose business to any of his rival competitors, has put him ahead of the pack among restauranters operating in Beijings fine dining scene.</p> <p> Nagase has already lived in China for six years. For him, everything here is still filled with a sense of novelty. China has become like my second home, he said.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi calls for solidarity, collaboration in global fight against COVID-19 ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096592</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096592.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 17:26:47 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- As of Friday, the worldwide count of COVID-19 cases has exceeded 520 million, with over 6 million related deaths.</p> <p> As the world is plagued by major challenges, not least a pandemic unseen in a century, Chinese President Xi Jinping has on multiple occasions called on the international community to take concerted actions against the virus.</p> <p> The following are some highlights of his remarks on how cooperation can help the world survive.</p> <p> April 21, 2022</p> <p> In his keynote speech at the opening ceremony of the Boao Forum for Asia Annual Conference 2022, Xi stressed that we need to work together to defend people's lives and health.</p> <p> For humanity to clinch a final victory against the COVID-19 pandemic, more hard efforts are needed. It is essential that countries support each other, better coordinate response measures and improve global public health governance, so as to form strong international synergy against the pandemic, said Xi.</p> <p> Jan. 17, 2022</p> <p> At the virtual session of the 2022 World Economic Forum, Xi pledged to embrace cooperation on jointly overcoming the pandemic and champion economic globalization.</p> <p> As COVID-19 is resurging with more variants and spreading faster than before, Xi stressed the importance of fully leveraging vaccines as a powerful weapon and ensuring the equitable distribution of vaccines to close the global immunization gap.</p> <p> Xi called on countries to strengthen international cooperation against COVID-19, carry out active cooperation on the research and development of medicines, jointly build multiple lines of defense against the coronavirus, and speed up efforts to build a global community of health for all.</p> <p> Dec. 31, 2021</p> <p> China has provided 2 billion doses of COVID-19 vaccines to more than 120 countries and international organizations for the global COVID response, Xi said in his 2022 New Year Address.</p> <p> "Only through unity, solidarity and cooperation can countries around the world write a new chapter in building a community with a shared future for mankind," he said.</p> <p> Nov. 29, 2021</p> <p> China and Africa should fight COVID-19 with solidarity, deepen practical cooperation, promote green development, and uphold equity and justice, Xi said at the opening ceremony of the Eighth Ministerial Conference of the Forum on China-Africa Cooperation via video link.</p> <p> On fighting COVID-19 with solidarity, Xi stressed the need to truly ensure the accessibility and affordability of vaccines in Africa.</p> <p> Oct. 31, 2021</p> <p> While addressing the 16th G20 Leaders' Summit via video link, Xi said that at present, the spread of the COVID-19 pandemic has triggered multiple crises.</p> <p> The development achievements made by the international community over the years have been seriously eroded and developing countries are facing unprecedented challenges and tests, Xi pointed out.</p> <p> The COVID-19 pandemic has once again shown that all countries, with high stakes in each other's future and converging interests, form a community with a shared future for mankind, Xi said, noting that promoting sustainable development in developing countries will benefit the people of the countries concerned, and also affect the future and destiny of the whole mankind and the Earth.</p> <p> Sept. 24, 2021</p> <p> While delivering a speech via video at the opening ceremony of the 2021 Zhongguancun Forum, Xi called on all countries to strengthen openness and cooperation in science and technology.</p> <p> Xi noted that nowadays profound changes unseen in a century are evolving rapidly in the world and the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic is far-reaching, presenting severe challenges for the recovery of the global economy.</p> <p> All countries in the world need to strengthen openness and cooperation in science and technology, explore ways and means of jointly solving important global issues through sci-tech innovation, address the challenges of the times together, and promote the noble cause of peace and development for all, said Xi.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ US media: 1 million COVID-19 deaths the benchmark of an unprecedented American tragedy ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096589</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096589.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 17:26:33 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205131708000440648616903.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 4761px;" /></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi's Economic Agenda: Charting roadmap for China's modern infrastructure system ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096515</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096515.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 16:27:32 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- In the face of COVID-19 flare-ups and increasing downward pressure on the economy, the Chinese leadership is looking at infrastructure investment to bolster growth while realizing the country's modernization goals.</p> <p> The country's renewed calls for infrastructure investment were reiterated at recent high-profile meetings chaired by Chinese President Xi Jinping, also general secretary of the Communist Party of China (CPC) Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission.</p> <p> During the meeting of the Central Committee for Financial and Economic Affairs on April 26, Xi, also head of the committee, urged all-out efforts to strengthen infrastructure construction in the country's endeavor toward a modern infrastructure system.</p> <p> From traditional infrastructures, such as water conservancy and transportation networks, to the new infrastructures led by cloud computing and artificial intelligence platforms, the meeting discussed a wide range of infrastructure development topics and gave full consideration to the various needs related to China's future development.</p> <p> Later that week, on April 29, a meeting of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee, chaired by Xi, reiterated the need to comprehensively reinforce infrastructure construction.</p> <p> These high-level announcements made during the two consecutive meetings highlighted the pivotal role of infrastructure in the national economy, said Sun Chuanwang, a professor at Xiamen University.</p> <p> The moves will further stimulate investment potential in the infrastructure sector and bring opportunities for the relevant industries and enterprises, Sun added.</p> <p> A flurry of pledges to ensure solid implementation followed. The Ministry of Transport, for instance, planned to advance infrastructure investment with a moderately proactive approach. Meanwhile, the National Development and Reform Commission (NDRC) urged to expand infrastructure investment in the fields of industrial upgrades, urban and rural construction and national security.</p> <p> Infrastructure serves as a pillar for economic and social development. Under Xi's leadership, China has made great advances in infrastructure construction, ranging from water conservancy and transportation projects, to information infrastructure, with the overall level improving in leaps and bounds.</p> <p> Concerned about people's well-being in border areas, Xi urged efforts to advance the construction of the Sichuan-Tibet Railway project with high quality, in an instruction made ahead of the construction of the Ya'an-Nyingchi section of the railway in November 2020.</p> <p> Describing the project as a vital step in facilitating the Party's general plan for governing Tibet in the new era, he stressed the project's important role in safeguarding national unity, promoting ethnic solidarity and consolidating stability in border areas.</p> <p> A few months later, aboard a train from Nyingchi Railway Station to the regional capital Lhasa, Xi inspected the construction along the railway and hailed the railway as a major move to boost Tibet's development and improve people's living standards.</p> <p> With the country's modernization drive high on his agenda, Xi met with the main scientists and project leaders of China's Five-hundred-meter Aperture Spherical Radio Telescope (FAST), the world's largest single-dish radio telescope, during his inspection trip in southwest China's Guizhou Province in February last year.</p> <p> Noting that the FAST is a major national scientific and technological infrastructure, Xi stressed the importance of science and technology in China's pursuit of building a modern socialist country.</p> <p> In addition to leveraging infrastructure investment to spur economic growth in the short term, China has also been striving to build technological and digital infrastructure as a part of its long-term goal to optimize the overall economic layout.</p> <p> As part of the digital information infrastructure, the number of 5G base stations in the country increased by 81,000 during the first quarter of the year, bringing the total to over 1.5 million.</p> <p> In the country's latest steps to ride the digitalization wave amid a surge of demand for computing capacity, China initiated works earlier this year on a mega project to establish eight national computing hubs and 10 national data center clusters in a bid to improve overall computing power and resource efficiency.</p> <p> "Computing power has already become an important infrastructure for the national economic development," the NDRC stated on its website, estimating China's demand for computing power to surge by over 20 percent annually in the coming years.</p> <p> As the Chinese economy enters into its critical stage of transformation and upgrading, a modern infrastructure system with a focus on shoring up weak links and fostering new growth drivers will lay a solid foundation for the country's medium and long-term development, said Fan Ruoying, a researcher with the Bank of China.</p> <p> Looking ahead, efforts should be made to improve cross-regional and cross-department coordination in organizing infrastructure investment, lift restrictions on market access for private enterprises, and further innovate investment and financing methods, Fan noted.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese Wisdom in Xi's Words: Minor steps can take one to a wider world ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096463</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096463.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 15:24:25 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- "Everything in life must be experienced by oneself; it is the minor steps that take one to a wider world." President Xi Jinping quoted this line from an ancient Chinese poem to encourage young Chinese to strive for progress.</p> <p> The poem was written by Fan Peng, a Chinese poet in the Yuan Dynasty (1271-1368). Xi, also general secretary of the Communist Party of China (CPC) Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, cited the line while addressing a ceremony held in Beijing to mark the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC) on Tuesday.</p> <p> Speaking at the ceremony on Tuesday, Xi called on CYLC members to be models of hard work and dedication, take the lead in remaining committed to standing on the side of the people, and be realistic, pragmatic, and down-to-earth.</p> <p> Realizing the Chinese Dream of national rejuvenation is a relay race of history in which today's young people should strive for excellent performance, said Xi, adding that the times have always endowed young people with historical responsibilities.</p> <p> "We believe a nation will be strong only when its young people are strong and a nation will make progress only when its younger generations make progress," said Xi. "We have always believed that the future of our nation rests on youths."</p> <p> The CYLC was founded on May 5, 1922, under the direct leadership of the CPC.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi Focus-Closeup: The undaunted nurse ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096193</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096193.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:15:37 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Liu Jiayi, a young nurse in China, came under the global spotlight when President Xi Jinping praised her on an international platform.</p> <p> Xi shared her story during a speech at a meeting of the United Nations (UN) in 2020, expressing his admiration for medical workers, including nurses.</p> <p> Liu was among the 40,000-plus health workers from across the country who rushed to the central province of Hubei in 2020 when it was fighting a fierce battle against the COVID-19 epidemic.</p> <p> "The moment I put on the protective suit, I am not a kid anymore." -- Xi cited Liu's words from a TV interview when she was told by a journalist that she is still very young, and needs to be taken care of.</p> <p> "Those words moved the whole nation," Xi said while sharing Liu's story at the meeting marking the 25th anniversary of the Fourth World Conference on Women.</p> <p> Coming from the city of Huizhou, Guangdong Province, about 1,000 km south of Hubei's capital Wuhan, Liu was the youngest member of the medical-assistance team dispatched by the province to assist with Wuhan's fight against the novel coronavirus.</p> <p> She volunteered to join the team during the Lantern Festival in February 2020. It was the furthest distance she had ever traveled from home, and the month she spent there was the longest time she had ever been away from her parents.</p> <p> At the UN meeting, Xi spoke highly of Liu and medical workers like her, saying "their courage and hard work have shown the very best of the medical profession" and "their devotion and sacrifice have kept the nation intact through difficult times."</p> <p> At a time when multiple Chinese cities are battling a resurgence of COVID-19 infections, a large number of nurses again threw themselves into the battle without hesitation.</p> <p> "They proved worthy of the great trust placed in them," as Xi rightly said in his greetings to nurses in 2020 ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12.</p> <p> The number of registered nurses in China had reached 5.02 million at the end of 2021, and there were about 3.56 nurses for every 1,000 people, according to official statistics.</p> <p> Xi hailed them for exemplifying the noble spirit of respecting and protecting life, healing the wounded and rescuing the dying, and being dedicated to the cause, and asked governments at all levels to care about nurses, focus more efforts on strengthening the nursing workforce, and improve the incentive mechanisms.</p> <p> Nursing is an important part of health care, Xi noted, calling on all members of society to show their appreciation and support for nurses.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi, Slovenian president exchange congratulations on 30th anniversary of diplomatic ties ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095991</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10095991.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 08:16:16 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping and his Slovenian counterpart Borut Pahor on Thursday exchanged congratulatory messages on the 30th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between the two countries.</p> <p> Xi pointed out that since the establishment of bilateral diplomatic ties 30 years ago, China and Slovenia, treating each other with respect and as equal, have achieved positive results in mutually beneficial cooperation and witnessed increasing cultural and people-to-people exchanges, which brings tangible benefits to the people of the two countries.</p> <p> In the face of COVID-19, the people of the two countries have supported each other, demonstrating the profound friendship between China and Slovenia, he said.</p> <p> Xi stressed that he attaches great importance to the development of China-Slovenia relations, saying that he is ready to work with Pahor to take the 30th anniversary of diplomatic ties as a new starting point, seize the historic opportunity of jointly building the Belt and Road, strengthen the alignment of development strategies of the two sides, and deepen practical cooperation, so as to inject new impetus into the development of bilateral relations for the benefits of the two countries and their people.</p> <p> In his message, Pahor earnestly congratulated China on its leapfrog development in various fields, saying that bilateral relations between Slovenia and China enjoy a long history and have seen rapid development since diplomatic ties were established 30 years ago.</p> <p> He added that economic and trade cooperation has been fruitful and the fields of cooperation are growing, among which ice and snow sports have become a new highlight of cooperation.</p> <p> As a member of the European Union, Slovenia actively supports enhancing Europe-China relations and is committed to delivering the fruits of cooperation to both sides and the international community, said the president.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Infographics: Highlights of Xi Jinping's speech at ceremony marking centenary of Communist Youth League of China ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095967</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095967.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 18:55:22 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121840000055297013633.jpg" style="width: 700px; height: 1244px;" /></p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121840000246181092025.jpg" style="width: 700px; height: 1244px;" /></p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121840000384879139060.jpg" style="width: 700px; height: 1244px;" /></p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121840000500897544328.jpg" style="width: 700px; height: 1244px;" /></p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121841000011188596423.jpg" style="width: 700px; height: 1244px;" /></p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121841000127437882063.jpg" style="width: 700px; height: 1244px;" /></p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121841000246834622589.jpg" style="width: 700px; height: 1244px;" /></p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121841000355899764708.jpg" style="width: 700px; height: 1244px;" /></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi's speech at ceremony marking centenary of Communist Youth League of China published ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095847</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095847.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 16:31:47 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- A speech by Chinese President Xi Jinping at a ceremony marking the centenary of the Communist Youth League of China in Beijing has been published.</p> <p> Xi, also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, delivered the speech on May 10.</p> <p> The booklet was published by the People's Publishing House and is available at Xinhua Bookstore outlets across the country.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ How Washington's zero-sum fixation is derailing its own agenda ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095833</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095833.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 16:26:43 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121517000433574677063.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 506px;" /></p> <p> <span style="color:#0000ff;">The US has pledged to rally to the cause of fighting climate change; but isn't its coercive tariff on solar panels only serving to stymie that mission? (Graphic: Zero-sum or zero-carbon/People's Daily Online)</span></p> <p> The Glasgow climate summit held last year was largely viewed as a chance for redemption. After the grim outcome of the (2C) mitigation target set at the 2009 Copenhagen summit, humanity's "last chance" to save the planet, nations were nudged to give climate cooperation another shot. Few world leaders are more zealous and vocal on the matter than US president Joe Biden, who has proposed a portfolio of ambitious goals and called for joint collaboration between major players and, in particular, the US and China.</p> <p> Then, last February, in a surprise move, the Biden administration announced that it would extend the Trump-era Section 201 tariffs slapped on solar panels, in a bid to "continue facilitating positive adjustment to competition" from imported photovoltaic cells. Though the administration did offer some clues on the "positive adjustment," almost four years after the tariffs were levied, experts argued that America's solar industry remained nascent in its development despite full-blown trade barriers and that the decision came at an emissions cost.</p> <p> In an opinion essay published earlier this month in <em>The Hill</em>, John Paul Helveston, an American researcher, debated that tariffs won't help the US build a "robust solar industry." He contended that China's tremendous R&amp;D efforts on photovoltaic (PV) innovations, which helped slash the prices of most PV panels from $2,000 per kilowatt to just $300 per kilowatt, cannot be simply duplicated. It is highly unlikely that another nation will be able to "replicate China's skills in the time frame needed to avoid the worst consequences of climate change," he cited an article he co-wrote in <em>Science </em>back in 2019, adding, "Rather than continuing the Trump-era tariffs on Chinese solar panels, the US and others should be partnering with Chinese firms to obtain low-cost technologies and components to increase domestic deployment of renewables as fast as possible to meet the narrow window left to decarbonize."</p> <p> Low-cost solar technologies and components, however, have been the very items subject to Washington's ongoing investigation.</p> <p> The New York Times reported on April 29 that, amidst an investigation by the US Commerce Department targeting Chinese-made PV parts, the US solar industry has been "frozen," with over 300 solar projects being "canceled or delayed." American energy enterprises, big and small, have all been dragged into the quagmire of self-censorship over Chinese solar parts. "The investigation is having a catastrophic negative impact on the renewable energy sector and driving up electricity prices. With each day the tariff investigation continues, the country is falling further behind in achieving our climate goals," said Nick Bullinger, COO of a Chicago-based solar company, in an interview that appeared in the <em>Times </em>article.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121524000530389177826.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>U.S. President Joe Biden (R) speaks during an event, at the White House in Washington, D.C., the United States, on May 9, 2022. Biden said that the administration is "discussing" whether to drop hiked tariffs on Chinese products. (Photo by Ting Shen/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> From the perspective of environmental benefits or from the standpoint of economic interests, Washington's 4-year-long-and-counting solar clampdown is cost-ineffective, as it collides with even Biden's own climate agenda.</p> <p> US president Joe Biden attended the Glasgow summit with high hopes100% renewable energy by 2035; but the Solar Energy Industries Association (SEIA), an NGO, estimated that America's current production capacity only makes up 15% of its demand. Neither will taxing and purging Chinese solar panels or PV parts help "bring jobs back home," since even with heavy tariffs the US remains heavily dependent on imported PV products.</p> <p> Besides, the volume of jobs generated by solar installations in the US is ten times larger than the manufacturing jobs created by the nation's entire solar sector, according to the US National Renewable Energy Laboratory (NREL). As a letter sent to President Biden last January by eight American senators (from both parties) stated, the Section 201 tariffs had "led to the loss of more than 62,000 American clean energy jobs and 10.5 gigawatts of foregone solar deployment." It is difficult then to tell who the tariffs and investigation are designed to punish: overseas solar producers or the American labor force?</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121527000336131916818.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on Nov. 19, 2021 shows the U.S. Capitol building in Washington, D.C., the United States. (Photo by Ting Shen/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> But it's not hard to detect what formula is being applied in America's zero-carbon solutionits default zero-sum fixation. After all, the one-nation's-gain-representing-another's-loss mindset takes various shapes in the China-US relations from Washington's point of view.</p> <p> On the global stage, it is reflected in Washington's unreasonable belief that China's global presence, such as donating COVID-19 vaccines to developing nations, will undermine the superpower's global influence.</p> <p> In the economic sphere, it is manifested in America's obsession with punitive tariffs, which it deems will help reverse trade deficits and boost domestic industry, even though the burden will ultimately be shifted towards American consumers in the form of rising prices.</p> <p> In the technological and academic realms, it is showcased in America's year-long crackdown on Chinese tech companies and its unjustified witch-hunt targeting Chinese academics and students.</p> <p> ... ...</p> <p> The aforementioned aspects of Washington's zero-sum practices are epitomized by its now-stagnant solar industry, which in turn has demonstrated why such a mindset won't work. Internationally, it will risk hindering the joint cause of emissions reduction; economically, it will impede the low-hanging fruits and long-term benefits brought by the should-be full-fledged solar sector; and, from the perspectives of innovation and technological progress, it will further dampen the outlook of cooperation on green innovations.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121521000527071017527.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 800px;" /></p> <p> <em>Aerial panoramic photo taken on April 21, 2022 shows the Dalad Photovoltaic Power Base in Dalad Banner, north China's Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region. (Xinhua/Liu Lei)</em></p> <p> Dwelling on a planet that is currently plagued by a global pandemic (accompanied by inflation and a possible recession), haunted by continuous wars and conflicts, and overshadowed by the looming threat of global warming, we all know that a zero-sum fixation and a Cold-War mindset won't help fix any of these global problems. On the contrary, they are destined to make the planet warmer, wars deadlier, and other global puzzles more insoluble.</p> <p> For Washington, it needs to face the reality that it cannot achieve technological hegemony or climate leadership by setting up a new Iron Curtain to deter and isolate China. Returning to a rational and pragmatic China policy is the sole way to nurture healthy and sustainable China-US ties and encourage the two sides to work together on issues of common and global concern. Conversely, the zero-sum mindset is bound for a lose-lose path.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi's moments with disaster-hit people ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095818</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095818.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 15:17:40 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <center> <video controls="controls" poster=" http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/5/12/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_fc313006842db708647248562af1134d.jpeg" src=" http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/5/12/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_17b40746150168711d17ab4cc3298255.mp4" style=" width: 830px; height:550px;"> <p> &nbsp;</p> </video> </center> <p> President Xi Jinping once said, "I have always been concerned about people in disaster-hit areas. I feel relieved when I see people's life and work are protected and full of hope."</p> <p> Xi has visited disaster victims many times. Here are some of those moments. Check it out!</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily App</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Interview: Global Security Initiative reflects China's commitment to upholding world peace, prosperity: Pakistani expert ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095656</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095656.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:34:31 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> ISLAMABAD, May 11 (Xinhua) -- The Global Security Initiative proposed by Chinese President Xi Jinping is an important step in the right direction, reflecting China's commitment to upholding world peace, security and prosperity, a Pakistani expert said recently.</p> <p> Adhering to the concept of building a community with a shared future for mankind, China continued to play a vital role in global growth, development and security while promoting authentic multilateralism, rejecting a Cold-War mentality, and maintaining a policy of non-interference, Farhat Asif, president of the Institute of Peace and Diplomatic Studies, an Islamabad-based think-tank, told Xinhua in a recent interview.</p> <p> "There is a lot more potential in the new initiative ... providing a vision of comprehensive, cooperative and sustainable security will help the countries who would be part of the initiative to grow further in a secure and peaceful environment," the expert said.</p> <p> Asif said that China has been working on global economic development and launched several initiatives, including the Belt and Road Initiative (BRI) and Global Development Initiative, which have enabled people across the world to reap the benefits of win-win cooperation. After all, sustainable peace and security are based on prosperity.</p> <p> More than 140 countries of different religions, cultures, languages and socio-economic statuses are part of the BRI, showing inclusiveness and a harmonious relationship between them, she said.</p> <p> The expert noted that the Global Security Initiative proposed by China is more people-centric which seeks safety and security for everyone in the world as opposed to some Western countries' unilateral pursuit of their own safety based on hegemonic designs.</p> <p> The containment and Cold-War mentality of the West has severely undermined global peace and security, creating a grim humanitarian crisis and security challenges internationally, she said.</p> <p> The recent Russia-Ukraine conflict is a "classic example" in this case which arose when certain groups of countries ignore security demands of other countries while ensuring absolute security for themselves, the expert said, adding that "there is a requirement for these countries to opt for dialogue and diplomacy instead of fueling it further."</p> <p> The expert said that technological innovations and the development of social media have strengthened interconnection and interdependence among countries. The world has become a global village that needs real multilateralism and enhanced cooperation rather than unilateralism to combat challenges, including the pandemic, climate change and food security.</p> <p> As the security of one country is linked with the security of another, the new initiative proposed by China, which is more focused on human development and security, will allow an inclusive participation of every country, she said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Collection of Xi's diplomatic speeches published ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095633</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095633.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:17:14 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- The first and second volume of a collection of diplomatic speeches by Chinese President Xi Jinping has been published by the Central Party Literature Press.</p> <p> Compiled by the Institute of Party History and Literature of the Communist Party of China (CPC) Central Committee, the book includes 136 speeches delivered at international events between March 2013 and November 2021 by Xi, also general secretary of the CPC Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission.</p> <p> Xi, as the chief architect of major country diplomacy with Chinese characteristics, has delivered speeches on multiple international occasions, proposing a series of new ideas, new propositions and new initiatives with distinctive Chinese features, which reflect the call of the times and lead the trend of human progress.</p> <p> They are a major part of Xi Jinping Thought on Diplomacy and of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era.</p> <p> They bear significant guidance for the establishment of a new type of international relations, the building of a global community of shared future, and creating a favorable international environment for realizing the Chinese Dream of national rejuvenation.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Commentary: China, Germany should enhance cooperation during times of uncertainty ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095613</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095613.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:03:12 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping had a virtual meeting with German Chancellor Olaf Scholz on Monday. Facing complex changes in the international landscape and various challenges to world peace and development, the leaders of the two countries have been guiding bilateral relations from a high level, providing valuable momentum for greater China-Germany and China-EU cooperation.</p> <p> Today, peace and development are under threat due to rampant hegemonism and exacerbated global divisions. The onset of the Russia-Ukraine conflict has reignited the flames of war in Europe.</p> <p> Such an alarming increase in threats to global security and development has led to an urgent call for more stability and certainty in navigating these turbulent times.</p> <p> In his meeting with Scholz, Xi said that under the current circumstances, it is particularly important for the two countries to maintain sound and steady growth of bilateral ties and better harness the stabilizing, constructive and steering role of this relationship.</p> <p> This not only serves the interests of the Chinese and German peoples but will also contribute significantly to world peace and tranquility, he said.</p> <p> There is no change in China's commitment to developing ties with Germany; there is no change in China's sincere wish for closer cooperation with Germany; and there is no change in China's conviction that China and Germany can make greater differences together, Xi emphasized.</p> <p> These remarks shed light on the value and significance of China-Germany relations, pointing the way to future cooperation and dialogue between the two countries.</p> <p> Meanwhile, past achievements have laid a solid foundation for the steady development of China-Germany relations. In the past five decades since the two countries established diplomatic ties, the bilateral relationship has shown great vitality, endurance, resilience and potential.</p> <p> While Germany is China's most important trading partner in Europe, China has been Germany's top trade partner for six consecutive years. The trade volume between them has mushroomed to more than 250 billion U.S. dollars in 2021 from less than 300 million dollars at the very beginning of diplomatic relations.</p> <p> Nearly 60 percent of German companies in China reported improved business operations last year, and 71 percent plan further investment in the country, according to a report released by the German Chamber of Commerce in China and KPMG.</p> <p> As for the question of how China and Germany manage to develop together and contribute to each other's success, Xi offered an appropriate answer: It is essentially attributable to a commitment to mutual respect and win-win cooperation, a valuable piece of experience and important principle that should be upheld all along.</p> <p> There is immense potential remains for the two countries to enrich their relations and deepen their mutually beneficial cooperation regarding climate change, macroeconomic policy, environmental protection, services trade, AI and digitalization.</p> <p> In addition, China is speeding up its efforts to foster a new development paradigm, which means broader market opportunities for Germany and all other countries.</p> <p> Xi called on the two sides to stand for true multilateralism, uphold international fairness and justice, defend the UN's central role in international affairs, safeguard basic norms governing international relations, promote an open world economy, and make global development more balanced, coordinated and inclusive.</p> <p> He also expressed his hope for Germany's active support for and participation in the Global Development Initiative and the Global Security Initiative, with a view to building a community with a shared future for mankind.</p> <p> Since Germany is a pivotal country in the EU, the continent's security is closely associated with Germany. Notably, the ongoing Ukraine crisis has pushed European security to a crossroads.</p> <p> On this issue, China always stands on the side of peace and makes its conclusion independently based on the merits of each matter, working in its own way to promote peace and defuse tensions.</p> <p> Xi has emphasized during that meeting: "It is important to make every effort to prevent the conflict from intensifying or magnifying to a point of no return."</p> <p> For that purpose, the European side needs to show historical responsibility and political wisdom, bear in mind the long-term stability of Europe, and promote a solution in a responsible manner, Xi said, stressing that the security of Europe should be kept in the hands of Europeans themselves.</p> <p> China's appeal for peace and stability has been widely welcomed in Europe and beyond. When reporting on the video meeting, many European media outlets, including Reuters, headlined Xi's call to prevent the Ukraine conflict from intensifying, fully reflecting how the international community supports China's take on this issue.</p> <p> In an unsettled international situation, sound and steady growth in China-EU relations remains more crucial than ever.</p> <p> The China-Europe relationship is not targeted at, subjugated to, or controlled by any third party, which is a strategic consensus that both sides must follow in the long run, Xi said.</p> <p> Therefore, Xi highlighted the importance for China and the EU, with a dialectical and long-term view, with mutual respect and with the right perception, to increase communication and enhance mutual trust.</p> <p> Deepening China-Germany and China-EU cooperation will serve the interest of both sides and even the whole world. By adhering to mutual respect, openness and inclusiveness; seeking common ground while reserving differences; and cooperating for win-win results, China-Germany and China-EU relations will indeed ride the wave of uncertainty towards a brighter future.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Experts speak highly of China's human rights progress ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095604</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095604.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:00:32 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> VIENNA, May 11 (Xinhua) -- Experts attending an international human rights seminar on Tuesday spoke highly of China's human rights development and highlighted China's efforts in promoting international dialogue and cooperation on human rights issues.</p> <p> The 2022 China-Europe Seminar on Human Rights was held both online and offline on Tuesday, with separate venues in the Austrian capital of Vienna and the central Chinese city of Wuhan.</p> <p> More than 100 human rights scholars, officials and representatives from international organizations attended the seminar, themed "Science and Technology and Human Rights."</p> <p> Heinz Fischer, former Austrian president and president of the Austria-China Friendship Association (ACFA), told Xinhua on the sidelines of the seminar that he had visited China many times since the 1970s and witnessed the country's rapid socio-economic development and progress in human rights cause.</p> <p> Fischer said China has transformed into a "highly industrialized" and "high-tech" country in decades.</p> <p> "This is incomparable. This is very impressive," he added.</p> <p> Hannes Fellner, a linguistics professor at the University of Vienna, said that China's poverty alleviation campaign, which lifted "hundreds of millions of people in China out of poverty," is "one of the greatest human rights feats in the history of humankind."</p> <p> China has also succeeded in advancing the human rights cause with the help of science and technology, Fellner added.</p> <p> Delegates at the seminar also applauded the seminar as an important platform to promote dialogue and mutual understanding on human rights issues between China and Europe.</p> <p> Although China and Europe may have different approaches to human rights, "it is necessary to exchange opinions in such a seminar with high-ranking participants," said Fischer.</p> <p> Gerd Kaminski, standing vice president of the ACFA, said the seminar helps promote dialogue on an equal basis and improve mutual understanding.</p> <p> Chinese Ambassador to Austria Li Xiaosi told Xinhua that China and Europe have both attached great importance to the seminar since its inauguration in 2015.</p> <p> Experts, scholars and officials from both sides have participated actively in the event and engaged in constructive dialogue to find consensus, which is conducive to the joint efforts to promote human rights development, Li said.</p> <p> The 2022 China-Europe Seminar on Human Rights was co-hosted by the China Society for Human Rights Studies and the ACFA.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Overseas Chinese youth inspired by Xi's speech to strive for better China ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095567</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095567.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:38:43 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping on Tuesday addressed a ceremony to mark the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Communist Youth League of China.</p> <p> The younger generation, according to Xi, should do their best to help realize national rejuvenation -- the greatest dream of the Chinese people since the Opium War of 1840.</p> <p> Overseas Chinese youth said that they will carry forward their dreams and missions, and forge ahead on the new journey to realize the Chinese Dream of national rejuvenation.</p> <p> Lan Tianzhang, deputy captain of the political work of the 20th Chinese peacekeeping engineering detachment to Lebanon, said the young peacekeepers in Lebanon have been taking concrete actions to fulfill their missions and safeguard world peace, adding that they will work hard to make more contributions to realizing the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation.</p> <p> Wang Xiaowei, manager of the fifth site office of the Phnom Penh-Sihanoukville Expressway invested by the China Road and Bridge Corporation, said they, as young workers serving the Belt and Road Initiative, feel proud of their mission and are more aware of the responsibilities of the young generation, adding that they will take roots in the frontline to ensure that the project becomes a high-quality one.</p> <p> Wang Yuqing, a Chinese teacher at the Confucius Institute at the University of Karachi in Pakistan, said that Xi's words greatly encouraged young teachers working at overseas Confucius Institutes and gave them the confidence to do a better job of telling China's stories.</p> <p> Miao Danying, a lecturer at the United Nations Visitors Service at Nairobi, said that an increasing number of Chinese people are serving in the United Nations and young faces are constantly emerging, showcasing Chinese culture and contributing Chinese talent in different positions.</p> <p> Miao believed that with the continuous development of China, the prospects for Chinese youth to realize their dreams will be even broader.</p> <p> Xia Yang, president of the Association of Chinese Students and Scholars in Japan, said that they must study hard and return home as soon as possible to contribute to China's development and prosperity as well as the rejuvenation of the nation.</p> <p> Li Feng, who is about to finish his studies at the University of Zagreb in Croatia soon and return to China, pledged to be a young person with lofty ideals and firm convictions, and contribute to the development and prosperity of the country.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Video conference held to share festive experience in Xinjiang ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095529</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095529.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:14:57 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> URUMQI, May 11 (Xinhua) -- Muslim residents and religious figures in northwest China's Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region shared their personal experiences in a video during the recently concluded Islamic holy month of Ramadan and Eid al-Fitr.</p> <p> From April 3 to May 2, Muslims of various ethnic groups in the region observed Ramadan. They celebrated Eid al-Fitr, which fell on May 3, while enjoying a one-day holiday, said Xu Guixiang, spokesperson for the regional government, during a video conference on Tuesday.</p> <p> Memet Juma, hatip of the Id Kah Mosque in Kashgar Prefecture, said that prayers visited the 550-year-old mosque every day, and thousands of people of different ethnic groups performed their traditional dances on the square in front of the mosque.</p> <p> Noting that Xinjiang is home to various ethnic groups and religious beliefs, Zumrat Obul, head of the regional united front work department, said that all normal religious activities are protected by law.</p> <p> In recent years, there has been great misunderstanding about the religious situation in Xinjiang, and the United States in particular has groundlessly claimed that religious freedoms are restricted in Xinjiang.</p> <p> "These ridiculous lies run completely counter to the facts," Xu said.</p> <p> "We would like to go on telling Xinjiang's true stories to the international community," Xu said. "We are also looking forward to welcoming more visitors to Xinjiang who can witness the prosperous and comfortable life here."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi's remarks on disaster prevention ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095491</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095491.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 08:48:21 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> May 12 marks National Disaster Prevention and Reduction Day in China. President Xi Jinping has always stressed a people-centered approach to disaster prevention and relief. Here are some of his remarks on the subject.</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/35/13944295689085450275.jpg" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 506px; width: 900px;" /></p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/58/15489890786641279994.jpg" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 506px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> &nbsp;</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/64/10284673369446562284.jpg" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 506px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Chinadaily.com.cn</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Commentary: Xi's words shed light on role of youth in national rejuvenation drive ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095404</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095404.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 08:17:11 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205120803000303221630925.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 659px;" /></p> <p> <em>Chinese President Xi Jinping, also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, delivers a speech at a ceremony marking the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC) at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, May 10, 2022. (Xinhua/Li Xueren)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- The Chinese leadership has once again underscored what role the youth should play in the nation's rejuvenation drive.</p> <p> In a speech on Tuesday, Chinese President Xi Jinping urged members of the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC) to be responsible, have firm convictions and work hard as the 73.7 million-strong organization celebrated its centenary.</p> <p> The younger generation, according to Xi, also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, should do their best to help realize national rejuvenation -- the greatest dream of the Chinese people since the Opium War of 1840.</p> <p> The destiny of any generation is closely connected with the era they live in. The youth have more opportunities to achieve their dreams when they chime with the cause of the Party and the people.</p> <p> The pursuit of the Chinese Dream is a relay race. Since completing the building of a moderately prosperous society in all respects in 2021, China has now embarked on a new journey -- building a great modern socialist country in all respects by the mid-21st century.</p> <p> Standing at a new historical juncture, Chinese youth in the new era should take on their responsibility, and they will be blessed with a spacious and promising platform.</p> <p> In his speech, Xi urged youth league members to "always stand on the high ground of ideals and convictions."</p> <p> Ideals and convictions serve as a beacon for life and pursuits. They determine a person's position and direction. Young people need to observe society, reflect on life, and create a future on the strength of wisdom.</p> <p> Xi said they should aim high at an early age and cultivate the trust in the Party, the confidence in socialism with Chinese characteristics and the belief in Marxism from the bottom of their heart.</p> <p> The importance of hard work was also highlighted by Xi.</p> <p> The rejuvenation of the Chinese nation will be no easy task. It will not be achieved by simply "beating drums and gongs." Daunting challenges are inevitable in this new journey.</p> <p> Chinese youth in the new era must work hard. Xi said the younger generation is the most energetic and enterprising and the least conservative force in society. The cause of the Party and the people could not have developed without the arduous dedication made by generations of young people.</p> <p> Chinese youth will always be the vanguard force in realizing the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation and meeting challenges in a world undergoing changes unseen in a century.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi sends congratulatory message to Hungary's new president Katalin Novak ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095037</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095037.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 09:58:11 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping on Tuesday sent a congratulatory message to Katalin Novak on her taking office as the Hungarian president.</p> <p> The development of China-Hungary relations, Xi said, has maintained at a high level in recent years, marked by frequent high-level exchanges, fruitful cooperation in various fields and sound cooperation in international and regional affairs.</p> <p> Xi said he attaches great importance to the development of China-Hungary relations, adding that he is ready to work with Novak to deepen political mutual trust and traditional friendship between the two countries.</p> <p> Xi also called for joint efforts to strengthen cooperation between the two countries both at the bilateral level and within the Belt and Road cooperation, the China-Central and Eastern European countries cooperation and other frameworks, and to promote the China-Hungary comprehensive strategic partnership to a new level so as to benefit the two countries and their peoples.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi's keynote speech at opening ceremony of Boao Forum for Asia Annual Conference 2022 published ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095011</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095011.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 09:57:10 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- A keynote speech by Chinese President Xi Jinping at the Boao Forum for Asia Annual Conference 2022 has been published.</p> <p> Xi delivered the speech, titled "Rising to Challenges and Building a Bright Future Through Cooperation," via video link at the opening ceremony of the event on April 21.</p> <p> The booklet was published by the People's Publishing House and is available at Xinhua Bookstore outlets across the country.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi attends ceremony marking centenary of Communist Youth League of China ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094459</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094459.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 08:41:23 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205110835000309862623395.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 644px;" /></p> <p> <em>Chinese President Xi Jinping, also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, delivers a speech at a ceremony marking the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC) at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, May 10, 2022. (Xinhua/Yue Yuewei)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping, also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, attended a ceremony held at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing on Tuesday marking the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Communist Youth League of China.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205110836000510091223544.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 608px;" /></p> <p> <em>Xi Jinping, Li Keqiang, Li Zhanshu, Wang Yang, Wang Huning, Zhao Leji and Han Zheng attend a ceremony marking the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC) at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, May 10, 2022. (Xinhua/Li Xueren)</em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205110838000065220006639.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></em></p> <p> <em>Chinese President Xi Jinping, also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, delivers a speech at a ceremony marking the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC) at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, May 10, 2022. (Xinhua/Yan Yan)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi tells Chinese youth to contribute energy, creativity to rejuvenation ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094865</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10094865.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 08:26:08 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/56/12782305718137599088.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Chinese President Xi Jinping, also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, delivers a speech at a ceremony marking the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC) at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, May 10, 2022. (Xinhua/Li Xueren)</em></p> <p> <strong>* Founded in 1922, the CYLC has proven itself to be the vanguard of the Chinese youth movement, Xi said.</strong></p> <p> <strong>* Xi told the League to always serve as the strongest "bridge" and "bond" that connect the Party and Chinese youth.</strong></p> <p> <strong>* League members should be patriotic and innovative, while not being misguided or intimidated by difficulties, Xi said.</strong></p> <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping on Tuesday hailed the contributions made by young communists over the past century, and called on them to offer energy and creativity to push forward national rejuvenation.</p> <p> Xi, also general secretary of the Communist Party of China (CPC) Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, made the remarks while addressing a ceremony held in Beijing to mark the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC).</p> <p> Founded in 1922, the CYLC has closely followed the Party's lead and written a "youthful chapter" in the rejuvenation of the Chinese nation, Xi said.</p> <p> The ceremony, broadcast from the Great Hall of the People to a national audience, was presided over by Wang Huning, and attended by Li Keqiang, Li Zhanshu, Wang Yang, Zhao Leji and Han Zheng. All of them are members of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee.</p> <p> The CYLC had more than 73.71 million members by the end of 2021.</p> <p> Speaking at the ceremony, He Junke, first secretary of the Secretariat of the CYLC Central Committee, attributed the robust vitality of Chinese youth in the new era to the leadership of the Party.</p> <p> Young people must play a vanguard role and closely follow the Party, He said.</p> <p> <strong>IMPORTANT FEATS</strong></p> <p> In his speech, Xi enumerated the contributions made by CYLC members in the past 100 years.</p> <p> League members have accomplished important feats in the victory of the Chinese revolution, the development of the motherland, reform and opening up and socialist modernization, as well as in securing historic achievements and shifts in the cause of the Party and the country in the new era, Xi said.</p> <p> The CYLC has proven itself to be the vanguard of the Chinese youth movement, he noted.</p> <p> Using past experience as an outline for the CYLC in the future, Xi said the League achieved success because it upheld the leadership of the Party, reinforced faith in communism and socialism, committed itself to national rejuvenation, and remained rooted in Chinese youth.</p> <p> Chinese youth in the new era, blessed with a spacious and promising platform, should also shoulder important responsibilities, Xi said.</p> <p> The pursuit of the Chinese Dream is a relay race, Xi said, adding that young Chinese today should strive to excel in contributing to national rejuvenation.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/11/1025736295095899647.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>A ceremony marking the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Communist Youth League of China is held at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, May 10, 2022. (Xinhua/Yue Yuewei)</em></p> <p> <strong>PARTY'S "SCHOOL" AND "BRIDGE"</strong></p> <p> On his expectations for the CYLC, Xi said the League should educate young people for the Party and always serve as a political school guiding the ideological progress of young people.</p> <p> The League should always be a vanguard force in mobilizing China's youth in continuous endeavor, he added.</p> <p> Xi told the League to always serve as the strongest "bridge" and "bond" that connect the Party and Chinese youth, as well as to conduct self-reform.</p> <p> League members must play exemplary roles in life and work, earnestly attend political training, and strive for the glorious goal of becoming qualified CPC members, Xi said, urging them to build up firm beliefs, and boost their courage and skills to carry out struggles.</p> <p> They should also be patriotic and innovative, while not being misguided or intimidated by difficulties, he added.</p> <p> Noting that the CPC is always worthy of trust and to be followed by young people, Xi said the Party always opens its door to young people and warmly welcomes them to become the new blood of the CPC.</p> <p> "The Party and the country place our hopes on young people!" Xi said.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/5/7592618890857070433.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>A ceremony marking the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC) is held at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, May 10, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhai Jianlan)</em></p> <p> "I feel so motivated and I will continue to make my youthful contributions to social development and the pursuit of the Chinese Dream," said Ruznaguri Shatar, a local League cadre in the city of Turpan in northwestern Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region, after hearing Xi's speech.</p> <p> The speech also inspired Zou Bin from central China's Hunan Province. Once a bricklayer, Zou is now a construction project manager and national lawmaker.</p> <p> "This is an era when everyone has the opportunity to shine," Zou said after hearing Xi's speech. "As a young Chinese working on construction sites, I will pay close attention to every detail of my work and help build quality projects and beautiful cities for the country."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi talks with Macron over phone ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094839</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10094839.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 08:14:30 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping spoke with French President Emmanuel Macron on the phone on Tuesday afternoon.</p> <p> Xi noted his close contact with Macron over the past five years, which has helped guide the two countries in sustaining the positive momentum of bilateral ties, conducting fruitful cooperation, and fulfilling the responsibilities of major countries on climate change, biodiversity conservation and other issues.</p> <p> In a world undergoing changes unseen in a century, China and France, two permanent members on the United Nations Security Council and independent major countries, should uphold "independence, mutual understanding, strategic vision and win-win cooperation," a commitment the two sides made when establishing diplomatic relations, stick to their close and enduring comprehensive strategic partnership, respect each other's core interests and major concerns, and strengthen coordination and cooperation in the bilateral, China-Europe and global contexts, he said.</p> <p> Xi added that China will keep close exchanges with France at all levels to promote the healthy growth of China-France relations and maintain world peace and stability.</p> <p> Xi stressed the need to identify, through bilateral dialogue mechanisms, cooperation priorities in the coming five years. He called on the two sides to step up cooperation in emerging areas including artificial intelligence and clean energy, while advancing cooperation in traditional areas like civilian nuclear energy, and aerospace.</p> <p> The Chinese president said China is ready to import more quality products from France, welcomes French financial and hi-tech companies to China for business cooperation, and hopes that the French side will provide a fair, equitable and non-discriminatory business environment for Chinese enterprises that conduct investment and cooperation in France.</p> <p> Xi said that it is important that China and France make good use of big occasions like the 60th anniversary of China-France diplomatic relations and the Paris Olympics, both to take place in 2024, as important opportunities to further increase people-to-people and cultural exchanges and enhance mutual understanding.</p> <p> He added that the two sides should follow true multilateralism, uphold the international system with the United Nations at its core and the international order based on international law, support multi-polarity and economic globalization, and deepen cooperation on climate change and biodiversity.</p> <p> Xi stressed that the two sides need to increase communication and coordination at the Group of 20 and on global food and energy security, expand trilateral cooperation in Africa and other regions, and explore cooperation on the Global Development Initiative and the Global Security Initiative.</p> <p> The Chinese president pointed out that the steady and sound growth of China-EU relations serves the interests of people in China, in Europe and in all other countries, adding that China appreciates France's commitment to strategic autonomy, and hopes that France will encourage the EU to keep a right perception of China and work with China in the same direction by managing differences properly and building on converging interests for closer cooperation in economy and trade, green and digital development, and people-to-people exchanges.</p> <p> Xi also expressed his hope for France, who holds the rotating presidency of the EU, to play a positive role in promoting the sound development of China-EU relations.</p> <p> For his part, Macron commended the open spirit with which the two sides have developed their relations since establishing diplomatic ties.</p> <p> Over the past five years, the two sides have carried out fruitful cooperation across the board, Macron said.</p> <p> For the next five years, France will work with China to deepen cooperation in areas including agriculture, aviation, civilian nuclear energy and culture and to scale up cooperation in climate change and biodiversity, with a view to greater achievements in France-China relations, said the French president.</p> <p> France is willing to play a positive role in the development of EU-China relations, he added.</p> <p> The two leaders also exchanged views on the situation in Ukraine and agreed that relevant parties should support Russia and Ukraine in restoring peace through negotiations.</p> <p> Xi stressed that China has been working in its own way to promote peace talks, and that China supports European countries in keeping the security of Europe in their own hands.</p> <p> He urged vigilance against bloc confrontation, which poses a bigger and more persistent threat to global security and stability.</p> <p> Macron noted the many common understandings between France and China on the issue of Ukraine, adding that France stands ready for closer coordination and cooperation with China at both bilateral and multilateral levels.</p> <p> France and the EU are committed to strategic autonomy and will not endorse or take part in bloc confrontation, he said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xiplomacy: Xi committed to strengthening China-Germany relations, China-EU ties ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094687</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094687.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 16:06:12 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping had a virtual meeting with German Chancellor Olaf Scholz on Monday, calling for joint efforts to leverage the stabilizing, constructive and steering role of their relationship.</p> <p> During the meeting, Xi also expressed his hope that Germany will play a positive role in developing a steady and sound China-EU relationship.</p> <p> On various occasions, Xi has elaborated on the importance of strengthening China-Germany relations as well as China-EU ties. The following are some highlights of Xi's remarks in this regard.</p> <p> May 9, 2022</p> <p> In the virtual meeting with Scholz, Xi said both China and Germany are major countries with important influence.</p> <p> Under the current circumstances, it is particularly important for the two countries to maintain sound and steady growth of bilateral ties and better harness the stabilizing, constructive and steering role of this relationship, Xi said.</p> <p> This not only serves the interests of the Chinese and German peoples but will also contribute significantly to world peace and tranquility, Xi added.</p> <p> Xi underscored that China and the EU are comprehensive strategic partners and each other's opportunity, and that the two sides have far more common interests than differences.</p> <p> It is important that the two sides, with a dialectical and long-term view, with mutual respect and with the right perception, increase communication and enhance mutual trust, Xi said.</p> <p> March 8, 2022</p> <p> During a virtual summit with French President Emmanuel Macron and Scholz, Xi noted that China and the EU share much common understanding on promoting peace, seeking development and advancing cooperation.</p> <p> Xi said it is important for the two sides to enhance dialogue, stay committed to cooperation, and promote steady and sustained progress of China-EU relations.</p> <p> China's development will create broader space for China-EU cooperation, Xi said, adding that the two sides must, under the principle of mutual benefit and win-win, further deepen green and digital partnerships as well as practical cooperation in various fields.</p> <p> Dec. 21, 2021</p> <p> In a phone conversation with Scholz, Xi said China attaches great importance to its relations with Germany, noting that the two countries should chart the general course of bilateral relations from a strategic perspective.</p> <p> Over the past half century, China-Germany relations have demonstrated ample vitality, endurance, resilience and potential, Xi said, adding that for the next 50 years, the two countries should embrace a global vision from a long-term perspective, forge ahead and strive for new development of China-Germany relations.</p> <p> Dec. 8, 2021</p> <p> In a congratulatory message to Scholz on his election as German chancellor, Xi said he is willing to work with Scholz to promote the bilateral ties to a new level.</p> <p> China and Germany are all-round strategic partners, Xi noted, adding that over the years, they have been adhering to mutual respect, seeking common ground while shelving differences and pursuing win-win cooperation, which has yielded results benefiting the two countries, their people and the world.</p> <p> Facing the major changes and a pandemic both unseen in a century, China and Germany have strengthened communication and cooperation, jointly supported the global fight against COVID-19 and promoted economic recovery, demonstrating their sense of responsibility as major countries, Xi said.</p> <p> Oct. 13, 2021</p> <p> During a virtual meeting with then German Chancellor Angela Merkel, Xi and Merkel reviewed the development of China-German and China-EU relations in recent years.</p> <p> Noting that 2022 marks the 50th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations, Xi said that keeping bilateral ties on the right course is of crucial importance.</p> <p> "China always views its relationship with Germany from a strategic and long-term perspective, and is ready to maintain high-level exchanges with the German side, promote mutual understanding and friendship between the two peoples, tap the potential for cooperation in traditional fields, while exploring new areas of pragmatic cooperation in energy transition and the green and digital economy, among other areas, to further advance bilateral ties," Xi said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi says that youth breeds infinite hope ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094671</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094671.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 15:05:16 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <center> <video controls="controls" poster=" http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/5/10/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_ec6796401816b467e0dce5d58e845a16.jpeg" src="http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/5/10/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_35050c2025c9e0cbee3b0fcd3e2a0244.mp4" style=" width: 830px; height:550px;"> <p> &nbsp;</p> </video> </center> <p> Chinese President Xi Jinping said that youth breeds infinite hope, and encouraged the members of the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC) to forge ahead on the new journey to realize the Chinese Dream of national rejuvenation.</p> <p> Xi made the remarks at a ceremony marking the centenary of the CYLC Tuesday in Beijing.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily App</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi sums up experience from youth league successes ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094518</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094518.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 14:03:09 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- The Party's leadership, firm beliefs and convictions, devotion to national rejuvenation, and its deep roots in the country's young people are key to the past and future successes of the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC), Chinese President Xi Jinping said Tuesday.</p> <p> Xi, also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, made the remarks at a ceremony marking the centenary of the CYLC in Beijing.</p> <p> Xi said the CYLC, since its founding in 1922, has been upholding the leadership of the CPC to ensure that China's youth movement follows the correct political direction.</p> <p> Following the instructions and guidance of the Party has been the political lifeline of the CYLC, he said.</p> <p> Over the past century, the CYLC's firm beliefs and convictions have served as the most fundamental and long-lasting source of cohesiveness, Xi said.</p> <p> He went on to commend the CYLC's devotion to national rejuvenation, which has consistently been the mainstream of China's youth movement, as well as its efforts to take deep roots among the country's youth by focusing its work on the overwhelming majority of young workers, farmers and other young people.</p> <p> "Both history and reality have shown that the CYLC is truly the vanguard of China's youth movement," Xi said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Hope of Party, country rests on youth: Xi ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094545</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094545.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 11:29:49 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping on Tuesday said the hope of the Communist Party of China (CPC) and the country rests on the youth.</p> <p> Xi, also general secretary of the CPC Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, made the remarks at a ceremony marking the centenary of the Communist Youth League of China in Beijing.</p> <p> Xi said for the Party and the country, youth are the most worthy of love and expectation, adding that young people are like saplings that thrive on the earth, and one day they will grow into towering trees.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi urges firm beliefs, fighting spirit in youth league members ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094544</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094544.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 11:29:43 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING,May 10 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping on Tuesday called on members of the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC) in the new era to build up firm beliefs, and boost their courage and skills to carry out struggles, among others.</p> <p> Xi, also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, made the remarks when addressing a ceremony held at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing marking the 100th anniversary of the founding of the CYLC.</p> <p> Xi urged CYLC members to be patriotic and innovative, while not being misguided or intimidated by difficulties.</p> <p> CYLC members shall also be hardworking and willing to make selfless contributions, said Xi, adding that they should promote virtue, perform good deeds and observe discipline.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi asks youth league to be vanguard force in mobilizing China's youth ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094543</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094543.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 11:22:03 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- President Xi Jinping on Tuesday told the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC) to shoulder its responsibilities and always be a vanguard force in mobilizing China's youth in continuous endeavor.</p> <p> Xi, also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, made the remarks at a ceremony marking the 100th anniversary of the founding of the CYLC.</p> <p> The cause of the Party and the people entails the endeavor and devotion by generations of young people, Xi said, stressing that young people should devote their youth to great undertakings of the Party and the people.</p> <p> Xi asked the league to unite and lead young people to follow the call of the Party and the people and work hard in places where the country needs them the most.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ CPC always open to youth: Xi ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094542</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094542.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 11:21:46 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping on Tuesday said the Communist Party of China (CPC) always opens its door to young people and warmly welcomes them to become the fresh blood of the Party.</p> <p> Xi, also general secretary of the CPC Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, made the remarks at a ceremony marking the centenary of the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC) in Beijing.</p> <p> Xi said Party organizations at all levels should attach great importance to the cultivation and development of young Party members, especially from outstanding CYLC members, to ensure that the socialist country will never change its nature.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ CPC always worthy of trust, following of youth: Xi ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094540</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094540.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 11:21:38 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping on Tuesday said the Communist Party of China (CPC) is a party that always maintains its youthful quality and is always worthy of the trust and following of young people.</p> <p> Xi said that a hundred years on from its founding, the Party is still in its prime, and remains focused on achieving lasting greatness for the Chinese nation.</p> <p> Xi, also general secretary of the CPC Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, made the remarks at a ceremony marking the centenary of the Communist Youth League of China in Beijing.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi stresses self-reform of youth league to maintain advanced nature ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094538</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094538.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 11:15:46 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping on Tuesday urged the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC) to have the courage to carry out self-reform to maintain its status as an advanced organization that closely follows the Communist Party of China (CPC) and keeps pace with the times.</p> <p> Xi, also general secretary of the CPC Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, made the remarks when addressing a ceremony held at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing to mark the 100th anniversary of the founding of the CYLC.</p> <p> Xi urged the CYLC to implement the overall leadership of the Party in the whole process of its work in all areas, follow the development path of people's organizations of socialism with Chinese characteristics, and further deepen reform.</p> <p> The CYLC should explore new models of its grassroots organizations in light of the new changes in young people's work and life, lead youth and students federations in upholding the banner of patriotism and socialism, and constantly consolidate and expand the youth patriotic united front, Xi said.</p> <p> He also highlighted the need to strengthen self-building of the CYLC.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi urges youth league to remain strongest bond between Party, youth ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094537</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094537.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 11:14:06 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping on Tuesday urged the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC) to remain as the strongest bond between the Communist Party of China (CPC) and the youth.</p> <p> Xi, also general secretary of the CPC Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, made the remarks when addressing a ceremony held at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing to mark the 100th anniversary of the founding of the CYLC.</p> <p> The greatest strength of the CYLC, as the youth's own organization, lies in its broad reach at the grassroots and its deep involvement with young people, Xi said.</p> <p> He asked the CYLC to continue serving young people, fulfill its responsibility in consolidating and expanding young people's support for the Party's governance, and offer solid help to the young people.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi asks youth league to be political school leading Chinese young people ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094534</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094534.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 11:13:21 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- President Xi Jinping on Tuesday told the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC) to always be a political school leading the ideological progress of young people.</p> <p> Xi, also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, made the remarks at a ceremony marking the 100th anniversary of the founding of the CYLC.</p> <p> Xi said the CYLC is a school for young people to understand socialism with Chinese characteristics and communism in practice, adding that the league should help them aim high at an early age and cultivate the trust in the Party, the confidence in socialism with Chinese characteristics and the belief in Marxism from the bottom of their heart.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi says young Chinese have bright prospects of realizing dreams ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094524</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094524.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 10:53:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Young Chinese people in the new era have bright prospects of realizing their dreams, Chinese President Xi Jinping said on Tuesday.</p> <p> Xi, also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, made the remarks at a ceremony marking the centenary of the Communist Youth League of China in Beijing.</p> <p> Comparing the realization of the Chinese Dream to a relay race, Xi called on young generations to strive for their best to help realize national rejuvenation.</p> <p> Xi said the young people shoulder heavy responsibilities and have a broad space to give full play to their talents.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi speaks of milestone significance of CYLC founding ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094509</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094509.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 10:46:58 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping on Tuesday said the founding of the Communist Youth League of China (CYLC) is a milestone in the history of the Chinese revolution and the history of youth movement.</p> <p> Xi, also general secretary of the Communist Party of China (CPC) Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, made the remarks at a ceremony held in Beijing marking the 100th anniversary of the founding of the CYLC.</p> <p> The CYLC was founded on May 5, 1922 under the direct leadership of the CPC.</p> <p> Xi said the founding mission of the CYLC is to unwaveringly follow the CPC and strive for the Party and the people.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi addresses ceremony marking centenary of Communist Youth League of China ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094478</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094478.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 10:35:27 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping, also general secretary of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and chairman of the Central Military Commission, started delivering a speech at a ceremony held at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing on Tuesday marking the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Communist Youth League of China.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
	</channel>
</rss>