<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title> World </title>
		<image>
			<title>People's Daily Online</title>
			<link>http://english.people.com.cn/</link>
			<url>http://english.people.com.cn/images/en/top_logo_e.gif</url>
		</image>
		<description>People's Daily Online</description>
		<link>http://english.people.com.cn/90777</link>
		<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ U.S. supermarket shooting leaves 10 dead, 3 injured ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096794</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096794.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 11:35:29 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NEW YORK, May 14 (Xinhua) -- An armored gunman killed ten people and injured three at a supermarket in Buffalo of New York State on Saturday, according to local enforcement officials.</p> <p> The suspect is an 18-year-old white man heavily armed with tactical gear and a helmet, said Buffalo Police Commissioner Joseph Gramaglia in a press briefing late Saturday.</p> <p> The gunman wore military-style clothing and body armor while carrying a rifle, according to reports.</p> <p> He had a camera and the shooting was live streamed, according to Gramaglia.</p> <p> The mass shooting is being investigated as a hate crime, said Stephen Belongia, the special agent in charge of the local office of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</p> <p> Gramaglia said 11 victims are black while the other two are white.</p> <p> The suspect drove to the supermarket around 2:30 p.m. (1830 GMT) and shot four people in the parking lot, said Gramaglia.</p> <p> "The shooter was not from this community. In fact, the shooter traveled hours from outside this community to perpetrate this crime on the people of Buffalo," said Buffalo Mayor Byron Brown.</p> <p> After shooting innocents inside the supermarket, the gunman once put the gun to his own neck but was persuaded by patrol officers to drop his gun, according to Gramaglia.</p> <p> The gunman has been taken into custody and transported to Buffalo Police Headquarters.</p> <p> The suspect will be arraigned on charge of murder in first degree Saturday evening, according to a district attorney.</p> <p> Named Tops Friendly Market, the supermarket is located in a black-dominated community, which is around two miles (3.2 km) northeast of downtown Buffalo.</p> <p> New York Governor Kathy Hochul, who was born in Buffalo, said she is on the way to Buffalo to assist with the response to the shooting and a family unification site has been set up for family members of the shooting victims.</p> <p> "We must do more to address the scourge of racism and anti-Semitism, and to pass commonsense gun safety measures to keep our communities safe," said U.S. Senator Kirsten Gillibrand from New York State.</p> <p> More than 28,000 people have died or been injured due to gun-related incidents in the United States this year, according to a database run by the nonprofit research group Gun Violence Archive.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Palestine warns against allowing Israeli settlers to visit Al-Aqsa Mosque ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096793</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096793.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 11:33:57 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> RAMALLAH, May 14 (Xinhua) -- Palestine on Saturday warned of the consequences of allowing Israeli settlers to visit the compound of the Al-Aqsa Mosque in the old city of Jerusalem during the "Second Jewish Passover" on Sunday.</p> <p> "These plans are an Israeli persistence to perpetuate visiting the Al-Aqsa as something imposed by force, to consolidate its temporal division to divide it spatially," the Palestinian Foreign Ministry said in a statement, adding that the Israeli government is responsible for the consequences should a conflict occur.</p> <p> Earlier on Saturday, the Jewish "Temple Mount" groups called through social media platforms on their Jewish fans to enter Al-Aqsa Mosque collectively on Sunday to mark the anniversary of the "Second Jewish Passover."</p> <p> The Palestinian Foreign Ministry called on the international community and the United States to intervene urgently and put pressure on the Israeli government to stop the settler groups' visits to the Al-Aqsa Mosque.</p> <p> In April, during the Muslim fasting month of Ramadan and the Jewish Passover, the Al-Aqsa compound witnessed fierce confrontations between Israeli police and Palestinian worshipers who protested against Jewish visits to their holy site.</p> <p> Tension at the Al-Aqsa Mosque could spark a military confrontation between armed Palestinian factions and Israel, similar to the last offensive waged by Israel on the Gaza Strip in May 2021.</p> <p> For Muslims worldwide, the Al-Aqsa Mosque in the old city of Jerusalem is their first shrine and third mosque. They call the holy place al-Haram al-Sharif, while Jews call it "The Temple Mount."</p> <p> The Palestinians want the eastern part of Jerusalem, which was occupied by Israel together with the West Bank and the Gaza Strip in 1967, as the capital of their future state.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Mass shooting in Buffalo being investigated as hate crime: U.S. Justice Department ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096792</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096792.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 11:33:54 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> WASHINGTON, May 14 (Xinhua) -- The U.S. Department of Justice (DOJ) is investigating the mass shooting in Buffalo, New York State, as a hate crime.</p> <p> U.S. Attorney General Merrick Garland said in a statement on Saturday night that the nation mourns the victims of "a senseless, horrific shooting" and the DOJ "is investigating this matter as a hate crime and an act of racially-motivated violent extremism."</p> <p> He vowed to conduct "a thorough and expeditious investigation into this shooting" and to seek "justice for these innocent victims."</p> <p> Federal law enforcement agencies, including the FBI, are working with Buffalo Police Department and other partners, according to Garland's statement.</p> <p> At least 10 people were killed by a gunman in a supermarket in Buffalo on Saturday afternoon. Three others were wounded but are expected to survive.</p> <p> The gunman, who's in custody, wore military-style clothing and body armor and opened fire with a rifle. The attack was live-streamed on a gaming platform.</p> <p> Out of the 13 victims, 11 are African Americans while two are white, according to Buffalo Police Commissioner Joseph Gramaglia.</p> <p> U.S. Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro Mayorkas has been briefed on the shooting, according to an official tweet from the department.</p> <p> "DHS (the Department of Homeland Security) is actively coordinating with all relevant local, state, and federal agencies and will continue to provide the Department's full support," the tweet read.</p> <p> The White House has also reacted to the incident, calling it a "horrific shooting."</p> <p> U.S. President Joe Biden "will continue to receive updates throughout the evening and tomorrow as further information develops," according to a statement from White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre.</p> <p> "The President and the First Lady are praying for those who have been lost and for their loved ones," Jean-Pierre added.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Why additional tariffs on Chinese goods should be discarded ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096786</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096786.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 11:33:30 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) -- As the additional tariffs imposed by the previous U.S. administration on Chinese products soured bilateral economic ties, continuously taking its toll on American businesses and consumers, it is high time the U.S. side discarded the false move.</p> <p> "Four years on, the trade war is still hurting U.S. consumers and companies, and forcing supply chain workarounds that make trade more complex and vulnerable," Christopher Tang, professor of supply chain management at the UCLA Anderson School of Management, said in a recent article published on the South China Morning Post.</p> <p> Like the professor, many more U.S. trade groups and economists have been urging the Biden administration to scrap Trump-era additional tariffs on Chinese imports, regarding such tariffs as counterproductive to the U.S. economy.</p> <p> At a time when world economic recovery is still strangled by the COVID-19 pandemic and the U.S. economy itself faces soaring inflation, it will be both a right and responsible choice for the country to remove all additional tariffs as soon as possible, analysts said.</p> <p> <strong>WHO PAYS THE PRICE</strong></p> <p> Four years after the U.S. tariff hikes on Chinese goods, it has been a clear fact that the acts have brought more costs to U.S. companies, consumers and farmers.</p> <p> "American businesses and consumers, not Chinese exporters, are bearing the cost of Trump-era tariffs in the form of higher prices on made-in-China parts and products," David J. Bulman, assistant professor of China Studies and International Affairs at the Johns Hopkins School of Advanced International Studies, said in an article published on The Hill earlier this year.</p> <p> Tariffs on Chinese goods have provoked retaliatory tariffs that have sharply reduced American exports to China, allowing other nations to move in on markets once dominated by the U.S., he noted.</p> <p> Since the additional tariffs were taken into effect, they have cost American companies 1.7 trillion U.S. dollars, and American household 1,300 U.S. dollars a year, Chinese Ambassador to the United States Qin Gang said during a recent interview with Forbes magazine, noting that the tariffs have not reduced the U.S. trade deficit.</p> <p> Americans for Free Trade, a broad coalition of trade organizations, recently warned that the Section 301 tariffs create an "additional economic burden" for American businesses, manufacturers, farmers, and families, make the United States less competitive globally and cause "disproportionate economic harm to an American economy grappling with ongoing inflation concerns."</p> <p> <strong>SOARING INFLATION PRESSURE</strong></p> <p> As the U.S. is experiencing the highest inflation in four decades, economists said eliminating additional tariffs on Chinese goods would help lower elevated inflation and stabilize inflation expectations.</p> <p> "The reasons to end the trade war with China keep piling up. Inflation is the latest case in point," David J. Bulman said.</p> <p> Data from the U.S. Labor Department showed Wednesday that U.S. consumer inflation in April surged by 8.3 percent from a year ago, marking the second straight month of inflation over 8 percent.</p> <p> Even Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen said in a recent interview with Bloomberg Television that removing Trump-era China tariffs would have some "desirable" effects on inflation and "it's worth considering."</p> <p> "Americans are unhappy about rising inflation and costs, so providing tariff relief soon is one way to lower prices and increase demand, especially for consumer goods," said the U.S.-China Business Council (USCBC), which represents 260 American companies that do business with China.</p> <p> <strong>BACK ON TRACK</strong></p> <p> As people from the American academic and industrial circles came to urge the government to drop additional tariffs on Chinese products, it is significant to recognize the essence of China-U.S. business ties and bring it back on track.</p> <p> The economic and trade relations between the world's two largest economies are mutually beneficial in nature and have been yielding win-win results.</p> <p> Taking employment for instance, U.S. exports of goods and services to China support hundreds of thousands of jobs across the country in almost every sector of the economy, according to the U.S. Export Report 2022 released by USCBC.</p> <p> "More than 300 congressional districts have over 1,000 jobs supported by exports to China, and eight are home to more than 10,000," the report said, noting that China remains an important market for U.S. exporters.</p> <p> In 2020 alone, the number of jobs supported by exports to China reached a total of 858,486, according to the USCBC's calculations.</p> <p> In addition to creating jobs, trade with China has helped increase the income of U.S. farmers as agricultural trade has been an important part of bilateral business activities.</p> <p> U.S. goods exports to China reached an all-time high in 2021, with oilseeds and grains seeing significant growth to cement their place as the top U.S. export to China, the USCBC report said.</p> <p> Last year, U.S. farmers sent 4.8 billion dollars more in oilseeds and crops such as soybeans, wheat, and corn, to China than they did the year before, bringing the latest total to 21.9 billion dollars.</p> <p> "As we face a complex and severe situation in agricultural development and food security worldwide, I firmly believe that China and the United States, as major agricultural producers, consumers and traders, should meet challenges together, maintain stable development of agriculture, enhance the resilience of agricultural supply chains, ensure food security domestically, and promote cooperation for international food security," Qin said.</p> <p> Despite the lingering COVID-19 disruptions, trade between China and the U.S. maintained sound momentum, rising 8.7 percent year on year to 1.56 trillion U.S. dollars in the first fourth months, demonstrating the high complementarity of the two economies.</p> <p> In the context of soaring prices, the removal of additional tariffs on Chinese goods meets the fundamental interests of American consumers and businesses, and is beneficial to the U.S., China and the whole world, China's commerce ministry spokesperson Shu Jueting said Thursday at a press briefing.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Ukraine says in talks with Russia over evacuation of 60 people from Azovstal ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096785</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096785.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 11:33:27 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> KIEV, May 14 (Xinhua) -- Ukraine and Russia are negotiating the evacuation of 60 people from the Azovstal steel plant in Mariupol, the state-run Ukrinform news agency reported Saturday.</p> <p> At the current stage, the evacuation concerns severely injured soldiers and medical workers, Ukrainian Deputy Prime Minister Iryna Vereshchuk was quoted as saying, who added that there are several hundred injured at the Azovstal plant in total.</p> <p> On Thursday, Vereshchuk said that Ukraine seeks to exchange 38 severely injured soldiers from Azovstal for the captured Russian military servicemen.</p> <p> Ukraine says all women, children and the elderly at the Azovstal plant were evacuated earlier this month.</p> <p> Mariupol, a key Azov Sea port city in eastern Ukraine, has seen one of the worst bouts of bloody violence in the Russia-Ukraine conflict.</p> <p> The Azovstal plant, which covers an area of about 11 square km, is the holdout of the Ukrainian forces in Mariupol.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Finland's ruling Social Democratic Party backs NATO application ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096779</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096779.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 11:01:40 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> HELSINKI, May 14 (Xinhua) -- The Party Council of the leading Finnish Social Democratic Party on Saturday endorsed the plan for making Finland a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO).</p> <p> The Party Council is the party's highest decision-making body between party conventions, which are held every two years.</p> <p> Joining NATO was backed by 53 members, while five voted against and two blank, the Council chair Sirpa Paatero told the media.</p> <p> Party chair, Prime Minister Sanna Marin had on Thursday announced her support for Finland going to NATO in a joint statement with President Sauli Niinisto.</p> <p> Also, the parliamentary group of the Social Democrats on Saturday expressed support for the would-be Finnish membership in NATO.</p> <p> According to media reports, two of the party's 40 Members of Parliament are expected to vote against it in the parliamentary plenary.</p> <p> Following the official decision by the social democrats, only the Left Alliance, out of the major parties in Finland, has not taken a decision in favor of NATO.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ In phone call with Finland's Niinisto, Putin says applying for NATO membership a "mistake" ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096776</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096776.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 11:01:35 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> MOSCOW/HELSINKI, May 14 (Xinhua) -- Russian President Vladimir Putin and his Finnish counterpart, Sauli Niinisto, held a phone conversation on Saturday and discussed Helsinki's intention to join the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO).</p> <p> In the call initiated by Helsinki, Niinisto informed Putin of Finland's decision to seek NATO membership in the next few days, according to a press release by the president's office of Finland.</p> <p> Meanwhile, the Kremlin said in a statement that "Putin stressed that abandoning the traditional policy of military neutrality would be a mistake, since there are no threats to Finland's security."</p> <p> Putin expressed concern that should Helsinki follow through with plans to join NATO, it may have a negative impact on Russia-Finland relations, the statement said.</p> <p> When discussing the situation in Ukraine, Putin said peace talks between Russian and Ukrainian representatives "were actually suspended by Kiev that does not show interest in a serious and constructive dialogue."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Feature: 50 years on, U.S. bombings still terrorize Cambodia ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096771</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096771.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 10:36:05 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> PHNOM PENH, May 14 (Xinhua) -- Yan Sam En is a farmer in northeast Cambodia's Chetr Borei district. One day, almost 20 years ago, the father of five was working in the forest close to his home when he found four cluster bombs, unexploded remnants of the U.S. carpet bombing that devastated the area in the 1960s.</p> <p> <strong>A USELESS PERSON</strong></p> <p> "I didn't want my children to play with the bombs, so I collected them, and as I did, one exploded. It blew off both my arms, and left me totally blind," Sam En told Xinhua on Friday. "I was 43 years old. I'm almost 61 now, but time has not healed me."</p> <p> Sam En says he has been nothing but a burden to his family since the blast. He cannot do anything. He just sits at home all day. "The U.S. deprived me of everything. In a few seconds, I went from breadwinner to useless person."</p> <p> The cluster bombs that claimed Sam En's eyes and arms are just a reminder of countless bombs that the U.S. dropped on Cambodia during the U.S.-Vietnam War, claiming countless other arms, legs and eyes, and thousands of lives. Between 1965 and 1973, the U.S. dropped 230,516 bombs in Cambodia. In April alone, at least five U.S. Mk 82 bombs, weighing about 500 pounds each, were found across the country. On May 5, a Cambodian bomb disposal team safely removed a U.S. bomb, weighing 2,000 pounds, from the Chaktomuk river opposite the Royal Palace in Phnom Penh.</p> <p> "At that time, I saw U.S. warplanes flying around. They dropped bombs to cut off roads and bridges," Sam En said. "We lived in fear every day and ran to hide in trenches when we heard the warplanes."</p> <p> Sam En said the U.S. has not provided any support to victims like him of its leftover bombs.</p> <p> <strong>'VICIOUS, UNDECLARED WAR'</strong></p> <p> Cambodian Prime Minister Samdech Techo Hun Sen wrote in his book "10 Years of Cambodia's Journey, 1979-1989" that the bombings killed "tens of thousands of civilians" in a "vicious, undeclared war"</p> <p> Ly Thuch, first vice president of the Cambodian Mine Action and Victim Assistance Authority (CMAA), said Cambodia is still suffering from the huge legacy of the U.S.-Vietnam war and Cambodia's own internal conflicts. "There are a lot of bombs scattered on the ground, under the ground and in the water. We have not even conducted a large-scale search for underwater bombs, yet," he told Xinhua.</p> <p> "Unexploded ordnance is a constant danger. Villages, farmland and rice fields still contain explosive remnants of war and the affected land cannot be farmed," he added.</p> <p> Joseph Matthews of BELTEI International University in Phnom Penh said because of U.S. bombs many people have lost their lives or been maimed. According to the CMAA, from 1979 to March 2022, unexploded ordnance and landmines had killed 19,816 people and injured 45,175 others in Cambodia.</p> <p> "I strongly believe that the U.S. is morally responsible for the suffering of these people and ethically and legally bound to adequately compensate the families of those who had lost their lives or were maimed by these unexploded ordnance and landmines," Matthews told Xinhua.</p> <p> <strong>WOUNDS TO BE HEALED</strong></p> <p> Chhum Thea is 62 now. He lost his left arm to a mine in Kampong Cham province in 1990.</p> <p> "U.S. planes bombed my village often during the war. The earth trembled as if it was an earthquake," he told Xinhua.</p> <p> The bombs caused huge destruction. The U.S. must help Cambodia and compensate the innocent victims. I want the U.S. to heal the wounds that it created."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese-built expressway starts trial run in Nairobi, invigorating Kenyan capital's growth vitality ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096765</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096765.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 10:35:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205151017000122246444476.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>James Macharia (3rd L), Kenya's cabinet secretary of the Ministry of Transport, Infrastructure, Housing and Urban Development, and other representatives applaud for trial runs of the Nairobi expressway in Nairobi, Kenya, on May 14, 2022. Kenya on Saturday began trial runs on the Chinese-built Nairobi expressway ahead of its commissioning in the next few weeks. (Photo by Fred Mutune/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> NAIROBI, May 14 (Xinhua) -- Kenya on Saturday began trial runs on the Chinese-built Nairobi expressway ahead of its commissioning in the next few weeks.</p> <p> James Macharia, the cabinet secretary of the Ministry of Transport, Infrastructure, Housing and Urban Development, said Saturday during a media briefing in Nairobi, the Kenyan capital, that there is massive interest among motorists to use the toll road that stretches from the western side of the city to the southeast edge of the metropolis.</p> <p> "It is one of the best pieces of infrastructure ever done in Africa. In fact, it's the longest expressway in Africa. And so, we are very proud today to come to witness the start of the trial run, which will be done for about three or four weeks," said Macharia, adding that 11,000 Kenyan road users have registered, and the number will go up to almost 50,000.</p> <p> The 27.1-km Nairobi expressway was financed and built by China Road and Bridge Corporation under a public-private partnership model. Full-scale construction of the about 600 million U.S. dollars infrastructure project began in September 2020.</p> <p> Macharia said the expressway has been built in record time because it has been completed one year ahead of schedule, and its impact will be positive on the economy. He observed that the infrastructure project represents a new dawn for Kenya as it will have a very big impact in terms of mobility, especially for motorists traveling between Jomo Kenyatta International Airport and Nairobi's central business district.</p> <p> Macharia said the Nairobi expressway is a private investment and therefore the government has not committed any money to the infrastructure project.</p> <p> "The Kenya government has not committed any money on this investment, we have not borrowed a single cent of the total amount of about 600 million U.S. dollars, which is about 70 billion shillings," he said.</p> <p> "The money which the government could have spent here has been now spent elsewhere." According to Macharia, the Nairobi expressway is a good example of the benefits of public-private partnership because it frees up public expenditure for use on social expenditures.</p> <p> "This is the most important thing for Kenyans to know that this public-private partnership is so important, because first of all, you don't borrow and it is not affecting our debt ratio," he added.</p> <p> Ibrahim Doboshek, a motorist, who took part in the trial run, told Xinhua that the standards of the road construction of the expressway are comparable to those in the advanced countries of the world. "I am so grateful because I used to take 2 to 3 hours on Mombasa road due to traffic but today I have used 10 minutes."</p> <p> George Were, another road user, who lives in Kitengela town which is about 30 km southeast of Nairobi's central business district, said that the new expressway is very convenient and fast. "I recommend guys to use it. I know there's the element of cost. But in terms of convenience, I think it is really value for money because a journey that used to take two hours is now down to less than 20 minutes."</p> <p> Before Saturday's trial run, an inaugural city marathon was held on the Nairobi expressway last Sunday, which attracted more than 8,000 runners to participate.</p> <p> "As a result of developing modern infrastructure projects like the Nairobi Expressway, the country will reap multiple benefits chief among them ease of travel, improved trade, investments and environmental health," Kenyan President Uhuru Kenyatta said during the award ceremony for marathon winners.</p> <p> During the construction period, the expressway had created more than 6,000 direct jobs, benefiting 200 sub-contractors and hundreds of other local suppliers of building materials such as steel, sand, cement and ballast.</p> <p> A new job has now emerged in Kenya -- toll attendant on the expressway.</p> <p> "I'm really excited about this job because it impacts positively on the country's development," Rodah Mwenje Okoth, who works as a toll attendant at the Nairobi expressway, told Xinhua that she underwent two months of intensive training before beginning her job.</p> <p> She said the road project has provided a lot of job opportunities to Kenyans while solving traffic congestion in the capital city.</p> <p> Like Okoth, more than 400 toll attendants are now working at the Nairobi Expressway.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 15th "Chinese Bridge" language competition held in Bulgaria ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096764</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096764.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 10:35:39 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> VELIKO TURNOVO, Bulgaria, May 14 (Xinhua) -- Bulgarian national qualifications of the 15th "Chinese Bridge" -- Chinese Proficiency Competition for Foreign Secondary School Students, were held here on Saturday.</p> <p> A total of 12 students demonstrated Chinese language and cultural skills at the first "Chinese Bridge" event held in person since the beginning of the COVID pandemic.</p> <p> It was jointly organized by the Chinese embassy in Sofia and the Confucius Institute at "St. Cyril and St. Methodius" University of Veliko Turnovo (UVT).</p> <p> Kristina Ivanova from Sofia's 138 High School for Western and Eastern Languages won the competition, and will represent the Balkan country at the finals in China.</p> <p> While addressing the event, China's Ambassador to Bulgaria Dong Xiaojun said the Chinese Language Bridge has become an Olympics and a kind of cultural carnival for the Chinese language and people learning Chinese.</p> <p> This was a useful experience for all participants, Dong said.</p> <p> He also said that many colleges and universities in Bulgaria have opened Chinese language programs. They educated a large number of talents fluent in Chinese language and culture, providing a solid intellectual basis for exchange and cooperation between China and Bulgaria in various fields, the ambassador said.</p> <p> Prof. Dimitar Dimitrov, Vice-rector of UVT, said that it was an "extraordinary event".</p> <p> According to him, Chinese language and culture have been taught at this university for about 30 years, and the Confucius Institute at the UVT has existed for 10 years.</p> <p> Thanks to the exceptional work of everyone related to the Chinese language and culture, it already had its roots throughout Bulgaria, Dimitrov said.</p> <p> The "Chinese Bridge" competition was first organized in Bulgaria by the Confucius Institute in 2008 to inspire Bulgarian students between 15 to 20 years old to learn Chinese and enhance their understanding of the Chinese culture.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Hamas warns against Israeli settlers' plan to "storm" Al-Aqsa Mosque ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096763</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096763.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 10:35:36 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> GAZA, May 14 (Xinhua) -- Hamas, the militant organization ruling the Gaza Strip, warned on Saturday against what it calls Israeli settlers' plan to "storm" the Al-Aqsa Mosque compound in East Jerusalem on Sunday.</p> <p> Earlier in the day, the Jewish Temple Mount groups called on Jews to visit the Al-Aqsa Mosque on Sunday to celebrate the annual Second Passover holiday, which this year coincides with the Nakba Day, or Day of the Catastrophe, marked by the Palestinians on May 15 every year, the day after Israel's declaration of independence in 1948.</p> <p> "Allowing the so-called Temple Mount groups to storm the Al-Aqsa Mosque on Sunday when the Palestinians mark their 74th Nakba Day is a dangerous escalation and constitutes a provocation toward the feelings of our people," Hazem Qassem, Hamas spokesman in Gaza, told reporters.</p> <p> This "would spark an open clash with the Israeli occupation forces ... and Israel would be fully responsible for the consequences," he said.</p> <p> The Al-Aqsa Mosque compound in the Old City of Jerusalem, known to Jews as the Temple Mount, is held as a holy site in both Islam and Judaism.</p> <p> Qassem also called on Palestinians in the West Bank, East Jerusalem, and Israel to gather at the Al-Aqsa Mosque on Sunday to confront the "storming" plan by the Israeli settlers.</p> <p> In April, when the Jewish Passover holiday coincided with the Muslim holy month of Ramadan, the Al-Aqsa Mosque compound witnessed fierce clashes between Palestinian worshippers and the Israeli police over the Jewish visit to the holy site.</p> <p> The continuing high tensions at the Al-Aqsa Mosque compound raise concerns about a possible military confrontation between armed Palestinian factions and Israel similar to the large-offensive offensive launched by Israel on the Gaza Strip in May 2021.</p> <p> The Palestinians want East Jerusalem, which was occupied by Israel together with the West Bank and the Gaza Strip in the 1967 Middle East war, as the capital of their future independent state.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ At least 10 killed in U.S. supermarket shooting ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096762</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096762.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 10:35:33 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NEW YORK, May 14 (Xinhua) -- At least ten people were killed by a gunman in a supermarket in Buffalo, New York State on Saturday afternoon, local media reported.</p> <p> The gunman wore military-style clothing and body armor with a rifle and opened fire after entering the supermarket located at a neighborhood dominated by black people, according to a report by The Associated Press.</p> <p> The shooter has been taken in custody, tweeted Buffalo Police Department.</p> <p> U.S. President Joe Biden has been briefed on "the horrific shooting" in Buffalo, according to the White House.</p> <p> Biden "will continue to receive updates throughout the evening and tomorrow as further information develops," White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said in a statement.</p> <p> The gunman is a white man in late teens or early 20s wearing a black helmet, according to a report by the New York Post citing two witnesses of the carnage.</p> <p> An investigation is under way to check if the gunman posted a manifesto online and the shooting was believed to be live-streamed, said the report, citing a local enforcement official.</p> <p> Investigators are also working to know if the shooting was racially motivated, the report added.</p> <p> Named Tops Friendly Market, the supermarket is located around 2 miles northeast of downtown Buffalo.</p> <p> New York Governor Kathy Hochul, who was born in Buffalo, said she is on the way to Buffalo to assist with the response to the shooting.</p> <p> More than 28,000 people have died or been injured due to gun-related incidents in the United States this year, according to a database run by the nonprofit research group Gun Violence Archive.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Biden briefed on "horrific shooting" in Buffalo: White House ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096761</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096761.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 10:35:30 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> WASHINGTON, May 14 (Xinhua) -- U.S. President Joe Biden has been briefed on "the horrific shooting" in Buffalo, state of New York, that took place on Saturday afternoon, according to the White House.</p> <p> Biden "will continue to receive updates throughout the evening and tomorrow as further information develops," White House press secretary Karine Jean-Pierre said in a statement.</p> <p> "The President and the First Lady are praying for those who have been lost and for their loved ones," the statement read.</p> <p> At least ten people were killed in the deadly shooting by a gunman in a supermarket in Buffalo, according to local media.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ U.S. urged not to rope in Southeast Asian countries out of geopolitical interests ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096756</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096756.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 09:32:02 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150908000197676617846.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on Nov. 23, 2021 shows the White House in Washington, D.C., the United States. (Photo by Ting Shen/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> <strong>The United States "shall fail in attempts to counter China, because most ASEAN countries want to expand economic exchanges and other cooperation with (their) regional neighbor China," Wilson Lee Flores, a columnist for the English daily The Philippine Star, told Xinhua.</strong></p> <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) -- The just-concluded U.S.-ASEAN summit will not draw regional countries closer to the U.S. side, and the U.S. attempt to court support among ASEAN in pursuit of its geopolitical interests is unlikely to gain traction, experts have said.</p> <p> U.S. President Joe Biden met leaders of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) countries at the White House during a summit held on Thursday and Friday, a move widely seen as an attempt by the world's sole superpower to pull members of the bloc into its camp against a rising China.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150910000074870687142.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>U.S. President Joe Biden arrives at the White House in Washington, D.C., the United States on Jan. 24, 2022. (Photo by Ting Shen/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> U.S. ATTEMPTS SHALL FAIL</p> <p> Against the backdrop of escalating tensions between Russia and Ukraine, the U.S.-initiated summit was widely viewed as a signal to highlight the importance of what America calls the "Indo-Pacific" region out of strategic concerns, and to counter the rising influence of China in the region.</p> <p> Lee Pei May, a political expert at the International Islamic University Malaysia, said while the summit occurred amid the tougher Russia-Ukraine conflict, the primary concern of the Biden administration is not about Russia, but more about ensuring a so-called "free and open" Indo-Pacific.</p> <p> "For the Biden administration to advance this vision, they have to get ASEAN countries on the American side and potentially for the U.S. to play a role in managing the disputes in the South China Sea," she said. "Such moves can be interpreted as challenging China's position in the region and hindering peaceful progress between China and ASEAN countries."</p> <p> The summit's significance lies in its timing, reported Foreign Affairs magazine on Wednesday. "It is being held as war rages in Ukraine, demonstrating that the United States has not lost its focus on the Indo-Pacific," the report said, adding "U.S. President Joe Biden seeks to better position his country in the wider geopolitical competition with China."</p> <p> Yet, the United States "shall fail in attempts to counter China, because most ASEAN countries want to expand economic exchanges and other cooperation with (their) regional neighbor China," Wilson Lee Flores, a columnist for the English daily The Philippine Star, told Xinhua.</p> <p> Flores noted that Washington was also aimed at convincing ASEAN countries to take tougher public positions and join its sanctions against Russia, which, likewise, shall fail. "Most of ASEAN seek to promote dialogue, diplomacy and stability in crisis areas due to ASEAN's traditional position of non-interference and upholding consensus."</p> <p> Joseph Matthews, a senior professor at the BELTEI International University in Phnom Penh, said that the United States should not use the summit to coerce and pressure ASEAN into submitting to its will and approach against Russia and China.</p> <p> Commenting on the Western sanctions and illegal embargoes on Russia, Ky Sereyvath, director general of the Institute of China Studies at the Royal Academy of Cambodia, said these sanctions will harm the global economy.</p> <p> "I think the rise in fuel prices will not slow down if the Ukraine crisis still continues and the U.S. still push this war forward," Sereyvath added.</p> <p> As the United States is scrambling to combat a sluggish economy and simmering social disorder amid COVID-19, its capability to fulfill promises to other countries has come under question.</p> <p> "The U.S. now has limited capacities to deliver on its promises, due to its own political and economic challenges, especially with the upcoming midterm elections in November," Flores cautioned.</p> <p> "The U.S. can still lobby to export its weapons to ASEAN. It can still attempt (to carry out) political or diplomatic initiatives. It can also attempt to pursue security alliances. But its waning economic activities and influence in Asia will weaken its strategic presence and leverage," the columnist noted.</p> <p> From the "Pivot to Asia" to the "Indo-Pacific Strategy," the United States has been teaming up its allies and regional countries to contain China. Washington never stops hyping up the concept of "Indo-Pacific" to peddle the targeted strategy at economic, political and military levels.</p> <p> A recent report by the U.S. Center for Strategic and International Studies showed that many ASEAN members have expressed concerns that the so-called "Indo-Pacific Economic Framework" is "primarily a political endeavor meant to counter China, rather than a sincere and thoughtful economic policy integration initiative."</p> <p> This viewpoint was echoed by Veronika Saraswati, researcher at Indonesia's the Center for Strategic and International Studies. "It is not hard to see that although the United States wants to strengthen its influence in ASEAN, it has not built cooperation with ASEAN countries in a more concrete level, only symbolic."</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150911000108339247797.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>ASEAN foreign ministers pose for a group photo during the ASEAN foreign ministers' meeting (AMM Retreat) in Phnom Penh, Cambodia, Feb. 17, 2022. (Photo by Sovannara/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> <strong>ASEAN NATIONS WON'T TAKE SIDE</strong></p> <p> Many believe that ASEAN members, now with a primary focus on post-pandemic economic recovery, will maintain neutrality at the forefront and neglect the attempts to pressure them into a U.S. sphere of influence.</p> <p> With China rising "sharply out of expectation," the United States "is afraid of losing its control" in Southeast Asia and found it necessary to hold tighter their hegemonic power, Saraswati pointed out.</p> <p> The Indonesian researcher stressed that Southeast Asian countries, including Indonesia, certainly do not want to be dragged into the competition between major powers.</p> <p> "Powerful countries should never use coercive measures to force other countries to choose side," she noted. "For a long time, the exercise of hegemonic power by the U.S. and its allies has had a deep impact on the survival and development of many countries."</p> <p> The United States will find itself unable to make any headway among ASEAN members, especially after Malaysia and Indonesia voiced concerns over the AUKUS trilateral security partnership involving Australia and Britain, said Azmi Hassan, a senior research fellow at Nusantara Academy for Strategic Research.</p> <p> Hassan gave the persuasive example that the United States has been unable to exert pressure on ASEAN over the Russia-Ukraine conflict, with most of the 10-member bloc abstaining from voting in favor of a resolution to suspend Russia from the United Nations Human Rights Council last month.</p> <p> "Bringing up controversial issues, forcing and coercing ASEAN member states to support its approach and agenda in the region, and trying to divide ASEAN on any issues will undermine the credibility and authenticity of the whole summit. The U.S. should be mindful of it," Matthews told Xinhua.</p> <p> Rather than pressing the bloc to follow its scenarios or agendas against other countries, Washington should use the meeting to express support for ASEAN's post-COVID-19 socioeconomic recovery, Kin Phea, director-general of the International Relations Institute at the Royal Academy of Cambodia, told Xinhua.</p> <p> "What the U.S. should do is encouraging ASEAN to adhere to its principle of centrality, solidarity and unity," he said, adding the United States should also respect ASEAN's rights in making decisions and refrain from using economic, political or security pressure to bargain with ASEAN or to force ASEAN to make decisions in its favor.</p> <p> "The U.S. must respect the common interests of the ASEAN, the region and the world, and should not put forward any scenarios or agendas that lead to ASEAN's rift and instability in the region," he said.</p> <p> <strong>VIGILANCE, UNITY URGED IN ASEAN</strong></p> <p> It is essential for the 10-member bloc to stand in solidarity against the U.S. interference for the sake of regional peace, stability, development and prosperity, Phea said.</p> <p> Matthews also urged ASEAN leaders to be vigilant about the Quadrilateral Security Dialogue among the United States, Japan, Australia and India, and the Australia-U.K.-U.S. pact, saying both military-cum-security alliances are posing a major security threat to ASEAN and the whole Asia region.</p> <p> "These alliances will trigger a conventional and nuclear arms race in the region, and thus destabilize peace and security, undermine economic development and destroy the ASEAN's centrality," he said.</p> <p> Unless it can demonstrate unity, ASEAN may find itself in a position where different members pursue different paths, which could compromise its cohesiveness, Lee cautioned. "This can be remedied by member states forging a consensus when dealing with the United States."</p> <p> "Having a consensus on key issues is not easy, but it is crucial as it would allow the members to speak with one united voice at the summit," the Malaysian expert noted. "The members can send a signal to the U.S. that ASEAN would remain neutral in whatever circumstances."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Finland, Sweden joining NATO are likely to have far-reaching implications ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096755</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0515/c90000-10096755.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 09:31:58 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150904000223799012230.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Swedish Foreign Minister Ann Linde (R) and Minister of Defense Peter Hultqvist attend a press conference on a security analysis in Stockholm, Sweden, on May 13, 2022. (Ninni Andersson/Government Offices of Sweden/Handout via Xinhua)</em></p> <p> <strong>Finland and Sweden have been members of the European Union since 1993, but until now they have been among a small minority of EU member states not part of the NATO military alliance. Once they join, it will leave only four of the EU's 27 member states Austria, Cyprus, Ireland, and Malta -- outside NATO.</strong></p> <p> Swedish Foreign Minister Ann Linde (R) and Minister of Defense Peter Hultqvist attend a press conference on a security analysis in Stockholm, Sweden, on May 13, 2022. (Ninni Andersson/Government Offices of Sweden/Handout via Xinhua)</p> <p> Finland and Sweden have been members of the European Union since 1993, but until now they have been among a small minority of EU member states not part of the NATO military alliance. Once they join, it will leave only four of the EU's 27 member states Austria, Cyprus, Ireland, and Malta -- outside NATO.</p> <p> ROME, May 14 (Xinhua) -- The likely ascension of Finland and Sweden to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) has been sparked by fears in those countries of the ongoing Russia-Ukraine conflict. But analysts said the development could have consequences that go beyond the current crisis.</p> <p> Finland and Sweden have been members of the European Union since 1993, but until now they have been among a small minority of EU member states not part of the NATO military alliance. Once they join, it will leave only four of the EU's 27 member states Austria, Cyprus, Ireland, and Malta -- outside NATO.</p> <p> It also means that 24 of NATO's 32 members will be members of the European Union.</p> <p> Analysts said that the two countries' membership in NATO will strengthen the alliance: both countries are among the world's richest nations, according to World Bank data, and military spending in both countries is broadly in line with NATO averages stated as a percentage of each country's gross domestic product.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0515/FOREIGN202205150905000415000754359.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Swedish Foreign Minister Ann Linde (6th L), Minister of Defense Peter Hultqvist (5th L) and other parliamentary party representatives present the result of a security analysis at a press conference in Stockholm, Sweden, on May 13, 2022. (Ninni Andersson/Government Offices of Sweden/Handout via Xinhua)</em></p> <p> "What this means is that the ties between NATO and the European Union will become even closer," Elena Sciso, an international law professor at Rome's LUISS University, told Xinhua. "Consider that the European Union's Lisbon Treaty from 2009 includes a clause on mutual, collective defense, just as NATO does."</p> <p> Nicolai von Ondarza, a political scientist and head of the European Union division at the German Institute for International and Security Affairs said Finland and Sweden were never "entirely neutral" when it came to security issues, noting their armed forces already coordinated activities with those from NATO countries and they shared intelligence. Instead, they practiced what he called "armed neutrality" -- meaning they are willing to use military force to maintain their neutrality if needed.</p> <p> "One of the things this will mean is that the Baltic Sea will now become largely a NATO Sea," von Ondarza said in an interview, referring to the body of water in northern Europe surrounded by Denmark, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Poland, and Germany -- all NATO member states -- in addition to Finland, Sweden, and Russia.</p> <p> "I also think we will see a policy shift when it comes to foreign and military policy that will shift from crisis management to territorial defense," he said.</p> <p> According to LUISS University's Sciso, there could be impacts of the move far beyond Europe. She noted that the Arctic Sea -- a nearly unpopulated region without major land mass thought to contain 160 billion barrels of oil and as much as 30 percent of the planet's natural gas is currently administered by eight countries that border it, five of which are members of NATO: Canada, Denmark, Iceland, Norway, and the United States. Once Finland and Sweden join NATO, that number will be seven of eight, with only Russia outside the alliance.</p> <p> "It's significant because the states that govern the area will be dominated by NATO," Sciso said. "The countries involved are obligated to respect rules agreed to for the region on things ranging from fishing rights to nuclear testing, but they remain sovereign states and two of them are the world's largest nuclear powers."&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Feature: Baby formula shortage worsening in U.S. prompts federal intervention ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096750</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096750.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 16:09:25 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> DENVER, the United States, May 13 (Xinhua) -- Grocery store shelves were bare of baby formula around Denver and other cities in the United States Friday as the federal government continued unprecedented steps toward accelerating production and distribution of the vital supplement.</p> <p> U.S. President Joe Biden defended his response to the crisis Friday as Republicans and conservative media attacked his administration's actions.</p> <p> "If we'd been better mind readers I guess we could have (reacted faster)," he told CNN at a press conference.</p> <p> Across the country, mothers took to social media and drove up to 50 miles to look around amid baby food formula shortage, People, an American weekly magazine that specializes in celebrity news and human-interest stories, said Friday, calling the situation "very, very scary."</p> <p> One mother also told the Denver Channel that "my entire family just goes and finds the formula when we they can."</p> <p> "My sister picked me up some in Arvada yesterday, my dad up in Thornton the other day," Ashlee Lane, the mother of a 7-month-old, said of her family's efforts scouring the Denver area for baby formula.</p> <p> Data released this week by Datasembly, which tracks baby formula stock at more than 11,000 stores, showed that 43 percent of the top-selling baby formula products were out of stock as of the week ending May 8, and in five states, more than half of the top-selling formula products were missing from stores.</p> <p> At busy retail giant Target in Boulder, 50 km northwest of Denver, baby formula supplies were scarce and most store shelves were empty on Friday.</p> <p> "Usually they tell us when more is coming in," a store inventory clerk told Xinhua, pointing to her hand-held computer. "But this says zero are coming in and zero are expected soon."</p> <p> Nearby, at high-end grocer Whole Foods, the story was the same, even with non-traditional formula products that catered to mothers with money seeking organic baby food solutions.</p> <p> "We really noticed it in the past week," customer service representative Julian Bell said, "although our stock has been dwindling for several weeks."</p> <p> On Friday, the Department of Health and Human Service's (HHS) website posted that "manufacturers have ramped up production 30-50 percent," and that "yesterday, President Biden spoke with retailers and manufacturers, including Walmart, Target, Reckitt, and Gerber, to discuss ways to get more formula quickly and safely onto store shelves."</p> <p> HHS pointed to the January recall of "certain powdered infant formulas" by industry leader Abbott Nutrition as a catalyst for the shortages, a federal response to four Michigan babies getting sick from the formula and two infant deaths between September and February.</p> <p> "The reason we're here is because the FDA (Food and Drug Administration) took the steps to ensure that babies were taking safe formula," White House press secretary Jen Psaki said at a press conference Thursday.</p> <p> "There were babies who died from taking this formula, so they were doing their jobs," Psaki said.</p> <p> Psaki announced a series of measures to alleviate the shortage, including efforts to speed up production and crack down on price gouging, as reports surfaced of individuals buying out store supplies and re-selling them on Ebay for huge profits.</p> <p> The Justice Department is now working with state attorney generals to monitor price-gouging in the formula market, and Biden said Thursday he had asked the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to investigate reports of price-gouging.</p> <p> The Biden administration is also working to increase imports of formula, a new solution as the United States produces 98 percent of its formula supply, according to an administration fact sheet.</p> <p> On Friday, Biden also called for cutting red tape on the types of formula parents can buy, calling on the FTC and state attorneys general to crack down on price gouging and unfair market practices, and increase the supply of formula through increased imports.</p> <p> Congressional Democrats joined the president in demanding answers from baby formula manufacturers.</p> <p> In letters to the heads of four baby formula companies, Democratic Reps. Carolyn Maloney of New York and Raja Krishnamoorthi of Illinois demanded documents and details about the shortage.</p> <p> "The national formula shortage poses a threat to the health and economic security of infants and families in communities throughout the country -- particularly those with less income who have historically experienced health inequities, including food insecurity," they wrote in letters sent to Mead Johnson Nutrition, Nestle USA, Perrigo Company and Abbott Nutrition.</p> <p> These companies control nearly 90 percent of the U.S. market for baby formula, the lawmakers said, requesting certain documents submitted by June 2.</p> <p> REPUBLICANS EXPLOIT THE CRISIS</p> <p> Republican leaders were quick to exploit the baby food crisis for their own political gain, slamming Biden on several fronts.</p> <p> "This is absolutely UNACCEPTABLE in America," Elise Stefanik, a New York House Republican, wrote on Twitter. "Sadly, this has become the norm because of Joe Biden's radical agenda."</p> <p> "Unsurprisingly, when I reached out in February from my office to the FDA we received no substantive response. Joe Biden simply has no plan," Stefanik told the media at a press conference Thursday.</p> <p> "Instead, bare shelves. Biden has continued to pass the buck. This is not a Third World country. This should never happen in the United States of America. We're unified in demanding action to address this crisis," she added.</p> <p> Rep. Ann Wagner, a Missouri Republican, joined in: "This is sadly Joe Biden's America."</p> <p> "Working families are already struggling to put food on the table due to the skyrocketing costs of every day items, and now they are facing a crisis that is threatening the very lives of their newborn children," Wagner said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Tomato fever grips India's Kerala, neighboring states sound alert ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096751</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096751.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 16:09:25 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NEW DELHI, May 14 (Xinhua) -- A viral fever has caused panic in the southern Indian state of Kerala, where at least 80 cases of what is locally known as tomato fever were reported, officials said Saturday.</p> <p> The viral disease, which gets its name "tomato fever" because of the red blister it causes, has raised concern in Kerala and the neighboring states of Tamil Nadu and Karnataka.</p> <p> Doctors say tomato flu comes with red rashes, skin irritation, and dehydration.</p> <p> The illness that experts say is contagious can also cause tiredness, joint pain, stomach cramps, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, coughing, sneezing, runny nose, high fever, or body ache. In some cases, it may also change the skin color of legs and hands, according to reports.</p> <p> In Kerala, the disease has been detected in children under five years of age.</p> <p> Tamil Nadu's Health Secretary J. Radhakrishnan on Friday urged the local residents not to panic as health authorities were monitoring the situation across the state.</p> <p> The Karnataka state government has sounded high alert in the districts bordering Kerala.</p> <p> Health officials in these districts have been directed to step up surveillance measures and maintain a constant vigilance on outpatient services at both private and public health institutions.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ India records 2,858 new COVID-19 cases, 11 more deaths ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096749</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096749.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 15:32:21 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NEW DELHI, May 14 (Xinhua) -- India's COVID-19 tally rose to 43,119,112 on Saturday, with 2,858 new cases registered in the past 24 hours across the South Asian country, showed the federal health ministry's latest data.</p> <p> Besides, 11 deaths from the pandemic were registered across the country since Friday morning, taking the death toll to 524,201.</p> <p> Currently there are 18,096 active COVID-19 cases recorded in India, a fall of 508 in the past 24 hours.</p> <p> So far, 42,576,815 COVID-19 cases have been cured and discharged from hospitals in the country, including 3,355 discharged in the past 24 hours.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 626 families receive cash assistance in central Afghan province ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096747</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096747.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 15:22:19 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> KABUL, May 14 (Xinhua) -- A total of 626 families have received cash assistance in Afghanistan's central Bamyan province, the Afghan Ministry of Refugees and Repatriation said on Saturday.</p> <p> The displaced and most vulnerable families identified by surveys in Shibar and Yakawlang districts of the province received 400 U.S. dollars each in cash assistance on Wednesday, the ministry said in a statement.</p> <p> The assistance was provided by the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR), according to the statement.</p> <p> It added that more humanitarian assistance would be provided to needy families in Afghanistan's far-flung provinces in the coming days or weeks.</p> <p> Following the U.S. forces' pullout from Afghanistan last August, Washington has imposed sanctions on the Taliban-run administration and frozen assets of more than 9 billion U.S. dollars of Afghanistan's central bank in a move weighing heavily on the battered economy in the war-torn Asian country.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Feature: 2 years on, anti-Asian hatred persists in New York ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096731</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096731.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:51:36 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NEW YORK, May 13 (Xinhua) -- About two and a half years into the COVID-19 pandemic, the United States has seen not only an increase in infections and deaths, but also an orgy of racism and hate crimes against minority groups, particularly the Asian-American community.</p> <p> Following an apparently random yet violent murder of a young Korean-American woman in a Chinatown apartment here in February, mourners placed flowers, candles, photos, and cardboard signs condemning anti-Asian hatred around a tree outside the residential building where Christina Yuna Lee was stabbed to death.</p> <p> While the shock of Lee's death had yet to wear off, mourners were outraged that the makeshift memorial for Lee had been repeatedly vandalized.</p> <p> The temporary memorial was first vandalized in the middle of the night just three days after Lee's death, and it continued to be vandalized even in broad daylight.</p> <p> "So five times last month, and it just keeps increasing. It is very sad," Brian Chin, Lee's former landlord, told Xinhua.</p> <p> According to video clips from a surveillance camera shared by Chin, a man kicked at the flowers, candles, and signs in the early morning on March 2, and another pedestrian pulled down a cardboard sign about a week later.</p> <p> Every attack on the memorial is pretty much anti-Asian and "it is very scary right now," said Chin, whose family came to the United States from China over 60 years ago.</p> <p> "They're doing it with hate. They see her picture. They see the flowers and candles," Chin added.</p> <p> Lee's tragic death followed the fatal shoving of Asian American Michelle Alyssa Go onto subway tracks by a man at Times Square station on Jan. 15 and the death of Yaopan Ma in January in a racially motivated attack in East Harlem.</p> <p> "Her (Lee's) death is part of an alarming pattern of unchecked, hateful violence against women, namely women of Asian descent and women of color that can no longer stand without consequence," said one of Lee's relatives in an appeal on Gofundme.com.</p> <p> For Chin, a middle-aged man, the continued anti-Asian hate crimes had brought about unprecedented depression.</p> <p> "I think everyone is terrified right now that they will be attacked on the subways, on the streets, and then the guy will be out on the same day," he said.</p> <p> According to Chin, this wave of anti-Asian hatred began with very vitriolic language which claims COVID-19 as the so-called "Chinese flu" or "Wuhan flu."</p> <p> Kathleen Flynn-hui, whose husband originally came from Hong Kong, said that anti-Asian prejudice affects her family on a daily basis.</p> <p> "We've kind of always felt it, but not as strongly as now," said Flynn-hui, adding that she "dealt with discrimination against my husband because he was Asian the whole time."</p> <p> Chin said the situation is deteriorating due to a combination of politics, the impact of new laws, and the new Manhattan District Attorney's lenient stance on crime.</p> <p> "The cops are doing their job, but they arrest them, and they're free the next day due to the laws," said Chin.</p> <p> Right now, much stronger laws are needed to protect the Asian community, Chin said, calling on lawmakers, the city council, and the mayor to take stronger and more enforceable action.</p> <p> The Committee of 100, a non-profit leadership organization of prominent Chinese Americans, recently called on U.S. elected officials, law enforcement, and responsible media to address racism, discrimination, and violence against Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders immediately with actionable and concrete results.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Australian opposition party maintains polling lead ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096729</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096729.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:43:50 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> CANBERRA, May 14 (Xinhua) -- Australia's opposition the Labor Party still maintains the lead as the federal election campaign entered its final week.</p> <p> According to the latest edition of Newspoll published on Friday night, the Labor Party holds a comfortable 54-46 lead over the Coalition on a two-party preferred basis.</p> <p> It marks the 20th consecutive Newspoll where the Coalition has trailed the Labor since November 2020.</p> <p> Significantly, the Coalition has not been able to make any inroads since Prime Minister Scott Morrison called the election on April 10.</p> <p> Newspoll found that 43 percent of voters identified Morrison as their preferred prime minister and 42 percent as Labor leader Anthony Albanese.</p> <p> It represents a major swing in Albanese's favor from a 46-37 lead for Morrison at the end of April.</p> <p> In a major shift of tone, Morrison promised to change his leadership style if re-elected.</p> <p> Admitting he can be "a bit of a bulldozer", Morrison promised to empathize more with Australians if given another term as the prime minister.</p> <p> "I will seek to explain motives and my concerns and empathize a lot more. But I tell you what, at the end of the day, what matters most is I get the job done," he told reporters.</p> <p> In response, Albanese, who on Saturday announced a Labor government would boost health spending by 970 million Australian dollars (673 million U.S. dollars), promised to unite the country.</p> <p> "A bulldozer wrecks things. A bulldozer knocks things over. I'm a builder, that's what I am," he said. "I will build things in this country."&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ U.S. urged not to rope in Southeast Asian countries out of geopolitical interests ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096718</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096718.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:28:13 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) -- The just-concluded U.S.-ASEAN summit will not draw regional countries closer to the U.S. side, and the U.S. attempt to court support among ASEAN in pursuit of its geopolitical interests is unlikely to gain traction, experts have said.</p> <p> U.S. President Joe Biden met leaders of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) countries at the White House during a summit held on Thursday and Friday, a move widely seen as an attempt by the world's sole superpower to pull members of the bloc into its camp against a rising China.</p> <p> U.S. ATTEMPTS SHALL FAIL</p> <p> Against the backdrop of escalating tensions between Russia and Ukraine, the U.S.-initiated summit was widely viewed as a signal to highlight the importance of what America calls the "Indo-Pacific" region out of strategic concerns, and to counter the rising influence of China in the region.</p> <p> Lee Pei May, a political expert at the International Islamic University Malaysia, said while the summit occurred amid the tougher Russia-Ukraine conflict, the primary concern of the Biden administration is not about Russia, but more about ensuring a so-called "free and open" Indo-Pacific.</p> <p> "For the Biden administration to advance this vision, they have to get ASEAN countries on the American side and potentially for the U.S. to play a role in managing the disputes in the South China Sea," she said. "Such moves can be interpreted as challenging China's position in the region and hindering peaceful progress between China and ASEAN countries."</p> <p> The summit's significance lies in its timing, reported Foreign Affairs magazine on Wednesday. "It is being held as war rages in Ukraine, demonstrating that the United States has not lost its focus on the Indo-Pacific," the report said, adding "U.S. President Joe Biden seeks to better position his country in the wider geopolitical competition with China."</p> <p> Yet, the United States "shall fail in attempts to counter China, because most ASEAN countries want to expand economic exchanges and other cooperation with (their) regional neighbor China," Wilson Lee Flores, a columnist for the English daily The Philippine Star, told Xinhua.</p> <p> Flores noted that Washington was also aimed at convincing ASEAN countries to take tougher public positions and join its sanctions against Russia, which, likewise, shall fail. "Most of ASEAN seek to promote dialogue, diplomacy and stability in crisis areas due to ASEAN's traditional position of non-interference and upholding consensus."</p> <p> Joseph Matthews, a senior professor at the BELTEI International University in Phnom Penh, said that the United States should not use the summit to coerce and pressure ASEAN into submitting to its will and approach against Russia and China.</p> <p> Commenting on the Western sanctions and illegal embargoes on Russia, Ky Sereyvath, director general of the Institute of China Studies at the Royal Academy of Cambodia, said these sanctions will harm the global economy.</p> <p> "I think the rise in fuel prices will not slow down if the Ukraine crisis still continues and the U.S. still push this war forward," Sereyvath added.</p> <p> As the United States is scrambling to combat a sluggish economy and simmering social disorder amid COVID-19, its capability to fulfill promises to other countries has come under question.</p> <p> "The U.S. now has limited capacities to deliver on its promises, due to its own political and economic challenges, especially with the upcoming midterm elections in November," Flores cautioned.</p> <p> "The U.S. can still lobby to export its weapons to ASEAN. It can still attempt (to carry out) political or diplomatic initiatives. It can also attempt to pursue security alliances. But its waning economic activities and influence in Asia will weaken its strategic presence and leverage," the columnist noted.</p> <p> From the "Pivot to Asia" to the "Indo-Pacific Strategy," the United States has been teaming up its allies and regional countries to contain China. Washington never stops hyping up the concept of "Indo-Pacific" to peddle the targeted strategy at economic, political and military levels.</p> <p> A recent report by the U.S. Center for Strategic and International Studies showed that many ASEAN members have expressed concerns that the so-called "Indo-Pacific Economic Framework" is "primarily a political endeavor meant to counter China, rather than a sincere and thoughtful economic policy integration initiative."</p> <p> This viewpoint was echoed by Veronika Saraswati, researcher at Indonesia's the Center for Strategic and International Studies. "It is not hard to see that although the United States wants to strengthen its influence in ASEAN, it has not built cooperation with ASEAN countries in a more concrete level, only symbolic."</p> <p> ASEAN NATIONS WON'T TAKE SIDE</p> <p> Many believe that ASEAN members, now with a primary focus on post-pandemic economic recovery, will maintain neutrality at the forefront and neglect the attempts to pressure them into a U.S. sphere of influence.</p> <p> With China rising "sharply out of expectation," the United States "is afraid of losing its control" in Southeast Asia and found it necessary to hold tighter their hegemonic power, Saraswati pointed out.</p> <p> The Indonesian researcher stressed that Southeast Asian countries, including Indonesia, certainly do not want to be dragged into the competition between major powers.</p> <p> "Powerful countries should never use coercive measures to force other countries to choose side," she noted. "For a long time, the exercise of hegemonic power by the U.S. and its allies has had a deep impact on the survival and development of many countries."</p> <p> The United States will find itself unable to make any headway among ASEAN members, especially after Malaysia and Indonesia voiced concerns over the AUKUS trilateral security partnership involving Australia and Britain, said Azmi Hassan, a senior research fellow at Nusantara Academy for Strategic Research.</p> <p> Hassan gave the persuasive example that the United States has been unable to exert pressure on ASEAN over the Russia-Ukraine conflict, with most of the 10-member bloc abstaining from voting in favor of a resolution to suspend Russia from the United Nations Human Rights Council last month.</p> <p> "Bringing up controversial issues, forcing and coercing ASEAN member states to support its approach and agenda in the region, and trying to divide ASEAN on any issues will undermine the credibility and authenticity of the whole summit. The U.S. should be mindful of it," Matthews told Xinhua.</p> <p> Rather than pressing the bloc to follow its scenarios or agendas against other countries, Washington should use the meeting to express support for ASEAN's post-COVID-19 socioeconomic recovery, Kin Phea, director-general of the International Relations Institute at the Royal Academy of Cambodia, told Xinhua.</p> <p> "What the U.S. should do is encouraging ASEAN to adhere to its principle of centrality, solidarity and unity," he said, adding the United States should also respect ASEAN's rights in making decisions and refrain from using economic, political or security pressure to bargain with ASEAN or to force ASEAN to make decisions in its favor.</p> <p> "The U.S. must respect the common interests of the ASEAN, the region and the world, and should not put forward any scenarios or agendas that lead to ASEAN's rift and instability in the region," he said.</p> <p> VIGILANCE, UNITY URGED IN ASEAN</p> <p> It is essential for the 10-member bloc to stand in solidarity against the U.S. interference for the sake of regional peace, stability, development and prosperity, Phea said.</p> <p> Matthews also urged ASEAN leaders to be vigilant about the Quadrilateral Security Dialogue among the United States, Japan, Australia and India, and the Australia-U.K.-U.S. pact, saying both military-cum-security alliances are posing a major security threat to ASEAN and the whole Asia region.</p> <p> "These alliances will trigger a conventional and nuclear arms race in the region, and thus destabilize peace and security, undermine economic development and destroy the ASEAN's centrality," he said.</p> <p> Unless it can demonstrate unity, ASEAN may find itself in a position where different members pursue different paths, which could compromise its cohesiveness, Lee cautioned. "This can be remedied by member states forging a consensus when dealing with the United States."</p> <p> "Having a consensus on key issues is not easy, but it is crucial as it would allow the members to speak with one united voice at the summit," the Malaysian expert noted. "The members can send a signal to the U.S. that ASEAN would remain neutral in whatever circumstances."&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Jen Psaki leaves role as White House press secretary ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096716</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096716.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:13:43 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> WASHINGTON, May 13 (Xinhua) -- Jen Psaki left her role as the White House press secretary on Friday.</p> <p> "I want to say thank you to the president and the first lady. They entrusted me in serving in this role for the last 15 months," Psaki said during her last briefing at the White House.</p> <p> She also extended appreciation to the White House's press team, as well as to reporters in the James S. Brady Press Briefing Room.</p> <p> The appearance was Psaki's 224th White House briefing over her tenure that began the day Joe Biden was sworn in as U.S. president in January 2021.</p> <p> Karine Jean-Pierre is the new White House press secretary, becoming both the first African American and openly LGBTQ person to hold the position.</p> <p> As an assistant to the U.S. president, the White House press secretary provides daily briefings for the media on the administration's activities and agenda.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ U.S. uses democracy as pretext for interference -- experts ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096713</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096713.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:10:46 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> CAIRO, May 14 (Xinhua) -- The United States has been exploiting democracy, human rights and aid as tools and weapons to incite division around the world and meddle in other countries' internal affairs, say political experts.</p> <p> "To influence domestic policies in recipient countries ... the U.S. has provided assistance to serve its goals and achieve its interests," Ayman Okeil, general manager of the Cairo-based Maat for Peace, Development, and Human Rights, told Xinhua in a recent interview.</p> <p> THE NED AS A PROXY</p> <p> Among all the proxies Washington uses to serve its political agenda in other countries, the National Endowment for Democracy (NED), which was founded in 1983 as a bipartisan, non-profit institution by the U.S. government, is one of the most active.</p> <p> Nominally a non-governmental organization that provides support for democracy abroad, the NED in fact relies on continuous financial support from the White House and the U.S. Congress, and takes orders from the U.S. government.</p> <p> Okeil described the NED as one of Washington's "soldiers" for interfering in other countries' decision-making process.</p> <p> The NED has worked as a substitute for the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) in cultivating pro-U.S. opposition activists for subverting lawful governments and provoking uprisings in the Arab countries under the pretext of promoting democracy, he said.</p> <p> According to Saeb Rawashdeh, a political analyst at the Jordan Press Foundation, the NED was founded as a tool for projecting political influence in different sovereign states that the U.S. government has labeled as "non-democratic, totalitarian, authoritarian and anti-American."</p> <p> The NED supported opposition groups in other countries, which were trained to represent Washington's interest, rather than the vital interests of their own nations and states, Rawashdeh pointed out.</p> <p> Echoing Rawashdeh's point, Okeil said that the NED has spent millions of U.S. dollars to support political parties, labor unions, dissident movements, and media in dozens of countries.</p> <p> The organization has been employed as the "mastermind" behind separatist riots, color revolutions, and political crises around the world, with the aim of toppling legitimate governments and creating U.S. puppets in targeted countries, said Ahmad Ashqar, a Syrian journalist and political expert.</p> <p> The NED makes sure that nations across the globe do what the United States wants them to do and in no way feel confident and capable of pursuing their own political/ideological agendas, Rawashdeh said. "And this is also what the U.S. foreign policy is doing for decades."</p> <p> A NEW TYPE OF IMPERIALISM</p> <p> The United States, unfortunately, has created a new type of imperialism, by occupying foreign countries with money and forces and interfering in their choice of leaders and party compositions, Okeil told Xinhua.</p> <p> Unlike the funds that came from some countries like China, which help improve health, education and development sectors, the U.S. economic aid is always with conditions attached, he noted</p> <p> Okeil's words are not groundless. According to a study by the American University in Cairo in November 2021, the NED has allocated more than 606 million dollars in "democracy assistance" to Egypt in the period between 1990 and 2003. In 2008, the U.S. government provided 415 million dollars in economic assistance to Egypt, which includes 55 million dollars to support programs for promoting democracy.</p> <p> However, as Tariq Fahmy, a political science professor at the Cairo University, noted, the U.S. mode of democracy has not been successful in the Middle East, and it contradicts many countries' unique conditions.</p> <p> "We all saw the disgraceful role in provoking the Arab Spring via funding the protesters" under the cover of democracy and human rights, Fahmy said, explaining that such kind of imposed democracy couldn't breed stability.</p> <p> After the Arab Spring, many people in the Middle East have started to see the real objectives behind the U.S. aid when knowing that Washington had a role in inciting the Arab Spring uprisings via supporting, training and funding young protesters, Okeil noted.</p> <p> The U.S. model of democracy is not suitable for the world, and based on that model, the U.S. policies led to real crimes, Fahmy said.</p> <p> It's a fact that the United States has distorted the positive meaning of democracy and emptied such a notion of anything useful and beneficial for other countries, Ashqar argued.</p> <p> "We have seen several examples like in Syria, where the United States used democracy as a pretext to support separatist forces and radical ones to destabilize the legitimate government," he said. "The U.S. presence in Syria has achieved all but the so-called democracy."</p> <p> "Under the pretext of fighting terrorism and spreading democracy, the U.S. has stolen key areas in Syria rich with oil and gas, do you call that democracy?" asked the Syrian journalist.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 27 killed, 12 injured in Indian capital building fire ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096712</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096712.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 13:57:02 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NEW DELHI, May 14 (Xinhua) -- At least 27 people were killed and 12 others suffered burn injuries after a massive fire broke out in a three-storey commercial building in the Indian capital, senior police officer Sameer Sharma said Saturday.</p> <p> The fire broke out inside the building on Friday evening at 4:40 p.m. (local time) near the city's Mundka metro station, and the death toll became clear only by night.</p> <p> Reports said the fire started from the first floor of the building at an office of a CCTV cameras and router manufacturing company.</p> <p> Officials said the firefighting and rescue operations continued until early morning on Saturday. Police are yet to identify the deceased, and the injured have been admitted to Sanjay Gandhi Memorial Hospital.</p> <p> Firefighters used heavy cranes to reach the top floor of the building, and 27 fire tenders were sent to contain the blaze when smoke surrounded the entire building.</p> <p> Video clips showed people trying to escape the building using a rope and hanging from broken windows. Many people could be seen trying to jump to another building.</p> <p> "There was only one staircase and because of that people could not go out. I think the building did not have a proper no objection certificate (NOC) from the fire department," Satpal Bhardwaj, divisional officer of the Delhi fire department told media.</p> <p> Police said they have arrested the owners of the company, but the owner of the building who did not have safety clearance from the fire department is on the run.</p> <p> Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi has expressed grief over the deaths in the fire.</p> <p> "Extremely saddened by the loss of lives due to a tragic fire in Delhi. My thoughts are with the bereaved families. I wish the injured a speedy recovery," Modi wrote on social media.</p> <p> Chances of fire in Indian buildings are usually high as people often ignore safety standards vis-a-vis fire.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Russian, U.S. defense chiefs discuss Ukraine situation over phone ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096695</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096695.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 13:38:51 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) --The following are the latest developments in the conflict between Russia and Ukraine:</p> <p> More than 6.4 million people have been reached with vital humanitarian assistance in Ukraine since the country's military conflict with Russia started on Feb. 24, said UN humanitarians on Friday.</p> <p> This includes more than 5.7 million people who have been able to put food on their table. Cash assistance has been provided to over 655,000 people, allowing them to cover some of their most basic needs, said the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA).</p> <p> - - - -</p> <p> Russian Defense Minister Sergei Shoigu and U.S. Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin held a phone conversation on Friday to discuss the situation in Ukraine.</p> <p> During the call initiated by the American side, the defense chiefs discussed topical issues of international security, including the situation in Ukraine, the Russian Defense Ministry said in a brief statement.</p> <p> - - - -</p> <p> Ukraine is entering a new long-lasting phase of the military conflict with Russia, Ukrainian Defense Minister Olexiy Reznikov said on Friday.</p> <p> Russia has more resources than Ukraine, but Ukraine is receiving heavy weapons from its partners, Reznikov said, adding that some 1,500 Ukrainian soldiers will soon be trained to work with modern military equipment.</p> <p> - - - -</p> <p> Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky said that he stands ready for direct talks with Russian President Vladimir Putin, Zelensky's press service reported Friday.</p> <p> "I am ready to talk with Putin. But only with him. Without his mediators of any kind," Zelensky said in a video interview with Italian RAI TV, published on the official presidential Telegram account.</p> <p> - - - -</p> <p> Russian President Vladimir Putin and German Chancellor Olaf Scholz held a phone conversation on Friday to discuss the situation in Ukraine with an emphasis on the humanitarian aspect.</p> <p> Putin outlined in detail the logic and main objectives of Russia's special military operation and spoke about measures being taken by the Russian side to ensure the safety of civilians, the Kremlin said in a statement.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Slain Palestinian journalist buried in Jerusalem ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096687</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096687.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:50:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> JERUSALEM, May 13 (Xinhua) -- Shireen Abu Akleh, a Palestinian-American journalist who was killed while covering clashes in the occupied West Bank, was buried on Friday in Jerusalem.</p> <p> Thousands of Palestinians attended the burial, which started with a church service in east Jerusalem in the morning. Last respects were paid in the Old City, said her employer Al Jazeera TV, where she was laid to rest in a nearby cemetery.</p> <p> The Palestinian Health Ministry said Abu Akleh, 51, was shot by the Israeli troops in the northern West Bank city of Jenin on Wednesday morning while covering an Israeli military raid, and she died shortly after.</p> <p> Officials from the Al Jazeera network also accused Israel of deliberately killing the veteran journalist, while Israeli authorities initially claimed she was hit by indiscriminate gunfire from Palestinian militants.</p> <p> Also on Friday, the Israeli military issued initial findings of its probe, saying the gunfire was heavy in the vicinity of Abu Akleh and her team during the incident, and "it is not possible to unequivocally determine the source of the gunfire which hit and killed" her.</p> <p> "At the end of the initial investigation, a number of details requiring further clarification remained," the military added.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 866 COVID-19 patients discharged from hospitals on Chinese mainland ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096676</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096676.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:50:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) -- A total of 866 COVID-19 patients were discharged from hospitals after recovery on the Chinese mainland on Friday, the National Health Commission said in its Saturday report.</p> <p> That brought the mainland's total number of COVID-19 patients discharged from hospitals after recovery to 210,006 as of Friday.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Humanitarian aid reaches 6.4 mln people in Ukraine: UN ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096679</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096679.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:50:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> UNITED NATIONS, May 13 (Xinhua) -- More than 6.4 million people have been reached with vital humanitarian assistance in Ukraine since the country's military conflict with Russia started on Feb. 24, said UN humanitarians on Friday.</p> <p> This includes more than 5.7 million people who have been able to put food on their table. Cash assistance has been provided to over 655,000 people, allowing them to cover some of their most basic needs, said the UN Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (OCHA).</p> <p> More than 1.5 million people have received health care support, and around 352,000 people have been provided with clean water and hygiene products. Nearly 430,000 people have received protection services, psychosocial support and critical legal services, including support to internally displaced persons, it said.</p> <p> Despite this remarkable scale-up, many more people urgently need support, including those living in areas experiencing heavy fighting. The United Nations urges parties to the conflict to remove any barriers to the movement of humanitarian staff to ensure the continued delivery of life-saving assistance across Ukraine, said OCHA.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ UN chief mourns death of UAE president ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096659</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096659.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:34:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> UNITED NATIONS, May 13 (Xinhua) -- UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres on Friday mourned the death of United Arab Emirates (UAE) President Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan, who died at the age of 73.</p> <p> Guterres extended his condolences to the royal family and the government and people of the UAE, said Farhan Haq, deputy spokesman for the secretary-general, in a statement.</p> <p> Sheikh Khalifa led the UAE since 2004, succeeding his father, Sheikh Zayed bin Sultan Al Nahyan, the country's founder. Sheikh Khalifa also led the UAE through a significant period of its development, marked by great economic advances and a surge in its regional and global influence, said the statement.</p> <p> "The secretary-general reiterates the commitment of the United Nations to its close cooperation with the United Arab Emirates, including on humanitarian issues and interfaith dialogue, as well as on regional and global peace, security and sustainable development," it said.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Israeli missile attack kills 5 in central Syria ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096660</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096660.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:34:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> DAMASCUS, May 13 (Xinhua) -- Five people were killed and seven others injured after Israel attacked military sites in central Syria on Friday, state news agency SANA reported.</p> <p> Several missiles fired by Israel hit targets near the Masyaf area of Hama province, SANA reported, citing a military statement.</p> <p> The attack also caused property damage and set fire to the forest of Masyaf, according to the report.</p> <p> In an earlier report, SANA said that Syria has intercepted Israeli missiles in its central coast region.</p> <p> Explosions were heard in the Syrian coast cities of Banyas, Tartous, and Jableh, according to the report, adding most of the missiles were intercepted before reaching their targets.</p> <p> Israel frequently bombed Syria's military facilities while claiming it was striking pro-Iran militia bases.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 16 killed in massive building fire in Indian capital ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096658</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096658.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:34:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NEW DELHI, May 13 (Xinhua) -- At least 16 people were killed Friday in a devastating fire inside a commercial building in the Indian capital, officials said.</p> <p> The fire broke out at around 4:40 p.m. local time in the building located near the Mundka metro station in outer Delhi.</p> <p> "A total of 16 bodies were recovered from the three-storey commercial building which had caught fire this evening near Delhi's Mundka metro station," Atul Garg, director of the Delhi fire service, told local media.</p> <p> According to Garg, the third floor of the building was yet to be searched.</p> <p> Police officials said the death toll was likely to rise as many people were feared trapped in the building.</p> <p> "Rescue operation is underway in the building," a police official said.</p> <p> Officials said 24 fire tenders were at the spot to contain the blaze.</p> <p> "It's a massive fire and heavy cranes are being used to go up and douse the fire," a fire service official said.</p> <p> The cause of the fire is not immediately known. However, reports said the fire started from the first floor of the building which hosts an office of a CCTV camera and router manufacturing company.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ New Zealand PM tests positive for COVID-19 ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096653</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096653.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:21:29 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> WELLINGTON, May 14 (Xinhua) -- New Zealand Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern confirmed on Saturday that she had tested positive for COVID-19.</p> <p> "Despite best efforts, unfortunately, I've joined the rest of my family and tested positive for COVID-19," Ardern posted on social media on Saturday morning.</p> <p> Ardern has been isolating at home with her family since Sunday when her fiance Clarke Gayford tested positive.</p> <p> "We've been isolating since Sunday when Clarke first tested positive. Neve (Ardern's daughter) tested positive on Wednesday, and I returned a weak positive last night and a strong one this morning," said Ardern.</p> <p> "To anyone else out there, isolating or dealing with COVID, I hope you take good care of yourselves," said Ardern.</p> <p> New Zealand recorded 7,441 new community cases of COVID-19, 2,503 of which were reported in the largest city Auckland, the ministry of health said on Friday.</p> <p> To date, the country has reported 1,026,715 confirmed cases of COVID-19 since the beginning of the pandemic.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Commentary: Washington's small-clique politics won't fool SE Asia ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096638</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096638.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 09:49:33 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/18/4223263417608477262.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on Nov. 23, 2021 shows the White House in Washington, D.C., the United States. (Photo by Ting Shen/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> <strong>*The U.S. administration has long taken pleasure in organizing destructive meetings under the guise of constructive engagements. </strong></p> <p> <strong>*The so-called "Indo-Pacific Strategy" it is selling at this summit, for example, claims to maintain regional freedom and openness and respect ASEAN centrality in regional affairs, but in reality incites confrontation, undermines unity, and threatens cooperation and development in the region through such exclusive geopolitical blocs as AUKUS and Quad.</strong></p> <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- The White House is peddling its so-called "Indo-Pacific Strategy" against China and ramping up its pressure campaign of the Russia-Ukraine conflict during a two-day summit in Washington with leaders of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN).</p> <p> But its hope to pull ASEAN members into its camp will shrivel, as ASEAN countries have already woken up to Washington's typical hegemony, hypocrisy and egomania.</p> <p> The arrangement of the summit itself has laid bare Washington's double-dealing nature. Its disrespect for ASEAN members concerning scheduling issues despite its pledge of "enduring commitment" has sparked a wave of complaints among ASEAN members, resulting in a postponement of the summit from late March to May.</p> <p> Cambodian Minister attached to the Prime Minister Kao Kim Hourn said before the summit that if Washington was serious about improving its ties with ASEAN, it should have arranged bilateral meetings between the United States and ASEAN countries. ASEAN leaders "should be treated with respect and equality," he noted.</p> <p> The U.S. administration has long taken pleasure in organizing destructive meetings under the guise of constructive engagements. The so-called "Indo-Pacific Strategy" it is selling at this summit, for example, claims to maintain regional freedom and openness and respect ASEAN centrality in regional affairs, but in reality incites confrontation, undermines unity, and threatens cooperation and development in the region through such exclusive geopolitical blocs as AUKUS and Quad.</p> <p> Many sober minds in ASEAN have seen through this duplicity and bullying. Indonesia and Malaysia warned that AUKUS could lead to a major arms race in the region. A recent report by the U.S. Center for Strategic and International Studies showed that many ASEAN members have expressed concerns that the so-called "Indo-Pacific Economic Framework" is "primarily a political endeavor meant to counter China, rather than a sincere and thoughtful economic policy integration initiative."</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/71/5892171399547127135.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on March 24, 2022 shows the U.S. national flag (R) on the U.S. Embassy building in Moscow, Russia. (Xinhua/Bai Xueqi)</em></p> <p> Meanwhile, the White House will attempt in vain during this summit to talk ASEAN into imposing sanctions against Russia. Ever since the escalation of the current Ukraine crisis, Washington has been trying to exert pressure on ASEAN to take sides, but most of ASEAN members did not follow suit.</p> <p> On April 7, six of the 10-member bloc abstained from voting in favor of a resolution to remove Russia from the United Nations Human Rights Council, and two voted against it. Long adhering to an independent foreign policy, ASEAN members have urged solving the crisis through negotiation and dialogue.</p> <p> Moreover, some ASEAN members have been well aware of Washington's unspoken calculations to turn bloody sufferings of others into golden opportunities for profits in the Russia-Ukraine conflict. For example, during his visit to China in early April, Thai Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Don Pramudwinai said he appreciates China's objective and fair position on the Ukraine issue, that "Asian countries should maintain peace and stability in the region, jointly resist unilateral sanctions and long-arm jurisdiction that have no basis in international law, and prevent attempts to create tensions and replicate crises in the region."</p> <p> Playing small clique politics and forcing others to take sides -- Washington's old tricks to gain geopolitical interests -- work against ASEAN's will to uphold regional peace and stability and to realize sustainable economic development. Launching trade wars and breaking pacts -- Washington's classical acts of unilateralism -- severely disrupt normal trade exchanges and supply chains in the region and deal a heavy blow to ASEAN's economy. All those wrongdoings have tarnished Washington's credit and influence as the world's sole superpower, and driven it further apart from ASEAN members.</p> <p> The long arc of history teaches each and every country that acting without scruples almost always results in the reverse of what one desires. It is time for Washington to learn this lesson, abandon its old dream of Cold War hegemony, uphold an open and inclusive mindset, and play its due role in maintaining regional and global peace, stability and development.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Parliamentary analysis on increased security as NATO member questioned in Sweden ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096640</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096640.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 09:49:33 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/66/2114264619436768198.png" /></p> <p> <em>Swedish Foreign Minister Ann Linde (6th L), Minister of Defense Peter Hultqvist (5th L) and other parliamentary party representatives present the result of a security analysis at a press conference in Stockholm, Sweden, on May 13, 2022. A security analysis presented by the Swedish parliament on Friday that says a NATO membership would increase security for the Nordic country was questioned by several parties ahead of Sweden's historic decision on whether to be a new member of the trans-Atlantic military bloc. (Ninni Andersson/Government Offices of Sweden/Handout via Xinhua)</em></p> <p> STOCKHOLM, May 13 (Xinhua) -- A security analysis presented by the Swedish parliament on Friday that says a NATO membership would increase security for the Nordic country was questioned by several parties ahead of Sweden's historic decision on whether to be a new member of the trans-Atlantic military bloc.</p> <p> The security analysis, which serves as an important basis for Sweden's upcoming NATO membership decisions, has been prepared by all eight parliamentary parties, of which, the Left Party and the Green Party, however, do not support the report's conclusions as a whole.</p> <p> Although the analysis listed a number of advantages of possible Swedish membership in NATO, with an "increased security" as the main conclusion, it does not provide a recommendation on whether Sweden should join.</p> <p> However, the analysis is widely understood to serve as an important basis for the ruling Social Democrats' and the government's NATO decision, to be presented on Sunday and Monday respectively.</p> <p> "The main conclusion of a possible membership in NATO is that Sweden would become part of NATO's collective security," said Foreign Minister Ann Linde at a press conference on Friday.</p> <p> While the analysis assesses that Sweden will not be exposed to a conventional military attack as a reaction to a possible Swedish NATO application, Linde said that "an armed attack on Sweden can not be ruled out."</p> <p> "We see a democratic decline in several countries today, even among countries that are members of NATO, which is not clearly mentioned. The Green Party's basic attitude towards NATO has not changed." Maria Ferm, member of the Green Party, told Swedish Television, emphasizing her party's opposition to joining NATO.</p> <p> "We have therefore submitted a special opinion about this issue and about this analysis, because we do not agree with all the wording about NATO this analysis contains," Ferm emphasized.</p> <p> "I think there is no analysis of the risks that a Swedish NATO membership entails." Hakan Svenneling, a member of the Left Party told Swedish Television, "We are making the biggest change in Swedish security policy in a very long time. And freedom of alliance has been very important and served Sweden well for a long time, and could do so for a long time to come."</p> <p> "I am worried that every major conflict for a long time to come, for decades, will take place at Sweden's borders or in Sweden. This is something I do not want to be a part of, which is why I oppose Swedish NATO membership," Svenneling said.&nbsp;</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/6/691044886501688306.png" /></p> <p> Swedish Foreign Minister Ann Linde (R) and Minister of Defense Peter Hultqvist attend a press conference on a security analysis in Stockholm, Sweden, on May 13, 2022. A security analysis presented by the Swedish parliament on Friday that says a NATO membership would increase security for the Nordic country was questioned by several parties ahead of Sweden's historic decision on whether to be a new member of the trans-Atlantic military bloc. (Ninni Andersson/Government Offices of Sweden/Handout via Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ US media: 1 million COVID-19 deaths the benchmark of an unprecedented American tragedy ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096589</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096589.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 17:26:33 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205131708000440648616903.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 4761px;" /></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Grief of 1 million COVID deaths in U.S. ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096587</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096587.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 17:26:29 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/57/2130585533815472553.jpg" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; width: 404px; height: 800px;" /></p> <p align="center" class="pictext"> <em>COVID-19 death toll in the U.S. surpassed 1 million.</em></p> <p> Five months into 2022, some 160,000 died of COVID-19 in the U.S.</p> <p> Washingtons failed COVID control policy continues to take toll on American life.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ U.S. summit won't sway ASEAN centrality, say analysts ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096467</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096467.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 15:26:04 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> KUALA LUMPUR, May 13 (Xinhua) -- U.S. President Joe Biden is meeting with leaders of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) at a summit in Washington this week, in a move widely seen as an attempt by the United States to pull members of the bloc into its camp.</p> <p> Analysts believe that U.S. attempts to court support among ASEAN leaders in pursuit of its geopolitical interests are unlikely to gain traction.</p> <p> ASEAN leaders are more likely to emphasize their economic interests, analysts have said, adding the bloc members, who are seeking a post-pandemic economic recovery, will put ASEAN centrality at the forefront while deflecting any attempt to draw them into a U.S. sphere of influence.</p> <p> The summit officially commemorates 45 years of U.S.-ASEAN ties. It was initially scheduled for late March but was postponed due to scheduling issues.</p> <p> Azmi Hassan, a senior research fellow at Nusantara Academy for Strategic Research, said Wednesday that the United States has been unable to exert pressure on ASEAN over the Russia-Ukraine conflict, with most of the 10-member bloc abstaining from voting in favor of a resolution to suspend Russia from the United Nations Human Rights Council (UNHRC) last month.</p> <p> "I think President Biden must be wondering why ASEAN nation did not outright condemn Russia and did not support it wholeheartedly. This can especially be seen during the resolution to remove Russia from the UNHRC on April 7: Malaysia, Singapore, Indonesia, Thailand, Cambodia and Brunei abstained while Vietnam and Laos voted against it," Hassan told Xinhua in a phone interview.</p> <p> He also said that the United States will find itself unable to make any headway among ASEAN members, especially after Malaysia and Indonesia voiced concerns over the AUKUS trilateral security partnership involving Australia and Britain.</p> <p> "Overall, despite the ideas of geopolitical maneuvering, I think the most important issue that will be discussed among the participants will be the economic side, how to spur the trade between ASEAN and the U.S. post-pandemic. I think that will be the most important subject matter from ASEAN point of view," he said.</p> <p> Lee Pei May, a political expert at the International Islamic University Malaysia, said that while the summit is happening against the backdrop of escalating tensions between Russia and Ukraine, the primary concern of the Biden administration is not about Russia but more about ensuring a so-called "free and open" Indo-Pacific.</p> <p> "For the Biden administration to advance this vision, they have to get ASEAN countries on the American side and potentially for the U.S. to play a role in managing the disputes in the South China Sea. Such moves can be interpreted as challenging China's position in the region and hindering peaceful progress between China and ASEAN countries," she said.</p> <p> "ASEAN members can already anticipate that the summit is ideal for the Biden administration to stress the common interests and shared values between the U.S. and the ASEAN countries. The U.S. is expected to leverage these ideas to draw ASEAN closer to them," she added.</p> <p> Lee cautioned that unless it can demonstrate unity, the ASEAN bloc may find itself in a position where different members pursue different paths, which could compromise its cohesiveness. This can be remedied by member states forging a consensus when dealing with the United States.</p> <p> "Having a consensus on key issues is not easy, but it is crucial as it would allow the members to speak with one united voice at the summit," Lee said. "The members can send a signal to the U.S. that ASEAN would remain neutral in whatever circumstances."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Facts about Russia-Ukraine conflict: Russia vows retaliation against Finland's potential NATO membership ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096434</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096434.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 15:02:33 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- The following are the latest developments in the conflict between Russia and Ukraine:</p> <p> The Russian Foreign Ministry said Thursday that Finland's possible accession to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) would force Moscow to take "military-technical" retaliatory measures.</p> <p> Russia has repeatedly noted that while it is up to Finland to decide which measures it will take to ensure its national security, it must also be aware of the consequences of its actions, the ministry said.</p> <p> "Finland's accession to NATO will seriously damage Russian-Finnish relations as well as stability and security in Northern Europe," it added.</p> <p> - - - -</p> <p> On Thursday, the Ukrainian parliament approved a presidential decree on seizing the assets of Russia's state-run Sberbank and the state development corporation VEB.RF, Unian news agency reported, citing lawmaker Yaroslav Zheleznyak.</p> <p> The presidential proposal on the seizure of the assets of Russian financial institutions was supported by 334 lawmakers in the 450-seat assembly, Zheleznyak said.</p> <p> - - - -</p> <p> By waging a proxy war with Russia in Ukraine, Western countries ultimately risk turning the current conflict into a full-fledged nuclear war, Deputy Chairman of the Russian Security Council Dmitry Medvedev said Thursday.</p> <p> NATO countries increase the risk of a direct and open conflict with Russia by pumping weapons into Ukraine, training Ukrainian troops using Western equipment, dispatching mercenaries and conducting exercises near Russia's borders, Medvedev wrote on his Telegram.</p> <p> - - - -</p> <p> Russian forces carried out a rocket attack on a major oil refinery in Kremenchuk town in Ukraine's central Poltava region on Thursday, said the head of Poltava regional military-civilian administration Dmytro Lunin.</p> <p> "Today's shelling of the Poltava region is perhaps the largest during the full-scale war," Lunin wrote on Telegram.</p> <p> Twelve rockets hit the infrastructure facilities in Kremenchuk, with most of them striking the oil refinery, Lunin said.</p> <p> The attack caused a fire at the oil refinery, Lunin said, adding there were no casualties in the shelling.</p> <p> - - - -</p> <p> Ukraine is negotiating with Russia over the evacuation of seriously injured soldiers from the Azovstal steel plant in Mariupol, Ukrainian Deputy Prime Minister Iryna Vereshchuk said on Thursday.</p> <p> Ukraine seeks to exchange 38 severely injured soldiers from Azovstal for the captured Russian military, Vereshchuk wrote on Telegram.</p> <p> Currently, there are no talks on exchanging several hundred people, as reported by some media outlets, Vereshchuk said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 70 percent of Americans view inflation as "very big problem:" survey ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096376</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096376.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 13:47:32 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> WASHINGTON, May 12 (Xinhua) -- The U.S. public views inflation as the top problem facing the nation, with 70 percent of Americans viewing inflation as a "very big problem," according to a Pew Research Center survey released Thursday.</p> <p> Republicans and Democrats differ over what they see as major national problems.</p> <p> Inflation is the "top concern among Republicans and Republican-leaning independents," with 84 percent calling it a very big problem. A narrower majority of Democrats and Democratic leaners (57 percent) view inflation the same way.</p> <p> "Our goal, of course, is to get inflation back down to 2 percent without having the economy go into recession, or, to put it this way, with the labor market remaining fairly strong," U.S. Federal Reserve chairman Jerome Powell, whose second term was confirmed by the Senate Thursday, said in an interview with Marketplace.</p> <p> "I think it's a very challenging environment to make monetary policy," said Powell, noting that the central bank is "struggling" to restore price stability.</p> <p> The Pew Research Center survey showed that other big problems include affordability of health care (55 percent), violent crime (54 percent), gun violence (51 percent) and the federal budget deficit (51 percent).</p> <p> The survey noted that more than two years into the COVID-19 pandemic, just 19 percent of Americans rate the coronavirus outbreak as a very big problem for the country, the lowest share out of 12 issues included in the survey. In June 2020, in the early stages of the outbreak, 58 percent rated it as a very big problem, placing it among the top concerns at the time.</p> <p> The survey was conducted from April 25 to May 1 among 5,074 adults.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Flags ordered at half staff as U.S. nears 1 mln COVID-19 deaths ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096379</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096379.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 13:47:32 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/54/2940040028944866706.jpg" /></p> <p> U.S. national flag flies at half-staff near the Statue of Liberty to mourn 1 million American lives lost to COVID-19, New York, U.S. May 12, 2022. U.S. President Joe Biden ordered U.S. flags to be flown at half-staff to mark the tragic milestone of 1 million COVID-19 deaths for five days. (Photo: China News Service/Liao Pan)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/88/15219768223718661964.jpg" /></p> <p> U.S. national flag flies at half-staff at the Times Square to mourn 1 million American lives lost to COVID-19, New York, U.S. May 12, 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Liao Pan)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Ecns.cn</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Int'l visitors reach two year high as tourists pour back into Australia ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096355</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096355.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 12:44:45 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> SYDNEY, May 13 (Xinhua) -- With borders opening, Australia's reeling tourism industry has begun to see its first influx of international tourists in over two years.</p> <p> Managing director of the Australian Tourism Export Council (ATEC), Australia's peak tourism body, Peter Shelley said on Friday that a long period of uncertainty was beginning to come to an end.</p> <p> Australia's export tourism industry has endured two years of debilitating conditions where many businesses simply had no income or vision on when it would end, Shelley said.</p> <p> According to data released by Australian Bureau of Statistics (ABS) on Thursday, Australia's international visitors had reached their highest levels since February of 2020, when an estimated 647,000 international travelers arrived in Australia before its borders were shut in March.</p> <p> In April this year, 575,530 visitors arrived in Australia, 200,000 more visitors than the previous month.</p> <p> As a result, the pandemic has all but decimated Australia's 45 billion Australian dollars (about 31 billion U.S. dollars) export tourism industry, however, the ATEC said that government and industry would need to play an active role in its recovery.</p> <p> "Now we have our borders open we are seeing the green shoots of recovery and with export tourism businesses looking to rebuild their markets, this (is) an important time for government focus on investing in getting the industry back on its feet," said Shelley.</p> <p> The ATEC launched a tourism campaign dubbed "its time for tourism," which called for greater funding for peak tourism marketing body, Tourism Australia, and greater training for workers in the tourism industry.</p> <p> "While we rebuild our industry we also have the opportunity to innovate and improve business practices, support a more sustainable industry and create a tourism industry of the future," said Shelley.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ DPRK leader calls for quick action to contain COVID-19 ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096353</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096353.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 11:56:14 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> PYONGYANG, May 13 (Xinhua) -- Kim Jong Un, top leader of the Democratic People's Republic of Korea (DPRK), on Thursday called for quick action to contain the spread of COVID-19, when visiting the state emergency epidemic prevention headquarters, the official Korean Central News Agency reported.</p> <p> Kim examined the epidemic prevention situation "after the state epidemic prevention work was switched over to the maximum emergency epidemic prevention system," and learned about the nationwide spread of COVID-19, said the report.</p> <p> A fever whose cause couldn't be identified explosively spread nationwide from late April, and more than 350,000 people got fever "in a short span of time" and at least 162,200 of them recovered completely.</p> <p> On Thursday alone, some 18,000 persons with fever occurred nationwide. So far, up to 187,800 people are being isolated and treated, with six dead (one of them tested positive for the BA.2 sub-variant of Omicron), it said.</p> <p> "The simultaneous spread of fever with the capital area as a centre shows that there is a vulnerable point in the epidemic prevention system we have already established," Kim was quoted as saying.</p> <p> "It is the most important challenge and supreme tasks facing our Party to reverse the immediate public health crisis situation at an early date, restore the stability of epidemic prevention and protect the health and wellbeing of our people," he said.</p> <p> The official news agency reported Thursday that samples taken from patients with fever in Pyongyang on Sunday were "consistent with" the virus' highly transmissible Omicron variant.</p> <p> The DPRK has taken strict measures to ward off the virus by closing its borders soon after the outbreak of the pandemic, and had not confirmed a single case until Thursday.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Feature: African Americans reflect on disproportionate impact from "surreal" COVID-19 pandemic ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096224</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096224.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:16:39 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> WASHINGTON, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Greg Powers had never expected to see a major public health crisis, like the COVID-19 pandemic, in his lifetime. "It's just absolutely mind-boggling," he told Xinhua when describing his feeling of living through it. "It's surreal."</p> <p> The once-in-a-century pandemic has unimaginably claimed 1 million lives out of more than 82 million infections in the United States over the past two years or so, and changed the nation -- and the rest of the world -- in ways big and small.</p> <p> For Powers, an African American audio engineer who lives with his family in Arlington County, Virginia, on the East Coast, there has been no shortage of challenges because most of his assignments need to be worked on in studios -- forcing him to travel between home and workplace, which expose him to greater risks of catching the virus.</p> <p> To protect himself and also those around him, Powers masks up wherever he goes, although most Americans are no longer required to cover their faces indoors in public areas.</p> <p> Besides, in the first year of the pandemic, Powers wore gloves every single day at work when touching his equipment. He and his wife also chose to go to the pharmacy or grocery store late at night or very early in the morning to avoid contact with the crowd as much as possible.</p> <p> "I'm not catching COVID though it's still out there," Powers said of his precaution. "I don't really have any physical ailments ... I have loved ones who have it. So it's a situation where I want to be as safe as possible, and I'll keep my family safe."</p> <p> Powers, who has been fully vaccinated and received a booster shot, said the fact that there has been an obvious hesitancy among the African American community toward the vaccines is partly due to Washington's notorious record of using them to conduct medical experiments.</p> <p> Powers particularly referred to the infamous "Tuskegee Experiment" that began in 1932, in which hundreds of African Americans were recruited by doctors from the U.S. Public Health Service for a study to track the full progression of syphilis without effective care. In 1997, the White House issued a formal presidential apology for the study which was terminated in the 1970s. "They basically used people as Guinea pigs," Powers deplored. "There's a lot of distrust."</p> <p> Though Powers said he believes most African Americans "have gotten beyond that" and tried to be vaccinated in this pandemic, he would still feel "relatively safe" if he could see "a whole bunch of different people from different races and cultures" in the line for a vaccination.</p> <p> The vaccine hesitancy, along with an unequal distribution of healthcare and other resources, has contributed to the pandemic's disproportionate impact on African Americans who are more likely to suffer from preexisting medical conditions like obesity and diabetes, and who work as "essential workers" but are less likely to be insured than white people in the nation.</p> <p> In Washington, D.C., located just across the Potomac River from Arlington County, African Americans account for roughly half of the population, but nearly four in five COVID-19-related deaths in the U.S. capital. In the first few months of the U.S. vaccine rollout, African Americans received shots at a much lower rate than their white peers.</p> <p> "Well, racial inequality was baked into the recipe of the creation of the United States of America," Rashawn Ray, a senior fellow at Brookings Institution, wrote in an analysis published in April 2020.</p> <p> "Inequities in neighborhood resources and the healthcare system are manifestations of this recipe," warned Ray, also an African American. "And, when crises like the COVID-19 pandemic occur, inequalities are exacerbated rather than diminished."</p> <p> The disparities are even more pronounced in some suburban areas of the country. Bree Hartfield, born and reared in Beaumont, Mississippi, told Xinhua that there is only "a nurse practitioner but no doctor on staff" in the small town where she has seen "a lot of deaths, a lot of tragedies" throughout the pandemic.</p> <p> "African Americans do succumb to illnesses in a different way because of the lack of resources, the lack of opportunities to get the resources," Hartfield noted, attributing the phenomenon to "inequitable resources" and a lack of good leadership. "So equitable resources are what we would need to implement, especially into the small towns where I think money doesn't reach," she said.</p> <p> The pandemic has already taken a backseat in the United States to soaring inflation and the Ukraine crisis, as states and cities have lifted anti-pandemic restrictions. But Powers continues to see it as an issue "in the forefront" for him and "a tough situation," because "there are still people who are testing positive."</p> <p> U.S. President Joe Biden ordered flags at half-staff on Thursday to commemorate the deaths of 1 million Americans who lost their lives to COVID-19.</p> <p> "Today, we mark a tragic milestone: one million American lives lost to COVID-19," Biden said in a statement. "One million empty chairs around the dinner table. Each an irreplaceable loss. Each leaving behind a family, a community, and a nation forever changed because of this pandemic."</p> <p> COVID-19 cases and hospitalizations are on the rise in the United States, with new related deaths projected to resurge in coming weeks, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). "We are still in the middle of a pandemic, to be sure -- there's no confusion about that," top U.S. infectious disease expert and White House chief medical advisor Anthony Fauci has recently said.</p> <p> "COVID didn't have to kill most who died from it," former U.S. CDC Director and epidemiologist Tom Frieden tweeted on Thursday. "At least half of U.S. COVID deaths in 2020 were preventable through better public health action, and more than half of 2021 deaths were preventable through improved vaccination. We can save lives by taking reasonable precautions."</p> <p> Speaking of the nation's loss of more than 1 million lives to the pandemic, Hartfield said it is "an astronomical number" and that "it is terrible."</p> <p> "I do wish all the blessings for those families," she added. "But I just think this is an opportunity to reflect on the things that we could do better as a country."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ S.Korea says DPRK fires 3 short-range ballistic missiles into eastern waters ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096180</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096180.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:07:37 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> SEOUL, May 12 (Xinhua) -- The Democratic People's Republic of Korea (DPRK) fired three short-range ballistic missiles into its eastern waters, South Korea's Joint Chiefs of Staff (JCS) said Thursday.</p> <p> The JCS said in a statement that it detected the missiles, which were launched into the eastern waters from the Sunan area in Pyongyang at about 6:29 p.m. local time (0929 GMT).</p> <p> The JCS noted that South Korea was maintaining a full readiness posture in close cooperation with the United States while strengthening surveillance and vigilance.</p> <p> The DPRK testfire came five days after South Korea said the DPRK launched one short-range ballistic missile, presumed to be a submarine-launched ballistic missile (SLBM), off its east coast.</p> <p> The DPRK has launched projectiles 16 times this year, saying it test-fired a new type intercontinental ballistic missile (ICBM), Hwasongpho-17, on March 24.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ UN Security Council renews mandate of peacekeeping force in Abyei ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096138</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096138.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:24:35 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> UNITED NATIONS, May 12 (Xinhua) -- The UN Security Council on Thursday renewed the mandate of the UN peacekeeping force in Abyei, a territory contested by Sudan and South Sudan, by six months, till Nov.15, 2022.</p> <p> Resolution 2630, which won the unanimous support of the 15 members of the Security Council, also decides to extend the peacekeeping mission's mandate modification till Nov. 15, 2022.</p> <p> The Security Council first modified the mandate of the UN Interim Security Force for Abyei (UNISFA) in December 2011 to add tasks of supporting a Joint Border Verification and Monitoring Mechanism of Sudan and South Sudan, which gained independence from the former in July 2011.</p> <p> Resolution 2630 decides that UNISFA should maintain the authorized troop ceiling at 3,250 and the authorized police ceiling at 640.</p> <p> It urges the governments of Sudan and South Sudan to provide full support for UNISFA in the implementation of its mandate and deployment of UNISFA personnel. It reiterates that Abyei shall be demilitarized from any forces, as well as armed elements of the local communities, other than UNISFA and the Abyei Police Service.</p> <p> UNISFA was set up by the Security Council in June 2011 after a flare-up shortly before South Sudan's independence.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ EU to open "solidarity lanes" to help Ukraine's grain exports ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096132</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096132.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:17:02 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BRUSSELS, May 12 (Xinhua) -- The European Commission on Thursday proposed to establish new so-called "solidarity lanes" to ensure that Ukraine can export grain to the European Union (EU) and also import the goods it needs, from humanitarian aid to animal feed and fertilizers, as Ukraine's ports have been blocked due to Russia-Ukraine.</p> <p> Ukraine's inability to export its agricultural produce through Black Sea ports because of the blockade is threatening global food security and has prompted the development of an action plan to overcome this hurdle, the Commission said in a statement.</p> <p> Under normal circumstances, Ukraine exports 75 percent of the grain it produces, generating around 20 percent of its annual export revenues. Before the conflict, Ukraine's Black Sea ports handled 90 percent of its grain and oilseed exports.</p> <p> "Twenty million tonnes of grains have to leave Ukraine in less than three months using the EU infrastructure," Transport Commissioner Adina Valean said in a statement. "This is a gigantesque challenge, so it is essential to coordinate and optimize the logistic chains, put in place new routes and avoid, as much as possible, the bottlenecks."</p> <p> The Commission said that in spite of immediate efforts by the EU and its member states to ease border crossings between Ukraine and the EU, thousands of wagons and lorries are waiting for clearance on the Ukrainian side. The average current waiting time for wagons is 16 days, while it is up to 30 days at some borders. More grain is still stored and held back in Ukrainian silos ready for export.</p> <p> Among the challenges are differing rail gauge widths since the wagons used in Ukraine are not compatible with most of the EU rail network, so most goods need to be transhipped to lorries or wagons that fit the EU standard gauge.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Hospital labor expenses surge in U.S. during pandemic ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096127</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096127.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:06:36 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> LOS ANGELES, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Hospital labor expenses have increased by more than one-third from pre-pandemic levels in the United States, according to a new report.</p> <p> The report, released by U.S. healthcare consultancy company Kaufman Hall on Wednesday, noted that a nationwide shortage of healthcare workers made worse by the pandemic, and hospital and health systems' increased reliance on contract labor, is driving expenses upward and contributing to steep declines in profit margins.</p> <p> During the pandemic, almost one in five healthcare workers quit their jobs. One-third of nurses plan to leave their current roles by the end of 2022, with more than a quarter of those intending to become traveling nurses, according to the report, titled "The Financial Effects of Hospital Workforce Dislocation: A Special Workforce Edition of the National Hospital Flash Report."</p> <p> Contract labor as a percentage of total labor expenses increased more than five times the rate from pre-pandemic levels, said the report.</p> <p> Pre-pandemic, wage rates for contract nurses were almost double those for employed nurses. As the pandemic continued and labor shortages intensified, that wage gap increased significantly. As of March 2022, the median wage rate for contract nurses had risen to more than three times that of employed nurses, the report added.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ COVID-19 death toll in Europe tops 2 mln: WHO ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096124</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096124.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:05:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> COPENHAGEN, May 12 (Xinhua) -- The number of confirmed COVID-19 deaths has exceeded two million in Europe, the World Health Organization (WHO) Regional Office for Europe said on Thursday.</p> <p> The cumulative number of confirmed COVID-19 cases in the region has surpassed 218 million, and 2,003,081 COVID-19-related deaths have been reported.</p> <p> "While this number is devastating, it represents a fraction of the overall deaths directly and indirectly associated with COVID-19, as the WHO's report on excess mortality during the pandemic has shown," the office said in a statement.</p> <p> It noted that although the number of new infections is decreasing in the region, COVID-19 remains a lethal virus, particularly for unvaccinated and clinically vulnerable individuals.</p> <p> WHO Europe urged the broad public to take immediate and long-term action on multiple fronts.</p> <p> "These include protecting the most vulnerable, continuing to monitor the virus and its spread, keeping health systems ready for any developments of the pandemic, and tackling its long-term impacts," it said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Wealthy Americans buying second passports, citing pandemic, climate change, political turmoil: report ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096123</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096123.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:03:56 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NEW YORK, May 12 (Xinhua) -- The number of wealthy Americans applying for citizenship or residency in foreign countries has skyrocketed over the past three years as U.S. billionaires, tech entrepreneurs and celebrities look to create a "plan B" for their families, reported major news portal Insider last week, based on interviews with multiple investment migration firms.</p> <p> Latitude Residency &amp; Citizenship, a company which guides high-net-worth investors around the world through the application process, was quoted as saying that U.S. inquiries have increased 300 percent between 2019 and 2021.</p> <p> Henley &amp; Partners, one of the world's largest citizenship brokers, said sales to American nationals increased by 327 percent between 2019 and 2020 and an additional 10 percent in 2021.</p> <p> According to Dominic Volek, head of private clients at Henley &amp; Partners, there are "four C's" currently driving the investor citizenship industry: COVID-19, climate change, cryptocurrency, and conflict. The recent uptick in American applicants started during the Trump administration and escalated during pandemic lockdowns, he said.</p> <p> "In the very strict lockdowns there was a point where if you only had an American passport, you could not enter Europe," said Volek. "I think that made a lot of particularly ultra high net worth individuals realize that they're potentially a little bit more fragile than they thought."</p> <p> More than a dozen countries offer so-called "golden passports" and visas that allow affluent foreigners to receive citizenship or residency in exchange for investing in the country. The most expensive programs range from 1.1 million U.S. dollars in Malta to 9.5 million dollars in Austria, the Insider report said, citing Forbes.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
	</channel>
</rss>