<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title> China_Military </title>
		<image>
			<title>People's Daily Online</title>
			<link>http://english.people.com.cn/</link>
			<url>http://english.people.com.cn/images/en/top_logo_e.gif</url>
		</image>
		<description>People's Daily Online</description>
		<link>http://english.people.com.cn/90786</link>
		<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Choppers conduct high-intensity flight training ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095651</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095651.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:55:59 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121031000530249334254.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> Two pilots assigned to an aviation brigade under the PLA 81st Group Army inspect the helicopter prior to taking off during a round-the-clock flight training exercise on April 20, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Peng Bingjie)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121032000237329266514.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> Helicopters of different types attached to an aviation brigade under the PLA 81st Group Army take off in an orderly manner to participate in a round-the-clock flight training exercise on April 20, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Luan Cheng)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121032000453883109988.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 554px;" /></p> <p> Helicopters of different types attached to an aviation brigade under the PLA 81st Group Army fly in formation during a round-the-clock flight training exercise on April 20, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Luan Cheng)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121033000109520267818.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> A helicopter attached to an aviation brigade under the PLA 81st Group Army conducts nighttime flight training during a round-the-clock flight training exercise on April 20, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Luan Cheng)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Military Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Naval submarine flotilla conducts combat training exercise ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094654</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094654.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 14:44:31 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0510/FOREIGN202205101439000276489899183.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 678px;" /></p> <p> Two towboats attached to a submarine flotilla with the navy under the PLA Northern Theater Command jointly tow a submarine off a port during a maritime combat training exercise on April 19, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Shi Jialong)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0510/FOREIGN202205101439000526438685242.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 670px;" /></p> <p> A submarine attached to a submarine flotilla with the navy under the PLA Northern Theater Command is ready to set sail for the maritime combat training exercise on April 19, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Shi Jialong)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0510/FOREIGN202205101440000118538153963.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 676px;" /></p> <p> A submarine attached to a submarine flotilla with the navy under the PLA Northern Theater Command steams at full speed during a maritime combat training exercise on April 19, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Shi Jialong)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Military Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ In pics: Firefighter training drills in the flame in SW China's Tibet ]]></title>
	<news_id>10093959</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0509/c90000-10093959.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 11:22:38 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> A fire brigade in southwest China's Tibet Autonomous Region has organized a firefighting training drill under real fire scenes, which aims to improve firefighters' abilities in training and work.</p> <p> The trainees were divided into combat groups based on their experience, mastery of the strategies and physical capabilities. The groups then conduct practice drills. During the training period, the trainees are fully committed to the operation and behave in strict accordance with requirements and regulations.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ PLA encircles Taiwan island with carrier drills amid US, Japanese provocations ]]></title>
	<news_id>10093853</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0509/c90000-10093853.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 09:06:17 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="A naval formation consisting of aircraft carrier Liaoning has conducted take-off and landing drills in the South China Sea on Jan. 1, 2017. The formation, which is on a cross-sea area training exercise, involved J-15 fighter jets, as well as several ship-borne helicopters. Photo: Navy.81.cn" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220509/97/18436211811918612249.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>A naval formation consisting of aircraft carrier Liaoning has conducted take-off and landing drills in the South China Sea on Jan. 1, 2017. The formation, which is on a "cross-sea area" training exercise, involved J-15 fighter jets, as well as several ship-borne helicopters. Photo: Navy.81.cn</em></p> <p> Starting a routine, realistic combat training mission in the West Pacific about a week ago, the Liaoningaircraft carrier group of the Chinese People's Liberation Army (PLA) Navy has reportedly been practicing intensively over the past few days in the Philippine Sea to the east of the island of Taiwan and south of Japan, a location that experts said is a vital place to stop potential external interference in event of a reunification-by-force operation in the Taiwan Straits.</p> <p> With the carrier group to Taiwan's east, the PLA also reportedly dispatched an increased number of different types of warplanes and additional warships from the Chinese mainland west of the island of Taiwan, effectively surrounding and enclosing the island under the watch of US and Japanese aircraft carriers, which are serving as "perfect practice partners" for the PLA drills, analysts said.</p> <p> After reporting a PLA Navy flotilla, consisting of the aircraft carrier Liaoning, a Type 055 large destroyer, three Type 052D destroyers, a Type 052C destroyer, a Type 054A frigate and a Type 901 comprehensive supply ship, sailed from the East China Sea through the Miyako Strait to the Pacific Ocean on May 2, Japan's Ministry of Defense Joint Staff released monitoring reports for five consecutive days from Wednesday to Sunday. It said the carrier group conducted intensive, cross-day-and-night carrier-based aircraft training with live munitions in the Philippine Sea east of the island of Taiwan and south of Japan from Tuesday to Saturday.</p> <p> The Liaoningcarrier group was sailing slowly closer to the island of Taiwan as its drills went on, the Japanese releases show.</p> <p> The Philippine Sea where the Liaoningcarrier group is holding drills is a vital sea region should a reunification-by-force operation take place, Shi Hong, executive chief editor of Chinese mainland magazine Shipborne Weapons, told the Global Times on Sunday.</p> <p> By moving in tandem with aerial and maritime forces from the Chinese mainland, the carrier group could completely cut off the routes foreign forces may take if they militarily interfere with the Taiwan question, and this will bring significant advantages to the PLA, Shi said.</p> <p> Just as the Liaoningcarrier group was practicing to the east of Taiwan, Taiwan's defense authority reported significant increases of PLA warplane activities to the island's southwest and southeast in terms of both aircraft types and sortie numbers from Thursday to Sunday.</p> <p> A total of 31 PLA aircraft sorties featuring H-6 bombers, J-11 and J-16 fighter jets, KJ-500 early warning aircraft, Y-8 anti-submarine warfare aircraft and electronic warfare aircraft, as well as Ka-28 anti-submarine warfare helicopters were spotted by Taiwan's defense authority during those days.</p> <p> Since the Ka-28 is a vessel-based helicopter, it is almost certain that there were PLA warships sailing to the west of the island of Taiwan in addition to the Liaoningcarrier group in the east, observers said.</p> <p> By featuring many powerful vessels, the Liaoningcarrier group is already mighty by itself. It is possible that the carrier group and the forces from the mainland were having a joint exercise, testing different combinations of forces, practicing and enhancing all kinds of tactics, Shi said.</p> <p> PLA aircraft and vessels are not alone in the Philippine Sea, as Japanese and US forces are also present in the region.</p> <p> Japan's Ministry of Defense Joint Staff said that the Japan Maritime Self-Defense Force dispatched the Izumo, a de facto aircraft carrier, to monitor the PLA carrier group. According to the Fleet and Marine Tracker by the news website of the US Naval Institute, US Navy's Abraham Lincolncarrier strike group was also operating in the Philippine Sea at least as of May 2.</p> <p> They are the most realistic practice partners for the PLA, because they could be the real opponents the PLA one day might have to face in the region, Shi said, noting that their presence could serve as excellent grindstones that can help enhance the combat capabilities of the Liaoningcarrier group.</p> <p> While Senior Captain Gao Xiucheng, a spokesperson of the PLA Navy, said on Tuesday that the Liaoningcarrier group's drills are not targeted at another party, it is always one of the PLA's greatest goals to liberate Taiwan and achieve national reunification, and all secessionists and external interferences are by default potential targets of the PLA, a Beijing-based military expert told the Global Times, requesting anonymity.</p> <p> With some of the most influential Japanese politicians making wrong remarks on the Taiwan question recently, claiming that "Taiwan's concerns are Japan's concerns," and that "Ukraine may be East Asia tomorrow," and with US House Speaker Nancy Pelosi only "postponing" her visit to Taiwan after her alleged COVID-19 infection, it is important that the PLA releases a powerful deterrent with the drills and pragmatically enhances its combat capabilities, the expert said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Israel celebrates 74th Independence Day ]]></title>
	<news_id>10092780</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0506/c90000-10092780.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 09:44:56 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220506/31/14795060649477167159.png" /></p> <p> <em>Israeli President Isaac Herzog (R, front) and Prime Minister Naftali Bennett (L, front) attend an event for the distinguished service of soldiers during Israel's 74th Independence Day celebrations in Jerusalem, on May 5, 2022. Israelis joined a slew of national celebrations to mark the country's 74th Independence Day. (JINI via Xinhua)</em></p> <p> JERUSALEM, May 5 (Xinhua) -- Israelis joined a slew of national celebrations to mark the country's 74th Independence Day.</p> <p> This year's Independent Day began on Wednesday evening and will last till Thursday evening.</p> <p> A ceremony was held at Jerusalem's Mount Herzl, Israel's national cemetery, on Wednesday evening, during which, Mickey Levy, the country's parliament speaker, delivered a keynote speech and called for national unity.</p> <p> "I believe that we can succeed every day to choose to see the good in each other... to choose togetherness over divisions, to coexist," he said.</p> <p> On Thursday morning, official celebrations started at President Isaac Herzog's official residence in Jerusalem, with the delivery of citations for the distinguished service of soldiers.</p> <p> As singers and artists performed on stages across the country all through the night, hundreds of thousands of Israelis celebrated the national festival on the beaches or parks, waving flags and making barbecues.</p> <p> Israel declared independence on May 14, 1948, though it marks Independence Day on different dates every year based on the Hebrew calendar.</p> <p> In the Hebrew calendar, days begin in the evening, so Independence Day is observed from nightfall until the following evening of the designated day.</p> <p> Hundreds of thousands of Palestinians, who lived in this region, became refugees in the ensuing battles. The Palestinians who stayed became Israeli citizens and make up about 20 percent of Israel's 9.5 million population.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220506/99/13917080695023777775.png" /></p> <p> Israeli Air Force aircraft perform during an air show celebrating Israel's 74th Independence Day in Tel Aviv, Israel, on May 5, 2022. Israelis joined a slew of national celebrations to mark the country's 74th Independence Day. This year's Independent Day began on Wednesday evening and will last till Thursday evening. (Xinhua/Shang Hao)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220506/71/12602588828865250599.png" /></p> <p> Israeli Air Force aircraft perform during an air show celebrating Israel's 74th Independence Day in Tel Aviv, Israel, on May 5, 2022. Israelis joined a slew of national celebrations to mark the country's 74th Independence Day. This year's Independent Day began on Wednesday evening and will last till Thursday evening. (Gideon Markowicz/JINI via Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220506/1/14451389329090121385.png" /></p> <p> People wait for an air show celebrating Israel's 74th Independence Day on a beach in Tel Aviv, Israel, on May 5, 2022. Israelis joined a slew of national celebrations to mark the country's 74th Independence Day. This year's Independent Day began on Wednesday evening and will last till Thursday evening. (Gideon Markowicz/JINI via Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220506/15/4590078874295332743.png" /></p> <p> People watch an air show celebrating Israel's 74th Independence Day on a beach in Tel Aviv, Israel, on May 5, 2022. Israelis joined a slew of national celebrations to mark the country's 74th Independence Day. This year's Independent Day began on Wednesday evening and will last till Thursday evening. (Xinhua/Wang Zhuolun)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220506/88/5911130393748976812.png" /></p> <p> Israeli Air Force aircraft perform during an air show celebrating Israel's 74th Independence Day in Tel Aviv, Israel, on May 5, 2022. Israelis joined a slew of national celebrations to mark the country's 74th Independence Day. This year's Independent Day began on Wednesday evening and will last till Thursday evening. (Xinhua/Shang Hao)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220506/52/4696409489207343376.png" /></p> <p> Israeli President Isaac Herzog (R, front) speaks at an event for the distinguished service of soldiers during Israel's 74th Independence Day celebrations in Jerusalem, on May 5, 2022. Israelis joined a slew of national celebrations to mark the country's 74th Independence Day. (JINI via Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220506/35/18019627452741854103.png" /></p> <p> Israeli Prime Minister Naftali Bennett (C, front) speaks at an event for the distinguished service of soldiers during Israel's 74th Independence Day celebrations in Jerusalem, on May 5, 2022. Israelis joined a slew of national celebrations to mark the country's 74th Independence Day. (JINI via Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Air force unit conducts flight training ]]></title>
	<news_id>10092438</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0505/c90000-10092438.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 13:20:34 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0505/FOREIGN202205051314000218152288824.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> A fighter jet attached to an air force aviation unit under the PLA Southern Theatre Command takes off in an around-the-clock flight training exercise on April 18, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Huang Rongkai)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0505/FOREIGN202205051314000447359970457.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 525px;" /></p> <p> A fighter jet attached to an air force aviation unit under the PLA Southern Theatre Command lifts itself up in an around-the-clock flight training exercise on April 18, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Huang Rongkai)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0505/FOREIGN202205051315000102296465988.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> A fighter jet attached to an air force aviation unit under the PLA Southern Theatre Command soars to the sky in an around-the-clock flight training exercise at an air force base on April 18, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Huang Rongkai)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Military Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ S. Korea, U.S. to begin two-week combined air drills next week: Yonhap ]]></title>
	<news_id>10091928</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0503/c90000-10091928.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 15:54:31 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> The Republic of Korea (ROK) and the United States are set to begin two weeks of combined air drills next week, Yonhap reported on Tuesday.</p> <p> The allies are set to begin the two-week Korea Flying Training on Monday, May 9, the eve of the inauguration of President-elect Yoon Suk-yeol, who has vowed to bolster the Seoul-Washington security alliance under his slogan of "peace through strength."</p> <p> "The two air forces plan to begin the two-week training on the same scale as the past trainings," said Yonhap, citing an anonymous source.</p> <p> The ROK and the United States regularly stage military exercises, mainly in the spring and summer. However, the Democratic People's Republic of Korea has repeatedly expressed vehement opposition to joint drills, denouncing them as rehearsals for invasion.</p> <p> The combined forces of the ROK and the U.S. kicked off preliminary military drills last month ahead of the joint springtime military exercise.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: CGTN</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ In pics: training of Israeli air force aerobatic team ]]></title>
	<news_id>10091687</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0502/c90000-10091687.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 09:45:07 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/40/14962146106775831508.png" /></p> <p> Israeli air force aerobatic team flies during a training for the upcoming Independence Day celebrations in Tel Aviv, Israel, on May 1, 2022. (Tomer Neuberg/JINI via Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/52/13465684507697934988.png" /></p> <p> Israeli air force aerobatic team flies during a training for the upcoming Independence Day celebrations in Tel Aviv, Israel, on May 1, 2022. (Tomer Neuberg/JINI via Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/14/13209647139384493934.png" /></p> <p> Israeli air force aerobatic team flies during a training for the upcoming Independence Day celebrations in Tel Aviv, Israel, on May 1, 2022. (Tomer Neuberg/JINI via Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/48/1337554940576499340.png" /></p> <p> Israeli air force aerobatic team flies during a training for the upcoming Independence Day celebrations in Tel Aviv, Israel, on May 1, 2022. (Tomer Neuberg/JINI via Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/60/1530879250189209456.png" /></p> <p> Israeli air force aerobatic team flies during a training for the upcoming Independence Day celebrations in Tel Aviv, Israel, on May 1, 2022. (Tomer Neuberg/JINI via Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220502/22/13311486956955979218.png" /></p> <p> Israeli air force aerobatic team flies during a training for the upcoming Independence Day celebrations in Tel Aviv, Israel, on May 1, 2022. (Tomer Neuberg/JINI via Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China denounces "military threat" statement from Australia ]]></title>
	<news_id>10090966</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0429/c90000-10090966.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 09:54:05 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, April 28 (Xinhua) -- A Chinese defense spokesperson on Thursday urged some Australian politicians to correct their "China threat" ideology and avoid further damage to China-Australia military relations.</p> <p> Regarding the development of another country as a security threat, some people in Australia have created and spread groundless fear, said Tan Kefei, spokesperson for the Ministry of National Defense, at a regular press conference in response to recent statements from some Australian politicians.</p> <p> "Their actions will not only undermine regional security and stability, but also compromise their own images as well," Tan said.</p> <p> The military cooperation among the United States, Britain and Australia in highly sensitive fields such as nuclear submarines and hypersonic missiles, will aggravate confrontation and challenge peace and stability in the Asia-Pacific region, Tan said.</p> <p> "China has serious concerns about this," he said, reiterating that the country always upholds the path of peaceful development and adopts a defense policy that is defensive in nature.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Spokesperson blasts U.S. maritime bullying ]]></title>
	<news_id>10090965</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0429/c90000-10090965.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 09:53:58 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, April 28 (Xinhua) -- A Chinese military spokesperson on Thursday voiced resolute opposition to maritime bullying of the United States.</p> <p> Tan Kefei, a spokesperson of China's Ministry of National Defense, made the remarks at a regular press conference in response to an inquiry related to a recent report of the U.S. defense department on "freedom of navigation."</p> <p> Under the pretext of "freedom of navigation," the United States has been frequently sending military vessels and aircraft to violate other countries' sovereignty and endanger regional peace, said Tan, calling on relevant nations to jointly oppose such maritime bullying.</p> <p> Noting that the so-called "freedom of navigation operations" of the United States challenges the international order based on international law, continuously threatening navigation safety and escalating regional tensions, Tan asked the United States to reflect on the number of collisions and casualties caused by such operations.</p> <p> He also urged the United States to stop its so-called "freedom of navigation operations" and stop issuing such irresponsible reports. The United States should do more to contribute to regional peace and stability, Tan said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China, Oman vow to promote strategic partnership, military cooperation ]]></title>
	<news_id>10090908</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0429/c90000-10090908.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 09:40:35 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> MUSCAT, April 28 (Xinhua) -- Senior officials from China and Oman pledged on Thursday to further promote their strategic partnership and boost military cooperation.</p> <p> They made the pledge during a meeting between Omani Deputy Prime Minister for Defense Affairs Sayyid Shihab bin Tarik Al Said and visiting Chinese State Councilor and Minister of National Defense Wei Fenghe in Muscat, capital of Oman.</p> <p> Noting that Oman and China enjoy a long history of friendly exchanges, Shihab bin Tarik hailed the fruitful results of the Oman-China cooperation achieved in recent years in economy, trade, energy and other areas, adding that he believed that Wei's visit would further promote the bilateral strategic partnership.</p> <p> Oman, which pursues a foreign policy of developing friendly relations with all countries and is keenly aware of the complex factors behind many hotspot issues in the region, expected China to play a bigger role in regional and international affairs, the Omani official said.</p> <p> He lauded the two militaries for having carried out practical cooperation in equipment and personnel training in recent years, while calling for expanding the areas of cooperation so as to further push forward the bilateral military ties.</p> <p> For his part, the Chinese defense minister said that China is Oman's sole strategic partner, which fully demonstrates the uniqueness of the China-Oman relations.</p> <p> Under the guidance and care of their heads of state, China and Oman have witnessed a continuous and in-depth development in their bilateral relations, said Wei, while highlighting China's support for Oman in safeguarding national sovereignty, independence, and social stability.</p> <p> He also raised concerns about the interference from certain major countries in Middle Eastern affairs, which jeopardizes the stability and security in the region.</p> <p> China appreciates Oman's unique and positive role in promoting the political settlement of regional issues, said Wei, adding that China stands ready to work with Oman to enrich the bilateral strategic partnership and expand friendly cooperation in all areas.</p> <p> Calling the Omani military an important cooperative partner of the Chinese military, Wei said that the Chinese military is willing to work with its Omani counterpart to raise the level of cooperation in joint drills, military technology, logistics support, and personnel training.</p> <p> Also on Thursday, Wei held meetings with Omani Minister of the Royal Office Sultan bin Mohammed al Nomani and Foreign Minister Sayyid Badr Hamad al-Busaidi, during which the two sides had in-depth exchange of views on the regional and international security situations, bilateral military ties, and the Ukraine issue.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Iranian president meets with Chinese defense minister ]]></title>
	<news_id>10090457</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0428/c90000-10090457.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 10:44:57 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> TEHRAN, April 27 (Xinhua) -- Iranian President Ebrahim Raisi on Wednesday met with visiting Chinese State Councilor and Minister of National Defense Wei Fenghe.</p> <p> During the meeting, Raisi called for expanding the areas of cooperation between the two countries, and strengthening all-round cooperation, including in the military field.</p> <p> Iran and China share similar positions in international affairs and support each other, said the Iranian president.</p> <p> Iran, which opposes unilateralism, hegemonism and external interference, firmly supports China in safeguarding its core interests, Raisi said, while expressing gratitude to China for its long-term support and assistance during Iran's difficult times.</p> <p> For his part, Wei said that Chinese President Xi Jinping and Raisi have exchanged telephone calls and letters since last year, leading to new progress in building the comprehensive strategic partnership between the two countries.</p> <p> The Chinese minister said that his visit to Iran, which came against the backdrop of the current turbulent international situation, reflected the importance of the China-Iran relations, their firm mutual support and joint progress.</p> <p> He expressed China's strong support to Iran in safeguarding its national sovereignty and dignity, and its willingness to cooperate with Iran to deal with various risks and challenges, safeguard common interests, and jointly maintain regional and global peace and stability.</p> <p> The Chinese and Iranian militaries have expanded the areas of cooperation in recent years, Wei said, adding that the Chinese military is willing to maintain strategic communication with Iran, make good use of the cooperation mechanisms, and boost pragmatic collaboration so as to lift the bilateral military ties to a higher level.</p> <p> Earlier in the day, Wei held separate meetings with Chief of Staff of the Iranian Armed Forces Mohammad Bagheri and Iranian Defense Minister Mohammad Reza Ashtiani.</p> <p> During the meetings, the two sides had in-depth exchange of views on the regional and international security situations, Iran's nuclear issue and the situation in Ukraine. They also reached consensuses on expanding high-level strategic communication, deepening military exchanges, and conducting joint exercises and personnel trainings.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Turkmen president, Chinese defense minister agree to deepen military cooperation ]]></title>
	<news_id>10089842</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0427/c90000-10089842.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 10:21:37 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> ASHGABAT, April 26 (Xinhua) -- Turkmen President Serdar Berdimuhamedov and visiting Chinese State Councilor and Minister of National Defense Wei Fenghe voiced common willingness on Tuesday to promote bilateral cooperation.</p> <p> At a meeting with Wei in Ashgabat, Berdimuhamedov said that Turkmenistan attaches great importance to its relations with China, and the two countries have carried out high-level cooperation in the fields of politics, diplomacy, trade, culture, humanitarian and people-to-people exchanges, and established a strategic partnership.</p> <p> China is one of Turkmenistan's largest trading partners, the president said, adding that there are more than 1,400 Turkmen students studying in China, and students can major in the Chinese language in many Turkmen universities.</p> <p> Berdimuhamedov expressed the hope that the two militaries will strengthen practical cooperation in equipment technology, personnel training and other fields, and continuously push foward bilateral relations with new development.</p> <p> For his part, Wei said that under the strategic guidance of the two heads of state, China-Turkmenistan relations have achieved leap-forward development and are in their best period in history.</p> <p> On the occasion of the 30th anniversary of the establishment of bilateral diplomatic ties, China stands ready to cement solidarity with Turkmenistan and jointly build an even closer community with a shared future for the two countries, he said.</p> <p> China firmly supports Turkmenistan's permanent neutral status, firmly supports its pursuit of a development path suited to its national conditions, and firmly opposes external interference in Turkmenistan's internal affairs, Wei stressed.</p> <p> In recent years, military-to-military relations between the two countries have been developing steadily and their pragmatic cooperation has been deepening day by day, he noted.</p> <p> The Chinese military is willing to further expand areas of cooperation with Turkmenistan, enhance the effectiveness of cooperation and strive to elevate military-to-military relations to a higher level, Wei said.</p> <p> On the same day, Turkmen Defense Minister Begench Gundogdyev held a welcome ceremony for Wei and had formal talks with him.</p> <p> The two officials exchanged in-depth views on the international and regional security situations as well as the Ukrainian and the Afghan issues, and both agreed that the two militaries will continue strategic communication, conduct personnel training, and strengthen anti-terrorist and equipment technology cooperation.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Kazakh president, Chinese defense minister agree to strengthen military cooperation ]]></title>
	<news_id>10089296</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0426/c90000-10089296.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 10:00:44 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NUR-SULTAN, April 25 (Xinhua) -- Kazakh President Kassym-Jomart Tokayev and visiting Chinese State Councilor and Minister of National Defense Wei Fenghe voiced common readiness on Monday to step up bilateral cooperation.</p> <p> At a meeting with Wei in Nur-Sultan, Tokayev said Kazakhstan and China will celebrate the 30th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations this year, and over the past three decades, the two countries have become permanent comprehensive strategic partners, maintained high-level coordination in the international political arena, and achieved remarkable results in cooperation in various areas.</p> <p> Tokayev recalled that he has frequently interacted with Chinese President Xi Jinping in recent years, injecting strong impetus to the development of bilateral relations.</p> <p> The Kazakh president said he believes that relations between the two countries will see greater breakthroughs and achievements.</p> <p> Tokayev said Kazakhstan attaches great importance to the military cooperation with China and hopes that the two militaries will continue to strengthen practical cooperation in peacekeeping operations, joint exercises, personnel training, military technology and other fields.</p> <p> Wei said that Tokayev, an old friend of the Chinese people, has made outstanding contributions to the establishment and development of China-Kazakhstan permanent comprehensive strategic partnership.</p> <p> This year marks the 30th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic ties between China and Kazakhstan, Wei said, adding that under the strategic guidance of the two heads of state, bilateral relations have maintained a momentum of vigorous development and enjoy a very bright future, setting a good example of good-neighborly friendship and mutual benefit.</p> <p> China firmly opposes external forces deliberately instigating a "color revolution" in Kazakhstan and backs the Kazakh side in taking strong measures to safeguard national security and social stability, Wei noted.</p> <p> The senior Chinese official called for vigilance about certain major powers interfering in Central Asia to disrupt and undermine regional security.</p> <p> Wei said his visit demonstrated that China attaches great significance to and firmly supports Kazakhstan, noting that no matter what risks and challenges the two countries may encounter, they will jointly maintain regional stability and push ahead with the building of a community with a shared future for mankind.</p> <p> In recent years, the exchanges and cooperation between the Chinese and Kazakh militaries in various fields have been fruitful, he said, adding that the Chinese military is willing to continue to expand cooperation areas with the Kazakh side and deepen military-to-military relations between the two countries.</p> <p> On the same day, Kazakh Defense Minister Ruslan Zhaksylykov held a welcome ceremony for Wei and had formal talks with him.</p> <p> The two officials exchanged in-depth views on the international and regional security situations, the situation in Ukraine and the Afghan issue, and agreed that the two militaries will continue to strengthen strategic communication, conduct joint drills and training, and carry out practical cooperation.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China’s armed forces always a force of justice safeguarding world peace ]]></title>
	<news_id>10089261</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0426/c90000-10089261.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 09:32:46 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0426/FOREIGN202204260912000483907386017.png" style="width: 700px; height: 466px;" /></p> <p> <em>The 20th Chinese peacekeeping engineering contingent to Lebanon holds a solemn flag raising ceremony at its camp in southern Lebanon on Sept. 21, 2021, the International Day of Peace.</em></p> <p> Recently, 15 members of the 12th Chinese peacekeeping engineering contingent to South Sudan received the Sector Commander’s Commendation conferred by the Sector West Commander of the United Nations Mission in South Sudan (UNMISS) Brigadier General Measho Hagos Seyum for their outstanding achievements and great contributions in recent peacekeeping work.</p> <p> For a long time, China’s Blue Helmets have built a strong defense line to safeguard peace in regions beset by conflict, demonstrating China’s sense of responsibility as a major country.</p> <p> Peace is an aspiration and lofty goal shared by all mankind. UN Peacekeeping, as instrument developed for peace and began in 1948, is aimed at helping countries torn by conflict to create conditions for lasting peace, and has become an important means of safeguarding world peace and security.</p> <p> Over the past more than 70 years, UN peacekeepers have made selfless devotion and sacrifices in some of the toughest and most dangerous places in the world, while Blue Helmets have become a symbol of peace and hope in war-ravaged lands and Chinese Blue Helmets have grown into a key force in the UN peacekeeping operations (UNPKOs).</p> <p> In April 1990, China’s armed forces dispatched five military observers to the United Nations Truce Supervision Organization (UNTSO) and embarked on a new voyage as a participant in the UNPKOs. On April 16, 1992, China dispatched its first formed military unit of Blue Helmets to Cambodia for UN peacekeeping mission.</p> <p> Over the past 30 years or so, China’s armed forces have contributed a growing number of peacekeepers across an expanding range of deployments. From a few military observers at the outset of its involvement, China’s armed forces are now sending both formed units and military professionals. Chinese military peacekeepers serve on the UN missions in engineer, medical, transport, helicopter, force protection and infantry units, and as staff officers, military observers and seconded officers.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0426/FOREIGN202204260915000223391669694.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 424px;" /></p> <p> <em>All 410 members of the 19th batch of Chinese peacekeeping force to Lebanon are awarded the United Nations Peace Medal of Honor during a ceremony at the Chinese troops’ camp in Hanniyah village in southern Lebanon, June 16, 2021.</em></p> <p> Batches of Chinese military peacekeepers have embarked on one mission after another with courage and fortitude, becoming steadfast guardians of world peace.</p> <p> Since 1992, China has sent nearly 50,000 peacekeepers to 25 UNPKOs in more than 20 countries and regions, including Cambodia, the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC), Liberia, Sudan, Lebanon, Cyprus, South Sudan, Mali and the Central African Republic.</p> <p> China is the second largest contributor to both peacekeeping assessment and UN membership fees, and the largest troop-contributing country (TCC) among the permanent members of the UN Security Council.</p> <p> There are many touching stories about how Chinese peacekeeping forces have brought with them peace, security and the light of hope and warmth to people in war-torn areas.</p> <p> Since 2013, China has dispatched nine peacekeeping units to Mali, where they carried out duties including armed patrols and armed escorts and earned the reputation of “des troupes d'élite” of Sector East of the United Nations Multidimensional Integrated Stabilization Mission in Mali (MINUSMA).</p> <p> Over the past 16 years since the deployment of Chinese peacekeeping troops in Lebanon, Chinese peacekeepers successfully completed tasks including engineering construction and maintenance, providing medical services and humanitarian assistance, as well as clearing mines and explosives, during which they created the record of zero casualties for such tasks.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0426/FOREIGN202204260916000003330222646.jpg" style="width: 700px; height: 424px;" /></p> <p> <em>The United Nations Mission in South Sudan (UNMISS) holds an emergency drill for troops in the Juba sector and the UN police officers, April 24, 2020.</em></p> <p> The Chinese medical units in the DRC have run a twinning project in SOS Children’s Village Bukavu to offer help for 19 years. Touched by the love and care from the units, children in the village called the female members their Chinese mothers.</p> <p> In UNMISS, Chinese military peacekeepers have provided agricultural techniques, farming tools and vegetable seeds to local people. They were invited by local middle schools to teach lessons on Chinese culture and language.</p> <p> Chinese military peacekeepers are not only guardians of peace but also messengers of friendship.</p> <p> Jean-Pierre Lacroix, UN Under-Secretary-General for Peacekeeping Operations, said China’s contribution to UNPKOs is “very important”.</p> <p> Peace needs to be fought for and safeguarded. China is a builder of world peace, a contributor to global development and a defender of international order. And China’s armed forces will always be a force of justice safeguarding world peace.</p> <p> China’s Blue Helmets have constantly injected positive energy into world peace and will continue forging ahead courageously and unswervingly to safeguard peace with a strong sense of discipline and responsibility.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China’s home-built aircraft carrier Shandong starts 1st maintenance, refurbishment: media reports ]]></title>
	<news_id>10088888</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0425/c90000-10088888.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 14:09:30 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="The picture shows aircraft carrier Shandong berths at a naval port in Sanya. China's first domestically-made aircraft carrier Shandong (Hull 17) was officially commissioned to the PLA Navy at a military port in Sanya, South China's Hainan Province, on the afternoon of December 17, 2019, making China one of the few countries in the world that have multiple carriers. Chinese President Xi Jinping attended the commissioning ceremony for the new aircraft carrier, which was named after China's eastern province of Shandong, and handed military flag to Senior Captain Lai Yijun, commander of the ship. Photo:China Military" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220425/91/6363384386832638363.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>The picture shows aircraft carrier Shandong berths at a naval port in Sanya. China's first domestically-made aircraft carrier Shandong (Hull 17) was officially commissioned to the PLA Navy at a military port in Sanya, South China's Hainan Province, on the afternoon of December 17, 2019, making China one of the few countries in the world that have multiple carriers. Chinese President Xi Jinping attended the commissioning ceremony for the new aircraft carrier, which was named after China's eastern province of Shandong, and handed military flag to Senior Captain Lai Yijun, commander of the ship. Photo:China Military</em></p> <p> The Shandong, China's second aircraft carrier and the first developed domestically, reportedly started its first scheduled maintenance and refurbishment that is expected to enhance the flattop's usability after more than two years of active service. The procedure could involve the painting of new non-skid coating as well as repairs and upgrades for some subsystems, and the carrier would come back stronger than ever in a few months, observers said on Sunday.</p> <p> Moored in a berth at Dalian Shipyard in Northeast China's LiaoningProvince where the carrier was constructed, the Shandongwas receiving painting of new non-skid coating to its flight deck on Saturday, the 73rd founding anniversary of the Chinese People's Liberation Army (PLA) Navy, Hong Kong-based news website wenweipo.com reported on the day.</p> <p> This is the first scheduled usability enhancement maintenance of the Shandongback at its shipyard since its commissioning into the PLA Navy in December 2019 in Sanya, South China's Hainan Province, and the workers at the shipyard are working extra shifts for the refurbishment, according to the wenweipo.com report.</p> <p> The main dock of the Dalian Shipyard has been cleared after a civilian ship left on April 13, but the Shandonghas not yet entered the dock, the report said.</p> <p> On March 18, the Shandongsailed through the Taiwan Straits from south to north without aircraft on its flight deck, Reuters reported at the time, citing the island of Taiwan's defense authority and an anonymous source. Analysts said then that the carrier was likely on its way from its homeport in Sanya to its shipyard in Dalian for a regular maintenance.</p> <p> In addition to refreshing the non-skid coating of the flight deck, the maintenance could also feature the refurbishment, repair and upgrade of some subsystems that tends to wear and tear, like the arresting gear, the power system, pipelines and electronics systems, a military expert who requested anonymity told the Global Times on Sunday.</p> <p> A comprehensive examination to the carrier could be carried out, and upgrades and overhaul could be made to those parts that encountered problems or can be optimized based on the experiences gained over the past two years, the expert said.</p> <p> It is totally normal for aircraft carriers to conduct this kind of regular maintenance, and this procedure could take a few months, the expert said, noting that the Shandongwould become more powerful and combat-ready after the refurbishment.</p> <p> A refurbishment to the Liaoning, China's first aircraft carrier, took about six months, from July 2018 to January 2019, also in the Dalian Shipyard, according to media reports.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Aviation brigade organizes flight training after rain ]]></title>
	<news_id>10088539</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0424/c90000-10088539.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 15:49:17 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0424/FOREIGN202204241531000211192798073.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> A fighter jet attached to an aviation brigade with the air force under the PLA Southern Theater Command takes off after rain for a flight training exercise on March 25, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Xu Jingcheng)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0424/FOREIGN202204241532000112258770605.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> A fighter jet attached to an aviation brigade with the air force under the PLA Southern Theater Command glides at cruise speed during a flight training exercise on March 25, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Xu Jingcheng)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0424/FOREIGN202204241532000391443521262.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> A fighter jet attached to an aviation brigade with the air force under the PLA Southern Theater Command decelerates with the help of its drag parachute after a flight training exercise on March 25, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Xu Jingcheng)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Military Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China releases aircraft carrier-themed promotional video, hinting arrival of third one ]]></title>
	<news_id>10087748</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0422/c90000-10087748.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 15:25:27 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <center> <video controls="controls" poster=" http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/4/22/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_bdce6c47122bfbb2adba68a4c7f75ac2.jpg" src=" http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/4/22/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_5ae20bf062d59f959eb271e86feb9c5c.mp4" style=" width: 830px; height:550px;"> <p> &nbsp;</p> </video> </center> <p> To celebrate its 73rd birthday, the People’s Liberation Army Navy on Friday released a promotional video on Chinese aircraft carriers.</p> <p> The video contains rarely seen frames of the training, the interior of China’s two aircraft carriers <em>Liaoning</em> and<em> Shandong </em>and also details of the seamen’s work.</p> <p> The trailer of the video uses a subtle metaphor that a Navy soldier tells his mother that he plans to have a third child over the phone, hinting at China’s third aircraft carrier.</p> <p> Joining the Navy in 2012 and 2019, respectively, <em>Liaoning</em> and <em>Shandong</em> have completed a variety of tasks as trailblazers in Navy transformation, contributors to China’s army building and a witnesses to a stronger China. Now, they are ready to be joined by a third member.</p> <p> <em>(Compiled by Chen Rui)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily App</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Submarines get missile loading at pier ]]></title>
	<news_id>10087718</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0422/c90000-10087718.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 14:49:11 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0422/FOREIGN202204221436000522203587480.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 675px;" /></p> <p> Sailors load missiles onto the submarines on March 22, 2022. Submarines attached to a navy flotilla under the PLA Northern Theatre Command had their ammunitions refreshed on March 22. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Wu Haodong)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0422/FOREIGN202204221438000145172765249.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 675px;" /></p> <p> Sailors load missiles onto the submarines on March 22, 2022. Submarines attached to a navy flotilla under the PLA Northern Theatre Command had their ammunitions refreshed on March 22. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Wu Haodong)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0422/FOREIGN202204221439000124286387031.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 675px;" /></p> <p> Sailors load missiles onto the submarines on March 22, 2022. Submarines attached to a navy flotilla under the PLA Northern Theatre Command had their ammunitions refreshed on March 22. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Wu Haodong)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Military Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's newly commissioned amphibious assault ship Guangxi undergoes training ]]></title>
	<news_id>10087692</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0422/c90000-10087692.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 14:17:11 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <center> <video controls="controls" poster=" http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/4/22/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_dcb13e7c0c2c7aecf79ce744042e6247.jpg" src=" http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/4/22/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_32921cc6d7d8a82cc5e95cf839f22e29.mp4" style=" width: 830px; height:550px;"> &nbsp;</video> </center> <p> Aiming at the requirements of amphibious operations and high seas operations in the future, China’s amphibious assault ship Guangxi of the People’s Liberation Army Navy carried out training exercises on navigation, combat rescue and damage control.</p> <p> As the first domestically developed type 075 amphibious assault ships, the accelerated formation of combat capacity of the ships of Hainan and Guangxi is significant to the improvement of China's amphibious operating capability and combat system.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily App</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese defense minister holds phone talks with U.S. counterpart ]]></title>
	<news_id>10086911</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0421/c90000-10086911.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 10:23:02 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, April 20 (Xinhua) -- Chinese State Councilor and Minister of National Defense Wei Fenghe on Wednesday held phone talks with U.S. Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin.</p> <p> In the phone talks, Wei said that China and the United States should earnestly implement the consensus reached by the two heads of state.</p> <p> China hopes to establish sound and stable major-country relations with the United States, Wei said, adding that in the meantime, China will defend its national interests and dignity.</p> <p> The United States should not underestimate China's determination and capability, Wei said.</p> <p> The two militaries should enhance mutual trust, strengthen dialogue and exchanges, manage risks and crises, and carry out practical cooperation, so as to ensure the normal and stable development of bilateral military-to-military relations, he said.</p> <p> If the Taiwan question is not handled properly, it will have a subversive effect on China-U.S. relations, Wei stressed, adding that the Chinese military will resolutely safeguard national sovereignty, security and territorial integrity.</p> <p> Austin said that the United States will strengthen military exchanges and cooperation with China in a candid and open manner, and the United States adheres to the one-China policy.</p> <p> Austin said that the two sides should manage competition and risks in a responsible way and properly handle the difficulties facing the two militaries.</p> <p> The two sides also exchanged views on issues such as maritime and air security and the situation in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Defense minister stresses China's resolve, warns against US provocations in ‘late’ first phone talk with Austin ]]></title>
	<news_id>10086723</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0421/c90000-10086723.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 08:32:20 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="Chinese State Councilor and Defense Minister Wei Fenghe " src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220421/77/1065672713939100225.jpg" style="height: 540px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p align="center" class="pictext"> <em>Chinese State Councilor and Defense Minister Wei Fenghe</em></p> <p> Chinese State Councilor and Defense Minister Wei Fenghe had a phone call with US Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin on Wednesday at the latter's request, with Wei stressing the importance of the Taiwan question, while demanding the US to stop its military provocations at sea, and not to throw mud or threaten China with the Ukraine issue.</p> <p> The dialogue, the first since Austin became US Defense Secretary in January 2021, will hopefully provide stability to the two countries' military-to-military ties and avoid and reduce misjudgments by letting the US better understand China's bottom line and core interests at a very challenging time in the China-US relations, analysts said.</p> <p> Wei said that China and the US should implement the consensus reached by the two countries' top leadersin earnest, pledge mutual respect, coexist peacefully and avoid confrontation. The US should fulfill its promise of not seeking a new Cold War with China, should not aim to change China's system, the revitalization of its alliances should not target China, that the US does not support "Taiwan independence," and that it has no intention to seek a conflict with China.</p> <p> China hopes to build a sound and steady major power relationship with the US, and it will also safeguard its national interests and dignity. The US should not underestimate China's determination and capability, Wei said.</p> <p> The two countries' militaries should enhance mutual trust, boost conversation and communication, manage and control risks and crises, and carry out pragmatic cooperation to ensure the normal, steady development of the two countries' military-to-military relations, Wei said.</p> <p> Wei stated a solemn position over the Taiwan question, as he stressed that Taiwan is an inalienable part of China, and this is a fact and a status quo no one can change.</p> <p> It will bring a disruptive impact on China-US relations if the Taiwan question is not handled well, and the Chinese military will resolutely safeguard national sovereignty, security and territorial integrity, Wei said.</p> <p> Austin said that the US is willing to promote the implementation of the important consensus reached by the two countries' top leaders, and it will enhance exchanges and cooperation in the military field with a sincere and open attitude.</p> <p> The US stays committed to the one-China policy, Austin said.</p> <p> Both sides should manage and control competition and risks with responsible manners, and deal well with challenges that the military ties between the two countries are facing, the US defense secretary said.</p> <p> The biggest significance of the dialogue between two countries' defense ministers is that China and the US could avoid and reduce misjudgments by better understanding each other's bottom lines and not challenge each other's core interests, Song Zhongping, a Chinese military expert and TV commentator, told the Global Times on Wednesday.</p> <p> China does not seek hegemony but it will not allow the US to challenge its red lines in terms of core interests, Song said.</p> <p> Hopefully, the talk can provide stability for the two countries' military-to-military ties and a resumption of high-level military communications, Song said.</p> <p> The defense ministers' talk came after a video call between the two countries' top leadersin March, which was deemed constructive, and teams from both countries were directed to promptly follow up and take concrete actions to put China-US relations back on the track of steady development, the Xinhua News Agency reported at the time.</p> <p> China-US relations have been in a very difficult time, with all kinds of challenges stacked together, but the two countries' leaderships know they have wide and deep common interests, and those cannot be ignored because of the challenges, a Chinese expert on foreign affairs told the Global Times on Wednesday, requesting anonymity.</p> <p> Wei and Austin's phone call is a chance to enable the two militaries to better understand each other's strategic intent and enhance the management of tensions in places like the South China Sea and the Taiwan Straits, the expert said.</p> <p> China warned the US that is should not go further on the Taiwan question, not to mention supporting "Taiwan independence" forces, as this is a major question of principle that involves national sovereignty, security and development interests, Song said. China must make clear its bottom line to the US in order to safeguard peace and stability, and the Chinese mainland has the legal basis, the capability and the determination to resolve the Taiwan question, including by force, he said.</p> <p> The Chinese People's Liberation Army (PLA) Eastern Theater Command on Friday organized multi-services and arms, dispatching forces including destroyers, frigates, bombers and fighters, and conducted joint combat alert patrols and drillsincluding a maritime assault, in the forefront of the East China Sea and in waters and aerial areas around the island of Taiwan, when a group of US lawmakers were visiting the island.</p> <p> A total of 11 PLA aircraft, namely a Y-8 electronic warfare aircraft, two H-6 bombers, a KJ-500 early warning aircraft and seven J-16 fighter jets, entered the island of Taiwan's self-proclaimed southwestern air defense identification zone on Wednesday, Taiwan's defense authority said on the day.</p> <p> Wei and Austin exchanged views over air and maritime safety issues, with China demanding the US to stop making military provocations from the sea.</p> <p> China and the US have already established mechanisms for the safety of air and maritime encounters, but the US military has been increasing close-in reconnaissance operations on China with aircraft and vessels, Song said.</p> <p> In 2021, US large spy planes carried out about 1,200 aerial close-in reconnaissance sorties on China, with US aircraft carrier strike groups, amphibious ready groups and nuclear-powered attack submarines repeatedly entering the South China Sea, according to the monitoring by the South China Sea Strategic Situation Probing Initiative, a Beijing-based think tank.</p> <p> This increases the risk of an accident and could lead to serious consequences, and the US must stop making such provocations, or the Chinese military would have to deal with them, experts said.</p> <p> The two defense ministers also discussed the situation in Ukraine, and China urged the US not to use the Ukraine issue to throw mud at, threaten and pressure China.</p> <p> <strong>First conversation</strong></p> <p> This is the first time Wei and Austin have had a direct conversation since Austin became Pentagon chief, observers noted.</p> <p> In May 2021, Western media reported that Austin had yet to talk to Chinese military leaders "despite repeated attempts," but that was because Austin, in an unprofessional and unfriendly actof disregarding diplomatic protocol and international common practice, requested to meet with Xu Qiliang, vice chairman of the Central Military Commission, instead of Wei, sources told the Global Times at the time.</p> <p> This time, it was also the US side that proposed the call, but with the right person, observers pointed out.</p> <p> A reason why the US requested the call is probably because the US acknowledges China as its greatest strategic competitor, but in the meantime the risk of a real conflict must be avoided, analysts said.</p> <p> Another reason is that the US might want China's help with the Ukraine crisis, and put pressure on China over its ties with Russia amid the Ukraine crisis, but its attempt to sow discord between China and Russia is bound to be futile, Song said.</p> <p> China-US relations, as the most important relations in the world, have big influence potentials on the Russia-Ukraine issue, Song pointed out, noting that the US is fanning the flames and stirring up troubles at the cost of the Russians, Ukrainians and Europeans to serve its own hegemonic interests, and China on the other hand is promoting talks and peace.</p> <p> The anonymous foreign affairs expert said that the US might be worried whether China could have some sorts of military coordination and cooperation with Russia.</p> <p> China's Ministry of Foreign Affairs has repeatedly said that it is disinformation from the US that Russia has asked China for military assistance, and China's position on the Ukraine issue is consistent and clear, as China has been playing a constructive part in promoting peace talks.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ High speed, AI trends for future helicopters: Chinese attack chopper designer ]]></title>
	<news_id>10085803</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0419/c90000-10085803.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 10:01:36 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="Attack helicopters attached to a naval aviation brigade under the PLA Eastern Theater Command sit in formation on the parking apron during a flight training exercise in April 19,2021. Photo:China Military" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220419/72/4564480985229976292.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 540px;" /></p> <p> <em>Attack helicopters attached to a naval aviation brigade under the PLA Eastern Theater Command sit in formation on the parking apron during a flight training exercise in April 19,2021. Photo:China Military</em></p> <p> High speeds and artificial intelligence (AI) are among the trends in the development of future helicopters, a top Chinese military helicopter designer said during a recent public lecture, giving a glimpse into the possibilities of the country's next-generation choppers, which could feature completely new designs and configurations.</p> <p> The world has made concrete steps in the development and application of high-speed rotorcraft, with the US commissioning the V-22 Osprey tilt-rotor transport aircraft and conducting test flights for the S-97 Raider and SB-1 Defiant helicopters. Within 10 years, it will be the norm for helicopters, or rotorcraft in general, to feature high speeds, Wu Ximing, deputy head of the Chinese Aeronautical Establishment, said during the lecture organized by the China Science and Technology Museum on Sunday.</p> <p> Unlike the traditional configuration of previous helicopters, the new ones will have very different designs, including those that were made to break the physical speed limit of about 300 kilometers an hour restricted by the traditional design, said Wu, who is also the chief designer of the Z-10, the main battle attack helicopter used by the Chinese military.</p> <p> It will require exploration and innovation by helicopter designers to achieve high speeds while maintaining the vertical takeoff and landing capabilities, Wu said.</p> <p> Since Wu gave a general time frame of 10 years for most helicopters to achieve high speed, it can be expected that China could also reveal its high-speed helicopters within 10 years, a Chinese military expert told the Global Times on Monday, requesting anonymity.</p> <p> China's helicopter makers have reportedly conducted test flights for at least two types of helicopters with innovative designs: one is a blended-wing body multi-rotorvertical takeoff and landing aircraft, the other is a helicopter with a completely different, innovative design.</p> <p> Helicopters will also be empowered by AI, and this means that a digital helmet or screen could replace the control levers on a helicopter, as AI could understand voice commands from the pilot, give suggestions on flight routes, or even make independent decisions under harsh environments or in complex missions, Wu said. "Intelligent technologies will greatly reduce the workload of the pilot in flying the chopper."</p> <p> AI will enable the intelligent flight of a single helicopter, the coordinated flight of multiple helicopters, and the autonomous carrying out of missions, according to Wu's presentation.</p> <p> With the rapid development of information technologies like 5G and 6G, it is possible that the helicopter could get larger computing capacity from ground-based systems through a network, and this could optimize the helicopter's capabilities and enhance its efficiency, Wu said.</p> <p> The use of AI will apply not only to helicopters, but also to aircraft in general, including fighter jets, the anonymous expert said.</p> <p> The development of drones is another future trend for helicopters, as drones do not lead to casualties. They are not restricted by a human pilot's physical limits and can be used in harsh environments, Wu pointed out, while they cost less and offer higher survivability.</p> <p> Miniature drone helicopters are also a viable option in missions like tactical reconnaissance, as they are easy to carry and can penetrate hostile defenses stealthily, Wu said.</p> <p> China has developed a type of portable reconnaissance drone helicopter dubbed the Hummingbird, which is only 15 centimeters long and weighs only 35 grams, China Central Television reported in February.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ NATO's expansion to worsen Ukraine crisis, decay European security ]]></title>
	<news_id>10084935</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0416/c90000-10084935.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 14:23:16 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> WARSAW/MOSCOW, April 16 (Xinhua) -- Transferring massive weapons to Ukraine, massing a large number of troops in eastern Europe, and welcoming Sweden and Finland to join the alliance, NATO has been very much engaged itself so far in the conflict between Russia and Ukraine.</p> <p> Analysts say NATO's disregard of Russia's legitimate concerns on security issues and its continuous expansion is the root cause of the outbreak and escalation of this conflict. If it continues to slim down the small buffer zone left between Russia and itself, the situation will undoubtedly go worse.</p> <p> <strong>DEPLOYMENT IN THE EAST</strong></p> <p> NATO's eastern flank usually refers to the three Baltic countries, namely Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania, as well as Poland, Slovakia, Hungary, Romania, and Bulgaria.</p> <p> Before the escalation of the Russia-Ukraine conflict, NATO deployed one combat force in each of the three Baltic countries and Poland, and implemented a rotation mechanism with non-permanent garrison troops there.</p> <p> But for now, NATO doubles the size of the four above-mentioned combat forces and declared four new NATO battlegroups in Bulgaria, Hungary, Romania, and Slovakia at the NATO summit held last month.</p> <p> NATO is seen by many as a Cold War vestige, and has been questioned over the necessity of its existence after the end of the Cold War.</p> <p> The military alliance promised in the 1990s that it would not expand "one inch eastward," according to then U.S. Secretary of State James Baker. However, led by the United States, NATO has expanded eastward five times since 1999, increasing the number of member countries from 16 to 30, advancing more than 1,000 km eastward, and reaching the Russian border.</p> <p> RECRUITMENT IN THE NORTH</p> <p> In addition to strengthening deployments on the eastern flank, NATO is also recruiting new members on the north wing. NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg has repeatedly said that if Finland and Sweden apply to join NATO, NATO will welcome them and ensure that their entrance will be accepted soon.</p> <p> In a recent interview with The Telegraph, Stoltenberg said that the alliance is "in the midst of a very fundamental transformation" that will reflect "the long-term consequences" of Russia's military operation.</p> <p> Both Finland and Sweden have long pursued a policy of military non-alignment. After the disintegration of the Soviet Union, NATO has failed to win over the two countries several times.</p> <p> But now Finland and Sweden made some changes in their positions in face of the Russia-Ukraine conflict, delivering anti-tank weapons and ammunition to Ukraine.</p> <p> Some analysts point out that before the escalation of the Russia-Ukraine conflict, Russia had repeatedly confirmed and confided its red line to both the United States and NATO, for which both showed a total disregard. If NATO continues to fan the flames such as taking in new members, it will lead to further escalation of the situation.</p> <p> <strong>CONFRONTATIONAL GESTURE</strong></p> <p> When answering a question about the prospect of the countries which may join NATO, Dmitry Peskov, press secretary of Russian President Vladimir Putin, told reporters on Monday that further expansion of NATO, including the admission of Finland and Sweden into the alliance, will not contribute to security in Europe.</p> <p> "In itself, the alliance is rather a tool sharpened for confrontation. This is not an alliance that ensures peace and stability. Further expansion of the alliance, of course, will not bring additional security to the European continent," the Kremlin spokesman said.</p> <p> Dmitry Belik, a member of Russia's State Duma Committee on International Affairs, said on Monday that NATO seeks to build up its military presence near the Russian borders, but the entry of Finland and Sweden into NATO will not benefit these countries, and "Russia will not watch this indifferently."</p> <p> "This issue seriously affects our security, so we will be forced to take retaliatory steps," he told the Izvestia newspaper.</p> <p> "The accession of Finland and Sweden to NATO puts them in a very difficult position," he added.</p> <p> According to military expert Viktor Litovkin, in the event that Finland and Sweden decide to join NATO, Russia will justifiably strengthen the Russian-Finnish border, as well as the entire water area of the Gulf of Finland.</p> <p> "Russia will have to strengthen ground forces and air defense, deploy significant naval forces in the Gulf of Finland in the event of Finland and Sweden joining the alliance," the expert noted.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Submarine bears off port for maritime training drills ]]></title>
	<news_id>10084928</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0416/c90000-10084928.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 13:37:35 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0416/FOREIGN202204161334000157875483072.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 675px;" /></p> <p> <em>Two towboats attached to a submarine flotilla with the navy under the PLA Northern Theater Command jointly tow a submarine to bear off a port for the maritime combat training drills on March 23, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Wu Haodong)</em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0416/FOREIGN202204161334000262041321060.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 675px;" /></p> <p> <em>Two towboats attached to a submarine flotilla with the navy under the PLA Northern Theater Command jointly tow a submarine to bear off a port for the maritime combat training drills on March 23, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Wu Haodong)</em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0416/FOREIGN202204161334000444545918094.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 675px;" /></p> <p> <em>A submarine attached to a submarine flotilla with the navy under the PLA Northern Theater Command bears off a port for the maritime combat training drills on March 23, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Wu Haodong)</em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0416/FOREIGN202204161334000546778156897.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 675px;" /></p> <p> <em>A submarine attached to a submarine flotilla with the navy under the PLA Northern Theater Command bears off a port for the maritime combat training drills on March 23, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Wu Haodong)</em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0416/FOREIGN202204161335000040890744062.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 675px;" /></p> <p> <em>A submarine attached to a submarine flotilla with the navy under the PLA Northern Theater Command bears off a port for the maritime combat training drills on March 23, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Wu Haodong)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Military Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ PLA drills around Taiwan targeted at US lawmakers' visit, rehearse 'real action' once necessary ]]></title>
	<news_id>10084860</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0416/c90000-10084860.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 11:24:07 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0416/FOREIGN202204161110000136559052883.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 540px;" /></p> <p> <em>Two Su-35 fighter jets and a H-6K bomber fly in formation on May 11, 2018. The People's Liberation Army (PLA) air force conducted patrol training over China's island of Taiwan on May 11. Su-35 fighter jets flew over the Bashi Channel in formation with the H-6Ks for the first time, which marks a new breakthrough in island patrol patterns, said Shen Jinke, spokesperson for the PLA air force. Photo:China Military</em></p> <p> The Chinese People's Liberation Army (PLA) Eastern Theater Command on Friday organized multi-services and arms, dispatching forces including destroyers, frigates, bombers and fighters, and conducted joint combat alert patrols and drills including maritime assault, in the forefront of the East China Sea and in waters and aerial areas around the island of Taiwan, when a group of US lawmakers were visiting the island. Chinese mainland experts said the pointed military operation not only serves as a warning to US House Speaker Nancy Pelosi who could still visit Taiwan after "postponing" her travel due to COVID-19 infection, but also goes beyond deterrence by preparing for potential, real actions that would resolve the Taiwan question once and for all when necessary.</p> <p> The operation targets the US' recent wrong signals on the Taiwan question, as the US' wicked tactics are totally useless and dangerous, Senior Colonel Shi Yi, spokesperson for the PLA Eastern Theater Command, said on Friday in a press release.</p> <p> "Those who play with fire will burn themselves. The command troops always maintain high alert and will firmly safeguard national sovereignty and security and regional peace and stability," Shi said.</p> <p> Six PLA aircraft - four J-16 fighter jets and two J-11 fighter jets - entered Taiwan's self-proclaimed southwest air defense identification zone on Friday, the island's defense authority said.</p> <p> Senior Colonel Wu Qian, spokesperson of China's Ministry of National Defense, said in a press release on Friday that US congressmen visited the island of Taiwan in a deliberate provocation disregarding China's strong opposition. The visit severely violated the one-China principle and the regulations of the Three Joint Communiqués between China and the US, seriously harmed the political foundation of China-US ties, and caused a further escalation of tensions in the Taiwan Straits.</p> <p> The PLA Eastern Theater Command's joint combat alert patrols and pointed drills are necessary actions taken based on the current security situation in the Taiwan Straits and the needs to safeguard national sovereignty, Wu said.</p> <p> China's Foreign Ministry spokesperson Zhao Lijian said clearly that Friday's military operation was targeted at the US congressional delegation's visit to Taiwan island.</p> <p> The PLA is ready for battle and will take any necessary measure to resolutely crush attempts of interference by external forces and secessionist moves of "Taiwan independence" forces, in order to resolutely safeguard China's national sovereignty and territorial integrity, Wu said.</p> <p> The remarks by the spokespersons came after a delegation composed of six US congressmen arrived in Taiwan for a stopover that analysts said targets the Chinese mainland with the "Taiwan card" and aims for more military sales to the island by hyping "mainland threats."</p> <p> Veteran anti-China politicians like Bob Menendez, chairman of the Senate foreign relations committee, and Republican member of the Senate budget committee Lindsey Graham were the two notable names in the delegation. They met with the island's regional leader Tsai Ing-wen on Friday.</p> <p> Spokesperson of China's Ministry of Foreign Affairs and the Taiwan Affairs Office of the State Council also slammed the US congressmen's Taiwan visit on Friday.</p> <p> <strong>Beyond deterrence</strong></p> <p> Song Zhongping, a military expert and TV commentator, told the Global Times on Friday that the PLA's operation is a large-scale joint combat exercise organized by the Eastern Theater Command and participated by not only the Navy and Air Force, but also likely other military arms and branches.</p> <p> It covered a wide region and was pointedly designed to solve the Taiwan question, including taking over the air superiority and the control of the sea, and all of the missions are integrated together, Song said. In addition to waters and aerial areas around the island of Taiwan, the drills also covered the forefront of the East China Sea, and that is because the PLA not only would need to take military actions against "Taiwan independence" forces and their armed forces, it might also have to face the potential military intervention by the US and Japan, he pointed out.</p> <p> The drills aimed to crush the reckless secessionist illusions, Song said, noting that attempts to deter Taiwan secessionists and their US support now seem to have little effect, and that is why the PLA has to prepare for a real military conflict, and if secessionists and their supporters cross the red line stated by the Anti-Secession Law, the PLA will resolutely turn the exercises and all of the plans into action, and solve the Taiwan question once and for all.</p> <p> If the US or Taiwan secessionists insist on making further provocations, the PLA could expand the drills in terms of both quality and quantity by adding more forces and more training courses, a Beijing-based military expert told the Global Times on Friday, requesting anonymity.</p> <p> Friday's patrols and drills mainly practiced taking control of air superiority and the sea and likely did not feature actual landing, as no amphibious landing ships were involved. It is also unknown if the drills practiced long-range precision strikes by the Army's long-range rocket artillery and the Rocket Force's DF ballistic and CJ cruise missiles, while the Navy's two aircraft carriers likely did not participate, observers said.</p> <p> It is only a matter of time for the PLA's most powerful equipment including the J-20 stealth fighter jets and aircraft carriers to join drills around Taiwan, analysts said.</p> <p> There is still room for the PLA to be better prepared for battle, and the secessionists and external forces should have a clear idea that the PLA has overwhelming advantages within the first island chain, the expert said.</p> <p> Earlier this month, media reports suggested that US House Speaker Nancy Pelosi could visit the island of Taiwan on April 10. But she then said she tested positive for COVID-19 and had to "postpone" her Asia trip.</p> <p> The PLA drills on Friday are also a warning to Pelosi, who could still visit Taiwan after her recovery. Analysts told the Global Times that more powerful measures from China await Pelosi if she does visit the island.</p> <p> Compared with previous reactions by the PLA, Friday's drills more concretely and clearly expressed China's statement that it would use force to safeguard sovereignty and territorial integrity, Zhuo Hua, an international affairs expert at the School of International Relations and Diplomacy of Beijing Foreign Studies University, told the Global Times on Friday.</p> <p> US politicians should fully realize the huge risks, as the China-US ties have entered a highly sensitive and complex period. It could be catastrophic to the peace and stability in East Asia if the US cannot contain its domestic faction struggle and makes more provocative moves related to the Taiwan question, Zhuo said.</p> <p> Wang Jianmin, a senior cross-Straits expert at Minnan Normal University, told the Global Times on Friday that unlike previous announcements that said the PLA's actions around the waters near the Taiwan island were routine, the Friday announcement said directly that the exercise was a response to the US' provocations over the Taiwan question.</p> <p> After the military conflict between Russia and Ukraine started, the US has intensified provocations over the Taiwan question as it wants to instigate a similar crisis on the island of Taiwan. The Chinese mainland should stay rational in the face of such strategy to prevent falling into the US' trap, but at the same time, the mainland should also clearly and stoutly show its firm resolution and capacity to reunify the country when it is necessary, Wang noted.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Ukraine opens 9 humanitarian corridors ]]></title>
	<news_id>10084835</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0416/c90000-10084835.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 10:29:24 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> KIEV, April 15 (Xinhua) -- Ukraine on Friday created nine humanitarian corridors to allow civilians to leave conflict-affected areas, Ukrainian Deputy Prime Minister Iryna Vereshchuk said on Telegram.</p> <p> The safe routes were established to allow civilians to flee Mariupol city in the eastern Donetsk region and Berdyansk, Tokmak and Energodar towns in the southern Zaporizhzhia region via private transport.</p> <p> Besides, the Ukrainian authorities will evacuate civilians from five towns and villages in the eastern Luhansk region.</p> <p> On Thursday, 2,557 people were evacuated from conflict-affected areas in Ukraine.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Ukraine says fighting for Mariupol continues ]]></title>
	<news_id>10084822</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0416/c90000-10084822.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 10:18:50 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> KIEV, April 15 (Xinhua) -- Ukrainian Defense Ministry's spokesman Olexandr Motuzyanyk said Friday that Ukrainian forces continued fighting with the Russian military for the Azov Sea key port city of Mariupol, the Ukrinform news agency reported.</p> <p> "The Russian army is constantly recruiting additional units to storm the city, and as of now there are active battles near the Ilyich plant and in the port zone of Mariupol," Motuzyanyk said.</p> <p> He emphasized that the Russian forces have not gained full control of the city after almost seven weeks since the siege began.</p> <p> The Ukrainian military recently carried out a tactical operation on joining the forces of two military units in Mariupol and now they are trying to unblock the city, Motuzyanyk said.</p> <p> On Wednesday, Ukrainian presidential advisor Oleksiy Arestovych said that the 36th Marine Brigade had broken fighting lines and joined the Azov Battalion in Mariupol, strengthening the defense of the city.</p> <p> Mariupol in eastern Ukraine saw one of the worst violence in the Russia-Ukraine conflict.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Serbia confirms procurement of Chinese FK-3 air defense missile system: media ]]></title>
	<news_id>10083820</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0414/c90000-10083820.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 09:25:57 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="Soldiers assigned to a surface-to-air missile brigade of the air force under the PLA Southern Theater Command operate a crane to hoist and load an air-defense missile onto a launching platform during a recent maneuver. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Yuan Hai and Xiang Kun)" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220414/92/10184973391560258352.jpg" style="height: 540px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Soldiers assigned to a surface-to-air missile brigade of the air force under the PLA Southern Theater Command operate a crane to hoist and load an air-defense missile onto a launching platform during a recent maneuver. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Yuan Hai and Xiang Kun)</em></p> <p> Serbia has procured the Chinese FK-3 air defense missile system, Serbian President Aleksandar Vucic reportedly confirmed on Wednesday, after reports emerged on Saturday that the Chinese People's Liberation Army (PLA) Air Force was delivering the air defense equipment via Y-20 large transport aircraft.</p> <p> As the export version of the PLA's HQ-22, the FK-3 can significantly enhance Serbia's national defense capabilities, at a time when NATO is dividing the world and could complicate the security situation around Serbia, Chinese analysts said on Wednesday.</p> <p> Serbia procured the Chinese FK-3 air defense missile system transparently, complying with laws and regulations, and it followed procedures, Vucic said, China Central Television (CCTV) reported on Wednesday. Vucic was accused by other politicians of "arming the country by the hands of competitors of Europe and NATO."</p> <p> Serbia has found its own path based on the will of its people, and the Serbian people are proud of themselves for protecting their own country by themselves rather than letting NATO do it in their names, Vucic was quoted in the CCTV report as saying.</p> <p> The CCTV report came after foreign reports said a large number of the PLA Air Force's Y-20 cargo planeswere spotted in Serbia on Saturday, and speculation claimed that the FK-3 air defense missile system was being delivered to the Serbian military.</p> <p> The FK-3 is an all-weather, medium-to-long range surface-to-air defense missile system that can carry out missions in complex electromagnetic environments. It can intercept targets including fixed-wing aircraft, drones, cruise missiles, tactical air-to-ground missiles and helicopters, according to promotional materials distributed at previous defense exhibitions.</p> <p> As a medium-altitude air defense weapon comparable to the US' Patriot air defense missile, the FK-3 missile system can serve as a powerful deterrent against aircraft including fighter jets and bombers that are on missions like defense penetration, precision strikes and bombing, Wang Ya'nan, chief editor of Aerospace Knowledge magazine, told the Global Times on Wednesday.</p> <p> It will play a very important role for Serbia at a time when the security situation in Europe is changing, Wang said. As the conflict between Russia and Ukraine goes on, many countries are gravitating toward or away from the West, and the US-led NATO is the one that is dividing the world, he said.</p> <p> Serbia has been a victim of air raids, so it is natural that the country invests in its air defense capabilities, analysts said. In 1999, NATO launched a 78-day bombing of Yugoslavia, causing thousands of casualties including three Chinese citizens, and displacing hundreds of thousands.</p> <p> As an air defense system, the FK-3 is defensive in nature, and it will not harm regional peace and stability, experts said.</p> <p> In order to carry out an annually scheduled cooperation project between China and Serbia, China recently sent transport aircraft of the PLA Air Force to Serbia to deliver normal military goods, Zhao Lijian, spokesperson of China's Ministry of Foreign Affairs, said at a regular press conference on Monday, when a reporter asked him to confirm if China recently delivered the HQ-22 air defense system to Serbia, and if the move was related to the current situation in Ukraine.</p> <p> This project is not targeted at any third party, nor is it related to the current situation, Zhao said, noting that media should not interpret it too much.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ US claims of China’s nukes ‘excuse for own expansion’ ]]></title>
	<news_id>10082908</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0412/c90000-10082908.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 15:02:10 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="DF-41 intercontinental ballistic missile Photo: Fan Lingzhi/GT" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220412/44/14202833386733832488.jpg" style="height: 573px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p align="center" class="pictext"> <em>DF-41 intercontinental ballistic missile Photo: Fan Lingzhi/GT</em></p> <p> US military leaders, politicians and media have been repeatedly hyping the so-called China nuclear arsenal expansion, highlighted recently again by a report by the Wall Street Journal, and these speculations are an excuse for the US to expand its own nuclear arsenal and push the "China threat" theory, Chinese experts said on Monday.</p> <p> China has accelerated the expansion of its nuclear arsenal because of a change in its assessment of the threat posed by the US, the Wall Street Journal reported on Saturday, citing people "with knowledge of the Chinese leadership's thinking."</p> <p> The report comes only days after Admiral Charles Richard, the head of US Strategic Command, claimed on April 5 that China's first test of an intercontinental ballistic missile-launched hypersonic glide vehicle last July is a "technological achievement with serious implications for strategic stability," as the hypersonic vehicle flew 40,000 kilometers for more than 100 minutes, marking "the greatest distance and longest flight time of any land attack weapon system of any nation to date," Richard wrote in the testimony, Bloomberg reported on April 5.</p> <p> Both the Wall Street Journal and Richard claimed that China has been building more than 100 suspected missile silos in China's remote western region that could be used to house nuclear-tipped missiles capable of reaching the US.</p> <p> These are pure speculations, and the US has been hyping this topic for a long time, and it is nothing new, Zhang Junshe, a senior research fellow at the Naval Research Academy of the People's Liberation Army, told the Global Times on Monday.</p> <p> By repeatedly hyping and building up tensions, the US is creating an excuse to expand its own nuclear arsenal, despite the US' nuclear triad leading China in both quality and quantity, Zhang said.</p> <p> The US is retiring its Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missiles that entered service in the 1960s, and is now developing the new Sentinel intercontinental ballistic missile. So it is obvious why the US is finding a reason for this upgrade, a Chinese nuclear strategy expert told the Global Times.</p> <p> Xu Guangyu, a Chinese military expert, told the Global Times on Monday that the US relies on its nuclear capability to maintain its hegemony, so it wants to use the "China threat" theory as an excuse.</p> <p> The eastward expansion of the US-led NATO would ultimately aim to not only contain Russia, but also China, so hyping China's so-called nuclear expansion is also a way to hype the "China threat" theory, Xu said.</p> <p> Fu Cong, Director General of the Arms Control Department at the Chinese Foreign Ministry, said in a media briefing in Januarythat China has no plans to drastically expand its nuclear arsenal but will continue to modernize it under the changing security environment.</p> <p> China is the only major nuclear power in the world to announce the no-first-use policy, and it maintains the minimum level of nuclear capability required to safeguard national sovereignty and territorial integrity, Zhang said, noting that facing the current needs in national defense, China needs to continue to develop its nuclear arsenal, and the US is exaggerating it.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Spotting of six Y-20 cargo planes in Serbia 'displays China's strategic transport capabilities' ]]></title>
	<news_id>10082180</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0411/c90000-10082180.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 09:06:49 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="A Y-20 large transport aircraft attached to an aviation division under the PLA Western Theater Command flies at a predetermined altitude during a flight training mission on January 4, 2021. (eng.chianmil.com.cn/Photo by Liu Shu)" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220411/64/18424485452652925940.jpg" style="height: 540px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>A Y-20 large transport aircraft attached to an aviation division under the PLA Western Theater Command flies at a predetermined altitude during a flight training mission on January 4, 2021. (eng.chianmil.com.cn/Photo by Liu Shu)</em></p> <p> A fleet of six Y-20 cargo planes of the Chinese People's Liberation Army (PLA) Air Force was reportedly spotted in Serbia on Saturday, with observers saying on Sunday that it could be the largest overseas operation by the Chinese domestically developed large transport plane yet, displaying the country's strategic transport capabilities.</p> <p> Citing commercial flight trackers, US news website thedrive.com reported on Saturday that the six Y-20 aircraft were first spotted heading west in Turkish airspace late Friday night, and later local residents took photos of the Y-20s, which allegedly landed in Nikola Tesla Airport in Belgrade, Serbia. The aircraft later flew over the Bosphorus Strait in Turkey again on their way back to China.</p> <p> China has not made an official announcement about the mission as of press time, but the Global Times learned that the Y-20s indeed have carried out such a flight.</p> <p> A whopping six Y-20 large transport aircraft could mark an unprecedented overseas operation, Chinese military observers said.</p> <p> It is a new record that an overseas mission features six Y-20s, and it is also very rare to see so many Y-20s being deployed at the same time, Fu Qianshao, a Chinese military aviation expert, told the Global Times on Sunday.</p> <p> The mission reflects a significant improvement in the PLA Air Force's long-range strategic transport capabilities, as well as the large transport aircraft's logistics support and maintenance capabilities in intercontinental flights, Fu said.</p> <p> It is more difficult to organize a large fleet featuring six Y-20s compared with only one or two of the aircraft, Song Zhongping, a Chinese military expert and TV commentator, told the Global Times on Sunday.</p> <p> China has used the Y-20 for several missions to Europe in the past. For example, the PLA used a Y-20 to carry 105 members of the PLA honor guardto join the Russian Victory Day parade held in Moscow in June 2020.</p> <p> Unlike just flying to Russia, it would need the Y-20s to fly through several other countries in order to reach Serbia from China, so China must have had much coordination and communication with these countries and gained their authorization in order to realize the flight, Song said.</p> <p> The mission of the Y-20s to Serbia remains unknown, with thedrive.com speculating that the aircraft could be delivering the FK-3, the export version of the Chinese HQ-22 surface-to-air missile system, to Serbia.</p> <p> Analysts told the Global Times that the cargo must be large and heavy to require as many as six Y-20s.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China strongly opposes latest US arms sales to Taiwan; PLA vows to take powerful measures ]]></title>
	<news_id>10081154</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0407/c90000-10081154.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 16:46:37 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="Two Su-35 fighter jets and an H-6K bomber fly in formation on May 11, 2018. The People's Liberation Army (PLA) air force conducted patrol training over China's island of Taiwan.(Photo: Xinhua)" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220407/10/6263088319687186674.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Two Su-35 fighter jets and an H-6K bomber fly in formation on May 11, 2018. The People's Liberation Army (PLA) air force conducted patrol training over China's island of Taiwan.(Photo: Xinhua)</em></p> <p> China strongly opposes US approval of a $95-million package including technical assistance of Patriot missiles to China's Taiwan region, which severely violates the one-China principle &amp;3 joint communiqués and rudely interferes in China's internal affairs: Defense Ministry.</p> <p> The PLA will take powerful measures, resolutely defeat all external interference and "Taiwan independence" secessionist attempts and firmly safeguard national sovereignty and territorial integrity: Defense Ministry.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ U.S. reveals test of hypersonic missile in mid-March ]]></title>
	<news_id>10080490</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0406/c90000-10080490.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 14:20:25 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> WASHINGTON, April 5 (Xinhua) -- The United States revealed on Tuesday a recent test of a hypersonic weapon.</p> <p> The test that took place in mid-March was kept quiet for two weeks to "avoid escalating tensions with Russia," CNN reported, citing a U.S. defense official familiar with the matter.</p> <p> The Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) -- the Pentagon's research and development branch -- said that they completed a free flight test of the Hypersonic Air-breathing Weapon Concept (HAWC).</p> <p> This is the second successful flight in the DARPA's HAWC program. Last September, a different vehicle configuration from another contractor team also reached hypersonic flight.</p> <p> The HAWC is a cooperation program between the DARPA and U.S. Air Force to develop air-launched hypersonic cruise missiles.</p> <p> Air-breathing vehicles utilize air captured from the atmosphere to achieve sustained propulsion.</p> <p> The speed and maneuverability of such hypersonic cruise missiles allow both evasion of defenses and quick strikes.</p> <p> In the defense budget for the fiscal year 2023, the White House asked for 7.2 billion U.S. dollars for developing and fielding long range fires, including hypersonic missiles.</p> <p> A U.S. government agency has identified 70 efforts related to the development of hypersonic weapons, expected to cost nearly 15 billion dollars between 2015 and 2024.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese defense spending open, transparent: spokesperson ]]></title>
	<news_id>10078699</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0401/c90000-10078699.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 09:05:59 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, March 31 (Xinhua) -- A Chinese military spokesperson on Thursday refuted malicious accusations regarding China's defense budget from some Western officials and media outlets, stressing that Chinese military spending is open and transparent.</p> <p> The growth of China's military strength helps maintain world peace, while the United States is the main culprit and backstage manipulator in undermining world peace and stability, said Wu Qian, spokesperson for China's Ministry of National Defense.</p> <p> The wars launched by the United States in Iraq, Afghanistan and other countries have resulted in severe civilian casualties and loss of property, leading to huge humanitarian disasters, he noted.</p> <p> The United States has ranked first in military spending for years, accounting for about a quarter of the world's total, the spokesperson said, adding that the United States has the world's largest and most advanced nuclear arsenal and is the only country with chemical weapons stockpiles.</p> <p> China's socialist system, strategic decision to follow the path of peaceful development, its independent foreign policy of peace, and its cultural traditions of considering peace and harmony as fundamentals determine that the country will pursue a national defense policy that is defensive in nature, Wu said.</p> <p> The spokesperson also slammed Japan for hyping up China's "lack of transparency" on defense expenditure.</p> <p> China has been submitting reports on its military expenditure to the United Nations every year since 2008, Wu stressed.</p> <p> Japan's groundless criticism of China's defense budget aims to seek excuses for its military expansion and breaking the post-war international order, he said.</p> <p> Japan has consistently increased its defense budget in recent years to develop high-end weapons and create tensions, which is very dangerous and has aroused the high vigilance of the international community, Wu noted.</p> <p> "We urge Japan to draw lessons from history and be cautious in its words and deeds on military security," he said.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China issues new regulations on management of soldiers ]]></title>
	<news_id>10078149</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0331/c90000-10078149.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 09:46:09 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, March 30 (Xinhua) -- With the approval of Xi Jinping, chairman of the Central Military Commission (CMC), the CMC has issued a series of new regulations on the management of People's Liberation Army (PLA) soldiers.</p> <p> The interim regulations on non-commissioned officers and conscripts, together with several supporting documents issued by the CMC, are aimed at enhancing professionalism and stability among non-commissioned officers, while allowing conscripts to play a more fundamental role in the development of China's military talent, the military authorities said.</p> <p> They will also help boost the management of PLA soldiers by perfecting the recruitment, training, rank promotion, benefits and demobilization system for non-commissioned officers and conscripts, and will play a vital role in building a high-quality military that follows the leadership of the Communist Party of China, the authorities said.</p> <p> The new regulations will all go into effect on March 31.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ PLA fighter jets hold cross-regional drills over 5,000km, show capabilities ]]></title>
	<news_id>10078138</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0331/c90000-10078138.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 09:39:06 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="A fighter jet attached to an aviation brigade under the PLA Air Force soars into the sky in a flight training exercise on March 8, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Cui Baoliang) " src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220331/68/17562211299969600928.jpg" style="height: 540px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>A fighter jet attached to an aviation brigade under the PLA Air Force soars into the sky in a flight training exercise on March 8, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Cui Baoliang)</em></p> <p> The Chinese People's Liberation Army (PLA) Air Force recently organized a cross-day-and-night, cross-regional maneuver exercise that saw multiple types of fighter jets flying across more than 5,000 kilometers in less than 20 hours, covering different terrains including plateaus and the sea, demonstrating not only the outstanding capabilities of the pilots and warplanes, but also the strong logistics support capabilities of all air bases involved, experts said on Wednesday.</p> <p> Starting the drills, warplanes including the J-11B and the J-11BS attached to a brigade affiliated with the PLA Air Force took off from an air base in Central China and headed toward an unfamiliar region thousands of kilometers away, China Central Television (CCTV) reported on Tuesday.</p> <p> During the maneuver, the aircraft formation penetrated mock hostile aerial defenses, flew from the plains to the sea, and arrived at the designated air base overcoming fatigue from the extended flight, CCTV reported.</p> <p> As night fell, the warplanes took off again and started another long-endurance flight and maneuver to another air base, the report said, noting that the whole cross-regional maneuver exercise lasted nearly 20 hours.</p> <p> "We carried out this long-range flight not only throughout the day and night, but also took off and landed at many unfamiliar air bases. We flew across a variety of terrains with a total range of more than 5,000 kilometers, as the pilots had to deal with not only weather changes as they flew across different regions, but also unexpected mock combat challenges along the way," Guo Enyun, the commander of the brigade, said on CCTV.</p> <p> A distance of 5,000 kilometers means that, if flying in a straight line, a plane can travel across the entire country, observers said.</p> <p> "The exercises lasted from the day to early morning as we went through terrains like plains, plateaus and the sea. This honed both our will and skill under realistic combat scenarios," Zhong Haifeng, a pilot at the brigade, was quoted in the report as saying.</p> <p> The flight paths used in the drills were designed to be close to real combat, as different terrains were taken into consideration in defense penetration and air assault sessions, Gao Ruipeng, a staff officer at the brigade, said in the report.</p> <p> The mock combat sessions were organized without the red and blue teams knowing each other's plans, and this exercised the pilots' air-to-ground combat and attack capabilities, Gao said.</p> <p> China is a large country with all kinds of terrains, and fast-flying warplanes may travel across all those places in a short time, Fu Qianshao, a Chinese military aviation expert, told the Global Times on Wednesday.</p> <p> The exercise has demonstrated the outstanding skills of the pilots, who can operate from air bases in different terrains, altitudes, temperatures and weather conditions, which have a huge impact on how aircraft perform, Fu said. It also showed the strong logistics support capabilities of all air bases, which would need to carry out maintenance, refuel and munitions reloading for the aircraft that are not based there.</p> <p> Aircraft from other regions of China can support the region where reinforcements are needed, analysts said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese military to award August 1 Medal to outstanding personnel ]]></title>
	<news_id>10077429</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0330/c90000-10077429.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 08:10:06 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, March 29 (Xinhua) -- With approval from Xi Jinping, chairman of the Central Military Commission (CMC), the CMC will award the August 1 Medal to outstanding personnel on the occasion of the 95th anniversary of the founding of the Chinese People's Liberation Army (PLA).</p> <p> The August 1 Medal, conferred by the CMC chairman, is the highest honor in the Chinese military. It is granted to those military personnel who have made outstanding contributions to safeguarding national sovereignty, security and development interests, and to advancing the modernization of national defense and the armed forces.</p> <p> Priority consideration will be given to model figures who emerge on the country's great journey of strengthening its armed forces under Xi's leadership, the military authorities said.</p> <p> The CMC general office has issued guidelines for the medal nomination, urging military units at all levels to select model figures in the building of a world-class military in the new era.</p> <p> The 95th anniversary of the founding of the PLA will be marked on Aug. 1 this year.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ US increases presence in S. China Sea ]]></title>
	<news_id>10077191</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0329/c90000-10077191.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 10:42:31 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220329/5/14953338109708293661.jpg" style="height: 503px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Fishing boats sail across the Qiongzhou Strait as the summer fishing moratorium ended in the South China Sea, Aug 16, 2021. [Photo/Xinhua]</em></p> <p> <strong>Drills expand in scale and frequency, focus on preparing for real combat, report says</strong></p> <p> From massive military drills to record spy plane activities, the United States military drastically intensified its presence in the South China Sea last year, which serves to undermine China's security interests and increase the risk of friction in the region, according to Chinese experts.</p> <p> A report published on Sunday by the South China Sea Strategic Situation Probing Initiative, a Beijing-based think tank tracking US military operations with open source data, said the US carried out at least 95 military exercises in the South China Sea last year, 10 more than in 2019.</p> <p> In August 2021, the US, along with Australia, the United Kingdom and Japan, carried out "Large Scale Exercise 21", its largest naval exercise in 40 years, involving around 25,000 military personnel operating across 17 time zones from Europe to Asia.</p> <p> Hu Bo, director of the think tank, said the US military has maintained a fairly strong presence near China since 1949, but in recent years it has considerably ramped up its operations in the region and made them more public.</p> <p> These US military drills not only saw expanding scale and frequency, but also focused on preparing for real combat, with China being the clear target, according to the report.</p> <p> Around 1,200 sorties of maritime patrol and reconnaissance aircraft conducted close-in intelligence gathering over the South China Sea last year, the report said.</p> <p> The US set multiple records in November, including 94 sorties, the greatest number in a single month, and 10 flights, which was the highest number in a single day.</p> <p> In addition, November also saw the US reach its closest surveillance distance to China's territorial water baseline at 15.9 nautical miles, or around 29 kilometers, said the report. Twelve nautical miles outward from this baseline is China's territorial sea, while water inside the baseline is considered inland waters.</p> <p> "The US is continuously setting records in terms of the distance between its reconnaissance aircraft and China's territorial sea baseline, which poses increasingly high military risks," the report said.</p> <p> Meanwhile, US ocean surveillance ships and maritime survey vessels carried out operations for a total of 419 sea days. A sea day is a day spent in transit between port calls.</p> <p> This meant that there was always at least one of these vessels operating in the South China Sea throughout the entire year, according to the report.</p> <p> Regarding activities by strategic military forces, the US sent amphibious landing and carrier strike groups to the South China Sea on 12 occasions in 2021, nearly double the previous year's total. Nuclear submarines also made at least 11 transits through the waters, along with 22 sorties by B-1B and B-52H strategic bombers.</p> <p> Hu said the US' "Indo-Pacific strategy" is deeply related to geopolitics and its desire to maintain maritime dominance in the region. As a result, the US will most likely continue to intensify its military activities near China, such as in the South China Sea, the East China Sea and the Taiwan Straits, he added.</p> <p> Meanwhile, the US is also encouraging and coordinating its allies, including Japan and Australia, to bolster their military capabilities and continue to stir up trouble in the South China Sea, he said.</p> <p> This trend is already in motion given the fact that Japan took part last year in 61 joint military drills with the US, while Australia announced it would acquire eight nuclear submarines with help from the US and the UK.</p> <p> "Japan has become the vanguard of the US' 'Indo-Pacific strategy', which will further support US military operations in the South China Sea," the report said. Australia's acquisition of a nuclear submarine capability will "very likely induce a new round of arms race in the region or even across the globe, and cast a shadow over peace and stability in the South China Sea".</p> <p> Hu said one of the ramifications of Washington's drastically increased military activities is that its military hardware and personnel would be severely stretched, leading to a greater risk of accidents and friction in the South China Sea.</p> <p> Recent examples include the USS Connecticut nuclear submarine colliding with an uncharted seamount in the South China Sea last year, and an F-35C fighter jet crashing on an aircraft carrier operating in the region in January.</p> <p> "In an era of peace, if one country maintains such a powerful military presence close to another country, it is hard for the former to convince people that it is doing it for peaceful purposes," Hu said.</p> <p> Washington's increased military operations pose a serious threat to China's sovereignty and national security, he said, China will therefore be forced to take necessary measures in response.</p> <p> Xia Liping, dean of the Institute of International and Public Affairs at Tongji University in Shanghai, said that even as the Ukraine crisis unfolds, the US military has not scaled down its activities in the South China Sea, highlighted by frequent transits of its carrier strike groups and drills in January and February.</p> <p> "The US views China as a long-term competitor, therefore it is willing to focus its maritime forces in the Asia-Pacific region," Xia said, adding that the increased military activities and the subsequent reporting and hype by US officials and media are also aimed at painting China as a regional threat.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ US, Philippines hold largest joint military drills in years ‘with different goals’ ]]></title>
	<news_id>10077060</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0329/c90000-10077060.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 09:24:47 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="Filipino soldiers participate in the Amphibious Landing training as part of the 2018 Balikatan Exercises between the Philippines and the United States in Zambales Province, the Philippines, on May 9, 2018.(Xinhua/Rouelle Umali) " src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220329/99/1037192312352142987.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Filipino soldiers participate in the Amphibious Landing training as part of the 2018 Balikatan Exercises between the Philippines and the United States in Zambales Province, the Philippines, on May 9, 2018.(Xinhua/Rouelle Umali)</em></p> <p> The US and the Philippines kicked off one of their largest joint exercises in years on Monday in a region where US media hyped them as facing Taiwan and the South China Sea, but experts pointed out that the Philippines will not become a pawn of the US after seeing what the US has done in Ukraine and Afghanistan.</p> <p> Codenamed Balikatan 2022, the annual joint military drills include 3,800 Filipino and 5,100 US military personnel, making it the largest iteration of the Philippines-US joint drills since 2015, the Xinhua News Agency reported.</p> <p> Balikatan 2022 will be conducted across the main Luzon island from Monday to April 8, Xinhua reported, noting that the drills will focus on "maritime security, amphibious operations, live-fire training, urban operations, aviation operations, counterterrorism, and humanitarian assistance and disaster relief."</p> <p> US media reports, including one by the AP on Monday, hyped that the drills will be a showcase of US firepower in the northern Philippines near the sea border with the island of Taiwan and also facing the South China Sea.</p> <p> "China will likely frown on the war drills, given their relative proximity to Taiwan," the AP claimed.</p> <p> However, the AP report also quoted Philippine military spokesperson Colonel Ramon Zagala as saying that the exercise is "for mutual defense, never for offense," and that "most of the military maneuvers have been planned a year ago and did not consider the recurring tensions in the Taiwan Straits."</p> <p> Cagayan Governor Manuel Mamba told the AP that "We have to engage China, but not in a war, because I know Taiwan is a powder keg." Cagayan is where amphibious landings with limited live-fire maneuvers are scheduled to be held this week.</p> <p> Some Philippine politicians also expressed concerns that the exercise might threaten regional security, Xinhua reported, quoting presidential candidate and labor leader Ka Leody de Guzman as saying that the Philippines should pursue an independent foreign policy, stressing that the country should not be a "pawn."</p> <p> By holding the drills, the US is trying to fan the flames and stir up troubles in the Asia-Pacific and benefit from it, just like it has done with the Ukraine crisis, Zhang Junshe, a senior research fellow at the Naval Research Academy of the People's Liberation Army, told the Global Times on Monday.</p> <p> From a geopolitical point of view, the US is aiming to deter China by rallying more allies and partners, and from an economic point of view, the US wants to sell weapons and equipment to the region, Zhang said.</p> <p> But judging from the remarks made by the Philippine side, the Southeast Asian country is not going to become a strategic pawn of the US after seeing what the US has done recently in Ukraine and Afghanistan, Zhang said, noting that the Philippines wants to enhance its troops' capabilities but not for offensive purposes.</p> <p> Ding Duo, a deputy director of the Research Center for Oceans Law and Policy at China's National Institute for South China Sea Studies, warned that despite the ongoing Ukraine crisis, the US is still hyping the situation in the South China Sea, which is a reflection that the US has set its eyes firmly on the Indo-Pacific region.</p> <p> The US could be seeking a proxy in the region to lead from the front in confronting China, just like what it has done with Ukraine, Ding warned.</p> <p> China must stay on high alert over US' tactic that could destabilize the region, although countries within the region should see US' intent clearly, the experts said.</p> <p> The foreign ministers of Indonesia, Thailand, the Philippines, Myanmar and Panama will visit China from Thursday to April 4, according to a Monday statement by Wang Wenbin, a spokesperson at China's Ministry of Foreign Affairs.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ US practices new war concepts with 100+ drills near China: think tank report ]]></title>
	<news_id>10076639</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0328/c90000-10076639.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 09:21:38 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="A ship-borne helicopter attached to a frigate flotilla with the navy under the PLA Southern Theater Command lands on the flight deck of the guided-missile frigate Wuzhou (Hull 626) under the guidance of a sailor during a maritime fire-fighting training operation in early December, 2021.Photo:China Military" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220328/14/35858552814709338.jpg" style="height: 540px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>A ship-borne helicopter attached to a frigate flotilla with the navy under the PLA Southern Theater Command lands on the flight deck of the guided-missile frigate Wuzhou (Hull 626) under the guidance of a sailor during a maritime fire-fighting training operation in early December, 2021. Photo:China Military</em></p> <p> The US held more than 100 large-scale military exercises near China last year, practicing and validating several new war concepts targeting the country, a Beijing-based think tank revealed on Sunday, shortly before the US and the Philippines are reportedly about to launch the "largest-ever" joint drills on Monday.</p> <p> A major reason behind the extensive drills with new tactics is that the US is aiming to contain China but is faced with the rapid development of the Chinese People's Liberation Army (PLA), and the US military is worried that its traditional instruments of war are becoming obsolete facing the PLA, analysts said.</p> <p> Based on publicly available information, the US military conducted 95 exercises in and near the South China Sea in 2021, with the actual number exceeding 100, the South China Sea Strategic Situation Probing Initiative (SCSPI) said in a report released on Sunday.</p> <p> Among the 95 drills, 14 consisted solely of arms of the US military, including the Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Army and Coast Guard. They featured training courses including anti-ship, anti-submarine, anti-sea mine, amphibious, cyberspace and maritime situational awareness missions.</p> <p> The other 81 were joint exercises with other countries including those along the coastlines of the South China Sea as well as those from outside the region including Japan, the UK, Australia, India, France and Canada, the SCSPI report said, noting that both the frequency and scale of the drills reached new highs.</p> <p> In 2021, the US military successively sent strategic platforms including four carrier strike groups, two amphibious ready groups, 11 nuclear-powered attack submarines and carried out 22 bombers sorties. This was in addition to conducting at least 1,200 aerial close-in reconnaissance sorties with large spy aircraft and 419 ship days of maritime survey and surveillance with spy ships to the South China Sea, with an obvious intent to deter China, the SCSPI said.</p> <p> The US also tried to validate some of its new war concepts like multi-domain operations, expeditionary advanced base operations, distributed maritime operations and littoral operations in a contested environment, as the US now acknowledges that China has the edge in the air and sea within the first island chain, the SCSPI said, citing US documents on the Indo-Pacific Strategy.</p> <p> The reason why the US military is developing new war concepts is that it knows all established US military bases, including those in Japan and South Korea as well as aircraft carriers, are no longer secure, so it needs more bases and it also needs to make them more mobile in a more distributed manner, Song Zhongping, a Chinese military expert and TV commentator, told the Global Times on Sunday.</p> <p> The US military is worried and panicked to see the growing combat capabilities of the PLA as the gap between them narrows quickly, so the US is looking not only at developing a new generation of weapons and equipment, but also creating new tactics and ways to engage in combat, Song said.</p> <p> New technologies, including standoff hypersonic weapons, antiballistic missile technologies, precision strike and missile defense systems, new maritime combat systems, directed energy weapons, next-generation nuclear-powered attack submarines and destroyers are all under development by the US, the SCSPI said.</p> <p> While the US is attempting to deter its imagined possibility of a "China expansion" by a frontier military presence, excessive deterrence would only result in more resolute countermeasures from China, and that will be the opposite of what the US wants, the SCSPI said.</p> <p> Deterrence and countermeasures as well as provocation and counter-provocation will be major strategic and tactical questions China and the US will have to deal with in the future, the report said.</p> <p> The report was released only one day before the annual US-Philippines Balikatan Exercise was scheduled to kick off. Media report said this year's Balikatan Exercise would be the "largest-ever," with about 5,100 US military personnel and 3,800 personnel from the Philippines participating from Monday to April 8 across Luzon.</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="In 2021, the US military strategy and operation on the South China Sea is featured by deterrence----strengthening forward military presence and targeted activities, to deter the imaginary “China might overreach”." src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220328/20/12291434871472235652.jpg" style="height: 2375px; width: 500px;" /></p> <p> <em>In 2021, the US military strategy and operation on the South China Sea is featured by deterrence----strengthening forward military presence and targeted activities, to deter the imaginary “China might overreach”.</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Air force aviation brigade conducts night flight training ]]></title>
	<news_id>9976134</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0325/c90000-9976134.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 16:48:08 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0325/FOREIGN202203251628000536735499031.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> A fighter jet attached to an aviation brigade under the PLA Air Force soars into the sky in a flight training exercise on March 8, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Cui Baoliang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0325/FOREIGN202203251628000162406216265.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> A fighter jet attached to an aviation brigade under the PLA Air Force soars into the sky in a flight training exercise on March 8, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Cui Baoliang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0325/FOREIGN202203251627000381446132757.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> A fighter jet attached to an aviation brigade under the PLA Air Force soars into the sky in a flight training exercise on March 8, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Cui Baoliang)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0325/FOREIGN202203251627000028385976786.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 506px;" /></p> <p> A ground crew member assigned to an aviation brigade under the PLA Air Force guides a fight jet to the runway after a night flight training exercise on March 8, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Cui Baoliang)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Military Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese military vows resolute countermeasures against provocation to destabilize Taiwan Strait ]]></title>
	<news_id>9975749</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0325/c90000-9975749.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 08:37:02 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, March 24 (Xinhua) -- A Chinese military spokesperson on Thursday said the Chinese People's Liberation Army stands ready to take all necessary means to resolutely counteract any provocation that undermines China's core interests and destabilizes the Taiwan Strait.</p> <p> Wu Qian, spokesperson for China's Ministry of National Defense, made the remarks in response to attempts of Taiwan's Democratic Progressive Party to link Ukraine issue with Taiwan question and the speculation of mainland's "military threat" by some U.S. politicians.</p> <p> Wu said Taiwan is not Ukraine, as the Taiwan question is China's internal affair that brooks no foreign interference.</p> <p> No individual or force can stand in the way of China's reunification, he added.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Scouts participate in reconnaissance ability assessment ]]></title>
	<news_id>9975478</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0324/c90000-9975478.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 11:14:10 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0324/FOREIGN202203241053000241528968466.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> Scouts assigned to a reconnaissance detachment of a brigade under the PLA Xizang Military Command run through the valley with full gears during a reconnaissance ability assessment on March 11, 2022. The assessment was aimed at verifying the troops' combat capability. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Yang Kai)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0324/FOREIGN202203241053000361749292246.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> Scouts assigned to a reconnaissance detachment of a brigade under the PLA Xizang Military Command run through the valley with full gears during a reconnaissance ability assessment on March 11, 2022. The assessment was aimed at verifying the troops' combat capability. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Yang Kai)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0324/FOREIGN202203241053000478060684922.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> Scouts assigned to a reconnaissance detachment of a brigade under the PLA Xizang Military Command run through the valley with full gears during a reconnaissance ability assessment on March 11, 2022. The assessment was aimed at verifying the troops' combat capability. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Yang Kai)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0324/FOREIGN202203241053000588479616520.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 603px;" /></p> <p> A scout assigned to a reconnaissance detachment of a brigade under the PLA Xizang Military Command rappels down the cliff during a reconnaissance ability assessment on March 11, 2022. The assessment was aimed at verifying the troops' combat capability. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Yang Kai)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Military Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Pakistan marks Republic Day with military parade ]]></title>
	<news_id>9975235</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0324/c90000-9975235.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 08:46:37 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220324/31/17048290025651419275.png" style="width: 900px; height: 599px;" /></p> <p> Pakistani jets perform during the Pakistan Day military parade in Islamabad, capital of Pakistan on March 23, 2022. Pakistan Day, also known as the Pakistan Resolution Day or Republic Day, is celebrated annually on March 23. (Xinhua/Ahmad Kamal)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220324/81/1285437906605624341.png" style="width: 900px; height: 599px;" /></p> <p> Pakistani fighter jets perform during the Pakistan Day military parade in Islamabad, capital of Pakistan on March 23, 2022. Pakistan Day, also known as the Pakistan Resolution Day or Republic Day, is celebrated annually on March 23. (Xinhua/Ahmad Kamal)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220324/12/14088173510344143388.png" style="height: 599px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> A Pakistani fighter jet performs during the Pakistan Day military parade in Islamabad, capital of Pakistan on March 23, 2022. Pakistan Day, also known as the Pakistan Resolution Day or Republic Day, is celebrated annually on March 23. (Xinhua/Ahmad Kamal)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220324/89/13609019810972151321.png" style="width: 533px; height: 800px;" /></p> <p> A Pakistani jet performs during the Pakistan Day military parade in Islamabad, capital of Pakistan on March 23, 2022. Pakistan Day, also known as the Pakistan Resolution Day or Republic Day, is celebrated annually on March 23. (Xinhua/Ahmad Kamal)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220324/67/16335801178126244859.png" style="height: 599px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Pakistani jets perform during the Pakistan Day military parade in Islamabad, capital of Pakistan on March 23, 2022. Pakistan Day, also known as the Pakistan Resolution Day or Republic Day, is celebrated annually on March 23. (Xinhua/Ahmad Kamal)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220324/60/7688090560836002568.png" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Pakistani jets perform during the Pakistan Day military parade in Islamabad, capital of Pakistan on March 23, 2022. Pakistan Day, also known as the Pakistan Resolution Day or Republic Day, is celebrated annually on March 23. (Xinhua/Ahmad Kamal)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220324/22/9784559679774206910.png" style="width: 603px; height: 800px;" /></p> <p> Pakistani jets perform during the Pakistan Day military parade in Islamabad, capital of Pakistan on March 23, 2022. Pakistan Day, also known as the Pakistan Resolution Day or Republic Day, is celebrated annually on March 23. (Xinhua/Ahmad Kamal)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220324/29/9333329749056607941.png" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Parachutists perform during the Pakistan Day military parade in Islamabad, capital of Pakistan on March 23, 2022. Pakistan Day, also known as the Pakistan Resolution Day or Republic Day, is celebrated annually on March 23. (Xinhua/Ahmad Kamal)</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220324/1/6682414421830921701.png" style="height: 599px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> Pakistani jets perform during the Pakistan Day military parade in Islamabad, capital of Pakistan on March 23, 2022. Pakistan Day, also known as the Pakistan Resolution Day or Republic Day, is celebrated annually on March 23. (Xinhua/Ahmad Kamal)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ US admiral hypes ‘China militarization’ in S.China Sea ]]></title>
	<news_id>9974260</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0322/c90000-9974260.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 08:55:21 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> <strong>Move a political farce to copy Ukraine crisis in Asia-Pacific: analysts</strong></p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="The amphibious dock landing ships Wuzhishan (Hull 987), Kunlunshan (Hull 998) and Changbaishan (Hull 989) attached to a landing ship flotilla with the navy under the PLA Southern Theater Command steam alongside in waters of the South China Sea during a maritime training exercise on November 18, 2020. The exercise lasted four days, focusing on 10 subjects including comprehensive defense, Landing Craft Air Cushion's (LCAC) transfer, visit, board, search and seizure (VBSS) operation, and live-fire operations. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Liu Jian)" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220322/58/11559823044131715102.jpg" style="height: 540px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>The amphibious dock landing ships Wuzhishan (Hull 987), Kunlunshan (Hull 998) and Changbaishan (Hull 989) attached to a landing ship flotilla with the navy under the PLA Southern Theater Command steam alongside in waters of the South China Sea during a maritime training exercise on November 18, 2020. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Liu Jian)</em></p> <p> A top US military commander on Sunday again hyped the so-called militarization by China in the South China Sea by personally participating in an aerial close-in reconnaissance on Chinese islands and reefs in the region together with journalists, which is a move that Chinese analysts said on Monday could be a political farce attempting to copy the Ukraine crisis in the Asia-Pacific, rallying allies, partners and other countries in the region to confront China.</p> <p> US Indo-Pacific Commander Admiral John C. Aquilino claimed on Sunday that China has "fully militarized" at least three of several islands it built in the South China Sea by arming them with anti-ship and anti-aircraft missile systems, laser and jamming equipment, and fighter jets, "in an increasingly aggressive move that threatens all nations operating nearby," AP reported on Monday.</p> <p> Aquilino made the remarks on board a US Navy P-8A reconnaissance aircraft that flew near the Nansha Islands, including the Meiji, Zhubi and Yongshu reefs, and the aircraft was repeatedly warned by Chinese callers that it illegally entered Chinese territory and should move away, AP reported.</p> <p> While claiming that the US' main objective in the region is "to prevent war" through deterrence and promote peace and stability, Aquilino said that the US is prepared to fight and win "should deterrence fail," with AP noting that Aquilino leads the largest US command with 380,000 military and civilian personnel covering 36 nations and territories.</p> <p> The Nansha Islands and adjacent waters are Chinese territories and China has sovereignty over them. It is China's rights to construct necessary facilities on its own territory to safeguard sovereignty and territorial integrity, just like any other country does, Ding Duo, deputy director of the Research Center for Oceans Law and Policy at China's National Institute for South China Sea Studies, told the Global Times on Monday.</p> <p> The biggest pusher of militarization in the South China Sea is the US, as the US military has been frequently conducting military operations in the South China Sea even if the country is far from the region, Ding said.</p> <p> "It is not reasonable that the US disallows China to deploy defensive military facilities on its own territory, while at the same time the US sends warships and warplanes to China's doorsteps in the South China Sea on a daily basis," Ding said.</p> <p> In 2021, US large spy planes carried out about 1,200 aerial close-in reconnaissance sorties on China, with some of them coming near 20 nautical miles of the Chinese mainland's territorial baseline. US aircraft carrier strike groups and amphibious ready groups entered the South China Sea 13 times, more than doubling the activities of 2020, and at least 11 US nuclear-powered attack submarines were spotted in or near the South China Sea, including the Seawolf-class USS Connecticut, which had an accident in the region, according to monitoring from the South China Sea Strategic Situation Probing Initiative, a Beijing-based think tank.</p> <p> US warships also repeatedly trespassed into China's territorial waters in the South China Sea, leading to countermeasures by the Chinese People's Liberation Army (PLA) to warn them away.</p> <p> Fu Qianshao, a Chinese military expert, told the Global Times on Monday that these provocative US activities could gather intelligence on the PLA, while also prepare the US for a potential military conflict with China.</p> <p> It is necessary for China to make proper constructions to safeguard national sovereignty, security and territorial integrity, and the US has no right to make irresponsible remarks on this, Fu said, noting that the US has made Guam the world's largest island military base, and also built many military bases in countries like Japan and South Korea.</p> <p> The US is using rouge logic and applying double standards, which make no sense, analysts said.</p> <p> Despite the ongoing Ukraine crisis, the US is still hyping the situation in the South China Sea, which is a reflection that the US has set its eye firmly in the Indo-Pacific region, Ding said.</p> <p> In addition to the increasing US military activities in the South China Sea, including drills, reconnaissance operations and military exchanges with countries in the region, the US may also attempt to stir up trouble in the international public opinion and diplomatic fields, Ding warned.</p> <p> It could be just like what the US has done with Ukraine, as it could seek a proxy in the region to lead from the front in confronting China, with others following, Ding predicted.</p> <p> By flying personally to the South China Sea with journalists, Aquilino is staging a political farce to win attention and again build up tensions in the region after the world has shifted its eyes to Europe, another Chinese military expert who requested anonymity told the Global Times on Monday.</p> <p> China must pay high attention to the situation, and must not allow the US to copy the Ukraine crisis in the South China Sea, Fu said, noting that the situation in the region, despite its complexity, has been relatively stable recently.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Senior Russian navy commander killed in Ukraine: Sevastopol governor ]]></title>
	<news_id>9973908</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0321/c90000-9973908.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 13:12:07 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> MOSCOW, March 21 (Xinhua) -- A senior naval commander from Russia's Black Sea Fleet had been killed in Ukraine, said governor of Sevastopol, a port city on the Crimea Peninsula, on Sunday.</p> <p> Post-Captain Andrei Paliy, the fleet's deputy commander, died during fighting in the eastern Ukrainian port city of Mariupol, Mikhail Razvozhayev said on the messaging app Telegram.</p> <p> Sevastopol is the base of Russia's Black Sea Fleet.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Russia-Ukraine conflict highlights racist double standard in the West ]]></title>
	<news_id>9973863</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0321/c90000-9973863.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 11:06:02 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0321/FOREIGN202203211100000219746097483.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>People board a bus in Irpin, Ukraine, March 5, 2022. (Photo/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> The ongoing Russia-Ukraine conflict has garnered widespread attention across the globe. The wall-to-wall coverage and outpouring of reactions to the Russia-Ukraine conflict from the West has raised eyebrows at its double standard toward other humanitarian crises, which has unsheathed flagrant racist and biased attitudes toward the value of non-white lives that also matter.</p> <p> CBS News senior correspondent in Kyiv Charlie D'Agata, for instance, has faced a widespread backlash due to his discriminatory comments on the Ukraine crisis: "This isn't a place, with all due respect, like Iraq or Afghanistan that has seen conflict raging for decades. This is a relatively civilized, relatively European – I have to choose those words carefully, too – city where you wouldn't expect that, or hope that it's going to happen," he said.</p> <p> The seasoned correspondent was forced to apologize later, saying he spoke "in a way I regret." However, his remarks are not part of an isolated incident. Ukraine's former deputy general prosecutor David Sakvarelidze spoke to the BBC, suggesting that it is harder for him to watch white people fleeing the conflict.</p> <p> "It's very emotional for me because I see European people with blue eyes and blonde hair being killed," Sakvarelidze said. The BBC presenter responded: "I understand and of course respect the emotion."</p> <p> Likewise, a visibly emotional ITV News correspondent Lucy Watson proclaimed: "Now the unthinkable has happened to them, and this is not a developing, Third World nation; this is Europe," as if victims from the world's other humanitarian crises had naturally been inclined to expect to wake up to a devastating war.</p> <p> One French commentator on BFM TV, France's most-watched cable news channel, also came under fire, implying that it's much more conceivable to have attacks in other regions of the world. "We are in a European city and we have cruise missile fire as though we were in Iraq or Afghanistan, can you imagine," he said.</p> <p> Coverage on the Russia-Ukraine conflict has veered into a troubling tone on race and the international status of migrants. Journalists report on the conflict in shock as if bloodshed was the exclusive purview of non-white communities. Such attitudes are strewn across the West and have underlined the Western side's ingrained double standard – namely, valuing white lives over those dying in conflicts outside Europe.</p> <p> Ukraine's refugee crisis has revealed the West's double standards even more clearly. Whopping numbers of people have fled Ukraine, and they are being welcomed as refugees should be by countries across Europe that previously closed their doors to others.</p> <p> The Russia-Ukraine conflict has witnessed Western countries' tremendous "solidarity" – providing a steady flow of "support" – in response to the humanitarian crisis. However, Ukraine is not the only country suffering from a humanitarian crisis. Why do these Western countries treat humanitarian crises outside Europe with indifference and unspeakable brutality?</p> <p> "[Afghan people] must be wondering what makes their humanitarian crisis so unimportant. Is it the color of their skin? Is it that they are not white? They're not European? That their problems come from a U.S. gun or a U.S. invasion," Irish Member of the European Parliament, Clare Daly questioned, denouncing Western countries for treating other humanitarian crises much more lightly compared to the Ukraine crisis.</p> <p> Trivializing wars in the Middle East and dehumanizing entire populations is not new in the West. The past decades have witnessed Western countries' brazen attitude toward wars in the Middle East that claimed hundreds of thousands of lives and displaced millions of people. Missiles from the U.S. landed in the Middle East frequently, but voices from Western media disappeared and reactions were subdued quickly. Casualties in the Middle East seem to be more tolerable to Western media and politicians than those in the present Ukraine crisis, as years of dehumanization have turned the Middle Eastern people into nothing but a statistic confined to the unread columns of newspapers.</p> <p> CNN political correspondent Julia Ioffe made a horrific comparison between Syria and Ukraine in a clip circulating on social media, which displays the most egregious ramifications of the West's dehumanization of the Middle East. "It's one thing for sarin gas to be used on people far away Syria who are Muslim and who are of a different culture but what is Europe going to do when it's used on European soil on Europeans," she said, suggesting people from the Middle East are inferior to Europeans and that it is somehow acceptable for them to be killed.</p> <p> The vastly different treatment received by Ukrainians and those of Middle Eastern nationalities on the part of Western countries, in addition to the casual racism displayed in Western coverage of the Ukraine crisis, has laid bare Western biases, prejudices and double standards, which should be of no surprise. In fact, no life is worth more than another. So until Western countries do away with its racist double standard and treat humanitarian crises with equal weight, it simply has "no credibility," just as Daly opined with great gusto in front of the cameras of Western media.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 3D printing speeds up production of missiles ]]></title>
	<news_id>9973827</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0321/c90000-9973827.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 10:22:15 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> China Aerospace Science and Industry Corp, the nation's largest missile maker, is taking advantage of additive manufacturing technology, commonly known as 3D printing, to accelerate the design and production of cruise missiles, engineers said.</p> <p> "It takes about one to two months for dozens of technicians and workers to manufacture a gas rudder (used on a cruise missile) with traditional machining methods because it involves a succession of processes like casting and welding," said Zhang Chunhu, a senior technician at CASIC's Third Academy. "And a rudder is only a small part on a missile, so you can imagine how much manpower and time it takes to build a whole cruise missile by traditional means.</p> <p> "But now, with 3D printing technology, a handful of workers can make a rudder within a week. The 3D-printing-enabled procedure can save us a great deal of labor, time and cost, and is much better than mechanical machining when it comes to weight and accuracy control for our products."</p> <p> Zhang said a mechanically made rudder has rough surfaces that require workers to use machines and a lot of time to smooth them, and during that process, a large proportion of metal is chopped off and wasted. By comparison, a 3D printed one has very smooth surfaces with a tiny amount of redundant material－usually just a few grams－which means it is almost ready for installation on a missile.</p> <p> "Thanks to 3D printing technology, our production efficiency and quality have substantially improved," Zhang said.</p> <p> Jiao Shikun, an engineer at the academy's Technological Innovation Center for Additive Manufacturing, said 3D printers have enabled workers to increase the raw material utilization rate by dozens of times when it comes to manufacturing large missile components. The "printed" products have higher structural strength and a better pass rate, he added.</p> <p> He said CASIC's Third Academy is the largest user of 3D printers in China's aerospace industry, and its technicians are using the technology to make many cruise missile parts such as engines and fuselage panels.</p> <p> Zhang and Jiao said they will cooperate with weapons designers at the academy to introduce 3D printing technology in the design of new missiles.</p> <p> "Designers can consider which components are suitable to be 'printed'. This technology can give engineers more space for imagination and innovation and allow them to design advanced, sophisticated components that would be difficult for traditional methods to manufacture but easy for 3D printers," Zhang said. "It is no exaggeration to say that 3D printing technology will revolutionize the design work of missiles."</p> <p> The technology also has huge potential in the academy's production of unmanned aircraft, he said.</p> <p> Wu Peixin, a defense industry observer in Beijing, said it is likely that in the future, 3D printers will be taken to the battlefield to allow soldiers to print and assemble missiles on the spot based on their needs.</p> <p> China's aviation and space industries have used 3D printers widely on their production lines. Chinese scientists also carried out space-based 3D printing experiments on the country's new-generation manned spacecraft during its first flight test in May 2020.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Submarine flotilla in combat training ]]></title>
	<news_id>9973805</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0321/c90000-9973805.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 09:58:36 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0321/FOREIGN202203210949000396588383870.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 506px;" /></p> <p> A submarine attached to a naval flotilla under the PLA Northern Theater Command sails in the waters during the combat training drills on January 4, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Wu Haodong)</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0321/FOREIGN202203210950000128383974451.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 506px;" /></p> <p> A submarine attached to a naval flotilla under the PLA Northern Theater Command sails in the waters during the combat training drills on January 4, 2022. (eng.chinamil.com.cn/Photo by Wu Haodong)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Military Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ S.Korea says DPRK fires suspected shots from rocket launchers ]]></title>
	<news_id>9973586</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0320/c90000-9973586.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 15:48:02 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> SEOUL, March 20 (Xinhua) -- The Democratic People's Republic of Korea (DPRK) on Sunday fired four suspected shots from the multiple rocket launchers off its west coast, said South Korea's Yonhap news agency citing military officials.</p> <p> South Korea's presidential office Cheong Wa Dae said the same day that it convened a vice-ministerial emergency meeting to discuss the situation this morning.</p> <p> The parameters data will be analyzed under close cooperation between South Korea and the United States, and the South Korean government will keep on alert and keep an eye on the recent moves of the DPRK, the meeting said.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
	</channel>
</rss>