<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title> China_Society </title>
		<image>
			<title>People's Daily Online</title>
			<link>http://english.people.com.cn/</link>
			<url>http://english.people.com.cn/images/en/top_logo_e.gif</url>
		</image>
		<description>People's Daily Online</description>
		<link>http://english.people.com.cn/90882</link>
		<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Shanghai reports 194 confirmed, 1,487 asymptomatic local COVID-19 cases ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096654</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096654.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:34:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> SHANGHAI, May 14 (Xinhua) -- China's Shanghai reported 194 confirmed locally transmitted COVID-19 cases and 1,487 local asymptomatic cases on Friday, the municipal health commission said Saturday.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Miao ethnic people start new life after poverty alleviation resettlement ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096591</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096591.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 17:26:37 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> CHANGSHA, May 13 (Xinhua) -- A chunk of air-dry smoked meat hangs in the hallway of Wu Jinjian's residence in Fenghuang County, central China's Hunan Province, emitting a pleasant smoky flavor.</p> <p> Four years ago, Wu and his wife along with their parents, and their three children left their hometown, a remote mountain village in Fenghuang County. As part of the local poverty alleviation program, they relocated to a three-story building in the resettlement area in the center of Heku Township.</p> <p> In 2018, the local government built 756 new buildings in Heku Township for poor households looking to relocate. A total of 4,784 people from 932 poverty-stricken Miao ethnic households were gradually relocated to Heku from four surrounding townships.</p> <p> The Heku resettlement area is the largest centralized resettlement area for Miao ethnic group in Hunan Province.</p> <p> Not long after moving in, Wu's family fell in love with their new residence.</p> <p> The newly constructed building features yellow walls, grey tiles, and arching eaves, showcasing the popular architectural style of the Miao ethnic group. Schools, hospitals, farmers' markets, and even a basketball court all help make life more convenient for the new communities.</p> <p> Adapting to the new lifestyle, however, is a significant challenge for people from remote mountainous villages. Local government officials had to teach to them how to use new equipment, such as door locks, windows, gas stoves, taps, and toilets.</p> <p> Of course, some people still hold a strong attachment to their hometown. They return to the villages where they used to live and work, and visit their relatives, said Shi Chengbang, Party chief of Mituo Village.</p> <p> Art groups, including ethnic dance and folk music groups, have been organized to preserve the culture of local ethnic minorities. Relocated villagers can also earn some money via the performances presented by these groups.</p> <p> The government has established clothing and luggage manufacturing industries in the resettlement area to create jobs for the relocated villagers in order to sustainably increase their income. Meanwhile, jobs for public services, such as cleaners and guards, are also available in their new communities.</p> <p> After the resettlement, villagers have found they have more business opportunities, and some relocated households have started to run small shops or stalls.</p> <p> Since 2015, the Chinese government has implemented poverty alleviation relocation programs to address the needs of nearly 10 million poor people and help lift them out of poverty. By the end of 2020, a total of 35,000 resettlement areas were built across the country and more than 9.6 million people bid farewell to old villages and embarked on a journey to establish a new life.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ About 50,000 affected by heavy rains in China's Guangxi ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096563</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096563.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 16:38:10 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NANNING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- As of 5 p.m. Thursday, about 50,000 residents of south China's Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region have been affected by floods caused by extensive heavy rains that began on May 8, the regional emergency management department said.</p> <p> During the period, rainfall affected a total crop area of over 3,800 hectares, caused 19 households to collapse and severely damaged 34 households.</p> <p> On Thursday alone, downpours lashed the eastern area of Guangxi and some of its coastal areas, while some parts even suffered from thunderstorms and strong winds. Some areas logged 150 to 250 mm of precipitation with the maximum hourly rainfall reaching 60 to 90 mm.</p> <p> Starting from 6 p.m. on Thursday, the regional meteorological authorities raised its emergency response level for rainstorms to level IV and warned local residents to watch out for possible landslides and other geological disasters.</p> <p> China has a four-tier disaster relief emergency response system, with Level I being the most severe.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Beijing starts new round of mass nucleic acid testing ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096518</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096518.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 16:38:10 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/2/13390066884613598138.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 581px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> A staff member registers information for a resident at a nucleic acid testing site in Haidian District of Beijing, capital of China, May 13, 2022. Beijing has started three additional rounds of mass nucleic acid testing in 12 districts from Friday to Sunday, as the Chinese capital races against time to contain the latest resurgence of COVID-19 infections. (Xinhua/Ren Chao)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/37/10059102390185117301.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> A medic takes a swab sample from a resident for nucleic acid test at a community in Haidian District of Beijing, capital of China, May 13, 2022. Beijing has started three additional rounds of mass nucleic acid testing in 12 districts from Friday to Sunday, as the Chinese capital races against time to contain the latest resurgence of COVID-19 infections. (Xinhua/Ren Chao)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/30/11032742398256818678.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 650px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> A medic takes a swab sample from a child for nucleic acid test at a community in Haidian District of Beijing, capital of China, May 13, 2022. Beijing has started three additional rounds of mass nucleic acid testing in 12 districts from Friday to Sunday, as the Chinese capital races against time to contain the latest resurgence of COVID-19 infections. (Xinhua/Ren Chao)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/9/14835603154588394485.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 606px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> A medic takes a swab sample from a resident for nucleic acid test at a community in Haidian District of Beijing, capital of China, May 13, 2022. Beijing has started three additional rounds of mass nucleic acid testing in 12 districts from Friday to Sunday, as the Chinese capital races against time to contain the latest resurgence of COVID-19 infections. (Xinhua/Ren Chao)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Delivery services normal in Beijing amid COVID-19 resurgence ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096480</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096480.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 15:51:24 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/41/10376126946297508681.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>A delivery man carries a package to a community in Chaoyang district, Beijing, May 13, 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Hou Yu)</em></p> <p> Delivery services would not suspend amid the COVID-19 resurgence in Beijing.</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/41/4518531019130589401.jpg" /></p> <p> A man delivers packages to a community in Chaoyang District, Beijing, May 13, 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Hou Yu)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/99/16077405613729356211.jpg" /></p> <p> Delivery men arrange packages in Chaoyang district, Beijing, May 13, 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Hou Yu)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Ecns.cn</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Immigration authority refutes false info slandering China's entry-exit policies ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096377</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096377.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 15:51:19 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- China's National Immigration Administration (NIA) on Friday dismissed false overseas media reports on its border control practices, saying such rumors aim to distort and discredit the country's entry and exit policies.</p> <p> Recently, some overseas media outlets have hyped disinformation suggesting China has suspended issuing passports to citizens, or prevented people from leaving the country.</p> <p> Such disinformation is intended to undermine the country's legal, targeted and effective entry-exit management measures introduced under the backdrop of maintaining regular COVID-19 response approaches, said an NIA spokesperson.</p> <p> The administration has firmly implemented a strategy to prevent both inbound cases and domestic resurgences since the COVID-19 outbreak, effectively reducing the risk of infection caused by individuals entering or exiting the country, the spokesperson said.</p> <p> Immigration agencies at all levels across the country have improved entry and exit measures to offer timely passport services for people who need to go overseas for study, business, research, medical treatment or other purposes, according to the NIA.</p> <p> Authorities have also expedited passport services for people heading overseas to help with the anti-COVID fight or transfer relief supplies.</p> <p> The spokesperson, however, warned that the global pandemic is far from over and there is a great deal of uncertainty concerning how it will develop. With the risk of being infected still high, the NIA advised people to refrain from non-urgent and unnecessary cross-border travel.</p> <p> People who need to enter or exit the country can access information from the official NIA website, WeChat account or hotline, the spokesperson noted.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China rolls out measures to support youth employment ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096478</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096478.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 15:45:54 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- China Friday announced a raft of measures to help young people, especially college graduates, find jobs and set up businesses in the latest move to stabilize employment.</p> <p> The State Council detailed supportive policies in a document, including subsidies to employers that hire more graduates and guaranteed loans for young entrepreneurs.</p> <p> Key groups including college graduates are under pressure to secure jobs as there will be a record number of new graduates from universities and colleges this year.</p> <p> The government vowed to create more jobs in manufacturing upgrades, emerging industries, and services.</p> <p> Micro, small, and medium-sized enterprises that employ more graduates will get social insurance subsidies, guaranteed loans, interest discounts, and tax and fee reductions. The platform economy will be encouraged to play a more significant role in creating jobs. The state-owned enterprises will also recruit more.</p> <p> College graduates starting their own businesses will enjoy favorable policies, including one-off subsidies and tax breaks, and government-invested incubators will allocate 30 percent of facilities to them for free.</p> <p> Those meeting economic hardship can also have their repayment of student loans deferred and interest reduced or exempted, according to the document.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Young teacher devotes over a decade to teaching hearing-impaired students the art of dance ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096432</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096432.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 15:03:56 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Giving up better career opportunities, Li Zhen, a 34-year-old dance teacher, has been teaching students with hearing disabilities how to dance to the rhythm of a silent world for about 12 years now.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205131422000444335847187.jpeg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Li Zhen gives a class to students. (Changjiang Daily/Peng Nian)</em></p> <p> Li graduated from the School of Music at Central China Normal University in Wuhan, capital city of central China’s Hubei Province in 2010. He won several gold prizes when participating in national dance competitions during his university days. After graduating from the university, he rejected decent offers from employers such as the Hubei Song and Dance Troupe and instead became a teacher at the Wuhan No. 2 School for the Deaf in the provincial capital.</p> <p> However, Li was very frustrated in the beginning because he was unfamiliar with sign language and was unable to communicate efficiently with his students.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205131456000508086070524.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Li Zhen gives instruction to students. (Changjiang Daily/Peng Nian)</em></p> <p> To solve the problem, Li began to bury himself in learning sign language and had managed to get a good command of sign language in only two months.</p> <p> Li teaches his students how to feel the rhythm of the music by putting his hands in the air to clap the rhythm and make gestures.</p> <p> Over the past years, Li led the school’s art troupe to win 11 national awards. More than 70 of his students were enrolled in their ideal universities thanks to their exceptional skills and his guidance. In 2018, Li’s students defeated other teams comprised of children with no disabilities and took the crown at an international cheerleading open held in Italy.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205131457000201324186795.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 427px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Li Zhen gives instruction to students. (Changjiang Daily/Peng Nian)</em></p> <p> On March 4, 2022, Li used sign language to conduct 50 individuals with hearing impairment, who staged a Winter Paralympic Waltz together with 40 individuals without disabilities at the opening ceremony of the Beijing 2022 Paralympic Winter Games at the Bird’s Nest.</p> <p> Liu Xin, the headmaster of the school, said that Li has had many opportunities to seek a better career these years, but he has nonetheless chosen to continue on in his role as a teacher at the school.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Young Chinese vaccine developer strives to defeat COVID-19 ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096386</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096386.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 14:18:19 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <center> <video controls="controls" poster=" http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/5/13/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_cb762812499df8ab9dafc250249f7b5f.jpeg " src=" http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/5/13/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_284117d1421f3d2d081f7e6adf97f0db.mp4" style=" width: 830px; height:550px;"> <p> &nbsp;</p> </video> </center> <p> Liang Hongyang, head of the Scientific Research Management Department of Sinopharm’s Beijing Institute of Biological Products, cut short his vacation and headed back to his office in Beijing without a second thought after he received a call to kick off a COVID-19 vaccine development project on Chinese New Years Eve, an occasion when people are supposed to reunite with their family.</p> <p> Faced with a raging virus, he led his team in round-the-clock scientific research with determination and created his company’s first COVID-19 vaccine, which brought hope to the global population.</p> <p> “Keep on striving even if you are shedding tears, ” Liang said to Chinese youth, looking back at his battle against the virus.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily App</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Beijing subways enhance disinfection ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096380</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096380.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 13:58:18 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/68/3242823333564571592.jpg" /></p> <p> Cleaning staff disinfect a subway station in Beijing, May 12, 2022. Beijing has closed some subway stations to curb its COVID-19 outbreak. (Photo: China News Service/Jia Tianyong)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/5/2905802962295403209.jpg" /></p> <p> Cleaning staff disinfect a subway station in Beijing, May 12, 2022. Beijing has closed some subway stations to curb its COVID-19 outbreak. (Photo: China News Service/Jia Tianyong)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/85/4477613106734334821.jpg" /></p> <p> Cleaning staff disinfect a subway station in Beijing, May 12, 2022. Beijing has closed some subway stations to curb its COVID-19 outbreak. (Photo: China News Service/Jia Tianyong)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/47/3524992914563698671.jpg" /></p> <p> Cleaning staff disinfect entrance gates at a subway station in Beijing, May 12, 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Jia Tianyong)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Ecns.cn</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese mainland reports 312 new local COVID-19 cases, 227 in Shanghai ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096203</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096203.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:32:03 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205130957000312714085287.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 639px;" /></p> <p> <em>A customer scans the QR code before entering a grocery store in Jiading District of east China's Shanghai, May 9, 2022. (Xinhua/Li He)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- The Chinese mainland on Thursday reported 312 confirmed local COVID-19 cases, of which 227 were in Shanghai, the National Health Commission said on Friday.</p> <p> Apart from Shanghai, seven other provincial-level regions on the mainland saw new locally transmitted COVID-19 cases, including 42 in Beijing and 15 in Henan.</p> <p> Shanghai also reported 1,869 locally transmitted asymptomatic infections Thursday, out of a total of 2,140 such cases newly identified on the mainland.</p> <p> Following the recovery of 614 COVID-19 patients who were discharged from hospital on Thursday, there were 6,944 confirmed COVID-19 cases receiving treatment in hospitals across the Chinese mainland.</p> <p> Thursday saw two deaths from COVID-19, both in Shanghai.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 614 COVID-19 patients discharged from hospitals on Chinese mainland ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096205</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096205.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:16:26 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- A total of 614 COVID-19 patients were discharged from hospitals after recovery on the Chinese mainland on Thursday, the National Health Commission said in its Friday report.</p> <p> That brought the mainland's total number of COVID-19 patients discharged from hospitals after recovery to 209,140 as of Thursday.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Shanghai reports 227 confirmed, 1,869 asymptomatic local COVID-19 cases ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096200</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096200.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:16:19 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> SHANGHAI, May 13 (Xinhua) -- China's Shanghai reported 227 confirmed locally transmitted COVID-19 cases and 1,869 local asymptomatic cases on Thursday, the municipal health commission said Friday.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Green transformation brings life changes on Loess Plateau ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096198</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096198.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:15:47 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> TAIYUAN, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Imagine groups of people laying down mats and tents in the shade while enjoying spring scenery surrounded by green grass and flowing water. This may sound like a secluded scene in the wild, but this tranquil environment is actually in an urban area.</p> <p> Qiu Yu had never thought about camping in the park near Fenhe River, about 10 km north of downtown Taiyuan City, the capital of north China's Shanxi Province.</p> <p> "Couple of years ago, there was nothing but the river and wild trees, and almost no one would like to come," said the 36-year-old camping-lover.</p> <p> The change occurred in October 2021 when the ecological restoration project of the 43-km-long Taiyuan section of the Fenhe River was completed, providing a leisure space for citizens to get close to nature.</p> <p> The Loess Plateau in Shanxi is the largest loess area in the world. In the past, the area was known for its ecological fragility and soil erosion. As a heavy industry base, Taiyuan suffered from heavy air and water pollution.</p> <p> Since the beginning of this century, a drive for green and sustainable development has swept China, and ecological restoration projects have been carried out in the Fenhe River valley and many other places on the Loess Plateau.</p> <p> This green transformation has not only given residents more choices for leisure and entertainment but has also been the bread and butter for many.</p> <p> Lyu Fuqin planted over 1.3 hectares of scholar trees and apricot trees in the past month.</p> <p> "I used to cut trees to cook and make fire, but now I plant them," said the 52-year-old living in Linxian County, Lyuliang City. He is now a forester, and bid farewell to his former life as an ordinary farmer who struggled to make ends meet.</p> <p> As a former poverty-stricken area, 91 percent of the land area in Lyuliang City is hilly and mountainous. In the past few years, the city has combined afforestation and poverty alleviation, which has not only significantly improved the environment but also helped a group of poor households increase their incomes.</p> <p> "As a forest planter, I now earn more than 40,000 yuan (about 5,944 U.S. dollars) yearly," Lyu said, adding that he had built a two-story house, and funded a wedding for his youngest son.</p> <p> Over the past few years, nearly 100,000 people have participated in the afforestation projects in Lyuliang, including 65,000 former poor households, and their annual per capita income has increased by about 5,000 yuan, the official data showed.</p> <p> Moreover, the project has elevated the forest coverage rate in the city to 28.6 percent by the end of 2021.</p> <p> The stereotype of the Loess Plateau as an arid and lifeless place is quietly changing. According to official statistics, the average precipitation in Lyuliang has increased by 81.8 mm annually from 2016 to 2020, and the amount of sediment flowing into the Yellow River has reduced by more than 7 million tonnes.</p> <p> By constructing terraced fields on hillsides to develop agriculture in the 1960s and 1970s, Dazhai Village in Xiyang County was famous worldwide. About 10 million domestic and international visitors have visited the area.</p> <p> However, the villagers have stopped building terraced fields, and started to return farmland to forests and developing ecotourism.</p> <p> The former agricultural pace-setter, which once built more than 53 hectares of terraced fields, has returned about 20 hectares of arable land to forests at present.</p> <p> "I prefer working here rather than in big cities," said 31-year-old native Li Zhenjiang, who used to work in Beijing. He finally settled in the village by running two souvenir shops, earning more than 100,000 yuan a year.</p> <p> Through the development of ecotourism, the collective income of Dazhai reached 23 million yuan in 2020, and the annual per capita income has reached 26,000 yuan.</p> <p> "Why should I go out to make a living, when I can make money on my doorstep? As the environment gets better, the village will become more prosperous in the future," said Li.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's ecology sees historic turning point: official ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096195</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096195.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:15:47 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- China's ecological environment has witnessed a historic turning point over the past decade, an official said Thursday.</p> <p> "We have seen fewer hazy days and black and smelly water bodies, and have enjoyed bluer skies and more lucid waters and lush mountains," Han Wenxiu, a senior official with the Central Committee for Financial and Economic Affairs, said at a press conference.</p> <p> China's afforested land has accounted for about a quarter of the world's total, and its CO2 emissions per unit of GDP have dropped about 34 percent, Han said.</p> <p> The country has also topped the globe in installed capacity of wind and photovoltaic power and other green energy, and in the production and sales of new energy vehicles, Han said.</p> <p> As a faithful advocate of the Paris Agreement, China has announced targets of peaking CO2 emissions before 2030 and achieving carbon neutrality before 2060, Han said.</p> <p> <strong>CONCRETE EFFORTS</strong></p> <p> Ecological protection has been high on the policy agenda of the world's second-largest economy over the past decade as solid actions have been taken to advance ecological development and push the country toward a green future.</p> <p> Accountability has been ensured as lists of responsibilities have been drawn up by central and local authorities and environmental inspections have been launched and deepened, Ye Min, vice minister of ecology and environment, said at the press conference.</p> <p> China has enacted or revised 13 laws and 17 administrative regulations covering the prevention and control of air, water and soil pollution, accompanied by meticulous efforts to guarantee the laws are strictly enforced.</p> <p> The national carbon market has started trading and the national green development fund has been set up. At the end of 2021, outstanding green credit amounted to 15.9 trillion yuan (about 2.36 trillion U.S. dollars).</p> <p> To encourage the green shift of businesses, China has incorporated more than 3.3 million fixed pollution sources into sewage management and has issued catalogs on products that pose high environmental risks or are crucial to environmental protection.</p> <p> China has also vigorously improved public awareness of environmental protection and promoted green lifestyles.</p> <p> To build a beautiful China, Ye said continued efforts have to be made in cutting carbon emissions, fighting pollution and improving environmental governance. He also stressed the importance of local accountability, business participation, public oversight and market-oriented mechanisms.</p> <p> <strong>LOW-CARBON TRANSITION</strong></p> <p> As China's ecological advance has entered a critical period focusing on carbon reduction, enormous progress has been made in its transformation to green and low-carbon development.</p> <p> Speaking at the press conference, Hu Zucai, deputy director of the National Development and Reform Commission, listed a series of major achievements from the widespread use of clean power to more efficient energy consumption.</p> <p> The installed capacity of renewable energy in China has exceeded 1 billion kilowatts, with that of hydropower, wind power, solar power and biomass power all ranking first in the world. The share of clean energy has risen from 14.5 percent to 25.5 percent in the country's energy consumption mix.</p> <p> Ultra-low emission coal-fired power generation has exceeded 1 billion kilowatts, leading the world in efficiency and emission reduction.</p> <p> Progress has also been noticeable in energy conservation. China's average annual economic growth of 6.5 percent over the past years was powered by a mere 3 percent annual increase in energy consumption. The energy consumption intensity has dropped 26.2 percent, which is equivalent to saving 1.4 billion tonnes of standard coal or an emission cut of 2.94 billion tonnes of CO2.</p> <p> Looking forward, Hu stressed that China's carbon reduction push is a profound, systemic reform that cannot be achieved easily or swiftly. "The phasing out of traditional energy must be based on the safe and reliable replacement by new energy sources."</p> <p> China will step up efforts to develop new energy, Hu said, adding that 450 million kilowatts of hydropower, wind power and solar power generation capacity will be built in deserts, with the first projects totaling 85 million kilowatts having broken ground.</p> <p> The task of peaking CO2 emissions and achieving carbon neutrality will be advanced in an orderly, forceful and effective manner, and new progress will be made continuously, he said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Beijing: A 7-minute race to save life amid COVID-19 pandemic ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096186</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096186.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:08:22 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <center> <video controls="controls" poster=" http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/5/13/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-XianJiangNan_a9a879ed6de628e59fff6dec5f68e3bc.jpeg" src=" http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/5/13/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-XianJiangNan_5dd31f3a769507af9cfa0af012117bb2.mp4" style=" width: 830px; height:550px;"> <p> &nbsp;</p> </video> </center> <p> On May 8, 2022, a residential compound in Chaoyang District, Beijing, went into quarantine management as three people inside tested positive during a preliminary COVID screening. However, in the same evening, at 9:20 p.m., the local police station received an emergency call reporting that an elderly person in the compound was suffering from a sudden heart attack and was in urgent need of medical treatment. Two police officers on duty then set off for the compound on short notice.</p> <p> When they arrived, the patient had already passed out and her husband was desperate for help. In light of the situation, the police called up the hospital to arrange for an emergency room and decided to transfer the patient there in their police car.</p> <p> The siren sounded and the lights flashed as the police car raced at full speeds on a life-saving mission. An emergency route was made clear for the car, with it only taking 7 minutes for the patient to get to the hospital.</p> <p> In retrospect, 5 more minutes would likely have made the difference between life and death, said the doctor who successfully completed an emergency surgery for the patient. In the end, one life has been saved and a family has therefore been shielded from tragedy. Yet there’s no time for the police officers to linger around after their efforts, as they must return at once to engage in the intense work of enforcing COVID-19 regulations.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese university to compile textbooks for intangible cultural heritage studies ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096179</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096179.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:07:37 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> TIANJIN, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Tianjin University in north China's Tianjin Municipality has launched its textbook compiling project for the undergraduate and master's courses on intangible cultural heritage studies, a milestone in building China's fledging discipline of these cultural heritage studies.</p> <p> In October 2021, China authorized Tianjin University to grant the country's first interdisciplinary master's degree in intangible cultural heritage studies. It marked the relevant talent cultivation entering a new stage and China's intangible cultural heritage preservation undertaking shifting from mere "rescuing" to more scientific approaches.</p> <p> As an interdisciplinary major, studies on intangible cultural heritage involve humanities, social science, and natural science. The new discipline aims to educate talents able to undertake intangible cultural heritage investigation and identification, inheritance and protection, publicity, transformation, and utilization.</p> <p> The first edition of the textbooks will be published in three volumes, covering its general theory, studies on folk literature and art, and oral history of the cultural heritage inheritors. The textbooks will likely be compiled within this year.</p> <p> "The textbooks will establish a complete knowledge system. It would be a rigorous and clear theoretical system for these studies to find a unique educational way and help cultivate research and management talents for intangible cultural heritage education," said Feng Jicai, chief editor of the textbook series and also a renowned Chinese writer.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Beijing to conduct 3 more rounds of mass COVID-19 testing ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096168</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096168.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:06:56 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Beijing will conduct three additional rounds of mass nucleic acid testing in 12 districts from Friday to Sunday, as the Chinese capital races against time to contain the latest resurgence of COVID-19 infections.</p> <p> The 12 districts include all the urban and major suburban districts, namely, Dongcheng, Xicheng, Chaoyang, Haidian, Fengtai, Shijingshan, Fangshan, Tongzhou, Shunyi, Changping, Daxing and Beijing Economic-Technological Development Area, Xu Hejian, a spokesperson for the Beijing municipal government, told a press briefing on Thursday.</p> <p> Xu called on locals to reduce personnel flows to cut off the transmission chain of the virus, assuring that the city's routine operation and the supply of daily necessities will not be affected.</p> <p> Beijing reported 36 new locally transmitted COVID-19 infections between 3 p.m. Wednesday and 3 p.m. Thursday, Pang Xinghuo, deputy head of the Beijing municipal disease prevention and control center, told reporters.</p> <p> Thirty-two cases were detected among people under closed-off management and four were found in mass screening in communities, Pang said, adding that among the new infections, 32 are moderate or mild cases and four are asymptomatic carriers.</p> <p> Beijing has reported 928 locally transmitted infections since April 22. Currently, it has 17 high-risk areas and 37 medium-risk areas for COVID-19.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China to defer social insurance premium payments for epidemic-hit firms ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096175</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096175.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:06:56 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Chinese authorities have recently announced a new payment deferral of social insurance premiums for the sectors severely hit by the COVID-19 outbreaks, as the latest move to alleviate the financial burden of these industries.</p> <p> The country has planned to temporarily defer the premium payments of old-age insurance, unemployment insurance, and workplace injury insurance for the hard-hit catering, retail, tourism, civil aviation, highway, waterway and railway transportation industries, according to a statement jointly released by the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security and the State Taxation Administration (STA).</p> <p> Individual businesses and workers in flexible employment that have difficulties in paying basic old-age insurance premiums in 2022 are allowed to defer the payments until the end of 2023, Zheng Wenmin, an official with the STA told a press conference Thursday.</p> <p> The policies are expected to pump up over 80 billion yuan (about 11.89 billion U.S. dollars) of cash flows for firms and individuals, and play an underpinning role in relieving cash strains for smaller firms and stabilizing employment, Zheng said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China to continue bolstering support for unemployed people ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096176</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096176.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 10:06:56 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- China will continue to step up support for unemployed people to ensure their basic living needs, according to the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security.</p> <p> Policies to expand the coverage of unemployment insurance will be extended for one more year, Gui Zhen, an official with the ministry said Thursday.</p> <p> Unemployment insurance benefits will be gradually raised to 90 percent of the minimum wage standards, Gui added, noting that efforts will be made to ensure unemployed people have easy access to insurance benefits through various channels.</p> <p> In the first quarter of 2022, the surveyed urban unemployment rate averaged 5.5 percent, basically unchanged from the same period last year.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Rooftop vegetable gardens built atop middle school in Jiangxi give students practical hands-on experience ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096133</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096133.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:46:45 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> <em>A middle school in Ganzhou, east China's Jiangxi Province has transformed the rooftops of its school buildings into little farms. (Photo/Zhu Haipeng)</em></p> <p> A middle school in Ganzhou, east China's Jiangxi Province has transformed the rooftops of its school buildings into little farms, becoming an organic classroom for students to learn practical skills by growing vegetables with their own hands.</p> <p> Each class has been assigned a parcel of dirt, where students have planted corn, peppers, tomatoes and other vegetables with the guidance of their teachers. During this process, students were able to experience the toils of labor and the joys of harvesting, in this way developing a greater respect for manual labor.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Over 4,200 endangered cranes spotted at China's largest freshwater lake ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096145</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096145.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:25:03 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NANCHANG, May 12 (Xinhua) -- A total of 4,264 Siberian white cranes, a critically endangered bird species, have been spotted over the winter and spring at Poyang Lake, China's largest freshwater lake, in east China's Jiangxi Province.</p> <p> The migratory birds began to travel north in late February. However, some wild cranes of the species were still at the lake in May, a relatively rare sight in previous years, said the Jiangxi Poyang Lake National Nature Reserve Administration at a video conference on Thursday.</p> <p> Researchers will keep an eye on the lingering cranes, said Luo Hao from the administration's scientific research department.</p> <p> Poyang Lake has an intact ecosystem and is an important wintering spot for waterfowl in Asia. The peak migration period for birds heading to the lake begins in mid-December and continues into early January.</p> <p> Rated as critically endangered on the International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN) Red List, the Siberian white crane, also known as the snow crane, has a global population of around 4,000.</p> <p> The other end of the migration route, Russia's Kytalyk National Park, has signed a memorandum of understanding on strategic cooperation with Jiangxi Poyang Lake National Nature Reserve Administration to jointly protect the wild birds.</p> <p> "The white cranes will visit Kytalyk National Park in batches all the way from China's Poyang Lake," said Sargylana Mikhailova with the Kytalyk National Park. "We will pass on the baton of protecting the wildlife, study their breeding conditions and share our research results with China."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Hong Kong's third-dose COVID-19 vaccination rate reaches 50 pct ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096144</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096144.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:24:54 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> HONG KONG, May 12 (Xinhua) -- The Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (HKSAR) government announced Thursday that about 3.38 million people had received their third COVID-19 vaccine dose as of Thursday, accounting for 50 percent of the population aged 12 or above.</p> <p> The HKSAR government appealed to eligible persons for receiving the third dose of COVID-19 vaccine as soon as possible to enhance protection and to prepare for the implementation of stage three Vaccine Pass at the end of this month.</p> <p> Patrick Nip, secretary for the civil service of the HKSAR government, said that at present, there are about 1 million people who are due to receive their third dose but have not yet done so.</p> <p> "We need the proactive response from every member of the public in boosting the vaccination rate together and building a stronger protective barrier to cope with the future risks brought about by potential emergence of new mutant strains," Nip said.</p> <p> Currently, the COVID-19 vaccination rates of persons aged three or above for the first and second doses are 91.5 percent and 85.6 percent respectively, he said.</p> <p> On Thursday, Hong Kong registered 115 new COVID-19 cases by nucleic acid tests, and 179 additional cases through self-reported antigen rapid tests, official data showed.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ International Nurses Day marked across China ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096101</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096101.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 08:50:23 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/31/9906418444196677603.png" /></p> <p> A nurse takes care of a newborn baby at a hospital in Lijiang, southwest China's Yunnan Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Zhao Qingzu/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/38/6802428589745238534.png" /></p> <p> A nurse checks the dripping speed for a patient at a hospital in Qianxi City, southwest China's Guizhou Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Fan Hui/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/21/3696712224587647877.png" /></p> <p> A nurse bandages the wound for a patient at a hospital in Beibei District of southwest China's Chongqing, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Qin Tingfu/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/62/12051792659458601194.png" /></p> <p> Nurses take care of newborn babies at a hospital in Yongzhou, central China's Hunan Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Jiang Keqing/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/81/15641353270114145485.png" /></p> <p> A medical worker takes a swab sample from a child for nucleic acid test at a school in Huaihua, central China's Hunan Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Su Yongzhu/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/79/10574270401653101347.png" /></p> <p> A medical worker takes a swab sample from a resident for nucleic acid test at a community in Suzhou, east China's Jiangsu Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Hang Xingwei/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/5/2276741767890977401.png" /></p> <p> A nurse prepares medicine at a hospital in Ji'an, east China's Jiangxi Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Li Jun/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/58/558887141685904350.png" /></p> <p> A nurse takes care of a patient at a hospital in Nanjing, east China's Jiangsu Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Su Yang/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/17/6777528903268143153.png" /></p> <p> A nurse works at the neonatal intensive care unit (NICU) in a hospital in Taizhou, east China's Jiangsu Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Tang Dehong/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/72/3578005953393818656.png" /></p> <p> A nurse takes care of a newborn baby at a hospital in Nanjing, east China's Jiangsu Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Fang Dongxu/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/21/11923214811250141509.png" /></p> <p> Nurses prepare medicine at a hospital in Hengyang, central China's Hunan Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Xiao Yahui/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/97/6380988369925771681.png" /></p> <p> A nurse cleans medical equipment at a hospital in Huai'an City, east China's Jiangsu Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Zhao Qirui/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/49/13336701086834705557.png" /></p> <p> Medical workers rush to an ambulance at a hospital in Handan, north China's Hebei Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Hao Qunying/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/19/15652838523534238647.png" /></p> <p> A nurse takes a swab sample from a child for nucleic acid test at a community in Yangzhou, east China's Jiangsu Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Meng Delong/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/61/7582656905271359013.png" /></p> <p> A nurse prepares to distribute medicine at a hospital in Tongren, southwest China's Guizhou Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Li He/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/23/907164961378887219.png" /></p> <p> A nurse takes care of a newborn baby at a hospital in Chishui, southwest China's Guizhou Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Cao Liang/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/45/3313220568986187237.png" /></p> <p> A nurse prepares for a surgery at a hospital in Tangshan, north China's Hebei Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Liu Mancang/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/6/9311339515984797718.png" /></p> <p> Nurses work at a hospital in Guiyang, southwest China's Guizhou Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Deng Gang/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/42/2276253065738352878.png" /></p> <p> A nurse sterilizes medical equipment at a hospital in Tongren, southwest China's Guizhou Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Ye Shunqiang/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/44/241859092328247412.png" /></p> <p> A nurse prepares medicine at a hospital in Tangshan, north China's Hebei Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Li Lei/Xinhua)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/76/8216127841899445044.png" /></p> <p> A nurse takes care of a newborn baby at the neonatal intensive care unit (NICU) in a hospital in Dingxi, northwest China's Gansu Province, May 12, 2022. The number of registered nurses in China has grown with an average annual rate of 8 percent over the past 10 years, reaching 5.02 million at the end of 2021, the National Health Commission said Wednesday, ahead of International Nurses Day, which falls on May 12. (Photo by Wang Kexian/Xinhua)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Beijing refutes rumors of lockdown, reassures of adequate food supplies amid hoarding ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096094</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096094.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 08:35:17 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="People queue up to register for nucleic acid test at a testing site in Chaoyang District, Beijing, capital of China, April 25, 2022. Starting from Monday, people who live and work in the Chaoyang District have to take nucleic acid test every two days till April 29 to curb the recent resurgence of COVID-19.Photo: Xinhua" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/52/11322226659032135472.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>People queue up to register for nucleic acid test at a testing site in Chaoyang District, Beijing, April 25, 2022. Photo: Xinhua</em></p> <p> Amid claims circulating that Beijing would be locked down, which led to local residents flooding supermarkets to hoard food, Beijing officials on Thursday clarified that these are just rumors, but local residents are suggested to stay at home and take nucleic acid testing in the following three days as a bid to curb transmission in communities as early as possible.</p> <p> Beijing reported 36 COVID-19 infections in the past 24 hours, among whom 32 were discovered in areas under management and four outside those areas, Pang Xinghuo, an official from the Beijing health authority, said at a press conference.</p> <p> Cases found in communities are still the biggest risk to and the main target of the zero-COVID strategy in Beijing, Xu Hejian, the spokesperson of the Beijing government, said at the press conference.</p> <p> In order to curb virus transmission in communities outside managed areas, Beijing will launch another three rounds of nucleic acid testing from Friday to Sunday in 12 districts, including Chaoyang, Haidian and Fangshan, Xu said.</p> <p> Residents in the these districts are suggested to work from home on Friday and stay home over the weekend, avoiding movement, according to Xu.</p> <p> Xu refuted rumors circulating on social media platforms, which claimed that officials would announce a citywide lockdown in Beijing. He noted that it is unnecessary to hoard food.</p> <p> Beijing has adequate supplies of goods and commodities to ensure people's daily lives during the epidemic, and take-away and delivery services would not be stopped, Xu said, calling for residents to stay calm and consume rationally.</p> <p> Meanwhile, many Beijing residents had dashed to hoard food amid the rumors. When the press conference started at 5 pm, photos circulating online showed that some people stopped shopping and carefully watched the press conference on their hand phones at supermarkets, waiting to find out whether the capital would be locked down.</p> <p> Beijing, as the capital of China, carries the hope for large Chinese cities to explore a more effective way to fight against Omicron rather than to lock down or launch static management whenever infections are found. The city is receiving some applause.</p> <p> An expert from the disease prevention and control system spoke highly of Beijing's decisive move to launch mass and frequent nucleic acid testing at an early stage. He told the Global Times on condition of anonymity that nucleic acid testing is the most effective way to find infections as soon as possible.</p> <p> Beijing had applied precise management in different districts in according to local epidemic situations to reduce the impact of epidemic management measures on people's lives to the lowest level, the expert noted.</p> <p> The Beijing municipal government also communicated with and released information to the public very promptly, which has helped reduce public fear. These are all experiences that could be followed by other cities in the future, the expert said.</p> <p> The overall number of COVID-19 cases in Beijing is at a low level, but we must know the low level came from the great efforts Beijing residents made to actively control the pandemic, a Beijing-based respiratory expert who requested anonymity told the Global Times on Thursday.</p> <p> Without these efforts, a large number of infections would emerge rather than individual cases, said the expert, emphasizing the necessity of COVID-19 prevention measures for the public to realize.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Health, wealth no zero-sum game in China's COVID battle ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096080</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096080.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 08:31:34 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205130827000104680171992.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 677px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on April 23, 2022 shows an assembly workshop of automaker SAIC Motor Company's Lingang base in Shanghai, east China. (Xinhua/Chen Jianli)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- In the face of mounting uncertainties due to COVID-19, one thing remains certain -- China will stick to its dynamic zero-COVID policy that has proven pragmatic and effective.</p> <p> That steadfast commitment, reaffirmed by the Communist Party of China leadership at a high-level meeting last week, came as the COVID-hit city of Shanghai has seen infections fall over the past 10-plus days and many manufacturers, including Tesla, gradually resume operations.</p> <p> Shanghai's response is a continuation of China's dynamic anti-COVID measures, which the world's most populous country has constantly fine-tuned and optimized according to the fluid reality.</p> <p> Beijing's attempts to juggle the COVID response and the economic and social development, which the Chinese leaders have stressed since the pandemic began, have proven efficacious.</p> <p> The country of a 1.4 billion population always upholds the philosophy that protecting health and wealth during a pandemic is by no means a zero-sum game.</p> <p> All anti-epidemic measures naturally come at a price, and there has been short-term downward pressure on the Chinese economy. However, claiming that this will stifle the expansion of the world's second-largest economy is as shortsighted as it is irresponsible.</p> <p> Over the longer term, China will benefit economically from the dynamic zero-COVID approach. It has, so far, prevented many deaths at home and seen the country's industries come through the pandemic largely unscathed.</p> <p> Mass quarantine, large-scale testing, and closed-off management all take a toll on the economy. But once the outbreak is under control, the economy is expected to maintain its resilience and extend its track record of growth with policy support.</p> <p> That has been demonstrated as Chinese cities once plagued by the pandemic, such as Shenzhen, still registered stable growth in the first quarter after waves of flare-ups died down thanks to China's zero-COVID strategy. In a report on Shenzhen this week, South China Morning Post focused on the factories in the Chinese technology hub running at near or full capacity while adhering to China's dynamic zero-COVID policy. The report said: "it has so far helped the government walk a fine line."</p> <p> By only sealing off cities or areas that have seen spikes in infections, launching swift screening and massive inoculation encouragement, and pledging ramped-up efforts to stabilize the economy, China has managed the economic side effects of its COVID-fighting measures and made its zero-COVID policy sustainable.</p> <p> China's war against COVID-19 is by no means an ideological campaign that "sacrifices its economic growth," as some Western media portrayed it. It's essentially a war to protect people's lives -- the foundation for all economic development.</p> <p> China's scientifically-based and precise reaction to the virus and an array of pro-growth policies explain why the Chinese economy is off to a steady start this year, with its GDP up 4.8 percent year on year in the first three months.</p> <p> The taming of the virus, a universal challenge facing the world, necessitates customized and responsive solutions that guarantee the best outcomes. The one that China has been adhering to is such a solution that suits itself.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Inflatable COVID-19 testing laboratory put into use in Shunyi District ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096049</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096049.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 08:21:34 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/59/8734175958886296519.png" /></p> <p> Staff members transfer boxes containing registered samples for nucleic acid test at an inflatable COVID-19 testing lab in Shunyi District of Beijing, capital of China, May 12, 2022. An inflatable COVID-19 testing laboratory was put into use recently in Shunyi District.</p> <p> The newly installed lab, with a designed daily testing capacity of 100,000 tubes, covers the testing demand of various towns from Shunyi, as well as regions in other districts such as Miyun and Tongzhou. (Xinhua/Ren Chao)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/80/17637534153867181664.png" /></p> <p> Staff members work at an inflatable COVID-19 testing lab in Shunyi District of Beijing, capital of China, May 12, 2022. An inflatable COVID-19 testing laboratory was put into use recently in Shunyi District.</p> <p> The newly installed lab, with a designed daily testing capacity of 100,000 tubes, covers the testing demand of various towns from Shunyi, as well as regions in other districts such as Miyun and Tongzhou. (Xinhua/Ren Chao)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/70/10828554780825069154.png" /></p> <p> A staff member works at an inflatable COVID-19 testing lab in Shunyi District of Beijing, capital of China, May 12, 2022. An inflatable COVID-19 testing laboratory was put into use recently in Shunyi District.</p> <p> The newly installed lab, with a designed daily testing capacity of 100,000 tubes, covers the testing demand of various towns from Shunyi, as well as regions in other districts such as Miyun and Tongzhou. (Xinhua/Ren Chao)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/95/15167713949070938991.png" /></p> <p> Staff members work at an inflatable COVID-19 testing lab in Shunyi District of Beijing, capital of China, May 12, 2022. An inflatable COVID-19 testing laboratory was put into use recently in Shunyi District.</p> <p> The newly installed lab, with a designed daily testing capacity of 100,000 tubes, covers the testing demand of various towns from Shunyi, as well as regions in other districts such as Miyun and Tongzhou. (Xinhua/Ren Chao)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/11/9385017740424758027.png" /></p> <p> A staff member transfers a box containing registered samples for nucleic acid test at an inflatable COVID-19 testing lab in Shunyi District of Beijing, capital of China, May 12, 2022. An inflatable COVID-19 testing laboratory was put into use recently in Shunyi District.</p> <p> The newly installed lab, with a designed daily testing capacity of 100,000 tubes, covers the testing demand of various towns from Shunyi, as well as regions in other districts such as Miyun and Tongzhou. (Xinhua/Ren Chao)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/32/18365552628446768276.png" /></p> <p> A staff member works at an inflatable COVID-19 testing lab in Shunyi District of Beijing, capital of China, May 12, 2022. An inflatable COVID-19 testing laboratory was put into use recently in Shunyi District.</p> <p> The newly installed lab, with a designed daily testing capacity of 100,000 tubes, covers the testing demand of various towns from Shunyi, as well as regions in other districts such as Miyun and Tongzhou. (Xinhua/Ren Chao)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/82/12209179522690682278.png" /></p> <p> Staff members work at an inflatable COVID-19 testing lab in Shunyi District of Beijing, capital of China, May 12, 2022. An inflatable COVID-19 testing laboratory was put into use recently in Shunyi District.</p> <p> The newly installed lab, with a designed daily testing capacity of 100,000 tubes, covers the testing demand of various towns from Shunyi, as well as regions in other districts such as Miyun and Tongzhou. (Xinhua/Ren Chao)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/32/14398130864885926128.png" /></p> <p> Photo taken on May 12, 2022 shows an inflatable COVID-19 testing lab in Shunyi District of Beijing, capital of China. An inflatable COVID-19 testing laboratory was put into use recently in Shunyi District.</p> <p> The newly installed lab, with a designed daily testing capacity of 100,000 tubes, covers the testing demand of various towns from Shunyi, as well as regions in other districts such as Miyun and Tongzhou. (Xinhua/Ren Chao)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220513/97/7802542414030113509.png" /></p> <p> A staff member transfers samples for nucleic acid test at an inflatable COVID-19 testing lab in Shunyi District of Beijing, capital of China, May 12, 2022. An inflatable COVID-19 testing laboratory was put into use recently in Shunyi District.</p> <p> The newly installed lab, with a designed daily testing capacity of 100,000 tubes, covers the testing demand of various towns from Shunyi, as well as regions in other districts such as Miyun and Tongzhou. (Xinhua/Ren Chao)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Half of hospitalized COVID-19 infected report symptom two yrs after infection: study ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095964</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095964.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 17:10:41 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- The longest follow-up study to date on COVID-19 showed that two years after infection, half of the patients who were admitted to the hospital still have at least one symptom.</p> <p> The study published on Thursday in the journal Lancet Respiratory Medicine revealed that nearly 1,200 participants in China infected with the coronavirus that caused COVID-19 tend to have poorer health and quality of life than the general population.</p> <p> The researchers from China-Japan Friendship Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Peking Union Medical College and Tsinghua University School of Medicine evaluated the health of 1,192 participants with acute COVID-19 treated at Jinyintan Hospital in Wuhan between January 7 and May 29, 2020, at six months, 12 months, and two years.</p> <p> The group, with a median age of 57 at discharge, is assessed for a six-minute walking test, laboratory tests, and questionnaires on symptoms, mental health, health-related quality of life, if they had returned to work, and healthcare use after discharge.</p> <p> The study showed that six months after initially falling ill, 68 percent of them reported at least one long COVID symptom, and by two years after infection, 55 percent of them reported symptoms, among them such as fatigue, muscle weakness and sleep difficulties.</p> <p> Also, their complaints included joint pain, palpitations, dizziness, headaches and anxiety or depression, according to the study.</p> <p> "Our findings indicate that for a certain proportion of hospitalized COVID-19 survivors, while they may have cleared the initial infection, more than two years is needed to recover fully from COVID-19," said the paper's corresponding author Cao Bing with China-Japan Friendship Hospital.</p> <p> The authors admitted the limitations including the fact that those who did not participate in the study might have fewer symptoms than those who did, which may result in an overestimate of the prevalence of long COVID symptoms.</p> <p> But there is a "clear need to provide continued support to a significant proportion of people who have had COVID-19," said Cao.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 25 injured after passenger plane veers off runway in southwest China ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095962</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095962.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 17:10:41 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/51/1241763197874596555.png" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on May 12, 2022 shows the accident site where a passenger plane veered off the runway during take-off and caught fire at the Chongqing Jiangbei International Airport in southwest China's Chongqing.(Xinhua/Liu Chan)</em></p> <p> CHONGQING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Twenty-five people were injured after a passenger plane veered off the runway during take-off and caught fire at an airport in southwest China's Chongqing at around 8 a.m. on Thursday, airport sources said.</p> <p> The passenger plane operated by Tibet Airlines was carrying 113 passengers and nine crew members on board, said the sources.</p> <p> All people aboard the plane were evacuated and the injured were rushed to hospital for treatment.&nbsp;</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/29/15832756018573796833.png" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on May 12, 2022 shows the accident site where a passenger plane veered off the runway during take-off and caught fire at the Chongqing Jiangbei International Airport in southwest China's Chongqing.(Xinhua/Liu Chan)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ The migrant worker with an audience of millions ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095960</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095960.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 17:10:41 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/88/15572314605921645560.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>He Chuan shows followers his dishes during lunch break in a vlog recorded at a construction site in Dazhou, southwest China's Sichuan Province, April 29, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Xi)</em></p> <p> CHENGDU, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Like many other migrant workers on construction sites, He Chuan mixes concrete and lays bricks throughout the day. Unlike most, however, he has taken the trouble to document elements of his daily life through live-streaming. Adopting the online name "Brother Chuan", he has gained considerable online celebrity.</p> <p> Hailing from Dazhou in southwest China's Sichuan Province, He, 52, has spent many years as a migrant worker on building sites around China. He is not alone in this, with 25 million Sichuan farmers leaving the fields for city jobs across the country.</p> <p> Now back in his hometown, He continues to intersperse his construction work with vlogging, setting up his camera to live-stream his lunch breaks before an audience of hundreds, sometimes thousands. His wife Tang Wenshu partners up with him during the sessions, which mostly revolve around the food they are eating and comments on construction work.</p> <p> In one typical session, "Brother Chuan" can be seen serving his wife a bowl of rice and then wolfing down the rest from the rice cooker. Finally, he displays a piece of crispy griddled chicken, making many of his viewers drool.</p> <p> POPULAR VLOGGER</p> <p> Without any professional camera or technical training, the couple have recorded their simple daily life since 2018, drawing nearly 2 million followers on social media platforms with over 1,000 vlogs.</p> <p> "Although I'm neither handsome nor knowledgeable, I am optimistic and love working," said He, who has worked in construction for around 30 years.</p> <p> The couple's "studios" are always situated in buildings under construction. With bricks as chairs and storage boxes as tables, the two sweaty faces are always seen laughing and gobbling yummy food in front of the camera.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/94/1257202439096025382.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>He Chuan and his wife Tang Wenshu wave goodbye to their audiences at the end of an online show held at a building under construction in Dazhou, southwest China's Sichuan Province, April 29, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Xi)</em></p> <p> He said he is happy that viewers appreciate his attitude to life and how construction work has paid off.</p> <p> "Being recognized and learning new things from comments have driven me to share more," He said.</p> <p> INFLUENTIAL VOICE</p> <p> "I was nervous about live-streaming on camera initially," he said. However, his followers, the majority of whom are migrant workers and students, give him great support.</p> <p> From the online comments and private messages delivered to his mailboxes, He has found that viewers are mostly inspired by his devotion to work, as well as caring about his quality of life.</p> <p> His hard work received wider recognition in 2021 when he was given a vlogging award by Xigua Video, a video sharing platform. In his acceptance speech for "The Best Moment" award, he said, "If you once drew strength from my company, I hope you can hang in there for a little bit longer, and eventually overcome frustration and difficulties."</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/38/10800422076889118446.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>He Chuan (R) uses a camera to record his colleagues working at a construction site in Dazhou, southwest China's Sichuan Province, April 29, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Xi)</em></p> <p> Live-streams of "Brother Chuan" also create a platform where migrant workers can discuss topics that they care about, such as wage calculation, safety measures and retirement.</p> <p> "It is safer for aged workers to stop working at heights and leave construction sites, but their livelihoods should be taken into consideration," He said when chatting with his wife during a vlog discussing the welfare of aged migrant workers.</p> <p> Empowered by digital tools, migrant workers like He are making their voices heard and their lives more visible to wider audiences.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/86/11767624851983138714.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>He Chuan plasters a wall and his wife Tang Wenshu mixes mortar at a construction site in Dazhou, southwest China's Sichuan Province, April 29, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Xi)</em></p> <p> A LIVING WAGE</p> <p> Plastering brings the couple 600 yuan (about 89 U.S. dollars) per day, while He's new craft, vlogging, yields him 200 yuan per piece on average, contributing more to their household income than construction work.</p> <p> He started as a plastering apprentice decades back. Along with the rapid development of China's coastal regions, He and Tang joined the migration stream to seek a fortune in east China's Fujian Province in 2003.</p> <p> The couple dwelled in a 10-square-meter temporary shed and worked on scaffolds high above the ground for years, joining the construction of soaring skyscrapers and modern venues.</p> <p> As urbanization in western China has accelerated, the couple returned to their hometown of Dazhou in 2019 and are currently working on a construction site for a digital-economy industrial park.</p> <p> The couple have bought their riverside three-bedroom apartment in Dazhou and live with their two children. The elder son He Songlin edits videos and manages accounts for his father, while the younger son is studying in middle school.</p> <p> In a vlog recorded at their apartment, He handed his younger son a slice of cake and said, "Happy birthday, and I hope you go to the university of your choice." Tang also presented gifts to the boy.</p> <p> This modest family scene moved many viewers, who posted comments expressing their appreciation.</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/17/13943982861474035601.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>He Chuan and his wife Tang Wenshu at their home in Dazhou, southwest China's Sichuan Province, April 28, 2022. (Xinhua/Wang Xi)</em></p> <p> BETTER LIVELIHOODS</p> <p> According to China's National Bureau of Statistics (NBS), the number of migrant workers in the country reached 292.51 million in 2021, and their average monthly income has risen to 4,432 yuan, exceeding the national average of 2,927 yuan.</p> <p> Last week, the general offices of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and the State Council jointly issued a document stating that migrant workers will receive better support at the county level with regard to various public services, including housing, professional training, children's education, pensions and medical care.</p> <p> Among the countless fancy buildings that He has worked on, he likes building schools the most. Recently, he participated in the construction of a local vocational college. Seeing young people playing basketball on the playground he built, He said he was more than satisfied.</p> <p> His account profile on one short-video platform sums up the vlogger's constructive attitude: "I work hard to earn money to support my family, and contribute to the construction of our country."&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China cracks down on cross-border gambling, fraud ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095861</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095861.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 16:35:48 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- China has cracked some 11,000 cases related to illegal cross-border gambling and fraud since the beginning of 2021, the National Immigration Administration said Thursday.</p> <p> A total of 15,000 people involved in illegal outbound cross-border gambling activities have been caught, and 290 gangs organizing such illegal activities have been busted, said the administration.</p> <p> Any clues about such cross-border gambling activities should be reported to the public security organs, said the administration, adding that the administration's tip-off hotline 12367 also welcomes such clues.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's ecology sees historic turning point: official ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095832</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095832.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 15:30:04 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- China's ecological environment has witnessed a historic turning point over the past decade, an official said Thursday.</p> <p> "We have seen fewer hazy days and black and smelly water bodies, and have enjoyed bluer skies and more lucid waters and lush mountains," Han Wenxiu, a senior official with the Central Committee for Financial and Economic Affairs, said at a press conference.</p> <p> China's artificial afforestation has accounted for about a quarter of the world's total, and its CO2 emissions per unit of the gross domestic product have dropped about 34 percent, Han said.</p> <p> The country has also topped the globe in installed capacity of wind and photovoltaic power and other green energy, and in the production and sales of new energy vehicles, Han said.</p> <p> As a faithful advocate of the Paris Agreement, China has announced targets of peaking CO2 emissions before 2030 and achieving carbon neutrality before 2060, Han said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Shanghai vlog: 22-year-old building manager's life amid COVID-19 outbreak ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095785</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095785.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 15:17:12 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <center> <video controls="controls" poster=" http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/5/12/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_806789f46ee19237913837e95689a1e6.jpg" src=" http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/5/12/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_caf09eef31d6c6fa3d62ac41e523a974.mp4" style=" width: 830px; height:550px;"> <p> &nbsp;</p> </video> </center> <p> Millions of views, thousands of comments on a college girl's vlog about becoming a building manager and helping residents during Shanghai's citywide quarantine.</p> <p> La Hong, a building manager in a community of Shanghai told CGTN her daily tasks for the new role include distributing self-test kits, organizing nucleic acid PCR testing for residents, and distributing supplies to each of them. They also coordinate with the neighborhood committee on chat groups whenever residents have any issues.</p> <p> The freshness faded away quickly, she said, adding that getting things done are not easy. Sometimes things get complicated, when some residents are reluctant to cooperate. And sometimes, things "pile up."</p> <p> "I cried. At that time, I was just starting out as head of the building. Then all kinds of things went wrong. The neighborhood committee also felt that I wouldn't be able to do things, and all kinds of negative things accumulated and broke down," she recalled.</p> <p> But La persisted in her work and in recording her life. Her three episodes of “Serving as a Building Manager” have racked up some 15 million views on the Chinese video-streaming platform, Bilibili.</p> <p> The 22-year-old was one of the site's top unloaders in 2019, where she already has 2.8 million followers.</p> <p> "I've been shooting videos for five to six years, and they're just based on my daily life. It's part of my routine. I like documenting my life. This time, I had the opportunity to meet all kinds of people. I also learned about how to communicate with people," she said.</p> <p> "Everyone has different thoughts. I need to learn more about respect, open-mindedness, and the concept of coexistence," she added.</p> <p> Based on what she's learned so far, she said she's hoping to do more as a building manager.</p> <p> "I feel that we've reached a bottleneck period. We've all been at home for a certain period of time, so I'm trying to find ways to engage in some entertaining activities. Otherwise it will be really difficult," La noted.</p> <p> With more trust from her neighbors and more praise from her viewers, La said she's learned that there are more gains from stepping up to help out.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: CGTN</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Young dispatcher carries forward China's space dream ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095750</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095750.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 14:37:09 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <center> <video controls="controls" poster=" http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/5/12/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_3a8f63bcd6b3ac5b9758304ac2e5f536.jpeg" src=" http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/5/12/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_2fd8956cfeb7eeaae1465e88b994ef4d.mp4" style=" width: 830px; height:550px;"> <p> &nbsp;</p> </video> </center> <p> Bao Shuo, 29, the first post-90s female chief dispatcher with the Beijing Aerospace Control Center, was part of the project team of China's first Mars exploration mission, Tianwen-1.</p> <p> "Striving makes youth worthwhile. We are just seizing the day and striving for what we want to achieve. We are working for our goals and dreams," says Bao, touted by netizens as "an example for the post-90s generation."</p> <p> Bao said that doing one's bit to make our country stronger knows no age or gender limits and every aerospace worker is working hard for China's space dream.</p> <p> Click to hear more of her story and her team's space dream.</p> <p> <em>(Compiled by Chen Rui)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily App</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Heavy rainfall hits south China ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095722</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095722.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 13:54:07 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/81/5932040387095396757.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Aerial photo taken by drones shows the flooded Shangxi village in Guangzhou, south China's Guangdong Province, May 11, 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Chen Wenmin)</em></p> <p> The heaviest rainfall of this year swept south China, especially Guangdong Province on Wednesday.</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/89/15699939578467375841.jpg" /></p> <p> Aerial photo taken by drones shows the flooded Shangxi village in Guangzhou, south China's Guangdong Province, May 11, 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Chen Wenmin)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/24/16421971182660833044.jpg" /></p> <p> Aerial photo taken by drones shows the flooded Shangxi village in Guangzhou, south China's Guangdong Province, May 11, 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Chen Wenmin)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/74/5309280777375153834.jpg" /></p> <p> Heavy rain caused flooding in a field in Shangxi village, Guangzhou, south China's Guangdong Province, May 11, 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Chen Wenmin)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/27/14507781164954664723.jpg" /></p> <p> Villagers pumps water into Pajing river in Shangxi village, Guangzhou, south China's Guangdong Province, May 11, 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Chen Wenmin)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/50/13749084096350752954.jpg" /></p> <p> Aerial photo taken by drones shows the flooded Shangxi village in Guangzhou, south China's Guangdong Province, May 11, 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Chen Wenmin)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/10/4927450839877993610.jpg" /></p> <p> A banana field is flooded by heavy rain in Shangxi village, Guangzhou, south China's Guangdong Province, May 11, 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Chen Wenmin)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/35/10649633337845393899.jpg" /></p> <p> Trucks drive on a waterlogged road in Conghua district, Guangzhou, south China's Guangdong Province, May 11, 2022. (Photo: China News Service/Chen Wenmin)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Ecns.cn</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Paved road under construction in Gandong Township, Guangxi ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095748</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095748.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 13:35:45 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/96/13493505523828478392.png" /></p> <p> People work at a road construction site in Huazi Village, Gandong Township of Rongshui Miao Autonomous County, south China's Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, May 11, 2022.</p> <p> To provide convenient transportation to local villagers and boost rural revitalization, Gandong Township are now stepping up efforts to construct a paved road linking it with the county seat of Rongshui Miao Autonomous County. (Xinhua/Huang Xiaobang)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/87/14736834066224645043.png" /></p> <p> People work at a road construction site in Huazi Village, Gandong Township of Rongshui Miao Autonomous County, south China's Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, May 11, 2022.</p> <p> To provide convenient transportation to local villagers and boost rural revitalization, Gandong Township are now stepping up efforts to construct a paved road linking it with the county seat of Rongshui Miao Autonomous County. (Xinhua/Huang Xiaobang)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/47/15845539528701623479.png" /></p> <p> People work at a road construction site in Gandong Village, Gandong Township of Rongshui Miao Autonomous County, south China's Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, May 11, 2022.</p> <p> To provide convenient transportation to local villagers and boost rural revitalization, Gandong Township are now stepping up efforts to construct a paved road linking it with the county seat of Rongshui Miao Autonomous County. (Xinhua/Huang Xiaobang)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/36/2204321245676627800.png" /></p> <p> Machineries are used in road construction in Huazi Village, Gandong Township of Rongshui Miao Autonomous County, south China's Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, May 11, 2022.</p> <p> To provide convenient transportation to local villagers and boost rural revitalization, Gandong Township are now stepping up efforts to construct a paved road linking it with the county seat of Rongshui Miao Autonomous County. (Xinhua/Huang Xiaobang)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/3/12361418078402128495.png" /></p> <p> An excavator is used in road construction in Gandong Village, Gandong Township of Rongshui Miao Autonomous County, south China's Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, May 11, 2022.</p> <p> To provide convenient transportation to local villagers and boost rural revitalization, Gandong Township are now stepping up efforts to construct a paved road linking it with the county seat of Rongshui Miao Autonomous County. (Xinhua/Huang Xiaobang)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/59/12208417895587496475.png" /></p> <p> People work at a road construction site in Huazi Village, Gandong Township of Rongshui Miao Autonomous County, south China's Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, May 11, 2022.</p> <p> To provide convenient transportation to local villagers and boost rural revitalization, Gandong Township are now stepping up efforts to construct a paved road linking it with the county seat of Rongshui Miao Autonomous County. (Xinhua/Huang Xiaobang)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 571 COVID-19 patients discharged from hospitals on Chinese mainland ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095690</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095690.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:56:31 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- A total of 571 COVID-19 patients were discharged from hospitals after recovery on the Chinese mainland on Wednesday, the National Health Commission said in its Thursday report.</p> <p> That brought the mainland's total number of COVID-19 patients discharged from hospitals after recovery to 208,526 as of Wednesday.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese mainland reports 222 new local COVID-19 cases, 144 in Shanghai ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095692</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095692.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:56:31 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121036000294418317064.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 639px;" /></p> <p> <em>A customer scans the QR code before entering a grocery store in Jiading District of east China's Shanghai, May 9, 2022. (Xinhua/Li He)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- The Chinese mainland on Wednesday reported 222 confirmed local COVID-19 cases, of which 144 were in Shanghai, the National Health Commission said on Thursday.</p> <p> Apart from Shanghai, seven other provincial-level regions on the mainland saw new locally transmitted COVID-19 cases, including 35 in Beijing and 21 in Henan.</p> <p> Shanghai also reported 1,305 locally transmitted asymptomatic infections Wednesday, out of a total of 1,630 such cases newly identified on the mainland.</p> <p> Following the recovery of 571 COVID-19 patients who were discharged from hospital on Wednesday, there were 7,229 confirmed COVID-19 cases receiving treatment in hospitals across the Chinese mainland.</p> <p> Wednesday saw five deaths from COVID-19, all in Shanghai.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Shanghai reports 144 confirmed, 1,305 asymptomatic local COVID-19 cases ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095688</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095688.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:34:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> SHANGHAI, May 12 (Xinhua) -- China's Shanghai reported 144 confirmed locally transmitted COVID-19 cases and 1,305 local asymptomatic cases on Wednesday, the municipal health commission said Thursday.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Beijing reports 56 new local COVID-19 infections ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095629</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095629.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:12:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- Beijing reported 56 new locally transmitted COVID-19 infections between 3 p.m. Tuesday and 3 p.m. Wednesday, said local authorities during a press conference held Wednesday.</p> <p> The new cases were all detected among personnel under closed-off management. Among the new infections, 19 are asymptomatic carriers, said Pang Xinghuo, deputy head of the Beijing municipal disease prevention and control center, during the conference.</p> <p> Meanwhile, no patient with severe COVID-19 symptoms was found.</p> <p> Mass nucleic acid testings were organized in Beijing Tuesday, with over 14.5 million residents sampled.</p> <p> Among the samples, two tubes collected in a mixed testing approach from Haidian and Tongzhou districts were found to be positive. Relevant test result review and disease prevention and control measures are underway, said Li Ang, deputy director of the Beijing Municipal Health Commission.</p> <p> Hidden transmission sources in communities still exist and Beijing will use antigen testing as a supplementary measure to screen key risk groups and staff in key industries, according to local health authorities.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ In numbers：International Nurses Day ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095619</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095619.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:09:58 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/46/4906557290350645678.jpg" /></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Ecns.cn</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Bringing the magic of film to blind audiences in Tibet ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095606</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095606.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:00:32 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> LHASA, May 11 (Xinhua) -- When the animated film "Ne Zha" started playing, an auditorium of blind or partially sighted cinemagoers soaked in the vivid narrations and the odyssey of this Chinese mythical figure.</p> <p> Thanks to a public-service project named "Ever Shining Cinema," the film about Ne Zha, a devil born into a loving family and eventually emerging as a hero, can find its way into a special-education school in Lhasa, the capital of southwest China's Tibet Autonomous Region, on Tuesday.</p> <p> The school is home to around 250 students, including 51 with visual impairments.</p> <p> "I was filled with excitement. I love the movie," said visually impaired student Lhamo Drolkar. "The project and its barrier-free films enable us to enjoy the silver screen, just like the sighted moviegoers."</p> <p> The "Ever Shining Cinema" project was initiated at the end of 2017 by the Communication University of China, Beijing Gehua CATV Network Co., Ltd., and Oriental Jiaying Media Co., Ltd. It aims to interpret movies for visually impaired people through dubbing to meet their spiritual and cultural needs.</p> <p> China has about 17.3 million people with visual disabilities, according to the second national sample survey on disability.</p> <p> By the end of last year, the project had produced 416 barrier-free movies and one barrier-free TV series and held 254 public welfare screenings nationwide.</p> <p> In 2019, the "Ever Shining Cinema" project brought a barrier-free movie to Tibet for the first time.</p> <p> "In the future, we will strengthen ties with the visually impaired in Tibet and send more and better barrier-free movies there. We hope the barrier-free concept can take root in the snowy plateau region," said Zhao Shuping, a professor at the Communication University of China and the project instructor.</p> <p> The Marrakesh Treaty to Facilitate Access to Published Works for Persons Who Are Blind, Visually Impaired or Otherwise Print Disabled came into force in China on May 5.</p> <p> The treaty aims to eliminate copyright-related obstacles for print-disabled people in obtaining works. Experts believe it will create a broader space for the production and dissemination of barrier-free films and television dramas in China.</p> <p> "The vivid characters in the movies make me believe that through my efforts, I can create a bright life too," said Lhamo Drolkar.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Beijing meets all national air quality standards in 2021 for first time ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095600</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095600.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:48:23 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- Beijing saw all its six major ambient air pollutants in 2021 reach the level-II national standard for the city's first time, said the Beijing municipal ecology and environment bureau on Wednesday.</p> <p> The bureau released a report on the city's ecological environment situation in 2021 on Wednesday. According to the report, the city's average concentration of hazardous airborne particles PM2.5 last year was 33 micrograms per cubic meter, while the average concentration of PM10 was 55 micrograms per cubic meter.</p> <p> The PM2.5 reading is a gauge monitoring airborne particles of 2.5 microns or less in diameter, which can penetrate deep into people's lungs.</p> <p> Data released showed that other key air pollution readings, including sulfur dioxide, nitrogen dioxide, carbon monoxide and ozone, all reached the national standards during the period.</p> <p> Besides the improving air quality, none of the total 97 sections of Beijing's major water systems were graded Class V in terms of their water quality in 2021. The proportion of surface water at or above Grade III in the country's five-tier water quality system reached 75.2 percent, up 11.4 percentage points compared to the prior year.</p> <p> Meanwhile, about 116 kinds of phytoplankton, 195 kinds of zooplankton, 207 kinds of benthonic animals and 41 fish species were monitored in Beijing's main streams and tributaries, key lakes and large- and medium-sized reservoirs.</p> <p> Notably, the city's carbon dioxide emission per 10,000 yuan (about 1,486 U.S. dollars) of GDP last year fell by about 4 percent compared with 2020, said the report.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Work, production resumption underway in Zhengzhou ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095588</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095588.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:42:13 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/54/9190347370937599082.png" /></p> <p> Citizens purchase vegetables at a residential area in Zhengzhou, central China's Henan Province, May 10, 2022. Zhengzhou has resumed work and production from May 11 in the city other than closed-off management areas and restrictive control areas. (Xinhua/Li Jianan)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/13/7804610938947567461.png" /></p> <p> A medical worker takes a swab sample from a citizen for nucleic acid test at a residential area in Zhengzhou, central China's Henan Province, May 4, 2022. Zhengzhou has resumed work and production from May 11 in the city other than closed-off management areas and restrictive control areas. (Xinhua/Li Jianan)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/46/13200666287840182134.png" /></p> <p> A citizen takes a walk at a small garden in Zhengzhou, central China's Henan Province, May 11, 2022. Zhengzhou has resumed work and production from May 11 in the city other than closed-off management areas and restrictive control areas. (Xinhua/Zhang Haoran)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/37/4446895620937424161.png" /></p> <p> Aerial photo taken on May 11, 2022 shows vehicles running on a flyover in Zhengzhou, central China's Henan Province. Zhengzhou has resumed work and production from May 11 in the city other than closed-off management areas and restrictive control areas. (Xinhua/Li Jianan)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/44/391209879199553856.png" /></p> <p> A staff member of a shop does cleaning for reopening in Zhengzhou, central China's Henan Province, May 11, 2022. Zhengzhou has resumed work and production from May 11 in the city other than closed-off management areas and restrictive control areas. (Xinhua/Zhang Haoran)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/67/5768651614399244195.png" /></p> <p> Citizens purchase vegetables at a market in Zhengzhou, central China's Henan Province, May 10, 2022. Zhengzhou has resumed work and production from May 11 in the city other than closed-off management areas and restrictive control areas. (Xinhua/Li Jianan)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/12/4191186224296727268.png" /></p> <p> A staff member does cleaning in front of a shopping mall in Zhengzhou, central China's Henan Province, May 11, 2022. Zhengzhou has resumed work and production from May 11 in the city other than closed-off management areas and restrictive control areas. (Xinhua/Zhang Haoran)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/23/4026281254723777699.png" /></p> <p> A staff member of delivery service contacts a customer at a distribution center in Zhengzhou, central China's Henan Province, May 10, 2022. Zhengzhou has resumed work and production from May 11 in the city other than closed-off management areas and restrictive control areas. (Xinhua/Li Jianan)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/2/18170573579193872834.png" /></p> <p> A vendor arranges apples at a market in Zhengzhou, central China's Henan Province, May 10, 2022. Zhengzhou has resumed work and production from May 11 in the city other than closed-off management areas and restrictive control areas. (Xinhua/Li Jianan)</p> <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220512/78/7432059665066153538.png" /></p> <p> A citizen with a child gets tickets checked at the entrance of the Zhengzhou Zoo in Zhengzhou, central China's Henan Province, May 11, 2022. Zhengzhou has resumed work and production from May 11 in the city other than closed-off management areas and restrictive control areas. (Xinhua/Zhang Haoran)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ First-dose COVID-19 vaccination rate for elderly, disabled homes reaches 84 pct ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095570</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095570.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:41:57 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> HONG KONG, May 11 (Xinhua) -- The Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (HKSAR) government announced Wednesday that the overall vaccination rate for the first dose of COVID-19 vaccines at residential care homes (RCH) for the elderly and disabled persons has reached 84 percent.</p> <p> The HKSAR government launched the third stage of outreach vaccination service on April 15 and set the target of providing outreach vaccination service to unvaccinated RCH residents who have recovered from COVID-19, and those who are due to receive the next vaccine dose after their first or second dose by Tuesday.</p> <p> With efforts of various parties, the overall first-dose vaccination rate at RCHs based on the total number of RCH residents has risen from 55 percent in mid-March to 84 percent as of Tuesday, while the overall vaccination rates for the second and third doses at RCHs are 56 percent and 14 percent respectively.</p> <p> Patrick Nip, secretary for the civil service of the HKSAR government, said that under the COVID-19 pandemic, the elderly and RCH residents are the most vulnerable groups and are most in need of the protection conferred by the vaccines, urging the public to understand the risk of death faced by the elderly after being infected with COVID-19 and the efficacy of vaccines.</p> <p> A total of 16 outreach teams have been set up by the HKSAR government to provide health assessments and vaccination to residents of RCHs for the elderly and disabled persons as early as possible, involving a total of over 700 healthcare personnel.</p> <p> On Wednesday, Hong Kong registered 131 new COVID-19 cases by nucleic acid tests, and 149 additional cases through self-reported antigen rapid tests, official data showed.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Heavy rains affect 27,000 people in China's Guangxi ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095556</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095556.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:36:24 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NANNING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- Over 27,000 residents of south China's Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region have been affected by extensive heavy rains that began on Sunday, the regional emergency management department said on Wednesday.</p> <p> As of 5 p.m. Wednesday, rainfall has caused flooding in 22 counties across nine cities in the region, affecting more than 27,000 people.</p> <p> The affected crop area has totaled 2,392 hectares, leading to direct economic losses of 104 million yuan (about 15.4 million U.S. dollars).</p> <p> From 12 p.m. on Wednesday, the regional flood control and drought relief headquarters has upgraded its emergency response from Level IV to Level III, and has sent working groups to the cities to conduct flood control and relief work.</p> <p> China has a four-tier flood-control emergency response system, with Level I being the most severe.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Video conference held to share festive experience in Xinjiang ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095529</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095529.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:14:57 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> URUMQI, May 11 (Xinhua) -- Muslim residents and religious figures in northwest China's Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region shared their personal experiences in a video during the recently concluded Islamic holy month of Ramadan and Eid al-Fitr.</p> <p> From April 3 to May 2, Muslims of various ethnic groups in the region observed Ramadan. They celebrated Eid al-Fitr, which fell on May 3, while enjoying a one-day holiday, said Xu Guixiang, spokesperson for the regional government, during a video conference on Tuesday.</p> <p> Memet Juma, hatip of the Id Kah Mosque in Kashgar Prefecture, said that prayers visited the 550-year-old mosque every day, and thousands of people of different ethnic groups performed their traditional dances on the square in front of the mosque.</p> <p> Noting that Xinjiang is home to various ethnic groups and religious beliefs, Zumrat Obul, head of the regional united front work department, said that all normal religious activities are protected by law.</p> <p> In recent years, there has been great misunderstanding about the religious situation in Xinjiang, and the United States in particular has groundlessly claimed that religious freedoms are restricted in Xinjiang.</p> <p> "These ridiculous lies run completely counter to the facts," Xu said.</p> <p> "We would like to go on telling Xinjiang's true stories to the international community," Xu said. "We are also looking forward to welcoming more visitors to Xinjiang who can witness the prosperous and comfortable life here."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China charts route to urbanization with focus on county towns ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095522</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095522.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:07:23 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> The General Office of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and the General Office of the State Council recently released guidelines on advancing urbanization with a focus on county towns, setting out clear targets and specific tasks for the construction of urbanization.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205120856000071107151598.jpg" style="width: 829px; height: 503px;" /></p> <p> <em>A host promotes fishing rods via livestreaming platform at an e-commerce supplies base in Suning county, north China’s Hebei province, June 6, 2020. (People’s Daily Online/Yuan Liwei)</em></p> <p> County towns are an important component of China’s urban system. Official data indicated that by the end of 2021, the county towns of 1,472 counties in China had a combined permanent resident population of around 160 million and the urban areas of 394 county-level cities had approximately 90 million permanent residents, accounting for nearly 30 percent of the resident population in China’s urban areas when combined.</p> <p> Meanwhile, the number of counties and county-level cities made up about 65 percent of the country’s county-level administrative regions.</p> <p> “Promoting the construction of county towns can help accommodate rural migrants as local residents in cities and towns and improve the spatial layout of urbanization for coordinated development of cities of different sizes and small towns,” said an official with China’s National Development and Reform Commission (NDRC).</p> <p> There are a vast number of county towns in China, each of which has various forms and development paths. The development of many county towns is still confronted with certain constraints. Such problems as unsophisticated industrial platforms, incomplete supporting facilities and ageing public facilities have reduced county towns’ carrying capacity and attractiveness.</p> <p> According to the guidelines, China will clarify functions of county towns across the country, divide them into five categories according to their characteristics, and determine different development paths for them.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205120856000197874469606.jpg" style="width: 830px; height: 553px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo shows workers busy with production at an industrial park for high-end manufacturing in the economic development zone of Dangshan county, Suzhou city, east China’s Anhui province, Dec. 14, 2021. (People’s Daily Online/Cui Meng)</em></p> <p> The guidelines stated that efforts will be made to speed up the development of county towns surrounding large cities, actively cultivate county towns featuring professional functions, help county towns in main producing areas of agricultural products enjoy rational development, develop county towns in key ecological function areas in an orderly manner, and guide transformation and development of county towns that are losing population.</p> <p> The document also set out 25 tasks concerning five aspects of the development of county towns, including cultivating characteristic industries, improving municipal facility system, strengthening the supply of public services, raising the quality of living environment, and promoting the connection and complementarity among functions of county towns, townships, and villages.</p> <p> Industries serve as the foundation for the construction and development of county towns. China is going to enhance county towns’ capacity to support the development of industries, nurture characteristics, and achieve staggered development, pointed out the guidelines.</p> <p> The country will focus on developing industries with significant comparative advantages and a large capacity for driving the development of agriculture and rural areas as well as for employment in county towns, and coordinate the cultivation of local industries and receiving industrial relocation, according to the guidelines.</p> <p> Meanwhile, county towns should also improve the functions of industrial platforms and guide the cluster development of local industries; improve commercial distribution networks, develop logistics centers and specialized markets, and build distribution and transfer centers for industrial and agricultural products; and improve consumption-related infrastructure, enhance vocational skills training, and help migrant workers from rural areas, especially those facing difficulties, elevate their skills, quality, and ability to maintain stable employment, the document stressed.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205120856000356681681450.jpg" style="width: 828px; height: 621px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on April 17, 2022 shows picturesque spring scenery of a wetland park along Heihe River in Gaotai county, Zhangye city, northwest China’s Gansu province. (People’s Daily Online/Zheng Yaode)</em></p> <p> Efforts will also be made to raise county towns’ carrying capacity and attractiveness, including upgrading municipal facilities, improving public transportation facilities, smoothening channels for better connection and communication with other regions, and advancing digital transformation, according to the document.</p> <p> The guidelines also demanded deepening institutional innovation to provide a policy guarantee for the construction of county towns. For example, county towns are asked to remove all limits on household registration and establish diversified and sustainable investment and financing mechanisms.</p> <p> They should formulate reasonable investment and financing plans according to the nature and benefits of projects, noted the document.</p> <p> Local governments can increase investment in public welfare projects and provide support for eligible projects with the central government budget and their special-purpose bonds, said the document.</p> <p> The document also encouraged increasing medium and long-term loans and expressed support for the issuance of special corporate bonds by qualified enterprises for new urbanization in county towns.</p> <p> According to the guidelines, China will achieve important progress in urbanization with a focus on county towns by 2025; and, through a period of efforts after that, it will basically build modern county towns with distinctive characteristics, vitality, livable environment, and sound employment conditions across the country.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Female volunteer makes selfless effort to build ideal habitat for white cranes in E China’s Jiangxi ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095372</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095372.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 17:54:42 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205111748000512410705315.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 123px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo shows white cranes flying over the Nanchang Five Stars Siberian Cranes Sanctuary. (Photo/Ye Xueling)</em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205111749000068723404174.jpg" /></em></p> <p> <em>Photo shows white cranes inside the Nanchang Five Stars Siberian Cranes Sanctuary. (Photo/Zhou Haiyan)</em></p> <p> In 2017, Zhou Haiyan, a photography enthusiast, together with other photographers, rented a 200,000-square-meter lotus field in an attempt to use the lotus roots grown there to feed white cranes, which are under first-class state protection in China.</p> <p> Before taking up this job, Zhou had been a TV hostess. In 2013, she developed a new hobby in the form of photography, and every year since then she would take time to photograph birds at Poyang Lake in Nanchang, east China’s Jiangxi Province. The beautiful white cranes gradually were able to capture her heart.</p> <p> Growing lotus proved to be an arduous task for Zhou when she started. During the ploughing season, she often got up at 5 a.m. to prepare for the transplanting of lotus seedlings. Slogging through the sticky mud while wearing high-tube rubber boots, she soon found that her legs and feet would get drenched with sweat.</p> <p> Zhou and her colleagues spent more than 1 million yuan ($148,600) to build the lotus field, which is located near Poyang Lake. They waited several months before the white cranes finally began arriving at the field in November 2017. In the winter during the same year, more than 1,400 white cranes gathered around the lotus field.</p> <p> For nearly 10 months throughout the year, Zhou will remain at the lotus field, planting lotus seedlings, managing the field, waiting for the arrival of the white cranes and receiving visitors who came to watch the birds.</p> <p> Bird watchers, photographers and scholars from nearly 40 countries have visited the protection center. Thanks to the joint efforts of the Jiangxi Provincial Department of Forestry, the Nanchang Forestry Bureau, and the Nanchang High-tech Industrial Development Zone, the center was listed as a trial site for receiving an eco-compensation fund.</p> <p> Some people have suggested that Zhou should invite tourists to enter the protection center and charge them admission fees. However, Zhou refused to do so as she was determined to minimize any disturbance to the birds. She even dedicated the money she had been compensated for after the demolition of her home to running the center, despite her family’s opposition.</p> <p> In November 2018, when white cranes started to show up in the sky above the protection center, a parking lot which had just started construction near the farm scared the birds away. Zhou was sad and worried about this new development. She then reported the situation to the local government and in January 2019 the construction work was suspended.</p> <p> At the beginning of the same year, six institutes, including the Nanchang Five Stars Siberian Cranes Sanctuary, signed a memorandum of understanding for white crane research and protection.</p> <p> In August of the same year, Zhou underwent surgery to remove polyps from her stomach. On the fifth day after the surgery, when she was still hospitalized, Zhou got news that officials at the provincial level would inspect preparatory work for the upcoming Poyang Lake International Birdwatching Week. Believing that the event would be an opportunity for the development of the Nanchang Five Stars Siberian Cranes Sanctuary, Zhou immediately discharged herself from the hospital and returned to the sanctuary.</p> <p> During the Poyang Lake International Birdwatching Week, the sanctuary garnered the attention of increasingly more people, and after some important domestic and international guests visited the protection center, they all spoke highly of it.</p> <p> In the spring of 2020, the lotus farm was expanded to cover more than 666,666 square meters, and the infrastructure at the protection center was greatly improved. In the winter of the same year, the protection center received more than 2,800 white cranes.</p> <p> In November 2020, a nature education center and a museum for the popularization of knowledge about white cranes were both established near the Nanchang Five Stars Siberian Cranes Sanctuary.</p> <p> In 2021, more than 80,000 people visited the white crane protection center, a number that is bound to continue growing in the years ahead.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China to strengthen maritime public interest litigations ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095369</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095369.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 17:13:26 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- China's Supreme People's Court and Supreme People's Procuratorate have jointly issued a set of regulations to clarify the rules for handling public interest litigations concerning marine resources and environment.</p> <p> Such public interest litigations, which include both civil and administrative actions, shall be filed in specialized maritime courts, according to the document made public Wednesday.</p> <p> After finding acts detrimental to the marine ecology and resources, a procuratorate may inform the competent authority to bring a lawsuit, the document stated, adding that if the latter fails to do so, the procuratorate may file a civil public interest lawsuit at the maritime court.</p> <p> When a procuratorate finds that the department responsible has failed to perform its duty to supervise and handle marine-related illegal activities, resulting in an infringement of national interests or public interests, it shall put forward procuratorial suggestions to the department and file an administrative public interest lawsuit in case of the latter's further inaction.</p> <p> The judicial interpretation also stipulates that procuratorates may initiate incidental civil actions in public interest during criminal proceedings or separate civil public interest lawsuits. ■</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
	</channel>
</rss>