<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title> Foreign_Affairs </title>
		<image>
			<title>People's Daily Online</title>
			<link>http://english.people.com.cn/</link>
			<url>http://english.people.com.cn/images/en/top_logo_e.gif</url>
		</image>
		<description>People's Daily Online</description>
		<link>http://english.people.com.cn/90883</link>
		<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ U.S. urged not to rope in Southeast Asian countries out of geopolitical interests ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096718</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096718.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 14:28:13 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 14 (Xinhua) -- The just-concluded U.S.-ASEAN summit will not draw regional countries closer to the U.S. side, and the U.S. attempt to court support among ASEAN in pursuit of its geopolitical interests is unlikely to gain traction, experts have said.</p> <p> U.S. President Joe Biden met leaders of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) countries at the White House during a summit held on Thursday and Friday, a move widely seen as an attempt by the world's sole superpower to pull members of the bloc into its camp against a rising China.</p> <p> U.S. ATTEMPTS SHALL FAIL</p> <p> Against the backdrop of escalating tensions between Russia and Ukraine, the U.S.-initiated summit was widely viewed as a signal to highlight the importance of what America calls the "Indo-Pacific" region out of strategic concerns, and to counter the rising influence of China in the region.</p> <p> Lee Pei May, a political expert at the International Islamic University Malaysia, said while the summit occurred amid the tougher Russia-Ukraine conflict, the primary concern of the Biden administration is not about Russia, but more about ensuring a so-called "free and open" Indo-Pacific.</p> <p> "For the Biden administration to advance this vision, they have to get ASEAN countries on the American side and potentially for the U.S. to play a role in managing the disputes in the South China Sea," she said. "Such moves can be interpreted as challenging China's position in the region and hindering peaceful progress between China and ASEAN countries."</p> <p> The summit's significance lies in its timing, reported Foreign Affairs magazine on Wednesday. "It is being held as war rages in Ukraine, demonstrating that the United States has not lost its focus on the Indo-Pacific," the report said, adding "U.S. President Joe Biden seeks to better position his country in the wider geopolitical competition with China."</p> <p> Yet, the United States "shall fail in attempts to counter China, because most ASEAN countries want to expand economic exchanges and other cooperation with (their) regional neighbor China," Wilson Lee Flores, a columnist for the English daily The Philippine Star, told Xinhua.</p> <p> Flores noted that Washington was also aimed at convincing ASEAN countries to take tougher public positions and join its sanctions against Russia, which, likewise, shall fail. "Most of ASEAN seek to promote dialogue, diplomacy and stability in crisis areas due to ASEAN's traditional position of non-interference and upholding consensus."</p> <p> Joseph Matthews, a senior professor at the BELTEI International University in Phnom Penh, said that the United States should not use the summit to coerce and pressure ASEAN into submitting to its will and approach against Russia and China.</p> <p> Commenting on the Western sanctions and illegal embargoes on Russia, Ky Sereyvath, director general of the Institute of China Studies at the Royal Academy of Cambodia, said these sanctions will harm the global economy.</p> <p> "I think the rise in fuel prices will not slow down if the Ukraine crisis still continues and the U.S. still push this war forward," Sereyvath added.</p> <p> As the United States is scrambling to combat a sluggish economy and simmering social disorder amid COVID-19, its capability to fulfill promises to other countries has come under question.</p> <p> "The U.S. now has limited capacities to deliver on its promises, due to its own political and economic challenges, especially with the upcoming midterm elections in November," Flores cautioned.</p> <p> "The U.S. can still lobby to export its weapons to ASEAN. It can still attempt (to carry out) political or diplomatic initiatives. It can also attempt to pursue security alliances. But its waning economic activities and influence in Asia will weaken its strategic presence and leverage," the columnist noted.</p> <p> From the "Pivot to Asia" to the "Indo-Pacific Strategy," the United States has been teaming up its allies and regional countries to contain China. Washington never stops hyping up the concept of "Indo-Pacific" to peddle the targeted strategy at economic, political and military levels.</p> <p> A recent report by the U.S. Center for Strategic and International Studies showed that many ASEAN members have expressed concerns that the so-called "Indo-Pacific Economic Framework" is "primarily a political endeavor meant to counter China, rather than a sincere and thoughtful economic policy integration initiative."</p> <p> This viewpoint was echoed by Veronika Saraswati, researcher at Indonesia's the Center for Strategic and International Studies. "It is not hard to see that although the United States wants to strengthen its influence in ASEAN, it has not built cooperation with ASEAN countries in a more concrete level, only symbolic."</p> <p> ASEAN NATIONS WON'T TAKE SIDE</p> <p> Many believe that ASEAN members, now with a primary focus on post-pandemic economic recovery, will maintain neutrality at the forefront and neglect the attempts to pressure them into a U.S. sphere of influence.</p> <p> With China rising "sharply out of expectation," the United States "is afraid of losing its control" in Southeast Asia and found it necessary to hold tighter their hegemonic power, Saraswati pointed out.</p> <p> The Indonesian researcher stressed that Southeast Asian countries, including Indonesia, certainly do not want to be dragged into the competition between major powers.</p> <p> "Powerful countries should never use coercive measures to force other countries to choose side," she noted. "For a long time, the exercise of hegemonic power by the U.S. and its allies has had a deep impact on the survival and development of many countries."</p> <p> The United States will find itself unable to make any headway among ASEAN members, especially after Malaysia and Indonesia voiced concerns over the AUKUS trilateral security partnership involving Australia and Britain, said Azmi Hassan, a senior research fellow at Nusantara Academy for Strategic Research.</p> <p> Hassan gave the persuasive example that the United States has been unable to exert pressure on ASEAN over the Russia-Ukraine conflict, with most of the 10-member bloc abstaining from voting in favor of a resolution to suspend Russia from the United Nations Human Rights Council last month.</p> <p> "Bringing up controversial issues, forcing and coercing ASEAN member states to support its approach and agenda in the region, and trying to divide ASEAN on any issues will undermine the credibility and authenticity of the whole summit. The U.S. should be mindful of it," Matthews told Xinhua.</p> <p> Rather than pressing the bloc to follow its scenarios or agendas against other countries, Washington should use the meeting to express support for ASEAN's post-COVID-19 socioeconomic recovery, Kin Phea, director-general of the International Relations Institute at the Royal Academy of Cambodia, told Xinhua.</p> <p> "What the U.S. should do is encouraging ASEAN to adhere to its principle of centrality, solidarity and unity," he said, adding the United States should also respect ASEAN's rights in making decisions and refrain from using economic, political or security pressure to bargain with ASEAN or to force ASEAN to make decisions in its favor.</p> <p> "The U.S. must respect the common interests of the ASEAN, the region and the world, and should not put forward any scenarios or agendas that lead to ASEAN's rift and instability in the region," he said.</p> <p> VIGILANCE, UNITY URGED IN ASEAN</p> <p> It is essential for the 10-member bloc to stand in solidarity against the U.S. interference for the sake of regional peace, stability, development and prosperity, Phea said.</p> <p> Matthews also urged ASEAN leaders to be vigilant about the Quadrilateral Security Dialogue among the United States, Japan, Australia and India, and the Australia-U.K.-U.S. pact, saying both military-cum-security alliances are posing a major security threat to ASEAN and the whole Asia region.</p> <p> "These alliances will trigger a conventional and nuclear arms race in the region, and thus destabilize peace and security, undermine economic development and destroy the ASEAN's centrality," he said.</p> <p> Unless it can demonstrate unity, ASEAN may find itself in a position where different members pursue different paths, which could compromise its cohesiveness, Lee cautioned. "This can be remedied by member states forging a consensus when dealing with the United States."</p> <p> "Having a consensus on key issues is not easy, but it is crucial as it would allow the members to speak with one united voice at the summit," the Malaysian expert noted. "The members can send a signal to the U.S. that ASEAN would remain neutral in whatever circumstances."&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese-built expressway to boost Kenya's tourism sector: official ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096685</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096685.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 10:50:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> NAIROBI, May 13 (Xinhua) -- The Chinese-built Nairobi expressway is expected to boost the tourism sector in Kenya, a senior government official said.</p> <p> Najib Balala, the cabinet secretary of the Ministry for Tourism and Wildlife, told journalists in Nairobi, Kenya's capital, that trial runs by motorists are expected to commence on the facility from Saturday.</p> <p> "The future is bright for the tourism sector because the Nairobi expressway is expected to reduce travel time from the airport to various tourism destinations across the city," Balala said Thursday evening during the fifth-anniversary celebration of Park Inn Hotel, Nairobi.</p> <p> He observed that tourists have been facing delays in moving between the Jomo Kenyatta International Airport and Nairobi's central business district.</p> <p> "With the expressway, tourists will take about ten minutes from arrival at the airport to the city center, instead of taking more than two hours currently," he added.</p> <p> The 27.1-km Nairobi Expressway was financed and built by China Road and Bridge Corporation under a public-private partnership model and consists of four-lane and six-lane dual carriageways.</p> <p> The Kenyan official said the Nairobi expressway will ensure tourists can enjoy the city's beautiful scenery due to seamless connectivity. "We want tourists to enjoy a seamless travel experience from their arrival so as to enhance their tourism experience in Kenya."</p> <p> According to the Ministry for Tourism and Wildlife, the Nairobi expressway will also attract more international hotel brands to set up operations in Kenya's capital city as the level of traffic congestion reduces.</p> <p> A trial run of the expressway will be launched Saturday.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China voices opposition to smearing remarks by Japan, EU ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096635</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096635.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 09:49:33 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- China on Friday expressed firm opposition to recent smearing remarks and interference in China's internal affairs by Japan and the European Union (EU), urging them to abandon the zero-sum game mindset.</p> <p> Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Zhao Lijian made the remarks at a daily press briefing in response to a query about a joint statement issued by Japan and the EU at a summit on Thursday, which expressed "concerns" over the situation of the Diaoyu Islands, East China Sea, South China Sea and Taiwan Strait, as well as so-called human rights issues in Hong Kong and Xinjiang.</p> <p> Japan and the EU have hyped up China-related issues, made smearing remarks against China, interfered in China's internal affairs and instigated regional confrontation, Zhao said. "China is firmly opposed to such practice, and has lodged stern representation with relevant parties."</p> <p> Zhao said the Diaoyu Island and its affiliated islands have always been an inherent part of the Chinese territory, adding no matter what is said or done, the fact can never be altered that the islands belong to China.</p> <p> Regarding maritime issues, Zhao said China will firmly safeguard its territorial sovereignty and maritime rights and interests, and at the same time is ready to settle differences with relevant countries via consultations.</p> <p> As for issues related to Taiwan, Hong Kong and Xinjiang, Zhao said they all fall within China's internal affairs, which brook no interference by any external forces. "We urge relevant countries to focus on putting their own house in order."</p> <p> China's development means important opportunities for the world, Zhao said, citing facts that China's economy has contributed 30 percent to the world economic growth, and China's achievements in COVID-19 response have helped stabilize the global supply chain. The Belt and Road Initiative has benefited more than 180 countries and international organizations.</p> <p> "The so-called China threat theory has gone bankrupt in face of facts," Zhao said.</p> <p> Noting the world needs unity and cooperation more than ever before in face of challenges such as the resurgences of COVID-19 and lackluster economic recovery, Zhao urged Japan and the EU to abandon seeking ideological confrontation and a zero-sum game mindset, to practice real multilateralism and inject more positive energy into the world.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi, Croatian president exchange congratulations on 30th anniversary of diplomatic ties ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096601</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0514/c90000-10096601.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 09:01:22 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/94/13427338071703457134.jpg" style="height: 563px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on Oct. 20, 2020 shows the Peljesac Bridge under construction near Komarna, Croatia. (Milan Sabic/Pixsell via Xinhua)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 13 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping and his counterpart of the Republic of Croatia, Zoran Milanovic, on Friday exchanged congratulatory messages on the 30th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between the two countries.</p> <p> In his message, Xi pointed out that since the establishment of diplomatic ties 30 years ago, China and Croatia have always respected each other and treated each other as equals, adding that bilateral relations have withstood the test of international vicissitudes.</p> <p> Thanks to the concerted efforts of both sides, China and Croatia have enjoyed solid political mutual trust and achieved positive results in their cooperation in jointly building the Belt and Road, bringing benefits to the people of the two countries, he said.</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220514/37/10305212393747464001.jpg" style="height: 600px; width: 900px;" /></p> <p> <em>Airport staff unload medical supplies off a cargo aircraft from Shanghai of China in Zagreb, Croatia, April 12, 2020. (Xinhua/Gao Lei)</em></p> <p> In the face of the challenges caused by COVID-19, China and Croatia have joined hands to fight the pandemic and written a new story of bilateral friendship, Xi added.</p> <p> Noting that he attaches great importance to the development of the bilateral ties, Xi said he is ready to work with President Milanovic to take the 30th anniversary of diplomatic ties as an opportunity to consolidate political mutual trust between the two countries, strengthen the alignment of development strategies, and jointly pilot bilateral relations for greater development, so as to benefit the two countries and their people.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's dynamic zero-COVID policy saves lives, recovers economy: Pakistani FM ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096351</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096351.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 11:53:48 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> ISLAMABAD, May 13 (Xinhua) -- Pakistani Foreign Minister Bilawal Bhutto Zardari said on Thursday that China's dynamic zero-COVID approach is particularly successful in eliminating the virus, saving countless lives and swiftly recovering its economy.</p> <p> Zardari made the remarks during his virtual address to the 2nd Global COVID-19 Summit co-hosted by the United States, Belize, Germany, Indonesia, and Senegal.</p> <p> Every country and region will have to devise its own anti-virus strategy, and one-size-fits-all approach cannot be used to battle such pandemics, he said, adding that China's dynamic zero-COVID approach is rooted in China's realities.</p> <p> Zardari also lauded China for providing COVID-related assistance to countries that needed it, besides Pakistan.</p> <p> Talking about measures to control the virus, he said that any approach to deal with the pandemic must be grounded firmly in scientific evidence and logic, and responses, monitoring and evaluation should be guided by established methods of epidemiology and community medicine.</p> <p> The top Pakistani diplomat also said that international cooperation and coordination are of fundamental importance to the success of national efforts.</p> <p> "It has been evidently clear in the last two years that our survival hinges on our ability to work together," he said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Former Croatian president hails 30 years of diplomatic ties between Croatia, China ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096148</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096148.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:47:03 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> ZAGREB, May 12 (Xinhua) -- As this year marks the 30th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between Croatia and China, former Croatian President Ivo Josipovic told Xinhua in a recent interview that this would inject new impetus into the development of bilateral relations and open up new possibilities for cooperation.</p> <p> In May 1992, China, as a permanent member of the UN Security Council, recognized and established diplomatic relations with Croatia, which was of great significance because Croatia was still fighting for statehood and international recognition at that time, Josipovic said, adding that bilateral relations have developed well since the establishment of diplomatic ties, and practical cooperation has been continuously deepened.</p> <p> "Today, I think we have very good relations. We do not have any open issues, probably we should be more intensively engaged in establishing more cultural and economical cooperation," he said.</p> <p> Josipovic noted that bilateral contacts should be strengthened, not only between the two governments but also between businesses and cultural institutions, and that more projects should be launched for both sides.</p> <p> According to the former president, Croatia has always valued cooperation with China, the world's second largest economy, with the Chinese-built Peljesac Bridge serving as an example of bilateral cooperation.</p> <p> Josipovic also supports closer high-level political and economic ties and cooperation between China and the European Union, noting that global peace and stability, in which China has played a positive role, require cooperation among all countries.</p> <p> "Croatia is always in favor of it, and I am sure that our government will support the idea of better cooperation between the European Union and China," he said.</p> <p> China and Croatia established diplomatic relations on May 13, 1992. In 2005, the two countries established a comprehensive cooperative partnership, marking a new stage in the development of bilateral ties.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China urges U.S. to adopt serious measures to truly help ethnic minorities get over trauma ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096141</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096141.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:24:54 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- The United States should fulfill its commitment of "all men are created equal" with concrete actions, and adopt serious measures to truly help ethnic minorities get over their trauma, a Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson said on Thursday.</p> <p> Spokesperson Zhao Lijian made the remarks at a daily news briefing when asked to comment on a U.S. Interior Department report that at least 500 native American, Alaska Native and Native Hawaiian children died while in boarding schools operated or supported by the U.S. government.</p> <p> "Such a report is long overdue," Zhao said. Prior to that, the U.S. government had never kept official statistics on the real conditions of these schools, or verified the number of Indigenous children who went to the institutions, died there or were missing.</p> <p> In fact, the United States was reluctant to admit the existence of the history at first, and even tried to cover it up, Zhao added.</p> <p> Zhao said that the report shows from 1819 to 1969, indigenous children went through unfair treatment including whipping, sexual abuse, forced labor and severe malnourishment in more than 400 federal Indian boarding schools, and more than 500 children died as a result.</p> <p> Noting the United States is founded on the atrocious massacre and persecution of the indigenous population, Zhao said the maltreatment of Native Americans is the U.S. original sin convicted by the Indian boarding schools.</p> <p> Native Americans used to be the dominant population in North America, but their population has shrunk to represent only 2 percent of the current U.S. population after massacre and eviction, Zhao said.</p> <p> The United States adopted cultural assimilation and occupied Indian reservation with forced separation and resettlement of indigenous children, the spokesperson said, adding the trauma generations have gone through persists even till today.</p> <p> Native Americans are still under discrimination with worrying health conditions and destitution. Among all the ethnic communities of the United States, Native Americans have the lowest life expectancy, the highest poverty rate, the highest rate of youth alcohol abuse, and the lowest community doctor-to-patient ratio. In 2019, about 25 percent of Native Americans lived in poverty, which is 2.5 times that of the national average, Zhao said.</p> <p> "The dark history of Indian boarding schools is only a tip of the iceberg of the U.S.' systemic racial discrimination and human rights problems," he said.</p> <p> Noting racial minorities including Americans of Asian, African, Latin American descent and Muslims still cannot breathe or gain security, Zhao said statistics from U.S. research institutions revealed that anti-Asian hate crimes surged by 339 percent in 2021.</p> <p> From the "Tulsa Massacre" to George Floyd, and to Patrick Lyoya of Michigan who died of police violence not long ago, the list of African American deaths only grows amid racial discrimination, Zhao said.</p> <p> People of Latin American descent, accounting for 19 percent of the U.S. population, only possess 2 percent of the country's wealth. Up to 93.7 percent of Muslims in the United States are living in the shadows of Islamophobia, he added.</p> <p> "The United States should fulfill its commitment of 'all men are created equal' with concrete actions, and adopt serious measures to truly help ethnic minorities get over their trauma," Zhao said.</p> <p> More importantly, the United States should learn from history, treat the social endemic of racism, and avoid repeating the human tragedies time and again, he added.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Ethiopia's export to China grows amid booming trade, investment ties: Chinese ambassador ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096125</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096125.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:06:32 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> ADDIS ABABA, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Ethiopia's export to China has registered steady growth amid booming trade and investment cooperation between the two countries, Chinese Ambassador to Ethiopia Zhao Zhiyuan said Thursday.</p> <p> In 2021, compared with the previous year, Ethiopia's exports to China increased by 8 percent as new Foreign Direct Investment (FDI) from Chinese companies to Ethiopia grew by 346 percent, the official said.</p> <p> Zhao made the remarks during the China-Ethiopia Investment and Trade Cooperation Forum that was co-hosted by the Chinese Embassy in Ethiopia, the Ethiopian Investment Commission (EIC) and the Investment Promotion Agency of the Ministry of Commerce of China on Thursday in the Ethiopian capital Addis Ababa.</p> <p> The value of newly signed contract projects by Chinese companies in Ethiopia was up by 25 percent in the same period, Zhao said.</p> <p> According to the Chinese ambassador, Chinese FDI in Ethiopia and other main indicators of bilateral commercial cooperation has maintained good momentum during the first quarter of the current year.</p> <p> Zhao said for consecutive years, China has been Ethiopia's biggest trading partner, the top source of FDI and the largest project contractor, as the two countries deepen cooperation through the Belt and Road Initiative.</p> <p> "Practice has proved that no matter how the international situation changes, the overall direction of China-Ethiopia practical cooperation and long-term friendship will never change," Zhao told forum.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China, Ethiopia eye further augmenting investment, trade cooperation ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096122</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096122.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:03:56 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205130856000318359653893.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 642px;" /></p> <p> <em>Chinese Ambassador to Ethiopia Zhao Zhiyuan delivers a speech during the China-Ethiopia Investment and Trade Cooperation Forum in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, on May 12, 2022. Ethiopia and China on Thursday held the investment and trade cooperation forum that aimed at further augmenting trade and economic ties. (Xinhua/Wang Ping)</em></p> <p> ADDIS ABABA, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Ethiopia and China on Thursday held an investment and trade cooperation forum that aimed at further augmenting trade and economic ties.</p> <p> The China-Ethiopia Investment and Trade Cooperation Forum was co-hosted by the Chinese Embassy in Ethiopia, the Ethiopian Investment Commission (EIC) and the Investment Promotion Agency of the Ministry of Commerce of China in Addis Ababa, the Ethiopian capital.</p> <p> During the forum, a Memorandum of Understanding (MOU) on Investment Cooperation was signed between the two countries, which will serve as a new cooperation mechanism to promote investment cooperation and inject new impetus to the collaboration of the two countries.</p> <p> The forum, which was held in a hybrid format, brought together senior Ethiopian government officials, the business community from the two countries, as well as the Chinese diplomatic community in Addis Ababa. Senior Chinese government officials also took part in the high-level investment and trade forum virtually from China.</p> <p> While addressing the forum, Ethiopia's Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Demeke Mekonnen emphasized that the East African country has become one of the largest recipients of foreign direct investment (FDI) in Africa, in which Chinese engagement has injected a much-needed momentum to the country's drive.</p> <p> He said Chinese investment in communication technologies, large-scale infrastructure, industrial parks and manufacturing sectors have certainly augmented the efforts of the Ethiopian government to create a competitive and sustainable industrial development base.</p> <p> "Indeed, China has proven to be our most-trusted economic and political partner, and its support continues to reinforce the impressive growth trajectory of Ethiopia," Mekonnen said, declaring that the newly signed cooperative instrument "will play a unique role by developing institutional capacity of the EIC in promoting and facilitating Chinese investment inflows to new heights."</p> <p> The forum, among other things, aimed at implementing the Nine Programs of China-Africa cooperation announced by China at the Eighth Ministerial Conference of the Forum on China-Africa Cooperation (FOCAC), promoting China's Initiative for Peace and Development in the Horn of Africa, and facilitating development plans such as the joint building of programs under the Belt and Road Initiative.</p> <p> It further envisaged facilitating the implementation of the China-Africa Cooperation Vision 2035 as well as Ethiopia's Homegrown Economic Reform while further deepening China-Ethiopia comprehensive strategic and cooperative partnership.</p> <p> Vice Minister Qian Keming of Commerce of China, in addressing the forum via video link, on his part emphasized that since the establishment of diplomatic ties between the two countries more than 50 years ago, the political mutual trust between the two countries has been continuously deepened, and the cooperation in various fields such as economy and trade has achieved practical and fruitful results.</p> <p> "China and Ethiopia need to strengthen solidarity, deepen friendly cooperation, achieve mutual benefit and win-win results, and promote steady progress in economic and trade cooperation between the two countries," he said.</p> <p> He emphasized that the two countries need to implement the Nine Programs of China-Africa cooperation, deepen the synergy of development strategies, promote the healthy development of economic and trade cooperation, and enrich the exchange and cooperation mechanism.</p> <p> Qian affirmed that China is willing to join hands with Ethiopia to uphold the spirit of China-Africa friendly cooperation and jointly advance bilateral economic and trade cooperation to a new level, so as to bring more tangible benefits to the two peoples.</p> <p> China has been Ethiopia's largest trading partner and biggest source of investment for many consecutive years.</p> <p> In 2021, bilateral trade volume reached 2.66 billion U.S. dollars, of which, China imported commodities of nearly 370 million U.S. dollars from Ethiopia, a year-on-year increase of 8.1 percent.</p> <p> EIC Commissioner Lelise Neme also echoed the Ethiopian deputy prime minister's comments as she emphasized that the newly signed MOU will lay down a foundation for a strong economic relationship between the two countries.</p> <p> "China is not only a reliable development partner and consistent supporter of Ethiopia's development efforts but also a role model and exemplary on how to formulate and implement development policies and eliminate poverty to achieve inclusive and sustainable development," Neme said. "The growing Chinese investment in Ethiopia is a continuation of the generous development support that China provided through various channels, including the Belt and Road Initiative."</p> <p> Chinese Ambassador to Ethiopia Zhao Zhiyuan said the Investment and Trade Cooperation Forum is "highly timely and relevant" to promote the development of businesses between the two countries toward creating a more favorable business environment.</p> <p> "I am confident that, the signing of the MoU today to promote investment cooperation will create a new cooperation mechanism and inject new impetus to our collaboration," the ambassador said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese embassy launches media initiative to promote peace in South Sudan ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096119</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096119.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:02:46 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> JUBA, May 12 (Xinhua) -- The Union of Journalists of South Sudan and the Chinese embassy on Thursday launched a "My Peace" theme report project aimed at disseminating peace messages and encouraging mass participation, with the support from the Ministry of Peace Building of South Sudan.</p> <p> Stephen Par Kuol, the minister of Peace Building, said there is a need to portray South Sudan in a positive light globally after years of conflict ended with the signing of the 2018 revitalized peace deal.</p> <p> "South Sudan is emerging out of war and the war has been with us for a very long time, we just ended the conflict that resulted in the independence of this country then afterward we ran into another war," Par said during the launch of "My Peace" project in Juba, the capital of South Sudan.</p> <p> Par said embracing a peace agreement is key to transforming the mindsets of the South Sudanese population who have been traumatized by decades of war.</p> <p> "I think it is a progressive step in the right direction that the media is not only reporting the crisis in South Sudan, war and conflict but also positive developments," said the minister. He disclosed that the council of ministers recently passed a resolution to promote peace in South Sudan, adding that the media will be the vehicle for the dissemination of peace messages.</p> <p> Oyet Patrick Charles, the president of the Union of Journalists of South Sudan (UJOSS), encouraged media organizations to set the agenda for peace promotion in order to reach out widely to the public.</p> <p> "There are positive things happening and it is our duty to set an agenda, I would be very happy to see every media house having a program designed specifically on peace implementation," said Oyet.</p> <p> He disclosed that the dissemination of positive news on the peace process will inform people at the grassroots and also encourage them to participate in the process.</p> <p> Chinese Ambassador to South Sudan Hua Ning said the world's youngest nation has witnessed positive progress in the peace process that in turn has led to relative economic recovery.</p> <p> "The past three years have witnessed the positive outcomes of the peace process one after another. I have seen the gradual recovery of South Sudan's economy and the improvement of people's lives," Hua said.</p> <p> He stressed that despite persisting challenges in the peace process, the positive changes are obvious to all.</p> <p> "As a supporter, participant and contributor to the peace process of South Sudan, the Chinese embassy hopes that 'My Peace' project could enhance South Sudanese people's confidence and belief in peace, encourage them to better participate in the country's economic and social development to realize the country's long-term stability while improving their livelihoods through hard work," said the Chinese ambassador.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Achieving peace is best protection for children in Ukraine: Chinese envoy ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096106</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096106.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 08:55:15 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> UNITED NATIONS, May 12 (Xinhua) -- A Chinese envoy said Thursday that achieving peace is the best protection for children in Ukraine.</p> <p> "Achieving peace is the best protection for children. Dialogue and negotiation is the most realistic and feasible way to reach a cease-fire," said Dai Bing, China's deputy permanent representative to the United Nations. "The international community should encourage Russia and Ukraine to return to the negotiation track and to keep accumulating political conditions for the restoration of peace."</p> <p> China welcomes the presidential statement adopted by the Security Council on Ukraine on Friday, which calls for the peaceful settlement of international disputes and voices support for the UN secretary-general's efforts to promote peace, he told a Security Council meeting on the issue of children and education in Ukraine.</p> <p> Sanctions will not bring peace, but will only accelerate the spillover of the crisis, triggering sweeping food, energy, and financial crises across the globe, and making children around the world suffer the bitter consequences. Children living in conflict situations in Afghanistan, Yemen, the Horn of Africa, as well as the Sahel region are bearing the brunt of the humanitarian impact, he warned.</p> <p> "China once again calls on all parties to stay rational and exercise restraint, transcend prejudice and divisions, and make unremitting efforts for the early resolution of the crisis in Ukraine and for children to enjoy a peaceful future," said Dai.</p> <p> The conflict in Ukraine is inflicting on children pains foreign to their age. Protecting children from harm is an obligation under international law that must be fulfilled by parties to the conflict. China reiterates its call for securing children and the civilian infrastructure on which they depend, and to give priority to children in evacuation and humanitarian relief operations, he said.</p> <p> The conflict has uprooted more than half of the Ukrainian children. Millions of children have taken refuge in neighboring countries. China appreciates the safe shelter, humanitarian assistance, and psychological support provided by Ukraine and neighboring countries, as well as various UN agencies and other humanitarian organizations for those children. China calls on the international community to continue to step up relief efforts to ensure that every child in need can receive effective assistance, he said.</p> <p> Dai also called for efforts to reduce the risk of human trafficking, sexual exploitation and abuse faced by Ukrainian children seeking refuge, especially those separated or unaccompanied.</p> <p> China supports the World Health Organization in cooperating with Ukraine and the countries concerned to ensure that children can get routine immunization. China supports the UN Children's Fund in helping the Ukrainian government to provide educational supplies and learning opportunities for internally displaced children, and encourages host countries to integrate refugee children into their own education systems, in order to ensure that children's right to education is not disrupted, he said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China, Africa continue to expand clean energy cooperation ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096104</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096104.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 08:55:02 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Energy shortage has long hindered the social and economic development of Africa. In particular, power supply is a major bottleneck delaying the continent's industrialization.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205130847000207492518684.jpg" style="width: 826px; height: 544px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo shows a China-constructed 50MW solar power farm in Garissa, Kenya. (Photo courtesy of the IT Electronics Eleventh Design &amp; Research Institute Scientific and Technological Engineering Corporation Limited)</em></p> <p> According to World Bank statistics, 51.6 percent of the population in Sub-Saharan Africa did not have access to electricity in 2020, and an estimated 660 million people in the world would lack access in 2030, mostly in Sub-Saharan Africa.</p> <p> To vigorously develop clean energy and build a modern energy system is an inevitable choice for Africa as it is facing the dual challenges of industrialization and low-carbon transition.</p> <p> As a staunch supporter and important partner of Africa on the path of green development, China has implemented over 100 clean energy and green development projects under the framework of the Forum on China-Africa Cooperation (FOCAC), to support African countries in the better use of solar, water, wind, methane, and other clean energy resources and contribute to the sustainable development of Africa.</p> <p> Chinese constructors have built a 50MW solar power farm in Garissa, Kenya, the largest of its kind in East Africa. The plant, which was put into operation in 2019, produces over 76 million kWh of electricity each year on average, supplying power for over 380,000 people from 70,000 families and effectively relieving the pressure of power shortage in the African country.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205130847000051231464534.jpg" style="width: 830px; height: 553px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo shows the De Aar wind farm in Northern Cape, South Africa. (Photo courtesy of China Energy Investment Corporation)</em></p> <p> The De Aar wind farm in Northern Cape, South Africa, which went into operation in 2017, is the first wind power project in Africa that was invested, constructed and operated by China. The wind farm generates 760 million kWh of clean electricity each year, which is equal to the power produced by burning 215,800 tons of standard coal and reducing emission of 619,900 tons of carbon dioxide. While contributing to South Africa's low-carbon transition, the wind farm also creates jobs for the local community and drives the development of surrounding neighborhoods.</p> <p> Apart from major clean energy projects, medium- and small-sized new energy power generation and storage projects funded by China are also sprouting across Africa.</p> <p> A China-aided maintenance program for solar-powered street lamps in Central African Republic kicked off in Bangui, capital of the African country on April 8. The program provided the country with 100 sets of spare street lamps and also repaired damaged lampposts. It is a follow-up to a 2016 aid program in which China erected 200 street lamps for the main roads in Bangui, which was an outcome of the 10 major cooperation plans announced at the 2015 FOCAC Johannesburg Summit.</p> <p> It’s good to feed a man fish, but better to teach him to fish. The fund, technology and knowledge brought by China to Africa has further accelerated the green transition of the continent. On Feb. 18 this year, the 10th Luban Workshop, a Chinese-aided skill and technology training project, was launched in Madagascar. The project, implemented since 2018, has trained a batch of technical talents for African countries.</p> <p> In recent years, both China and Africa have taken new energy and green development as a focus of their cooperation.</p> <p> African Union's Agenda 2063 aims to enhance the abilities to respond to climate change and achieve sustainable development, and has launched a series of flagship projects of new energy. Many African countries also rolled out relevant policies.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205130846000257271771823.jpg" style="width: 830px; height: 703px;" /></p> <p> <em>Shan Chenglin, Chargé d'Affaires of the Chinese Embassy in Central African Republic hands over a batch of materials at the launching ceremony of a China-aided maintenance program for solar-powered street lamps in the African country held in Bangui, capital of Central African Republic, April 8, 2022. (Photo courtesy of the Chinese Embassy in Central African Republic)</em></p> <p> Last November, China issued a white paper titled "China and Africa in the New Era: A Partnership of Equals," stressing that it will strengthen exchanges and cooperation with Africa on climate change, clean energy, and other ecological and environmental fields.</p> <p> In the run-up to the Eighth Ministerial Conference of the FOCAC, China and Africa jointly prepared the China-Africa Cooperation Vision 2035, which proposed a new model for common eco-development of China and Africa by transforming to clean and low-carbon energy cooperation. The two sides also signed a declaration on climate change cooperation.</p> <p> Clean energy is a new common ground and a new area of growth for China-Africa cooperation. As the Belt and Road Initiative goes deeper and the FOCAC keeps releasing its potential, China and Africa will continue expanding their clean energy cooperation, innovating cooperation models and enriching the cooperation, so as to realize the vision of a green Africa.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ New Chinese ambassador presents Letter of Credence to Zambian president ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096095</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096095.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 08:50:23 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0513/FOREIGN202205130832000310932547353.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Zambian President Hakainde Hichilema (R, Front) poses for a photo with Chinese Ambassador to Zambia Du Xiaohui at State House in Lusaka, Zambia, on May 12, 2022. Du Xiaohui, the new Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the People's Republic of China to the Republic of Zambia, presented the Letter of Credence to Zambian President Hakainde Hichilema in Lusaka on Thursday. (Xinhua/Martin Mbangweta)</em></p> <p> LUSAKA, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Du Xiaohui, the new Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the People's Republic of China to the Republic of Zambia, presented the Letter of Credence to Zambian President Hakainde Hichilema in Lusaka, capital of Zambia on Thursday.</p> <p> The two sides held long and friendly talks afterward.</p> <p> Du said that it is a great honor and responsibility to be posted to Zambia.</p> <p> The China-Zambia all-weather friendship was personally forged by the older generation of leaders of our two countries. Carried forward through generations, it has taken deep root in our peoples' hearts, said Du.</p> <p> Since the establishment of diplomatic ties, China and Zambia have always followed the principles of mutual respect, equality and mutual benefit, accommodated each other's core interests and major concerns, advanced cooperation to the benefit of the people of our two countries, and upheld international fairness and justice and the common interests of developing countries, Du said.</p> <p> He said China attaches great importance to its relations with Zambia and stands ready to work with Zambia to make good use of the two platforms of Belt and Road Initiative and the Forum on China-Africa Cooperation to broaden friendly and mutually beneficial cooperation between the two countries and bring China-Zambia relations to a higher level.</p> <p> Hichilema said that Zambia and China enjoy a time-honored friendship with close ties of interests and fruitful cooperation in the fields of economy, culture and security.</p> <p> He thanked China for its great help in fighting COVID-19 and expressed his willingness to learn from China's development experience and conduct economic cooperation between the two countries.</p> <p> Hichilema said that there is no limit to Zambia-China cooperation. Zambia will continue to maintain sound relations between the two countries and the two peoples and further consolidate the foundation of friendship.</p> <p> Attaching great importance to the all-weather friendship between the two countries, the Republic of Zambia arranged a separate presentation ceremony for the Chinese ambassador, which is the first time that President Hichilema graced a separate presentation ceremony for a foreign envoy after taking office.</p> <p> The ceremony was solemn, warm and friendly. Stanley Kakubo, the Minister of Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation and senior diplomats of the Chinese Embassy in Zambia attended the ceremony.</p> <p> Du arrived in Zambia to assume duty on April 17, 2022.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China urges U.S. to promote regional peace, stability at upcoming U.S.-ASEAN summit ]]></title>
	<news_id>10096012</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10096012.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 08:16:21 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- The United States, as a non-regional country, should play a positive and constructive role in promoting regional peace and development, a Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson said Thursday, in response to reports that the upcoming U.S.-ASEAN summit will discuss issues related to China.</p> <p> "The United States should not use cooperation as a cover to force others to pick sides, or play with fire on issues concerning China's core interests," said Zhao Lijian, the spokesperson.</p> <p> It was reported that Kurt Campbell, the White House's Indo-Pacific policy coordinator, said that the United States hopes to take measures to maintain peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait.</p> <p> The United States continues to follow the one-China policy, does not support "Taiwan independence," and has no intention of taking provocative actions. But it "wants clarity about the desire to deter steps that would be provocative," according to Campbell.</p> <p> In response, Zhao said the one-China principle is a universal consensus of the international community and an established basic norm governing international relations.</p> <p> The United States should abide by the one-China principle and the three China-U.S. joint communiques, the political commitments made to China on the Taiwan question, and U.S. President Joe Biden's statement that the United States does not support "Taiwan independence," Zhao said.</p> <p> The United States should stop exploiting Taiwan-related issues to engage in political manipulation in an attempt to contain China, he added.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi, Slovenian president exchange congratulations on 30th anniversary of diplomatic ties ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095991</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0513/c90000-10095991.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 08:16:16 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping and his Slovenian counterpart Borut Pahor on Thursday exchanged congratulatory messages on the 30th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between the two countries.</p> <p> Xi pointed out that since the establishment of bilateral diplomatic ties 30 years ago, China and Slovenia, treating each other with respect and as equal, have achieved positive results in mutually beneficial cooperation and witnessed increasing cultural and people-to-people exchanges, which brings tangible benefits to the people of the two countries.</p> <p> In the face of COVID-19, the people of the two countries have supported each other, demonstrating the profound friendship between China and Slovenia, he said.</p> <p> Xi stressed that he attaches great importance to the development of China-Slovenia relations, saying that he is ready to work with Pahor to take the 30th anniversary of diplomatic ties as a new starting point, seize the historic opportunity of jointly building the Belt and Road, strengthen the alignment of development strategies of the two sides, and deepen practical cooperation, so as to inject new impetus into the development of bilateral relations for the benefits of the two countries and their people.</p> <p> In his message, Pahor earnestly congratulated China on its leapfrog development in various fields, saying that bilateral relations between Slovenia and China enjoy a long history and have seen rapid development since diplomatic ties were established 30 years ago.</p> <p> He added that economic and trade cooperation has been fruitful and the fields of cooperation are growing, among which ice and snow sports have become a new highlight of cooperation.</p> <p> As a member of the European Union, Slovenia actively supports enhancing Europe-China relations and is committed to delivering the fruits of cooperation to both sides and the international community, said the president.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ How Washington's zero-sum fixation is derailing its own agenda ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095833</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095833.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 16:26:43 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121517000433574677063.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 506px;" /></p> <p> <span style="color:#0000ff;">The US has pledged to rally to the cause of fighting climate change; but isn't its coercive tariff on solar panels only serving to stymie that mission? (Graphic: Zero-sum or zero-carbon/People's Daily Online)</span></p> <p> The Glasgow climate summit held last year was largely viewed as a chance for redemption. After the grim outcome of the (2°C) mitigation target set at the 2009 Copenhagen summit, humanity's "last chance" to save the planet, nations were nudged to give climate cooperation another shot. Few world leaders are more zealous and vocal on the matter than US president Joe Biden, who has proposed a portfolio of ambitious goals and called for joint collaboration between major players and, in particular, the US and China.</p> <p> Then, last February, in a surprise move, the Biden administration announced that it would extend the Trump-era Section 201 tariffs slapped on solar panels, in a bid to "continue facilitating positive adjustment to competition" from imported photovoltaic cells. Though the administration did offer some clues on the "positive adjustment," almost four years after the tariffs were levied, experts argued that America's solar industry remained nascent in its development despite full-blown trade barriers and that the decision came at an emissions cost.</p> <p> In an opinion essay published earlier this month in <em>The Hill</em>, John Paul Helveston, an American researcher, debated that tariffs won't help the US build a "robust solar industry." He contended that China's tremendous R&amp;D efforts on photovoltaic (PV) innovations, which helped slash the prices of most PV panels from $2,000 per kilowatt to just $300 per kilowatt, cannot be simply duplicated. It is highly unlikely that another nation will be able to "replicate China's skills in the time frame needed to avoid the worst consequences of climate change," he cited an article he co-wrote in <em>Science </em>back in 2019, adding, "Rather than continuing the Trump-era tariffs on Chinese solar panels, the US and others should be partnering with Chinese firms to obtain low-cost technologies and components to increase domestic deployment of renewables as fast as possible to meet the narrow window left to decarbonize."</p> <p> Low-cost solar technologies and components, however, have been the very items subject to Washington's ongoing investigation.</p> <p> The New York Times reported on April 29 that, amidst an investigation by the US Commerce Department targeting Chinese-made PV parts, the US solar industry has been "frozen," with over 300 solar projects being "canceled or delayed." American energy enterprises, big and small, have all been dragged into the quagmire of self-censorship over Chinese solar parts. "The investigation is having a catastrophic negative impact on the renewable energy sector and driving up electricity prices. With each day the tariff investigation continues, the country is falling further behind in achieving our climate goals," said Nick Bullinger, COO of a Chicago-based solar company, in an interview that appeared in the <em>Times </em>article.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121524000530389177826.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>U.S. President Joe Biden (R) speaks during an event, at the White House in Washington, D.C., the United States, on May 9, 2022. Biden said that the administration is "discussing" whether to drop hiked tariffs on Chinese products. (Photo by Ting Shen/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> From the perspective of environmental benefits or from the standpoint of economic interests, Washington's 4-year-long-and-counting solar clampdown is cost-ineffective, as it collides with even Biden's own climate agenda.</p> <p> US president Joe Biden attended the Glasgow summit with high hopes—100% renewable energy by 2035; but the Solar Energy Industries Association (SEIA), an NGO, estimated that America's current production capacity only makes up 15% of its demand. Neither will taxing and purging Chinese solar panels or PV parts help "bring jobs back home," since even with heavy tariffs the US remains heavily dependent on imported PV products.</p> <p> Besides, the volume of jobs generated by solar installations in the US is ten times larger than the manufacturing jobs created by the nation's entire solar sector, according to the US National Renewable Energy Laboratory (NREL). As a letter sent to President Biden last January by eight American senators (from both parties) stated, the Section 201 tariffs had "led to the loss of more than 62,000 American clean energy jobs and 10.5 gigawatts of foregone solar deployment." It is difficult then to tell who the tariffs and investigation are designed to punish: overseas solar producers or the American labor force?</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121527000336131916818.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on Nov. 19, 2021 shows the U.S. Capitol building in Washington, D.C., the United States. (Photo by Ting Shen/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> But it's not hard to detect what formula is being applied in America's zero-carbon solution—its default zero-sum fixation. After all, the one-nation's-gain-representing-another's-loss mindset takes various shapes in the China-US relations from Washington's point of view.</p> <p> On the global stage, it is reflected in Washington's unreasonable belief that China's global presence, such as donating COVID-19 vaccines to developing nations, will undermine the superpower's global influence.</p> <p> In the economic sphere, it is manifested in America's obsession with punitive tariffs, which it deems will help reverse trade deficits and boost domestic industry, even though the burden will ultimately be shifted towards American consumers in the form of rising prices.</p> <p> In the technological and academic realms, it is showcased in America's year-long crackdown on Chinese tech companies and its unjustified witch-hunt targeting Chinese academics and students.</p> <p> ... ...</p> <p> The aforementioned aspects of Washington's zero-sum practices are epitomized by its now-stagnant solar industry, which in turn has demonstrated why such a mindset won't work. Internationally, it will risk hindering the joint cause of emissions reduction; economically, it will impede the low-hanging fruits and long-term benefits brought by the should-be full-fledged solar sector; and, from the perspectives of innovation and technological progress, it will further dampen the outlook of cooperation on green innovations.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121521000527071017527.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 800px;" /></p> <p> <em>Aerial panoramic photo taken on April 21, 2022 shows the Dalad Photovoltaic Power Base in Dalad Banner, north China's Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region. (Xinhua/Liu Lei)</em></p> <p> Dwelling on a planet that is currently plagued by a global pandemic (accompanied by inflation and a possible recession), haunted by continuous wars and conflicts, and overshadowed by the looming threat of global warming, we all know that a zero-sum fixation and a Cold-War mindset won't help fix any of these global problems. On the contrary, they are destined to make the planet warmer, wars deadlier, and other global puzzles more insoluble.</p> <p> For Washington, it needs to face the reality that it cannot achieve technological hegemony or climate leadership by setting up a new Iron Curtain to deter and isolate China. Returning to a rational and pragmatic China policy is the sole way to nurture healthy and sustainable China-US ties and encourage the two sides to work together on issues of common and global concern. Conversely, the zero-sum mindset is bound for a lose-lose path.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi sends congratulatory message to Philippine President-elect Marcos ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095745</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095745.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 13:28:45 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 12 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping on Wednesday sent a congratulatory message to Ferdinand Romualdez Marcos on his election as president of the Republic of the Philippines.</p> <p> China and the Philippines are neighbors facing each other across the sea and partners through thick and thin, Xi said.</p> <p> In recent years, with the joint efforts of both sides, the bilateral relations have been consolidated and enhanced, bringing benefits to the people of both countries and contributing to regional peace and stability, Xi added.</p> <p> Xi stressed that both China and the Philippines are at a critical stage of development and their relations face important opportunities and enjoy broad prospects.</p> <p> Noting that he attaches great importance to the development of the bilateral ties, Xi said he is ready to establish a good working relationship with Marcos to uphold good-neighborliness and joint development, and further advance the bilateral comprehensive strategic cooperative relationship to benefit the two countries and their people.</p> <p> On the same day, Chinese Vice President Wang Qishan also sent a message to Sara Zimmerman Duterte-Carpio to congratulate her on her election as vice president of the Philippines.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese FM meets Pakistani counterpart ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095520</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095520.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:45:40 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0512/FOREIGN202205121044000218488327812.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 573px;" /></p> <p> <em>Chinese State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi meets with Pakistani Foreign Minister Bilawal Bhutto Zardari via video link in Beijing, capital of China, May 11, 2022. (Xinhua/Yue Yuewei)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- Chinese State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi on Wednesday met with Pakistani Foreign Minister Bilawal Bhutto Zardari via video link, calling on the two sides to thwart any attempt to undermine bilateral ties.</p> <p> Wang said that China and Pakistan are unique and time-tested all-weather strategic cooperative partners. The friendship between two sides will be passed on from generation to generation and will not be shaken or changed by a single incident.</p> <p> "China will, as always, firmly support Pakistan in safeguarding national sovereignty, security and dignity and in its commitment to national development and rejuvenation," Wang said, adding that China believes that Pakistan will also firmly stand with China on all issues concerning China's core interests.</p> <p> Bilawal said he was glad to have his first official bilateral activity since taking office as meeting with Chinese foreign minister.</p> <p> Bilawal said that both the ruling and opposition parties in Pakistan firmly support the bilateral friendship, which is the consensus shared by Pakistani people. Pakistan firmly upholds the one-China policy and supports China's positions on issues related to Taiwan, Xinjiang, Tibet and the South China Sea. And Pakistan fully supports the Belt and Road Initiative, especially the construction of the Pakistan-China Economic Corridor.</p> <p> The two sides also exchanged views on the safety of Chinese citizens and institutions in Pakistan.</p> <p> In regard to a series of terrorist attacks targeting Chinese nationals in Pakistan over a period of time, Wang said China and Pakistan should take immediate action and take firm and effective measures to deal with it.</p> <p> "The pressing task is to speed up the investigation of the perpetrators and punish them as soon as possible. We should take targeted measures to improve security protection for Chinese personnel, institutions and projects in Pakistan, give timely security warnings, and plug security loopholes so as to prevent similar incidents from happening again," said Wang.</p> <p> China will continue to support Pakistan in enhancing its counter-terrorism capability and is ready to join hands with Pakistan to thwart any attempt of undermining China-Pakistan relations, Wang added.</p> <p> Bilawal said that Pakistan condemns in the strongest terms the terrorist attack on the Confucius Institute at the University of Karachi. Pakistan firmly opposes all terrorist acts and will bring all criminals to justice.</p> <p> Pakistan is ready to strengthen cooperation with China to enhance its counter-terrorism capability and ensure the safety of all Chinese citizens in Pakistan, added Bilawal.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China welcomes upcoming visit of UN human rights chief ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095594</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095594.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:48:23 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- China welcomes the upcoming visit of the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights Michelle Bachelet to China in May, said a spokesperson for China's foreign ministry on Wednesday.</p> <p> Bachelet's trip to China will take her to the country's Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region. The preparatory team of the Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights has arrived in China and is currently undergoing quarantine in accordance with relevant anti-COVID-19 protocols, spokesperson Zhao Lijian told a daily press briefing.</p> <p> "The preparatory team has begun work and the two sides are discussing the specific arrangements for the visit," he said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China slams Australia for irresponsible remarks on China-Solomon Islands cooperation ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095589</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095589.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:48:23 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- A Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson on Wednesday slammed Australia for making irresponsible remarks on the China-Solomon Islands security agreement, urging Australia to cease wantonly criticizing Solomon Islands' independent foreign cooperation and stop exerting pressure and coercion.</p> <p> According to media reports, Australian Foreign Minister Marise Payne recently met her Solomon Islands counterpart Jeremiah Manele in Brisbane, Australia. Payne said that Australia holds concerns about the China-Solomon Islands security agreement, including the lack of transparency.</p> <p> "Since Australia declares its 'respect for Solomon Islands' sovereign decision-making,' it should act like it said," spokesperson Zhao Lijian said at a daily news briefing, noting the Pacific Island countries, including the Solomon Islands, are sovereign and independent countries, not a backyard of anyone.</p> <p> Zhao said that China has briefed on its security cooperation with the Solomon Islands on many occasions. He once again defended the signing of the inter-governmental framework agreement on security cooperation between China and the Solomon Islands as a right of two sovereign states.</p> <p> "It is normal cooperation in law enforcement and security, and consistent with international law and international customary practices," Zhao said, adding the security cooperation between the two countries is open and transparent and does not target any third party. It proceeds in parallel with the Solomon Islands' existing cooperation with other partners and regional mechanisms and conforms to the common interests of the Solomon Islands and the South Pacific region.</p> <p> "What we really need to worry about is the fact that Australia, without communication and consultation with the Pacific Island countries, pieces together military blocs and stimulates the arms race together with countries like the United States and the United Kingdom, and brings nuclear proliferation risks to the South Pacific region," Zhao said.</p> <p> "It is the deeds of Australia that is neither open nor transparent, which countries in the region are deeply concerned about," Zhao said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China slams U.S. for leaving unexploded bombs in Southeast Asia ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095528</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095528.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:17:58 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson Zhao Lijian on Wednesday slammed the United States for leaving tens of thousands of tonnes of unexploded bombs in Southeast Asian countries.</p> <p> "During the Vietnam War, the United States used cluster bombs and bio-chemical weapons and committed heinous crimes in Southeast Asian countries including Vietnam, Laos and Cambodia," Zhao told a regular press briefing.</p> <p> According to Cambodian media reports, a U.S.-made explosive device weighing almost one tonne and containing more than 500 kg of explosives was recently uncovered opposite the Royal Palace in the capital Phnom Penh. In April this year alone, at least five unexploded U.S. aerial bombs were discovered in Cambodia, each weighing more than 200 kilograms.</p> <p> In response to a question on the topic, Zhao said that the United States released more than 15 million tonnes of bombs, landmines and shells in Vietnam, of which about 80,000 tonnes are unexploded and remain scattered over nearly 20 percent of the country's territory, which has killed more than 40,000 people and wounded more than 60,000 since the end of the Vietnam War.</p> <p> "In Laos, the U.S. troops dropped 270 million bombs, weighing 2 million tonnes in total, meaning one tonne or 135 bombs for each person in the country," Zhao said.</p> <p> According to incomplete data from Yale University, from October 1965 to August 1973, the United States dropped 2.7 million tonnes of ordnance on Cambodia, said the spokesperson. Statistics from the Cambodian government show that from 1979 to 2021, nearly 20,000 people were killed and more than 45,000 people were crippled by unexploded ordnance including landmines.</p> <p> "History has proven that the United States is a destroyer of rules and order, a maker of violence and conflict, and a perpetrator of coercive diplomacy," Zhao said.</p> <p> He said it is a typical U.S.-style double standard for the United States to pin the labels of "coercion" and "militarization" on others while forming small cliques and instigating confrontation in the name of democracy, human rights and rules.</p> <p> "What the United States defends is its own hegemony and the 'rules of the gang' at the expense of the fundamental interests of small and medium-sized countries," the spokesperson said.</p> <p> It is the common aspiration of regional countries and the shared hope of the international community to seek peace, solidarity and cooperation rather than turmoil, division and confrontation, Zhao said.</p> <p> Noting that attempts to provoke bloc confrontation and create turbulence and tension will gain no support, Zhao said Asian countries will never allow the region to be used as a chessboard for major power rivalry or a chess piece for major power confrontation.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese envoy warns against more sanctions on DPRK ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095449</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0512/c90000-10095449.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 08:28:01 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> UNITED NATIONS, May 11 (Xinhua) -- A Chinese envoy on Wednesday warned against attempts to impose more sanctions on the Democratic People's Republic of Korea (DPRK).</p> <p> Dialogue and consultation is the only correct way to resolve the Korean Peninsula issue. The United States is a direct party to the issue and holds the key to breaking the deadlock. As such, it should take concrete actions to respond positively to the reasonable concerns of the DPRK and create conditions for an early resumption of dialogue, said Zhang Jun, China's permanent representative to the United Nations.</p> <p> Although the U.S. side claims to be willing to engage in unconditional dialogue, when it comes to actions, it is continuing to tighten sanctions and exert pressure. This is clearly not constructive, he told the Security Council. "The new draft resolution proposed by the United States, evoking Chapter VII of the UN Charter, is centered on furthering sanctions, which is not an appropriate way to address the current situation on the peninsula."</p> <p> The Security Council, over the years, has adopted numerous resolutions on the issue, which, while authorizing sanctions, have also stressed the need for a peaceful, political, and diplomatic solution to the nuclear issue on the Korean Peninsula. All these deserve equal attention, said Zhang.</p> <p> "Sanctions are but a means to an end, and should always serve the overall goal of political settlement. Equating sanctions to or replacing diplomatic efforts is completely putting the cart before the horse, and will not achieve the desired result," he said. "Despite the fact that sanctions have already had a negative humanitarian impact and collateral damage to other countries, the countries concerned are still in total denial, which is inconsistent with the conclusions of various international humanitarian agencies and the 1718 (DPRK Sanctions) Committee's panel of experts."</p> <p> In response to the latest situation, China and a number of Security Council members have all put forward reasonable proposals to explore ways to take strong actions and promote the political solution to the Korean Peninsula issue, in a way that best garners the consensus of council members. The draft resolution tabled by China and Russia is for this very purpose. Regrettably, the United States, which is the penholder of the DPRK non-proliferation issue, has turned a blind eye to the reasonable proposals of China and other relevant council members, and remains enamored superstitiously with the magic power of sanctions, said Zhang.</p> <p> "We believe that if the United States changes its negative attitude, it is possible for council members to reach a consensus. We hope that the council members will give serious consideration to the joint China-Russia draft resolution," he said.</p> <p> The issue of the Korean Peninsula should be looked at historically and comprehensively so as to understand the causes and consequences of the matter at hand. After 2018, there had been a general de-escalation of the situation. The DPRK took a series of measures to denuclearize and de-escalate the situation. The leaders of the DPRK and the United States met in Singapore and reached agreement on establishing a new type of DPRK-U.S. relations, building a peace mechanism on the peninsula, and advancing the denuclearization process. Regrettably, the U.S. side later reneged on its position, and did not reciprocate the DPRK's positive initiatives in accordance with the action-for-action principle, leading to an intractable impasse in the DPRK-U.S. dialogue, adding to the mutual distrust between the two countries, and stalling the denuclearization process, said Zhang.</p> <p> As a close neighbor, China is highly concerned about the situation on the Korean Peninsula, and has always insisted on maintaining peace and stability on the peninsula, denuclearizing the peninsula, and resolving problems through dialogue and consultation, he said. "We advocate that all parties concerned should prioritize the overall peace and stability on the peninsula, adhere to the direction of dialogue and consultation, meet each other halfway, resume meaningful dialogue at an early date, and explore effective ways to resolve each other's legitimate concerns in a balanced manner."</p> <p> China is seriously concerned about some recent negative developments, he said.</p> <p> Some countries are calling for the denuclearization of the DPRK, while they themselves are promoting cooperation on nuclear submarines, which carries serious risks of nuclear proliferation. Some countries profess their concerns about the DPRK's military development, while at the same time developing with much fanfare their own offensive weapons system such as hypersonic weapons. A certain politician in a certain country concerned even went so far as to openly advocate discussing nuclear sharing under the pretext of addressing security threats, he noted.</p> <p> China's Global Security Initiative is an important guide to resolving the issue of the Korean Peninsula. Security is indivisible. The security of one country cannot be based on the insecurity of another country. Such a concept works anywhere, anytime, he said.</p> <p> China once again calls on all parties concerned to jointly cherish and maintain peace and stability on the peninsula, work together to promote the establishment of a peace mechanism and denuclearization process on the peninsula, and play a constructive role to this end, Zhang said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ U.S. urged to adhere to one-China principle ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095246</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095246.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 15:28:48 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 11 (Xinhua) -- A Chinese government spokesperson on Wednesday warned the U.S. government against moves that deviate from the one-China principle.</p> <p> Zhu Fenglian, a spokesperson for the Taiwan Affairs Office of the State Council, made the remarks in response to a recent update to the "Taiwan fact sheet" displayed on the website of the U.S. Department of State, which removed wording on not supporting "Taiwan independence" and acknowledging China's position that Taiwan is part of China.</p> <p> Zhu said some people in the Taiwan region are playing up this issue, in an attempt to garner U.S. support for independence. "Such a move will not change the fact that Taiwan is a part of China."</p> <p> She also urged the U.S. government to adhere to the one-China principle and comply with the stipulations of the three China-U.S. joint communiques with concrete actions.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Second 2022 BRICS Think Tank Symposium Held ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095138</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095138.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 11:35:00 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205111130000526901657162.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 506px;" /></p> <p> On May 6, 2022, the second BRICS Think Tank Symposium was held in Chongqing both online and offline. The theme of this conference is “BRICS Cooperation and Global Development: New Era, New Mission, New Plan”, which was hosted by China Council for BRICS Think-tank Cooperation(CCBTC), the Chinese coordinator for BRICS think tank cooperation, and organized by Sichuan International Studies University, the vice-chairman organization of CCBTC. Think tank scholars and business representatives from BRICS countries carried out in-depth exchanges and discussions under the theme.</p> <p> Jin Xin, Secretary-General of CCBTC, director-general of the Research Office of the International Department of the CPC Central Committee, Ma Ranxi, Deputy Director-General of Publicity Department of Chongqing Committee of CPC and Director of Information Office of Chongqing Municipal Government, and Dong Hongchuan, President of Sichuan International Studies University delivered speeches respectively. Jin Xin said that at present, the shadow of a once-in-a-century pandemic and the conventional security risks are intertwined. Adjustments over the global governance system and the international landscape have gathered pace. The recovery of the world economy is weak and faltering, and the global development gap is widening. Amidst the great changes of the world, the era and the history, the international community, especially developing countries, is in dire need of economic recovery and common development, and generally hope to emerging market countries including BRICS to play a greater role in promoting economic recovery and common development. As China holds the rotating chair of the BRICS this year, it takes “Foster High-quality BRICS Partnership, Usher in a New Era for Global Development” as the theme of 2022 BRICS cooperation, with the hope to work with all BRICS countries to respond to the major concerns of the international community and build a more comprehensive, closer, more practical and more inclusive BRICS partnership to jointly achieve stronger, greener and sounder global development. Under new circumstances, in order to further deepen BRICS cooperation and promote common development: first, we should give priority to development and jointly promote economic recovery; second, we need to commit ourselves to inclusive development and focus on bridging the development gap; third, we should uphold innovation as the driver of growth and work together to achieve leapfrog development; fourth, we must adhere to green development and accelerate transformation towards green and low-carbon development.  </p> <p> Ma Ranxi said that local-level cooperation among BRICS countries is of great significance. Cooperation at the local level is counted as an important and specific means to promote BRICS practical cooperation, and can provide new ideas and suggestions from the bottom up to national-level cooperation. Chongqing, as a strategic stronghold of China’s western region development and a connection between “Belt and Road” initiative and the Yangtze River Economic Belt, will further expand pragmatic cooperation, people-to-people and cultural exchanges with other BRICS members, and provide more and stronger drivers for BRICS cooperation and global development by promoting local-level exchanges.</p> <p> Dong Hongchuan said that Sichuan International Studies University is an important base for foreign language education, foreign-related personnel training, as well as foreign language and culture, foreign economic and trade, and international studies in southwest China. It will continue to deeply involve itself in BRICS think-tank international exchanges and cooperation, build a base for think tank consultation, personnel training, and people-to-people exchange for BRICS research in western China, and make due contributions to promoting BRICS cooperation.   </p> <p> Zhu Chaowei, vice president of Sichuan International Studies University, Xu Xiujun, researcher of Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, Zhu Jiejin, professor of Fudan University, Sun Yiran, researcher of Shanghai Academy of Social Sciences, Jiang Shixue, distinguished professor of Shanghai University, Miao Jun, deputy general manager of Power China International Group Limited, Zhang Zhengping, rotating chairman of Chongqing Sokon Industrial Group Co., Ltd, and other Chinese think tank and business representatives believe that in the past 16 years, BRICS countries have made remarkable achievements in establishing New Development Bank and BRICS PartNIR innovation center, and formulating Strategy for BRICS Economic Partnership 2025. In the future, BRICS countries should continue to strengthen coordination in various fields of global governance, lead cooperation with development, promote security with development, raise their voice with development, and realize the role change from participants to leaders of global development , from hitchhikers to defenders and builders of international order , and from global public goods demanders to suppliers.    </p> <p> Think tank scholars and representatives from international institutions, such as Applied Economic Research of Brazil, Higher School of Economics of Russia, Observer Research Foundation, Gateway House of India, University of Johannesburg of South Africa, and ECLAC/UN Office in Brasilia, believe that in order to achieve the sustainable development goals, BRICS countries need to further deepen cooperation, conduct dialogue and exchanges with a more open mindset, mobilize their own resources, and work in synergy. On the one hand, BRICS countries should carry out domestic structural reforms, strive to change development modes, policies and models, vigorously develop human capital and social capital, coordinate competition objectives, and achieve fair development on the basis of law and regulations. On the other hand, BRICS countries should always adhere to multilateralism, promote effective global economic governance, and jointly counter the downward pressure and risks of the economy by improving mutual investment complementarity and carrying out scientific and technological innovation cooperation.</p> <p> <span style="color:#a9a9a9;"><em>（Source: International Department. Central Committee of CPC)</em></span></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi sends congratulatory message to Hungary's new president Katalin Novak ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095037</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095037.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 09:58:11 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping on Tuesday sent a congratulatory message to Katalin Novak on her taking office as the Hungarian president.</p> <p> The development of China-Hungary relations, Xi said, has maintained at a high level in recent years, marked by frequent high-level exchanges, fruitful cooperation in various fields and sound cooperation in international and regional affairs.</p> <p> Xi said he attaches great importance to the development of China-Hungary relations, adding that he is ready to work with Novak to deepen political mutual trust and traditional friendship between the two countries.</p> <p> Xi also called for joint efforts to strengthen cooperation between the two countries both at the bilateral level and within the Belt and Road cooperation, the China-Central and Eastern European countries cooperation and other frameworks, and to promote the China-Hungary comprehensive strategic partnership to a new level so as to benefit the two countries and their peoples.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China slams U.S. for changing Taiwan wording on State Department website ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095030</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095030.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 09:58:06 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- A Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson on Tuesday slammed the United States for changing wording related to Taiwan on its State Department website, saying the move will hollow out the one-China principle and will backfire.</p> <p> Spokesperson Zhao Lijian made the remarks when asked to comment on a recent update to the Taiwan fact sheet displayed on the website of the U.S. Department of State, which removes wording both on not supporting Taiwan independence and on acknowledging China's position that Taiwan is part of China.</p> <p> "There is but one China in the world, and Taiwan is an inalienable part of China's territory, with the Government of the People's Republic of China as the sole legal government of China," Zhao said, noting that these facts are the consensus of the international community and are universally recognized norms governing international relations.</p> <p> "The U.S. has made solemn commitments on the Taiwan question and the one-China principle in the three China-U.S. joint communiques," Zhao noted, saying that changing the wording on Taiwan is an act of political manipulation and an attempt to change the status quo in the Taiwan Strait, which will backfire and the U.S. itself will get burnt.</p> <p> Zhao urged the United States to abide by the one-China principle and the stipulations of the three China-U.S. joint communiques, as well as the political commitments it made to China on the Taiwan question.</p> <p> "The U.S. side should put into practice President Biden's statement that the U.S. does not support 'Taiwan independence,' and cease all political manipulation on Taiwan-related issues or any attempt to contain China with the Taiwan question," Zhao said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China, South Korea agree to boost pragmatic cooperation ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095023</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095023.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 09:57:45 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205110945000121026991172.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 640px;" /></p> <p> <em>Visiting Chinese Vice President Wang Qishan meets with South Korea's newly sworn-in President Yoon Suk-yeol in Seoul, South Korea, May 10, 2022. As Chinese President Xi Jinping's special representative, Wang attended the inauguration ceremony of Yoon earlier in the day. (Xinhua/Li Tao)</em></p> <p> SEOUL, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Visiting Chinese Vice President Wang Qishan and South Korea's newly sworn-in President Yoon Suk-yeol agreed on Tuesday to further bilateral ties and pragmatic cooperation.</p> <p> As Chinese President Xi Jinping's special representative, Wang attended the inauguration ceremony of Yoon earlier in the day. During the meeting with Yoon, Wang conveyed Xi's cordial greetings and best wishes to him.</p> <p> China and South Korea, as close neighbors and important partners, have witnessed all-round and rapid development in bilateral relations with increasing common interests since the establishment of diplomatic ties, Wang said, adding that in the face of a changing world and a pandemic unseen in a century, it's of greater importance for both sides, the region and the whole world to strengthen China-South Korea cooperation.</p> <p> China is willing to work with South Korea to continuously lift the China-South Korea strategic cooperative partnership to a higher level and in keeping with the times, he stressed.</p> <p> Wang proposed a five-point proposal on the next development of bilateral relations.</p> <p> Firstly, China and South Korea should enhance strategic communication and high-level exchanges, as well as further invigorate dialogue and exchanges at all levels.</p> <p> Secondly, the two sides should deepen pragmatic cooperation, strengthen the alignment of development strategies of the two countries, and deepen cooperation in key areas and third-party markets to upgrade bilateral cooperation.</p> <p> Thirdly, as China and South Korea are geographically linked, their peoples are connected by kinship and cultures enjoy a natural affinity, the two countries should give full play to this advantage and take the 30th anniversary of diplomatic ties and the China-South Korea Year of Cultural Exchanges as an opportunity to plan and implement more activities conducive to enhancing people-to-people friendship, so as to continuously inject positive energy into the growth of bilateral ties.</p> <p> Fourthly, the two countries should strengthen communication and coordination in international and regional affairs, be committed to upholding multilateralism and the free trade system, and promote regional and global development and prosperity.</p> <p> Fifthly, the two sides should jointly boost coordination and cooperation in the Korean Peninsula affairs and properly handle sensitive issues. China sincerely supports the two sides of the Korean Peninsula in improving relations and promoting reconciliation and cooperation, and stands ready to cement communication with South Korea to advance the denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and promote lasting peace on the peninsula.</p> <p> For his part, Yoon asked Wang to send his best regards to President Xi.</p> <p> Since the establishment of diplomatic ties, the two countries have witnessed rapid progress in the development of bilateral relations, and the two-way trade has reached an all-time high despite the COVID-19 pandemic, Yoon said.</p> <p> He noted that the South Korean government, on the basis of mutual respect, is ready to take the 30th anniversary of diplomatic ties as an opportunity to promote closer high-level strategic communication and exchanges at all levels, further strengthen exchanges and cooperation in all areas and enhance the people-to-people friendship, so as to usher in a new era for bilateral relations.</p> <p> South Korea is willing to strengthen communication and coordination with China to jointly promote peace, stability and prosperity on the Korean Peninsula, he added.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China congratulates on smooth Philippine presidential race: spokesperson ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095026</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095026.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 09:57:33 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- China congratulates the Philippines on the smooth holding of the presidential election and also congratulates the leading candidates, a foreign ministry spokesperson said Tuesday.</p> <p> Spokesperson Zhao Lijian made the remarks at a daily press briefing when asked to comment on the issue. Initial results show that presidential candidate Ferdinand Marcos Jr. and vice presidential candidate Sara Duterte-Carpio are poised to win.</p> <p> China hopes and believes that all political forces in the Philippines will continue to work together for national renewal and development, Zhao said.</p> <p> Calling the two countries "good partners of mutually beneficial cooperation," Zhao said under the strategic guidance of the two heads of state, bilateral relations have been steadily upgraded and have taken on a new look of vigorous development, benefiting the two peoples and making positive contributions to regional peace and stability.</p> <p> China is ready to work with the Philippines to continue to uphold good-neighborliness and friendship, focus on post-pandemic development, expand win-win cooperation, and bring more tangible benefits to the two peoples, the spokesperson said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China urges U.S. to respect sovereignty, dignity of Latin American countries ]]></title>
	<news_id>10095025</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10095025.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 09:57:33 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- The Summit of the Americas cannot simply serve U.S. self-interest, a Chinese foreign ministry spokesperson said Tuesday, urging the United States to respect the sovereignty and dignity of Latin American countries.</p> <p> Spokesperson Zhao Lijian made the remarks at a regular press briefing when answering a query about Cuba, Nicaragua and Venezuela possibly being excluded from the summit that will be hosted by the United States in Los Angeles in June.</p> <p> "The summit cannot solely apply American standards or serve U.S. self-interest. It cannot be reduced to an American summit," Zhao said.</p> <p> "Next year will mark the 200th year since the U.S. proposed the Monroe Doctrine," Zhao added, noting that the United States has not been a supporter of Latin American countries and has bullied them at will.</p> <p> The spokesperson said that not only has the United States failed to benefit Latin American countries, but it has also exploited them, imposed sanctions against them, exported inflation to them, engaged in political interference, regime subversion and political assassination in them, and even launched armed aggression against them.</p> <p> Despite opposition from the international community and regional countries, the United States insists on maintaining unilateral and illegal sanctions against some Latin American countries, smears the legitimate actions of Latin American countries to cooperate with other countries to seek development, and lacks basic respect for Latin American countries, Zhao said.</p> <p> "We hope the U.S. side will earnestly respect the sovereignty and dignity of Latin American countries, and earnestly abide by the basic norms governing international relations," Zhao said, adding that there is no market for the Monroe Doctrine in Latin America, or anywhere in the world.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China, Thailand vow to strengthen cooperation between legislatures ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094996</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10094996.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 09:56:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205110933000353055225116.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 597px;" /></p> <p> <em>Wang Chen, a member of the Political Bureau of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and vice chairman of the National People's Congress (NPC) Standing Committee, meets with Suchart Tancharoen, first deputy speaker of the House of Representatives of Thailand, via video link in Beijing, capital of China, May 10, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhang Ling)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Wang Chen, vice chairman of the National People's Congress (NPC) Standing Committee, met with Suchart Tancharoen, first deputy speaker of the House of Representatives of Thailand, via video link on Tuesday.</p> <p> Wang said that under the strategic guidance of the leaders of the two countries, the China-Thailand traditional friendship has become more profound and flourishing, and the two countries have firmly supported each other on issues concerning their core interests and major concerns.</p> <p> He added that China is ready to work with Thailand to give full play to the positive role of the legislatures, strengthen exchanges and mutual learning in rule of law, and advance the implementation of the Global Development Initiative and Global Security Initiative, contributing to the development of bilateral relations and enhancing friendship between the two peoples.</p> <p> Suchart Tancharoen said Thailand firmly upholds the one-China policy, expressing hopes to deepen exchanges between the legislatures of the two countries and provide a sound legal environment for bilateral practical cooperation.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205110934000547485809065.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> <em>Wang Chen, a member of the Political Bureau of the Communist Party of China Central Committee and vice chairman of the National People's Congress (NPC) Standing Committee, meets with Suchart Tancharoen, first deputy speaker of the House of Representatives of Thailand, via video link in Beijing, capital of China, May 10, 2022. (Xinhua/Zhang Ling)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ HKSAR gov't strongly refutes G7, EU statements on chief executive election ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094965</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10094965.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 09:04:25 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> HONG KONG, May 10 (Xinhua) -- The Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (HKSAR) government on Tuesday strongly refuted statements on the HKSAR's sixth-term chief executive election made by the foreign ministers of the Group of Seven (G7) countries and the EU high representative for foreign affairs and security policy.</p> <p> "We strongly oppose those unfounded criticisms and misleading comments on the chief executive election contained in the two statements," said a spokesperson for the HKSAR government, adding that they reflect a blatant interference in China's internal affairs including Hong Kong affairs, and are clearly out of line with international norms.</p> <p> Any allegation that the improved electoral system has weakened democracy in the governance of Hong Kong is misguided. On the contrary, the electoral system has broadened representation in the electorate for the chief executive election through expanding the Election Committee from 1,200 members from four sectors to 1,500 members from five sectors, the government spokesperson added.</p> <p> Likewise, under the improved electoral system, the Legislative Council's representativeness has been boosted. Its members are now returned by the Election Committee constituency, the functional groups in the functional constituencies, and direct elections in the geographical constituencies. This enables all social sectors to be represented in a fair and balanced manner, according to the spokesperson.</p> <p> "We strongly believe that improving the electoral system, ensuring 'patriots administering Hong Kong' and safeguarding the overall interests of society are conducive to the stable development of Hong Kong's democracy," the spokesperson said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Nine out of 10 Chinese see friendly China-ASEAN ties ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094925</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10094925.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 08:46:50 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> <strong>Nearly 80% consider US as ‘biggest disruptor’: GT survey</strong></p> <p align="center"> <img alt="Photo taken on Sept. 10, 2021 shows a view of the Nanning International Convention and Exhibition Center, the venue of the 18th China-ASEAN Expo and China-ASEAN Business and Investment Summit, in Nanning, capital of south China's Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region. The 18th China-ASEAN Expo and China-ASEAN Business and Investment Summit kicked off on Sep 10, in Nanning, highlighting the building of a closer China-ASEAN community with a shared future. Photo: Xinhua" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/51/9115663383985517959.jpg" /></p> <p> <em>Photo taken on Sept. 10, 2021 shows a view of the Nanning International Convention and Exhibition Center, the venue of the 18th China-ASEAN Expo and China-ASEAN Business and Investment Summit, in Nanning, capital of south China's Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region. The 18th China-ASEAN Expo and China-ASEAN Business and Investment Summit kicked off on Sep 10, in Nanning, highlighting the building of a closer China-ASEAN community with a shared future. Photo: Xinhua</em></p> <p> While China-related topic is expected to dominate the upcoming US-ASEAN summit, a recent survey showed that nearly 80 percent of Chinese respondents said the US is the biggest disruptor of the sound relations between China and ASEAN members but about 90 percent considered the China-ASEAN ties as friendly and over 75 percent hold a positive attitude toward their future.</p> <p> The survey was jointly conducted by the Global Times Research Center and Centre for Chinese Foreign Strategy Studies, Renmin University of China between March 15 and April 15 in 31 Chinese provinces, regions and municipalities among the general public aged 18 to 69 and college students. It collected 2,012 valid questionnaires from the general public and 1,150 from college students.</p> <p> About 61.8 percent of the respondents said they have a good impression of ASEAN, and those who have visited ASEAN members share high scores in terms of the impression about the region. On average, the level of affection of the Chinese public toward ASEAN, with a 3.8 score, is much higher than the other blocs and countries. The level for the EU is 3.2 and that for the US is 2.4.</p> <p> Most of the college students are impressed by the ASEAN's rich resources and culture. They also share a higher level of affection for the region than for the US, EU, Australia, Japan and other countries and regions.</p> <p> "Those results showed that China and ASEAN have developed very successful relations in the past two to three decades," Lü Xiang, research fellow at the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, told the Global Times. This results from the ramped-up efforts of China's diplomacy toward Southeast Asia.</p> <p> The survey also shows that although fewer Southeast Asian countries share divergences with China on questions like the South China Sea, those conflicts are under control, and have not become "the mainstream tone" for bilateral ties. The Chinese public supports and trusts China's policy and its relations with ASEAN, Lü said.</p> <p> Positive momentum</p> <p> Although 10 ASEAN members share vast differences, China has been handling the relations with them pretty well, either from diplomatic efforts or the infrastructure cooperation under the China-proposed Belt and Road Initiative, which all laid the foundation for the positive momentum in China-ASEAN ties, experts said.</p> <p> Over 90 percent of the respondents said they are interested in ASEAN, and nearly two-third of them share very high interests. For example, the culture and arts of the region have become a great attraction for the Chinese public. The region's business and trade, technology, nature, history and sports attract about 40 percent of the respondents, according to the survey.</p> <p> Among the surveyed college students, 54.3 percent said they know ASEAN and over 50 percent said they know the region's politics, geography, culture and economy.</p> <p> Some 90.4 percent of the respondents said China-ASEAN relations are "friendly" and over two-thirds took it as "very friendly" and "relatively friendly."</p> <p> "Those survey results are in line with Chinese people's objective perception of the development of China-ASEAN relations," Xu Liping, a research fellow on Southeast Asian studies at the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences in Beijing, told the Global Times recently.</p> <p> In China's neighboring diplomacy, ASEAN occupies a very important position, Xu said, noting that ordinary Chinese will have a higher degree of favorability and affinity for ASEAN, compared with Europe and the US.</p> <p> "This objectively shows that there is a strong internal driving force for the development of China-ASEAN relations, and strengthening cooperation and friendly people-to-people exchanges will continue to be the mainstream of bilateral relations," he said.</p> <p> While over 75 percent of the respondents hold a positive view toward the future development of China-ASEAN ties, the question of the South China Sea has become a major focus of China-ASEAN ties, which has been hyped and manipulated by countries like the US and Japan in stirring conflicts between China and ASEAN. And nearly 80 percent of the public surveyed said that the US is the biggest disruptor of the development of China-ASEAN relations.</p> <p> While the Chinese public shares high interests in ASEAN members, Singapore has become the country that attracted them the most. The average score of affection and interest for Singapore is above 4, with the highest score of 5, followed by Malaysia and Thailand , which both scored 3.8.</p> <p> Chinese students are most attracted by Singapore, and then Thailand and Malaysia.</p> <p align="center" style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="How Chinese view China-ASEAN relations Graphic: Deng Zijun/GT" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/31/13314858190647753623.png" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; height: 875px; width: 500px;" /></p> <p align="center" class="pictext"> <em>How Chinese view China-ASEAN relations Graphic: Deng Zijun/GT</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese VP attends SK president inauguration, showing sincerity in furthering ties amid US Indo-Pacific strategy push ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094920</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10094920.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 08:45:16 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Chinese Vice President Wang Qishan on Tuesday attended the inauguration of South Korean President Yoon Suk-yeol, reflecting China's wish to further relations and cooperate with South Korea to cope with challenges to regional stability and prosperity despite the US' continuous efforts to draw South Korea closer to its geopolitical camp and Indo-Pacific Strategy.</p> <p> Observers have predicted some adjustment and challenges in China-South Korea relations after the power transition in Seoul, considering the US' activities to sow discord and Yoon's remarks of enhancing South Korea's alliance with the US during the election campaign.</p> <p> US President Joe Biden will stop first in South Korea on May 20 during his first Asian trip since taking office to "highlight the US focus on Indo-Pacific," said White House official Kurt Campbell on Monday. Biden will then visit Tokyo and attend a QUAD summit there.</p> <p> The US has been putting much effort on winning over South Korea and engaging Seoul into its geopolitical camp, said Da Zhigang, director of the Institute of Northeast Asian Studies at Heilongjiang Provincial Academy of Social Sciences.</p> <p> Knowing South Korea won't easily join the security pact of QUAD and serve US interests at the expense of its ties with China, the US offered the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework (IPEF) to attract South Korea, while South Korea is interested in more platforms to communicate with Southeast Asia in regard to trade and supply chains, Da told the Global Times on Tuesday.</p> <p> The IPEF was proposed by the US in October 2021 and is expected to formally launch later this month. The South Korean government has decided to join the IPEF, a decision reflecting its intention to take a leading role in regional trade as an initial member of the framework, Business Korea reported Tuesday.</p> <p> The US' blueprint in the Asia-Pacific is to contain China's development by involving as many regional countries as possible to marginalize China in politics, economy and security. Yet other countries will prioritize their national interests rather than solely serve the US' needs, said Li Haidong, a professor from the Institute of International Relations at the China Foreign Affairs University in Beijing.</p> <p> China welcomes all its neighbors to develop balanced relations with other countries on an equal basis, as long as such relations do not harm China's interests, experts said.</p> <p> Yang Xiyu, a senior research fellow at the China Institute of International Studies, told the Global Times that China doesn't need to form its own camp to counter US' small cliques, but should maintain strategic confidence. "China is committed to building a better model -- a global system featuring equality, openness and win-win cooperation."</p> <p> China and South Korea are facing challenges and opportunities internally and externally, and should forge closer ties to jointly cope with those challenges, contributing Asian wisdom to global governance, experts said.</p> <p> For the new government, the major test is how to make best use of the diplomatic legacy of the Moon Jae-in administration, managing South Korea's foreign relations amid the US-China rivalry, properly handling the increasingly complicated geopolitical realities to maximize South Korea's interests, observers said.</p> <p> Vice President Wang met with Yoon after attending the latter's inauguration. Wang delivered President Xi Jinping's greetings to Yoon and raised suggestions on bilateral relations in the next phase.</p> <p> The two sides should enhance strategic communication and high-level exchanges, deepen practical cooperation in key fields and with third party market, hold more activities to enhance people-to-people friendliness, strengthen communication and coordination on regional and international affairs to safeguard multilateralism and free trade, and cooperate on the Korean Peninsula issue and properly handle sensitive topics, Wang said.</p> <p> Yoon asked Wang to deliver his greetings to Xi. Yoon said South Korea is willing to increase high-level exchanges, enhance cooperation of different areas, and push bilateral relations into a new chapter.</p> <p> Da noted the attendance of such a high-level Chinese official to the inauguration is unprecedented in China-South Korea relations, and fully demonstrates China's sincerity in further developing ties.</p> <p> Yoon's tone on many topics in his inauguration speech was softer than in his election campaign. It may take one to two months to observe Yoon's policy based on not only his remarks but also the new government's deeds, Da said.</p> <p> But as long as the two countries uphold the principle of mutual respect, wisely handle sensitive topics and push forward cultural exchanges to enhance mutual understanding, relations will remain stable, the expert said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China-donated Sinovac vaccine doses, medical equipment reach Benin ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094888</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10094888.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 08:34:16 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" border="0" src="/mediafile/pic/BIG/20220511/23/15380687527497077819.png" /></p> <p> <em>The Charge d'Affaires a.i. of the Chinese Embassy in Benin Yan Yan (R, Front) presents medical equipment to the cabinet director of the Beninese Ministry of Health Petas Akogbeto (L, Front) in Cotonou, Benin, on May 10, 2022. Benin on Tuesday received a batch of Sinovac COVID-19 vaccines as well as medical equipment donated by the Chinese government. (Photo by Seraphin Zounyekpe/Xinhua)</em></p> <p> COTONOU, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Benin on Tuesday received a batch of Sinovac COVID-19 vaccines as well as medical equipment donated by the Chinese government.</p> <p> The handover document was signed by the Charge d'Affaires a.i. of the Chinese Embassy in Benin Yan Yan and the cabinet director of the Beninese Ministry of Health Petas Akogbeto in Cotonou, a port city of Benin, Tuesday afternoon.</p> <p> This donation is composed of doses of Sinovac vaccine and syringes, x-ray machines, multi-parameter monitors, electric syringe pumps, medical beds, ECG devices and several resuscitation respirators.</p> <p> Speaking during the signing ceremony, Yan said that the support of China to Benin in the health sector is a living manifestation of the deep cooperation between the two governments and the deep friendship between the two peoples.</p> <p> "China and Benin are friends and brothers, which have very good cooperation in the health field to fight against the COVID-19 epidemic," he said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China urges G7 to cease interfering in its internal affairs ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094860</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10094860.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 08:30:15 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0511/FOREIGN202205110817000530201513751.jpeg" style="width: 900px; height: 728px;" /></p> <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- A Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson on Tuesday urged certain Western countries to immediately cease interfering in China's internal affairs after the Group of Seven (G7) foreign ministers and a European Union official expressed grave concerns over the chief executive election in Hong Kong.</p> <p> John Lee, 64, former chief secretary for administration of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (HKSAR) government, on Sunday won the first chief executive election since the improvement of the region's electoral system in 2021.</p> <p> "Certain Western countries and institutions are conspiring with each other to slander the election and grossly interfere in China's internal affairs. China expresses firm opposition to this and strongly condemns it," Foreign Ministry spokesperson Zhao Lijian told a regular news briefing.</p> <p> Some countries have ignored the fact that Hong Kong's democracy has improved and that mainstream public opinion seeks unity and prosperity, Zhao said.</p> <p> "They sound like 'preachers of democracy' when they point fingers at Hong Kong's democratic elections, its high degree of autonomy, and its human rights and freedoms, which only exposes their double standards and their attempt to bring chaos to Hong Kong and contain China," he said.</p> <p> "Hong Kong is China's Hong Kong. What kind of electoral system Hong Kong implements and what kind of democratic development path it explores are issues that fall entirely under the scope of China's internal affairs, and no external forces have the right to interfere," Zhao said.</p> <p> He said the Chinese government is resolved to fully and faithfully implement the "one country, two systems" principle and develop high-quality democracy suited to Hong Kong's reality, and any attempt from external forces to undermine this will be in vain.</p> <p> He expressed confidence that Hong Kong will usher in a new era of good governance that leads to prosperity.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi talks with Macron over phone ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094839</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0511/c90000-10094839.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 08:14:30 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping spoke with French President Emmanuel Macron on the phone on Tuesday afternoon.</p> <p> Xi noted his close contact with Macron over the past five years, which has helped guide the two countries in sustaining the positive momentum of bilateral ties, conducting fruitful cooperation, and fulfilling the responsibilities of major countries on climate change, biodiversity conservation and other issues.</p> <p> In a world undergoing changes unseen in a century, China and France, two permanent members on the United Nations Security Council and independent major countries, should uphold "independence, mutual understanding, strategic vision and win-win cooperation," a commitment the two sides made when establishing diplomatic relations, stick to their close and enduring comprehensive strategic partnership, respect each other's core interests and major concerns, and strengthen coordination and cooperation in the bilateral, China-Europe and global contexts, he said.</p> <p> Xi added that China will keep close exchanges with France at all levels to promote the healthy growth of China-France relations and maintain world peace and stability.</p> <p> Xi stressed the need to identify, through bilateral dialogue mechanisms, cooperation priorities in the coming five years. He called on the two sides to step up cooperation in emerging areas including artificial intelligence and clean energy, while advancing cooperation in traditional areas like civilian nuclear energy, and aerospace.</p> <p> The Chinese president said China is ready to import more quality products from France, welcomes French financial and hi-tech companies to China for business cooperation, and hopes that the French side will provide a fair, equitable and non-discriminatory business environment for Chinese enterprises that conduct investment and cooperation in France.</p> <p> Xi said that it is important that China and France make good use of big occasions like the 60th anniversary of China-France diplomatic relations and the Paris Olympics, both to take place in 2024, as important opportunities to further increase people-to-people and cultural exchanges and enhance mutual understanding.</p> <p> He added that the two sides should follow true multilateralism, uphold the international system with the United Nations at its core and the international order based on international law, support multi-polarity and economic globalization, and deepen cooperation on climate change and biodiversity.</p> <p> Xi stressed that the two sides need to increase communication and coordination at the Group of 20 and on global food and energy security, expand trilateral cooperation in Africa and other regions, and explore cooperation on the Global Development Initiative and the Global Security Initiative.</p> <p> The Chinese president pointed out that the steady and sound growth of China-EU relations serves the interests of people in China, in Europe and in all other countries, adding that China appreciates France's commitment to strategic autonomy, and hopes that France will encourage the EU to keep a right perception of China and work with China in the same direction by managing differences properly and building on converging interests for closer cooperation in economy and trade, green and digital development, and people-to-people exchanges.</p> <p> Xi also expressed his hope for France, who holds the rotating presidency of the EU, to play a positive role in promoting the sound development of China-EU relations.</p> <p> For his part, Macron commended the open spirit with which the two sides have developed their relations since establishing diplomatic ties.</p> <p> Over the past five years, the two sides have carried out fruitful cooperation across the board, Macron said.</p> <p> For the next five years, France will work with China to deepen cooperation in areas including agriculture, aviation, civilian nuclear energy and culture and to scale up cooperation in climate change and biodiversity, with a view to greater achievements in France-China relations, said the French president.</p> <p> France is willing to play a positive role in the development of EU-China relations, he added.</p> <p> The two leaders also exchanged views on the situation in Ukraine and agreed that relevant parties should support Russia and Ukraine in restoring peace through negotiations.</p> <p> Xi stressed that China has been working in its own way to promote peace talks, and that China supports European countries in keeping the security of Europe in their own hands.</p> <p> He urged vigilance against bloc confrontation, which poses a bigger and more persistent threat to global security and stability.</p> <p> Macron noted the many common understandings between France and China on the issue of Ukraine, adding that France stands ready for closer coordination and cooperation with China at both bilateral and multilateral levels.</p> <p> France and the EU are committed to strategic autonomy and will not endorse or take part in bloc confrontation, he said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Liaison office of central gov't slams G7 foreign ministers' statement on HKSAR chief executive election ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094716</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094716.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 16:25:35 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> HONG KONG, May 10 (Xinhua) -- The Liaison Office of the Central People's Government in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (HKSAR) on Tuesday firmly rejected and strongly condemned the comments by the foreign ministers of the Group of Seven (G7) countries and the European Union High Representative for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy.</p> <p> Their statement smeared the HKSAR's sixth-term chief executive election, and attacked the Chinese central government's policies towards Hong Kong, said a spokesperson for the office.</p> <p> The ministers and the EU high representative have turned a blind eye to the structural flaws of their own democratic systems, and wantonly attacked the HKSAR's chief executive election and the Chinese government's implementation of the "one country, two systems" policy, said the spokesperson, calling their statement a serious violation of international laws and the basic norms of international relations.</p> <p> The statement is full of arrogance and prejudice, ignoring the fact that the chief executive election was conducted in accordance with the law and that the result of the fair election is in line with Hong Kong people's aspirations, the spokesperson noted.</p> <p> The success of the sixth-term chief executive election has further implemented the principle of "patriots administering Hong Kong," fully demonstrated the advantages of HKSAR's new electoral system, and proved the new system is a good one that follows the "one country, two systems" principle and suits Hong Kong's realities, the spokesperson said.</p> <p> A Hong Kong with enduring stability and prosperity is not only in the interest of all Hong Kong people but also in the interest of the international community, according to the spokesperson.</p> <p> Any political manipulation and arbitrary intervention by external forces will not shake the Chinese central government's firm determination to comprehensively and accurately implement the "one country, two systems" principle, nor will they undermine the overall situation of Hong Kong's prosperity and stability, the spokesperson stressed.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xiplomacy: Xi committed to strengthening China-Germany relations, China-EU ties ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094687</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094687.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 16:06:12 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Chinese President Xi Jinping had a virtual meeting with German Chancellor Olaf Scholz on Monday, calling for joint efforts to leverage the stabilizing, constructive and steering role of their relationship.</p> <p> During the meeting, Xi also expressed his hope that Germany will play a positive role in developing a steady and sound China-EU relationship.</p> <p> On various occasions, Xi has elaborated on the importance of strengthening China-Germany relations as well as China-EU ties. The following are some highlights of Xi's remarks in this regard.</p> <p> May 9, 2022</p> <p> In the virtual meeting with Scholz, Xi said both China and Germany are major countries with important influence.</p> <p> Under the current circumstances, it is particularly important for the two countries to maintain sound and steady growth of bilateral ties and better harness the stabilizing, constructive and steering role of this relationship, Xi said.</p> <p> This not only serves the interests of the Chinese and German peoples but will also contribute significantly to world peace and tranquility, Xi added.</p> <p> Xi underscored that China and the EU are comprehensive strategic partners and each other's opportunity, and that the two sides have far more common interests than differences.</p> <p> It is important that the two sides, with a dialectical and long-term view, with mutual respect and with the right perception, increase communication and enhance mutual trust, Xi said.</p> <p> March 8, 2022</p> <p> During a virtual summit with French President Emmanuel Macron and Scholz, Xi noted that China and the EU share much common understanding on promoting peace, seeking development and advancing cooperation.</p> <p> Xi said it is important for the two sides to enhance dialogue, stay committed to cooperation, and promote steady and sustained progress of China-EU relations.</p> <p> China's development will create broader space for China-EU cooperation, Xi said, adding that the two sides must, under the principle of mutual benefit and win-win, further deepen green and digital partnerships as well as practical cooperation in various fields.</p> <p> Dec. 21, 2021</p> <p> In a phone conversation with Scholz, Xi said China attaches great importance to its relations with Germany, noting that the two countries should chart the general course of bilateral relations from a strategic perspective.</p> <p> Over the past half century, China-Germany relations have demonstrated ample vitality, endurance, resilience and potential, Xi said, adding that for the next 50 years, the two countries should embrace a global vision from a long-term perspective, forge ahead and strive for new development of China-Germany relations.</p> <p> Dec. 8, 2021</p> <p> In a congratulatory message to Scholz on his election as German chancellor, Xi said he is willing to work with Scholz to promote the bilateral ties to a new level.</p> <p> China and Germany are all-round strategic partners, Xi noted, adding that over the years, they have been adhering to mutual respect, seeking common ground while shelving differences and pursuing win-win cooperation, which has yielded results benefiting the two countries, their people and the world.</p> <p> Facing the major changes and a pandemic both unseen in a century, China and Germany have strengthened communication and cooperation, jointly supported the global fight against COVID-19 and promoted economic recovery, demonstrating their sense of responsibility as major countries, Xi said.</p> <p> Oct. 13, 2021</p> <p> During a virtual meeting with then German Chancellor Angela Merkel, Xi and Merkel reviewed the development of China-German and China-EU relations in recent years.</p> <p> Noting that 2022 marks the 50th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations, Xi said that keeping bilateral ties on the right course is of crucial importance.</p> <p> "China always views its relationship with Germany from a strategic and long-term perspective, and is ready to maintain high-level exchanges with the German side, promote mutual understanding and friendship between the two peoples, tap the potential for cooperation in traditional fields, while exploring new areas of pragmatic cooperation in energy transition and the green and digital economy, among other areas, to further advance bilateral ties," Xi said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China decries Japanese politician's comments on Taiwan ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094681</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094681.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 16:05:58 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <center> <video controls="controls" poster=" http://flvimage.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsimage/2022/5/10/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_56a924d2105d7fca7bb9ac2f6c7dde4c.jpeg" src="http://flv4.people.com.cn/videofile7//pvmsvideo/2022/5/10/HaiWaiChuanBoBu-ZhongWenXing_97380c8f83a3a86f67beba7cfd0b852d.mp4" style=" width: 830px; height:550px;"> <p> &nbsp;</p> </video> </center> <p> China firmly opposes countries with established diplomatic relations with China having any form of official contact with Taiwan, a Ministry of Foreign Affairs spokesperson said on Monday.</p> <p> Ministry spokesperson Zhao Lijian made the announcement in response to Japan Liberal Democratic Party member Suzuki Norikazu decrying Chinese mainland military aircraft entering Taiwan’s so-called “air defense identification zone.”</p> <p> "The Taiwan issue is an internal affair of China, not of Japan, so there is no need for Japanese individuals to force themselves into the spotlight," Zhao said.</p> <p> <em>(Compiled by Meng Gaohan; video edited by Teng Jiade)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily App</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China, UNHCR distribute humanitarian supplies to Afghanistan ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094651</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094651.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 14:43:07 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> KABUL, May 10 (Xinhua) -- A batch of humanitarian supplies, provided by China's South-South Cooperation Assistance Fund in cooperation with the United Nations Refugee Agency (UNHCR), have been distributed in Afghanistan on Monday.</p> <p> Speaking at the distribution ceremony held in the Afghan capital Kabul, Economic and Commercial Counselor of the Chinese embassy in Afghanistan Hu Guo'ai said China and Afghanistan are friendly neighbors linked by mountains and rivers, with exchanges between the two countries dating back to more than 1,000 years ago. The Chinese government has been highly concerned about the Afghan people who are suffering from a humanitarian crisis, and has continuously provided them with humanitarian assistance such as food, clothing, vaccines, tents and medicines.</p> <p> China's South-South Cooperation Assistance Fund provided funds for buying emergency relief supplies and supporting local education for vulnerable groups in Afghanistan. The batch of supplies purchased and distributed by the UNHCR includes kitchenware, blankets and gas tanks, the counselor said.</p> <p> All the supplies have been distributed all over Afghanistan, Hu said, adding the needy Afghans will get relief with the supplies.</p> <p> Kari, the representative of the recipient party and head of the Kabul Education Department, expressed his sincere gratitude to China for its long-term assistance to Afghanistan.</p> <p> Kari noted that China's assistance has greatly improved the learning conditions of Afghan students and will inspire them to study with more enthusiasm.</p> <p> Some 19.7 million Afghans were facing acute hunger, according to an analysis conducted in January and February by Food Security and Agriculture Cluster partners, including the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO), United Nations World Food Programme (WFP) and many non-governmental organizations.</p> <p> The FAO and the WFP said on Tuesday that they have provided humanitarian assistance to millions of people in Afghanistan, and are scaling up their programs to assist and support needy families.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China, Germany set to prosper from collaboration, mutual trust ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094626</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094626.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 14:07:45 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BERLIN, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Officials and business leaders in Germany pin great hopes on the collaboration and mutual trust between China and Germany, which they believe are key to the growth and prosperity of the two countries, which mark their five decades of diplomatic ties this year.</p> <p> China has been Germany's most important trading partner for six years in a row, starting from 2015, Germany's Federal Statistical Office (Destatis) said. In just 10 years' time from 1980 to 1990, China surged from the 35th to 14th place among the most important importers for Germany.</p> <p> "China's importance for German imports is growing steadily," Destatis noted.</p> <p> China is one of the world's most important growth markets and also an important partner for Germany in tackling global challenges such as the COVID-19 pandemic and climate change, said Juergen Friedrich, chairman and chief executive officer (CEO) of Germany Trade &amp;Invest, the country's foreign trade and inward investment agency.</p> <p> The aggregate volume of bilateral trade reached a new record in 2021, Friedrich said, adding that German companies in China "continue to express investment intentions, including the localization of production and research and development" in China.</p> <p> Noting that this year marks the 50th anniversary of the establishment of China-Germany diplomatic relations, Oliver Zipse, chairman of the Board of Management of BMW AG, said, "Our experience in China is a good example of successful collaboration between the two countries and between China and Europe."</p> <p> "From our perspective, collaboration and mutual trust are key to addressing the ongoing challenges that lie ahead for all of us. And they are key to creating growth and prosperity," he added.</p> <p> The future prospects are further brightened by China's policy decisions, said Zipse. "Looking ahead, we are encouraged by China's pledge to further open its market, as well as its efforts to promote green development and innovation."</p> <p> German companies attach great importance to practical and mutually beneficial cooperation with China and derive tangible benefits from their cooperation with China, said Wang Weidong, chief of the Economic and Commercial Department at the Chinese Embassy in Germany.</p> <p> Wang told Xinhua that German companies have a great interest in expanding and deepening their economic and trade cooperation with China.</p> <p> "China and Germany have made important achievements in their cooperation over the past 50 years for the benefit of the people of both countries and the world, and this mutually beneficial cooperation is particularly valuable in the turbulent situation facing the world today," Wang said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Group of Friends of Global Development Initiative holds high-level meeting ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094613</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094613.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 14:07:37 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> UNITED NATIONS, May 9 (Xinhua) -- The Group of Friends of the Global Development Initiative (GDI) on Monday held a high-level virtual meeting with the participation of Chinese State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi and UN Secretary-General Antonio Guterres.</p> <p> In a keynote speech delivered virtually, Wang called for an equal and balanced global development partnership and for support of the United Nations' overall coordination function in the implementation of the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development.</p> <p> Guterres, in a video message, called for joint efforts to advance the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).</p> <p> "We can't lose more ground. It's time to rescue the SDGs and give sustainable development a fighting chance -- for people, for planet, for our common future," he said.</p> <p> Participants in the high-level segment spoke highly of China's leading role in promoting sustainable development, and expressed their strong support for the GDI and the hope that the Group of Friends members will work together to deepen cooperation in priority areas so as to facilitate global development.</p> <p> In the discussion segment, representatives of the Group of Friends appreciated the convening of the high-level meeting and expected the group to expand and deepen practical cooperation.</p> <p> In concluding remarks, Zhang Jun, China's permanent representative to the United Nations, said the high-level meeting has not only pointed the way for future cooperation, but also strengthened confidence in the development of the group.</p> <p> "With today's meeting, the GDI has taken another step forward at the United Nations. Next, the group will continue its work centered around the three key areas of strengthening policy dialogue, sharing best practices, and promoting practical cooperation," he said.</p> <p> At the same time, he said, in light of the new situation, the group will also focus on the four areas of effectively addressing global crises, facilitating the implementation of the UN development agenda, deepening South-South cooperation, and tapping the potential of resources.</p> <p> The GDI Group of Friends was launched by China's Permanent Mission to the United Nations in January 2022.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China-proposed GDI platform to accelerate implementation of SDGs: Pakistani FM ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094455</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094455.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 10:01:18 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> ISLAMABAD, May 10 (Xinhua) -- Pakistani Foreign Minister Bilawal Bhutto Zardari has appreciated the China-proposed Global Development Initiative (GDI), dubbing it a useful platform to accelerate and coordinate efforts for implementing the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).</p> <p> While addressing the high-level virtual meeting of the Group of Friends of the GDI on Monday, Zardari expressed concerns over the reversal of progress in the implementation of SDGs, owing to multiple crises caused by the COVID-19 pandemic, climate change and geopolitical conflicts, according to the Foreign Ministry of Pakistan.</p> <p> He urged the Group of Friends of the GDI to address the challenges faced by the developing world and support emergency actions to increase cooperation in public health and vaccine equity, ensure food security, enhance energy production, promote a global green economy, stimulate trade and industrialization, and eliminate the digital divide, the ministry said in a statement.</p> <p> Multiple crises have enlarged the gap in financing for development, he said, adding that the international community should mobilize adequate resources for SDGs and fulfill the commitment of providing at least 100 billion U.S. dollars annually in climate finance.</p> <p> In his address, Zardari reaffirmed his country's resolve to further strengthen its all-weather strategic cooperative partnership with China, including through the rapid implementation of the China-Pakistan Economic Corridor (CPEC), a flagship project of the Belt and Road Initiative, the statement added.</p> <p> "Pakistan will continue its efforts to enhance cooperation with China through CPEC, to advance its national implementation of SDGs, in addition to participating actively in the work of the GDI Group of Friends to promote the common aspiration of a peaceful, prosperous and shared future for all mankind," he said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese vice president meets with S. Korean president ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094421</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094421.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 09:52:02 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0510/FOREIGN202205100941000561289514527.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 636px;" /></p> <p> <em>Visiting Chinese Vice President Wang Qishan meets with South Korea's outgoing President Moon Jae-in in Seoul, South Korea, May 9, 2022. Wang, Chinese President Xi Jinping's special representative, arrived here to attend the inauguration ceremony of President-elect Yoon Suk-yeol. (Xinhua/Li Tao)</em></p> <p> SEOUL, May 9 (Xinhua) -- Visiting Chinese Vice President Wang Qishan met with South Korea's outgoing President Moon Jae-in on Monday, saying China-South Korea relations have made significant progress over the past five years.</p> <p> Wang, Chinese President Xi Jinping's special representative, arrived here to attend the inauguration ceremony of President-elect Yoon Suk-yeol.</p> <p> Noting that this year marks the 30th anniversary of diplomatic relations, and the China-South Korea Year of Cultural Exchanges, Wang said the two countries have maintained close high-level exchanges, deepened practical cooperation and maintained smooth multilateral communication and coordination.</p> <p> The Chinese and South Korean economies are highly integrated, Wang said, adding that in particular, economic cooperation between the two countries managed to grow amid the sluggish global economy last year, demonstrating the resilience and great potential of bilateral economic cooperation.</p> <p> Wang said China and South Korea are close neighbors and major cooperative partners with broad common interests.</p> <p> "No matter how the international and regional situation changes, the fundamentals of China-South Korea friendly cooperation will not change and cannot be changed, which is an important inspiration from the history of bilateral relations," he noted.</p> <p> Wang said China is willing to join hands with South Korea in pushing forward the China-South Korea strategic cooperative partnership to benefit people of the two countries.</p> <p> China appreciates South Korea's important contributions to improving inter-Korean relations and promoting the political settlement of the Korean Peninsula issue, Wang said, noting that China stands ready to enhance communication and coordination with South Korea to make joint efforts to realize the denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and lasting peace and stability in the region at an early date.</p> <p> For his part, Moon said that over the past five years, South Korea-China relations have overcome difficulties and achieved development, expressing his hope that the next government will maintain such a momentum.</p> <p> South Korea speaks highly of China's constructive role in the Korean Peninsula affairs, Moon said, adding that the country is ready to work with China to take the 30th anniversary of diplomatic ties as an opportunity to further strengthen communication, expand cooperation and continuously enhance mutual understanding between the two peoples, so as to lift bilateral ties to a higher level.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0510/FOREIGN202205100943000252455070997.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 674px;" /></p> <p> <em>Visiting Chinese Vice President Wang Qishan meets with South Korea's outgoing President Moon Jae-in in Seoul, South Korea, May 9, 2022. Wang, Chinese President Xi Jinping's special representative, arrived here to attend the inauguration ceremony of President-elect Yoon Suk-yeol. (Xinhua/Li Tao)</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ NED is actually "second CIA" of U.S.: FM spokesperson ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094413</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094413.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 09:40:14 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 9 (Xinhua) -- The National Endowment for Democracy (NED), which takes orders directly from the U.S. government and manipulates NGOs through the provision of funding to conduct subversion, infiltration and sabotage to serve U.S. strategic interests, is actually the "second CIA" of the United States, a Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesperson said on Monday.</p> <p> Spokesperson Zhao Lijian made the remarks at a regular press briefing when asked about the Fact Sheet on the National Endowment for Democracy released by the Chinese Ministry of Foreign Affairs on Saturday.</p> <p> The fact sheet, with about 12,000 words in six sections, lays bare the true face of NED through hundreds of specific incidents gathered from public reports, Zhao said.</p> <p> He said the United States has long used democracy as a tool and a weapon to undermine democracy in the name of democracy, to incite division and confrontation, and to meddle in other countries' internal affairs, causing catastrophic consequences.</p> <p> "NED, as one of the U.S. government's main 'foot soldiers' and 'white gloves', has subverted lawful governments and cultivated pro-U.S. puppet forces under the pretext of democracy," Zhao said.</p> <p> NED was seen behind color revolutions instigated and orchestrated by the United States, including the disintegration of the Soviet Union, the Rose Revolution in Georgia, the Orange Revolution in Ukraine and the Arab Spring, Zhao said, adding that NED has been stirring up protests and demonstrations in Thailand, inciting the opposition parties in Nicaragua to seize power by force, funding anti-Cuba forces to manipulate public sentiment against the government, and long interfering in Venezuela's internal affairs through various means.</p> <p> "Hellbent on disrupting the world, NED has not brought social stability and development or contented lives and good work to other countries. On the contrary, it has caused a host of issues including withered livelihood, languishing economy and social confrontation," Zhao said.</p> <p> NED also extends its evil hand to China and invests heavily in anti-China programs every year to incite "Xinjiang independence," "Hong Kong independence," and "Tibet independence" activities by various means, said the spokesperson.</p> <p> "It also colludes with 'Taiwan independence' forces and attempts to incite division and disrupt stability across the Taiwan Strait, which has been met with indignation and opposition from the Chinese people on both sides of the Strait," Zhao said.</p> <p> Noting NED is actually the "second CIA" of the United States, Zhao said it is by no means an NGO that provides support for democracy abroad.</p> <p> "We believe the international community will see its true face more and more clearly, and more countries will expose its ugly track record in various forms," said the spokesperson.</p> <p> Noting peace and development remains the theme of our times, Zhao said those that meddle in other countries' domestic affairs are doomed to fail no matter what disguise they use.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China calls for global cooperation on fighting drought, desertification ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094402</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094402.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 09:37:36 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 9 (Xinhua) -- Chinese State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi on Monday called for enhanced international cooperation on fighting drought and desertification.</p> <p> Wang, as the special representative of Chinese President Xi Jinping, made the remarks via video link at a leaders' meeting on drought and sustainable land governance.</p> <p> He said that since the outbreak of the COVID-19 epidemic, developing countries have faced severe challenges in their economies and people's livelihoods, and the task of coordinating development and environmental protection is arduous.</p> <p> "Breaking the vicious circle of poverty and desertification and truly realizing the harmonious coexistence of man and nature requires the concerted efforts of the international community to find a better solution," Wang said.</p> <p> He listed solutions in three areas, as suggested by the Chinese side.</p> <p> First, international cooperation should be enhanced, Wang said, adding that developing countries, especially African countries, are facing more severe drought and desertification, and the international community should lend a helping hand.</p> <p> Second, green development should be firmly promoted, he said. Food security, climate governance and green development are the key areas of cooperation in the Global Development Initiative proposed by President Xi, which calls for efforts to alleviate drought and achieve sustainable land governance. China welcomes the active participation of all parties, said Wang.</p> <p> Third, international rules should be effectively improved, Wang said.</p> <p> "We should actively respond to the drought issues that African countries are concerned about, continuously develop and improve drought-control rules, and build a fair and reasonable desertification-control system," he said.</p> <p> Wang stressed that China is committed to jointly building a green Belt and Road, and through mechanisms such as the Forum on China-Africa Cooperation and South-South cooperation, China will work with African countries to promote the construction of a green Africa.</p> <p> The leaders' meeting on drought and land sustainable governance is a high-level meeting of the 15th session of the Conference of the Parties (COP15) of the United Nations Convention to Combat Desertification (UNCCD), hosted by Cote d'Ivoire.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ External interference in Hong Kong affairs doomed to be self-defeating: Commissioner's office of Chinese foreign ministry in HKSAR ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094407</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094407.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 09:35:46 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> HONG KONG, May 9 (Xinhua) -- The Office of the Commissioner of the Chinese Foreign Ministry in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (HKSAR) on Monday firmly rejected and strongly condemned the misleading comments of the foreign ministers of the Group of Seven (G7) countries and the European Union High Representative for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy.</p> <p> Their comments smeared the HKSAR's sixth-term chief executive election, the Chinese central government's policies towards Hong Kong, and Hong Kong's new electoral system, said a spokesperson for the office.</p> <p> The spokesperson pointed out that John Lee's winning of the HKSAR's six-term chief executive election by an overwhelming majority of votes fully reflected the great support for him by Hong Kong society.</p> <p> This successful election showed the new atmosphere under the new electoral system, displayed an upbeat mood of Hong Kong seeking unity and progress, and once again demonstrated the superiority of the new electoral system, the spokesperson said.</p> <p> Noting that more than 1,400 representatives, elected by various sectors, cast their votes in the election, and they widely represented different industries and interest groups, the spokesperson said the election is a whole-process democratic practice that fits Hong Kong's reality and features Hong Kong characteristics.</p> <p> The spokesperson said that the new electoral system of the HKSAR fully and faithfully implements the policy of "one country, two systems" and the HKSAR Basic Law, enforces the principle of "patriots administering Hong Kong," and develops quality democracy with Hong Kong characteristics.</p> <p> The spokesperson pointed out that the so-called "democratic elections" in some Western countries are essentially "elite" elections and political shows in which money talks.</p> <p> These countries only care about the election cycle, political party interests, and group interests, the spokesperson said.</p> <p> "They know how to look good during campaigning but fail to govern effectively after being elected," the spokesperson said. "They don't have in mind the fundamental and long-term interests of their people, which usually result in short-sighted policies and inefficient governance."</p> <p> Ignoring the structural deficiencies of their own democratic system and claiming to be "models of democracy," these pretentious countries are obsessed with pointing a finger at the democracy and human rights situation of others, and engaging in "wolf-pack tactics" to interfere in others' internal affairs, according to the spokesperson.</p> <p> "We fully believe the patriotic governance team elected under the new electoral system will unite and lead all sectors of Hong Kong society to open a new chapter for the city, and Hong Kong will certainly embrace new glory at a new starting point," the spokesperson said.</p> <p> "Any attempt to undermine Hong Kong's prosperity and stability will be in vain," the spokesperson stressed.</p> <p> The office urged the G7 politicians to respect the historical trend, abide by the principles of international law such as non-interference in others' internal affairs and the basic norms governing international relations, discard ideological prejudices and hypocrisy, stop interfering in China's internal affairs including Hong Kong affairs in any form, and no longer damage Hong Kong's prosperity and stability.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese spokesperson slams Western countries smearing Hong Kong election ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094401</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094401.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 09:33:10 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 9 (Xinhua) -- A Chinese spokesperson on Monday slammed a small number of Western countries' acts of smearing the latest election in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (HKSAR), the region's new electoral system, and the Chinese government's policy for the HKSAR.</p> <p> The just-concluded election of the sixth-term chief executive of the HKSAR represents a new success of Hong Kong in developing democracy that is suitable to its own conditions, said a spokesperson for the Hong Kong and Macao Affairs Office of China's State Council in a statement.</p> <p> The winner of the election received widespread trust and support of the general public in Hong Kong, said the spokesperson, noting that the groundless accusations by some Western countries will never distort solid facts.</p> <p> Certain politicians from a few Western countries have been pointing fingers at Hong Kong, which is nothing but an attempt to disrupt Hong Kong and contain China, said the spokesperson.</p> <p> However, these nonsensical talks will never stop Hong Kong's turnaround from chaos to stability and prosperity, the spokesperson added.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China calls for equal, balanced global development partnership ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094399</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094399.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 09:29:04 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, May 9 (Xinhua) -- Chinese State Councilor and Foreign Minister Wang Yi on Monday called for an equal and balanced global development partnership.</p> <p> Wang made the remarks when addressing the high-level virtual meeting of the Group of Friends of the Global Development Initiative (GDI).</p> <p> Noting that more than 100 countries expressed support, and as many as 53 countries have joined the Group of Friends, Wang said it fully shows that the GDI responds to the call of the times and meets the needs of various countries.</p> <p> Implementation of the United Nations 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development is the biggest consensus on global development, Wang said, adding that it should therefore continue to be a priority on the international cooperation agenda.</p> <p> Wang said all parties must honor their pledges and realize the 17 Sustainable Development Goals on schedule, oppose the politicization and marginalization of the development issue, continue to focus on the key areas most important to developing countries, and redouble efforts to raise living standards across the world.</p> <p> Wang called for creating a favorable environment to accelerate global development, improving the global governance system at a faster pace, increasing the representation and voice of emerging markets and developing countries, and building an open world economy.</p> <p> "It is important to uphold the right of people of all countries to choose their own development paths, and oppose interference in other countries' internal affairs and unilateral sanctions without basis in international law," Wang added.</p> <p> On building an equal and balanced global development partnership, Wang said developed countries should fulfill their development assistance pledges and scale up support in financing and technology.</p> <p> Developing countries need to deepen South-South cooperation and realize leapfrog development, Wang added, calling for more effective help from multilateral development institutions.</p> <p> Wang also called on all parties to support UN in giving full play to its overall coordination function in the implementation of the 2030 Agenda.</p> <p> China will enhance consultation with other emerging markets and developing countries, and hold a high-level meeting on global development at a proper time to discuss ways to promote development, Wang said.</p> <p> Wang also said that China will increase input in development, and further ramp up support for the South-South Cooperation Assistance Fund and the China-UN Peace and Development Fund.</p> <p> China will also build on the consensus to establish a pool of GDI projects to be participated by all parties, and release a Global Development Report in due time to promote international exchanges and sharing of development knowledge, Wang added.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Nepalese expert: CPC leads Chinese people to better life ]]></title>
	<news_id>10094367</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2022/0510/c90000-10094367.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 08:56:05 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> When the reporter walked into his office, Harish Chandra Shah, President of&nbsp;Nepal China Cultural and Educational&nbsp;Council, just finished a day’s work.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0510/FOREIGN202205100842000250312398134.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 460px;" /></p> <p> <em>Harish Chandra Shah, President of Nepal China Cultural and Educational Council, delivers a speech at an activity held by the council to celebrate the Chinese Lunar New Year, March 2018.</em></p> <p> Harish was voluble on topics about China. “I took all these photos in China. There is a story behind each of them,” he said, pointing at dozens of photos displayed in a bookcase in his office.</p> <p> Harish, his father and children have all forged a special bond with China. “My father paid a visit to China when I was little. After he returned home, he told me that the Chinese people are kind and hospitable and that China is the most reliable and a true friend of Nepal, which greatly influenced me. I always wanted to visit China since I was young,” he said.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0510/FOREIGN202205100842000397804636588.jpg" style="width: 498px; height: 640px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Harish Chandra Shah, President of&nbsp;Nepal China Cultural and Educational&nbsp;Council.</em></p> <p> In 1977, then 20-year-old Harish went to study in China. In the following seven years, he lived and studied in Beijing, and toured Hebei and Sichuan provinces and other places in China, witnessing how China took its first steps in implementing reform and opening-up.</p> <p> After he got back home, Harish chose a job that promotes friendly exchanges between Nepal and China. Because of his influence, Harish’s son and daughter also studied in China, and his wife has taught herself Mandarin. “Our family can speak with each other in fluent Mandarin,” Harish told People’s Daily.</p> <p> Harish shared with the reporter his visit to a village in southwest China’s Yunnan province.</p> <p> “In 2019, I took an investigation tour of a village near Kunming, capital city of Yunnan province, as a member of an investigation group. The local people have become better off by growing vegetables and flowers, some of which are sold to Malaysia and Indonesia. As the village speeds up development, new school, clinic and elderly care center have been built and residents have lived a better life,” Harish noted.</p> <p> Harish learned from local residents that the village was really poor just a few years ago and that it has been with the help and under the guidance of resident officials sent to the village for poverty alleviation that the village has taken on a new look.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0510/FOREIGN202205100842000555766423249.png" style="width: 600px; height: 399px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Nepal begins administering COVID-19 vaccines donated by China, April 2021. (Photo/Beijing Daily)</em></p> <p> “When I was there, I felt villagers’ heartfelt support for these resident officials and for the Communist Party of China (CPC). Only such a political party that adheres to a people-centered approach and leads the people to a better life can be popular with and supported by the people,” Harish pointed out.</p> <p> Three volumes of the English edition of “Xi Jinping: The Governance of China” were placed in a conspicuous spot in the bookcase in Harish’s office. The book series by Chinese President Xi Jinping have answers to all the questions related to the miracles in modern China, according to him.</p> <p> “I joined in the translation of the book series into Nepali. During the process, I consulted a large number of materials, from which I gained a better understanding of the Chinese leader’s foresight in governance and how he always keeps the people close to his heart,” Harish said.</p> <p> Harish pointed out that the lasting friendship between Nepal and China has been built on the basis of mutual respect and assistance.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2022/0510/FOREIGN202205100843000208711256180.png" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /></p> <p> <em>Members of a traffic rescue team of the Chinese People’s Armed Police Force, together with Nepalese workers, repair road damaged by an earthquake in Nepal, May 2015. (People’s Daily Online/Xie Jiang and Lu Wenkai)</em></p> <p> After a major earthquake hit Nepal in 2015, China stood firmly with the Nepalese people in Nepal’s disaster relief and post-disaster reconstruction. While overcoming difficulties and fulfilling its commitments to Nepal, China helped the latter achieve positive results in earthquake relief.</p> <p> During the global fight against the COVID-19 pandemic, China has also lent a hand to Nepal and provided COVID-19 vaccines for the country just when it was in need of them.</p> <p> “China has provided vaccines for and donated anti-epidemic supplies to us. Such timely and heart-warming help truly demonstrates the close friendship between our two countries,” Harish noted.</p> <p> According to Harish, China has not only provided vaccines for other developing countries including Nepal to close the “immunization gap”, but carried out win-win cooperation with many other countries in the joint construction of the Belt and Road to stabilize global economic development and actively practice the idea of building a community with a shared future for mankind.</p> <p> “I believe that with the joint efforts of the two governments and peoples, the Nepal-China friendship will bear more fruits,” he said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
	</channel>
</rss>